<page>
    <shortlink>application server settings advanced</shortlink>
    <topic>Advanced Settings</topic>
    <description>Advanced settings for configuring the Application Server.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Advanced settings tab</title>
                <link>images/advancedSettings.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Settings</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Systray Caption</name>
                    <description>The text to display in the Systray caption for the server.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum URI Length (bytes)</name>
                    <description>The maximum length of a URI that the server can receive in bytes.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>IP Address Binding</name>
                    <description>The maximum allowed requests per Keep-Alive connection before using a new connection.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>MIME Types File</name>
                    <description>The location of the MIME types file. The default name of the MIME types file is *[ui:MIMETypes.xml]*. MIME types can be extended by adding them to the MIME types file.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>License Lease</name>
                    <description>Settings for configuring the length of the license lease.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Lease Lifetime</name>
                            <description>Specify the lifetime of the license lease in minutes. Default value is 15.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Temporary Files</name>
                    <description>Configure how the server handles temporary file clean-up.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Remove files older than</name>
                            <description>Temporary files older than the specified number of minutes will be removed. Default value is 15.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Read Timeouts</name>
                    <description>Defines the maximum amount of time to wait for a response for a request header or request body.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Request Headers</name>
                            <description>Specify the read timeout for request headers in seconds. Default value is 30.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Request Body</name>
                            <description>Specify the read timeout for the request body in seconds. Default value is 60.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Build-In Resources</name>
                    <description>Control whether or not built-in resources are used.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>AJAX URL Processing</name>
                            <description>Enable or disable Ajax URL processing.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Internal Image Library</name>
                            <description>Enable or disable the use of the internal Alpha Anywhere image library.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Alpha Software Favicon</name>
                            <description>If checked, the Alpha Software favicon will be used in web applications.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Alpha JavaScript Library</name>
                            <description>Enable or disable the use of the Alpha Anywhere JavaScript Library.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Sessions</name>
                    <description>Options for controlling how the Application Server handles sessions.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Cookie Name</name>
                            <description>Default value is 'A5WSessionId'.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Lifetime in minutes</name>
                            <description>The length of a session, specified in minutes. If a session is inactive for longer than the specified time, it expires. Default value is 15.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Same Site Mode</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Same Site Mode]* specifies how cookies are served from the Application Server for cross-origin requests.</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Mode</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Unset</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is not set and is not sent with requests.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>None</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is set to "None". Cookies are sent in all contexts, including cross-origin. A SameSite policy of "None" requires [SSL].</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Lax</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is set to "Lax". Cookies are allowed to be sent in top-level navigation and in GET requests to third-party websites.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Strict</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is set to "Strict". Cookies are only sent in first-party context. Cookies are not sent to third-party websites.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                                <p>To learn more about Same Site cookies and solutions for common warnings, see *[extlink:SameSite Cookies (MDN)@https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Set-Cookie/SameSite]*</p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>You must set the Same Site policy to *[Unset]* or *[None]* if you are deploying PhoneGap Applications that must communicate with the Application Server.</p>
                            </important>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Transfer Maximums</name>
                    <description>Specify limitations for file upload (POST) and downloads.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Maximum file download size (MB)</name>
                            <description>The maximum file size allowed for download in MB. Default is 512.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Maximum POST body size (MB)</name>
                            <description>The maximum size permitted for a POST body in MB. Default is 32.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Automatic Log Rotation</name>
                    <description>Configure the application server to rotate log files daily or when the log file grows to a maximum size.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Rotate Daily</name>
                            <description>When enabled, log files will be rotated daily.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Rotate By Size</name>
                            <description>Rotate log files when a specified file size limit is reached.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Log File Size Limit (KB)</name>
                            <description>Defines the maximum size of a log file for the *[ui:Rotate By Size]* behavior.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Advanced Logging</name>
                    <description>Advanced logging options for tracing socket data and thread transitions.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Trace Socket Data</name>
                            <description>Enables logging of socket data. Socket logging should be turned off in a production environment.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Log Thread Transitions</name>
                            <description>Enables logging of Xbasic thread transitions. Thread logging should be turned off unless explicitly requested by Alpha Software for use in debugging.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="application server settings ssl">SSL</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="application server settings logging">Logging settings</ref>
    </see>
</page>