<page>
    <shortlink>alpha anywhere standard application server settings</shortlink>
    <topic>Configuring and Running the Classic Application Server</topic>
    <description>Overview of configuring and running the Classic Application Server and Development Server. The Application Server settings control the server behavior, including configuring TLS/SSL, custom error pages, HTTP Publishing, and security.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <description>The Application Server delivers web pages containing web components to your Internet users. It also handles Ajax requests from web and mobile applications built with Alpha Anywhere.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You use the Web Component Builder to build components (which know how to retrieve and display your data). Then you use the HTML Editor to place the components into HTML pages (with the .A5W extension). Finally, the Application Server delivers standard HTML, CSS, and JavaScript pages to your Internet connected users.</description>
            <note>At least one user must be logged onto the Windows computer hosting the Application Server for it to run. Consider the Application Server for IIS if you need to run as a Windows service with no users logged in.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Starting and Stopping the Server</title>
            <description>The Application Server must be started in order to receive requests. To start the Application Server:</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Open the Application Server settings dialog. For the Development Server, the settings dialog is found under *[ui:Web]* &gt; *[ui:Development Server]* on the *[ui:Web Projects Control Panel]*. For the Classic Application Server, click the Systray icon to open the settings dialog or right-click the Systray icon and select *[ui:Configure Server]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Development Server settings are found under the Web menu on the Web Projects Control Panel.</title>
                        <link>images/openDevServer.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Classic Application Server can be configured by clicking on the Systray icon after the Application Server has been launched</title>
                        <link>images/openServerStart.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:Start Server]* to start the server.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/startServer1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If prompted, click *[ui:Yes]* to confirm the action.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/startServer2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To stop the server:</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Open the Application Server settings dialog. For the Development Server, the settings dialog is found under *[ui:Web]* &gt; *[ui:Development Server]* on the *[ui:Web Projects Control Panel]*. For the Classic Application Server, click the Systray icon to open the settings dialog or right-click the Systray icon and select *[ui:Configure Server]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Development Server settings are found under the Web menu on the Web Projects Control Panel.</title>
                        <link>images/openDevServer.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Classic Application Server can be configured by clicking on the Systray icon after the Application Server has been launched</title>
                        <link>images/openServerStop.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:Stop Server]* to stop the server.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/stopServer1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If prompted, click *[ui:Yes]* to confirm the action.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/stopServer2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Classic Application Server can also be started and stopped through the right-click context menu available for the Systray icon. Right-click on the systray icon to open the menu and select *[ui:Stop server]* or *[ui:Start server]* to stop or start the server.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Select "Start server" to start the server</title>
                <link>images/contextServerStart.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>Select "Stop server" to stop the server</title>
                <link>images/contextServerStop.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Application Server Settings</title>
<!--list:.-->
<!--order:
General
Logging
Alerts
Access and Errors
TLS/SSL
Performance
Advanced
Other
-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Application Server's control panel is accessed by going to *[ui:Web]* &gt; *[ui:Development Server]* from within the Alpha Anywhere development environment or by selecting *[ui:Configure Server]* from the context menu for the Alpha Anywhere Classic Application Server's Systray icon.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Select Settings from the Systray right-click context menu or click the systray icon to open the Application Server settings dialog.</title>
                <link>images/configureServer.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Application Server Settings dialog is where the server is configured and controlled. Starting and stopping the server is as simple as using the Start Server and Stop Server buttons on this dialog box or on the System toolbar.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The Application Server Settings dialog.</title>
                <link>images/serverSettingsDialog.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>