<page>
    <shortlink>application server settings logging</shortlink>
    <topic>Logging Settings</topic>
    <description>The Logging tab controls the logging behavior of the Application Server. </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Logs are used to detect issues with applications and debug problems. </p>
        <p>When diagnosing problems with applications, Alpha Software may ask for logs from the Application Server. The Logging Settings can be used to enable logs and find the directories where log files are stored.</p>
        <p>Most logs should be disabled in a production environment.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
         <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Logging settings tab</title>
                <link>images/loggingSettings.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
       <section>
            <title>General Settings</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Enable Server Logging</name>
                    <description>Turns server logging on or off. When enabled, all client requests and server errors will be logged to the files specified below.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Access Log</name>
                    <description>The filename for the Access Log which records all client requests to your server. This log file will be in the Common Logfile Format which is used by most other web servers.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Server Error Log</name>
                    <description>The filename for the Error Log which records all errors generated on your server by client requests. This log can be helpful in troubleshooting application errors.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Trace Log Folder</name>
                    <description>The location where trace logs are created and stored.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Automatic Log Rotation</title>
            <description>Configure the application server to rotate log files daily or when the log file grows to a maximum size.</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Rotate Daily</name>
                    <description>When enabled, log files will be rotated daily.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Rotate By Size</name>
                    <description>Rotate log files when a specified file size limit is reached.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Log File Size Limit (KB)</name>
                    <description>Defines the maximum size of a log file for the *[ui:Rotate By Size]* behavior.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Debug Logging</title>
            <description>Logging for tracking down issues in an app.</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Raw HTTP Log</name>
                    <description>When enabled, causes the server to log the complete client request to the specified file. This information can be helpful while debugging an application but it is recommended that this is turned off in a production environment in order to maximize server performance.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Xbasic Error Log</name>
                    <description>Records and error stack for all Xbasic errors. Since this should remain empty during normal operation, it is recommended to always leave Xbasic Error Log enabled.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Administrative alerts</title>
            <description>
                <p>Administrative alerts can be sent from the Application Server by email and SMS.</p>
                <p>For email notifications, all that is required is a recipient email address. There is no email server configuration necessary, as emails will be sent using a special account, AppServerAlerts@alphasoftware.com. Multiple recipients may be specified by separating them with a comma.</p>
                <p> For SMS notifications, the customer must have their own Twilio account and provide the appropriate account information in the server's settings, along with the recipient SMS number. This functionality will work with a free Twilio account, but Twilio may impose limits on free accounts. Multiple recipients may be specified by separating them with a comma.</p>
                <p> Currently there are 4 different notification levels, detailed below. Each level includes all alerts from levels under it (higher number).</p>
                <p>Use the *[ui:Test Alerts]* button to test your configuration. This will send both a test email and a test SMS, if each are enabled, in order to confirm that the settings entered are working as expected.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Alert Level</name>
                    <description>Specify the alerting level. Each alert level includes all levels below it. For example, an alerting level of *[ui:Level 3 - Warning]* will also send *[ui:Level 2 - Alert]* and *[ui:Level 1 - Emergency]* alerts. Alert levels and the types of messages they send are described below:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Alert Level</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Level 1 - Emergency</name>
                            <description>Indicates something that requires immediate attention, as the server is no longer operating normally: Server failed to start and Server terminated abnormally (crash)</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Level 2 - Alert</name>
                            <description>Indicates something that needs attention very soon, as server functionality will be impacted: Server has started in an unlicensed mode.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Level 3 - Warning</name>
                            <description>Indicates a potential problem: Maximum threads are running (e.g. server is at full capacity) and Failed to create new threads.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Level 4 - Notice</name>
                            <description>Indicates an informational notice: Normal server start, Normal server stop, and Logs automatically rotated.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Send email</name>
                    <description>Check to enable email alerts.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Email to</name>
                    <description>A comma delimited list of email recipients.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Send SMS</name>
                    <description>Check to enable SMS (text message) alerts.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SMS to</name>
                    <description>A comma delimited list of SMS numbers.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Twilio SID</name>
                    <description>Your Twilio SID.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Twilio Token</name>
                    <description>Your Twilio token.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Twilio Number</name>
                    <description>Your Twilio number.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="application server settings advanced">Advanced Settings</ref>
    </see>
</page>