<page>
    <shortlink>application server settings other</shortlink>
    <topic>Other Settings</topic>
    <description>Other settings includes tools for testing connection strings, migrating Users and groups to the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS, and configuring HTTP Publish.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Other settings tab</title>
                <link>images/otherSettings.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>settings</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Open the Users and Groups Migration Genie</name>
                    <description>Use this genie to migrate users and groups fom an Alpha Anywhere application to an Alpha Anywhere for IIS application</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Open the Connection String Builder Genie</name>
                    <description>Use this genie to create a connection string that will connect from this server to the desired database.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>HTTP Publish</name>
                    <description>Settings for enabling and configuring HTTP publish.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Allow HTTP Publish?</name>
                            <description>Check to enable HTTP Publishing. You must save your changes after enabling HTTP Publish before you can configure publish permissions.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>HTTP Data Folder</name>
                            <description>Specify a folder where the HTTP publishing configuration is stored. Leave blank to store the HTTP publish data in the same folder as the Server Configuration XML file.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Set HTTP Publish Permissions</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>Configure the user credentials and permissions for HTTP publishing.</p>
                                <p>HTTP Publish is restricted and requires a user name and password for authorization. Use *[ui:Set HTTP Publish Permissions]* to configure credentials for users to allow publishing to the server.</p>
                                <p>A publish folder must be specified for each user profile. Selecting *[ui:&lt;webroot&gt;]* will allow publishing to the server webroot and any folder under the webroot.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="Publishing to a Remote Server Using HTTP">How to Configure and Publish an Alpha Anywhere Application to a server Using HTTP Publishing</ref>
        <ref link="test connection string on server">How to Test Connection Strings on the Application Server</ref>
    </see>
</page>