<page>
    <shortlink>grid properties javascript actions javascript actions property</shortlink>
    <topic>Javascript Actions</topic>
    <description>Javascript Actions enable you to call Action Javascript anywhere you can use JavaScript in the Grid Component.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Defining Javascript Actions is similar to defining Javascript Functions for your Grid Component, except that you can use the Action Javascript builder to write the Javascript code rather than hand-coding your function. The Actions that you define can be called by various event handlers in the Grid Component.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/javascriptActions1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Running an action is done by calling the [.runAction()] method of the Grid Component. For example:</description>
            <example><![CDATA['Calling an action:
        {grid.object}.runAction('myAction');]]></example>
            <figure>
                <link>images/javascriptActions2.png</link>
            </figure>
            <important>Action names must be unique. Action names are also case-sensitive.</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Some actions that you define using Action Javascript need to know what object invoked the action. For example, if you define an action that *[ui:opens a window]* and you want the window positioned *[ui:relative]* to the button that invokes the action, a reference object is required.</p>
                <p>In order for the *[ui:opens a window]* action to work, the [{grid.object}.runAction()] method needs a reference to the invoking object. This is done by passing a pointer to the object as the second parameter to the [.runAction()] method.</p>
                <p>The second argument is typically *[js:this]*, but it could be a pointer to any element on the page. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[var ele = $('ID_OF_SOME_ELEMENT');
{grid.object}.runAction('myAction',ele);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you do *[not]* do this, you will get a JavaScript error when the component tries to open the window relative to the button that invoked the action.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search={grid.object}.runAction Method">{grid.object}.runAction()</link>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search={grid.object}.runAction Method">.runAction()</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=javascript%20actions">Javascript Actions</ref>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search={grid.object}.runAction Method">{grid.object}.runAction Method</ref>
    </see>
</page>
