<page build="7888">
    <shortlink>uxlist charts</shortlink>
    <topic>Displaying Charts in Lists</topic>
    <description>Add a chart to your List layout using the List Chart field.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>You can create Lists which display charts in each List row. The available chart types are: line, bar, gauge and pie. The data in the chart comes from the data in the List row.</p>
        <p>In the image below, each row is displaying a Gauge, Line, and Pie chart. Notice that in the first List row, the gauge is red because the value is below a threshold value and in the second row it is green because the value is above the threshold value.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Gauge, Line, and Pie chart</title>
                <alt>Gauge, Line, and Pie chart</alt>
                <link>images/inlistcharts.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To add a chart to a List definition, go the Fields tab in the List builder and then click the Add Item button.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Add Item button</title>
                <alt>Add Item button</alt>
                <link>images/addingacharttoalist1.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>From the list of available item types, select Chart.</p>
                <p>Then click the smart field for the Chart properties to configure the chart.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Chart properties</title>
                <alt>Chart properties</alt>
                <link>images/addingacharttoalist2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The properties shown in the builder vary based on the type of chart you select. For example, in the image below, the builder for the Gauge chart is shown:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Gauge chart builder</title>
                <alt>Gauge chart builder</alt>
                <link>images/gaugechartbuilder.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Regardless of the chart type you select, the builder will have a property called Data points where you define the Javascript that returns the data to display in the chart. Typically you will return data from the current List row.</p>
                <p>For example, in the image below the Javascript for the Data points property is shown for the Pie chart.</p>
                <p>The pie has three slices and so the Javascript returns an array of 3 data points. In this case the data points are the point1, point2 and point3 fields in the current List row.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Defining data points</title>
                <alt>Defining data points</alt>
                <link>images/chartdatapoints.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Once you have configured the chart you can add the chart to the Layout just like you add any other control to a List Layout. For example, in the image below, the first three columns in the List layout display different charts.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Adding Charts to the List Layout</title>
                <alt>Adding Charts to the List Layout</alt>
                <link>images/listlayout_chart.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>In-row Charts</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can display charts in a List. Each row in the List can have a line, bar, pie or gauge chart and the data shown in the chart can come from other data in the List row.</p>
                </description>
                <date>10/3/2021</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/list_inrowcharting.mp4</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/list_IN_ROW_CHARTS.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>