<page build="7534">
    <shortlink>list twostate static images</shortlink>
    <topic>Two-state Static Images</topic>
    <description>Static images in a List can be configured as two-state images, which display a different image based on the static image's toggled state: on or off. </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Animation effects can help users follow an application's flow. For example, rotating an arrow to point down when a content area expands or changing an image from a 'hamburger' icon to an 'X' when displaying a dropdown menu. Static images in the List can be configured as "Two-state Images". A two-state image is an image where the image that is shown is rotated or swapped for another image when the image is clicked.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>A two-state static image being toggled between the on and off state.</title>
                <alt>An animated image showing a two-state image being toggled between the on and off state.</alt>
                <link>images/twosstateimagegif.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To add a two-state image to a List:</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open the List Builder</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the *[ui:Fields]* tab, click the *[ui:Add Item]* button and then select the *[ui:Static Image]* menu item.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Set the *[ui:Image name]*. This is the image shown for the initial state.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Check the *[ui:Two-state image]* property.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Optionally, specify the *[ui:Swapped image name]*. If you do not specify a different swapped image, then you should specify a *[ui:Rotation direction]* value other than *[none]* so that the displayed image changes when the image state is toggled.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify if the image should change state when clicked by setting the *[ui:Toggle on click]* property. If you do not check this property, the image state can only be changed programmatically by calling the [&lt;listObject&gt;.twoStateImageSet() method].</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify the *[ui:Rotation direction]*. The *[90]* and *[180]* options rotate in a clockwise direction. The *[-90]* and *[-180]* options rotate in a counter-clockwise direction.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Static Image Properties</title>
                <alt>Static Image Properties</alt>
                <link>images/twostateimages.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can add custom JavaScript to the [OnClick] event to trigger an event when the two-state image is toggled, such as opening a dropdown menu. The *[ui:OnClick]* event can be used to programmatically toggle the two-state image if you've unchecked *[ui:Toggle on click]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Two-state images</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common design pattern when building user interfaces is to add icons that change with animation when the icon is clicked. For example, you might have a 'hamburger' icon that displays a menu. When the icon is clicked, you might want the icon to animate into an different icon (i.e. an 'X' icon) to indicate clicking the icon closes the menu.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to create animated two-state images in a List.</p>
                </description>
                <date>03-06-2021</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://youtu.be/Vbsj91jICHg</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/twostateImage.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="listbuilder static image properties#section1_OnClick">OnClick</link>
        <link link="list twoStateImageSet method">&lt;listObject&gt;.twoStateImageSet() method</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="listbuilder static image properties">Static Image Properties</ref>
        <ref link="list twoStateImageSet method">List Object twoStateImageSet() method</ref>
    </see>
</page>