<page>
	<topic>Creating and Programming Hotspots with Xbasic</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>Many of the forms in the AlphaSports application have a set of images in the lower right corner. At first, you might think these were buttons with image labels. In fact, they are actually composed of two layered images and a set of Hotspots. A hotspot is similar to a button without a visible component. It is a rectangular region that responds to an OnPush event and will run either an Action Script or Xbasic code.</description>
	
	
</section>	
	<section>
	<title>Procedure: Creating and Programming a Hotspot with Xbasic 
</title>	
	<description>The following procedure assumes that the developer has opened the form in the Form Editor . Follow these instructions to format a hotspot similar to hotspot4 .
</description>
	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Sketch the hotspot on the form.
</description>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>When the Define Hotspot dialog box appears, click the Use Xbasic Editor option button.
</description>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Click OK. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Define_Hotspot_dialog.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Paste the following Xbasic code into the Code Editor.
</description>
<example><![CDATA[dim op as P

op = obj("help")
if (is_object(op)) then
    op.activate()
else
    form.view("help")
end if]]></example>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Click Close(X) .
</description>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Click Save All and OK.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>	
	</section>
	
<section>
	<title>An Explanation of the Xbasic Code</title>
<description>The first statement creates a pointer variable named op to refer to the Help form.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[dim op as P
]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>The next statement uses the obj() function to get a pointer to the Help form, if it exists.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[op = obj("help")]]></example>	
</section>	
	
	<section>
<description>If the pointer to the Help form exists, the Help form is open, and the is_object() function returns true. If it does not exist, the function returns false. The true alternative uses the activate() function to display the already open Help form.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[if (is_object(op))
    op.activate()
]]></example>	
</section>	
	
	<section>
<description>The false alternative uses the form.view() method to open and display the Help form.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[else
    form.view("help")
end if
]]></example>	
</section>	
	
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	
	<ref>Creating and Programming a Hotspot with Action Scripting</ref>
	<ref>The InvoiceReportMenu Form</ref>
	<ref>Using Xbasic to Create Queries</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>