<page>
    <shortlink>node services workspace</shortlink>
    <topic>Node Services</topic>
    <description>Node services can be called from Node modules, other Node services and Xbasic scripts.</description>
    <discussion>Node services can be created and managed from within Alpha Anywhere. The Node services category in the Web Projects Control Panel will filter the project to display node services in the project. A Node service can be created using the *[ui:[New] New]* toolbar button. Node services can also be added from the *[ui:Node]* menu in the *[ui:[More] More...]* options on the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/nodeServiceMenu.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Node Services can reference Node Modules in their implementation. Because Node Services can be called from Xbasic, this allows you to extend the capabilities of Xbasic using server-side JavaScript and Node Modules available through the extensive NMP (Node Packet Manager) library and any custom Node Modules you have created.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a New Node Service</title>
            <description>When the Node Services item has focus, the New button will create a new stub Node service that serves as a helpful starting point for defining a new service.</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button in the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/newItem.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If prompted, select *[ui:Node Service]* from the New File dialog.</description>
                    <note>Alpha Anywhere will automatically create a new Node Service, skipping the New File dialog, if the *[ui:Node Services]* category is selected in the Web Projects Control Panel.</note>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeService1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the *[ui:Create Node Service Stub]* dialog, enter a *[ui:Service name]*. Optionally check (or uncheck) the *[ui:Open service definition .js file after creating it?]* checkbox. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeService2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Alpha Anywhere will generate a Node Service stub. The stub includes comments that describe how to call the Node Service from Xbasic.</p>
                        <p>Create your Node service. Save your changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeService3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Calling a Node Service from Xbasic</title>
            <description>
                <p>Once you have defined your Node service, you can call it from your Xbasic code using the [node_request_result()] function.</p>
                <p>For example, say you have define a service called multiply and that this service takes as input x and y. Here is how you could call the service from Xbasic:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[dim pIn as p
pIn.x = 4
pIn.y = 3

dim pOut as p
pOut = node_request_result("multiply",pIn)

? pOut.error
= ""  'empty string indicates no errors.

?pOut.result
= 12]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/$$file.new.png">New</link>
        <link href="/images/$$navigate.down.png">More</link>
        <link link="api node request result function">node_request_result()</link>
    </links>
</page>