<page build="4184">
    <shortlink>node modules workspace</shortlink>
    <topic>Node Modules</topic>
    <description>Node modules can be called from Node Services and other Node modules.</description>
    <discussion>Node modules can be created and managed from within Alpha Anywhere. The Node modules category in the Web Projects Control Panel will filter the project to display node modules in the project. A Node module can be created using the *[ui:[New] New]* toolbar button. Node modules can also be added from the *[ui:Node]* menu in the *[ui:[More] More...]* options on the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/nodeModuleMenu.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>While Node Modules cannot be directly called using Xbasic, they can be used by Node Services. Node Services can be called from Xbasic scripts. See [Node Services] for more information.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a New Node Module</title>
            <description>When the Node Modules item has focus, the New button will create a new stub Node Module that serves as a helpful starting point for defining a new module.</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button in the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/newItem.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If prompted, select *[ui:Node Module]* from the New File dialog.</description>
                    <note>Alpha Anywhere will automatically create a new Node Module, skipping the New File dialog, if the *[ui:Node Modules]* category is selected in the Web Projects Control Panel.</note>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeModule1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the *[ui:Create Node Module Stub]* dialog, enter a *[ui:Module name]*. Optionally check (or uncheck) the *[ui:Open module definition .js file after creating it?]* checkbox. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeModule2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Alpha Anywhere will generate a Node Module stub. The stub includes comments that describe how to call the Node Module from Xbasic.</p>
                        <p>Create your Node Module. Save your changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/nodeModule3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/$$file.new.png">New</link>
        <link href="/images/$$navigate.down.png">More</link>
        <link link="node services workspace">Node Services</link>
    </links>
</page>