<page>
   <topic>PADR Function</topic>
   <syntax>Formatted_String as C = PADR(C,N length,C pad_string)</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>C</name>
         <description>A character string.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>length</name>
         <description>A positive integer representing the length of the Formatted_String. If Length is less than len(Unformatted_String), then Unformatted_String will be truncated to Length. Numeric</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>pad_string</name>
         <description>The character string to append to the end of Unformatted_String to position it within Formatted_String.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Pads the right side of a string with another string.</description>
   <discussion>
PADR() pads a C string on the right with a Pad_String, and returns a resulting string of the specified Length. If the length of Pad_String + C_string is less than the Length, the Pad_String is repeated to fill the remainder of the string.
   </discussion>
 
  
   <sections>
      
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>PADR can easily create a series of trailing characters like you find in a Table of Contents. Assume that your report summarizes the totals of multiple invoices for each customer. The following expression defines a calculated field that you can place in the Detail section to create a easily readable printout:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
padr(ltrim("Polucci"), 20, ".") + ltrim(str(200) ) -> Polucci.............200
]]></example>
       </section>
       
        <section>
            <description>The difference between using this method and including trailing characters as a Text object directly on a layout is that this method eliminates the gap that would appear between the end of a shorter value and the start of the Text object.
The following expression extracts the decimal places from a dollar value and pads the string with the cents symbol.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
padr(ltrim(str( (RETAIL - floor(RETAIL) ) * 100) + " "), 8, ".") -> "15 ....." for values such as 10.15 and 0.15.
]]></example>
       </section>
       
        <section>
            <description>Note : ANSI character 162 is the cents symbol; press ALT + 0162 on a numeric keypad to enter this character.
Assume that the above expression defines the calculated field CENTS. The following expression creates a string to format dollar values:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
case(RETAIL CENTS, RETAIL > = 1, ltrim(str(floor(RETAIL) ) ) + " dollars and " + CALC->CENTS) ? "10 dollars and 15 .....", if RETAIL contains 10.15 and "15 ....." if RETAIL contains 0.15.
]]></example>
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Character Formatting Functions</ref>
   </see>
</page>