<page>
    <topic>Choices</topic>
    <description>The Choices property lets you define the choices that will appear next to each checkbox.
      Clicking the [...] button next to Choices will open the Define Choices dialog. There are three options for how to define 
      the choices presented, Static, Dynamic, and Variable.
    </description>
  <sections>
      <section>
        <title>Defining Static Choices</title>
          <description>In this scenario you can manually enter the choices that you want to appear next to the checkboxes.</description>
          <steps>
            <step>
              <description>In the UX Builder open the UX Controls page. Scroll through the Data Controls menu and click on the [CheckBox] control
                to add a checkbox to the component. Highlight the control.
              </description>
              
            </step>
            
            <step>
              <description>In the CheckBox Properties section of the control properties click on the [...] button next to choices</description>
                <figure><link>images/static4.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
              <description>The Define Choices dialog will open. Check the "Static" radio control. </description>
                <figure><link>images/static2.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            <step>
              <description>Define a list of choices for the control. Seperate each choice by placing it on a new line.</description>
                <figure><link>images/static3.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            
            <step>
              <description>Run the component in Live Preview. </description>
              <figure><link>images/static.png</link></figure>
              <note>If the control appears to be wrapping reopen the Controls page, highlight the checkbox control, and adjust the Width or Height settings under the Field Properties section of 
                the Control Properties list.
              </note>
            </step>
            
          </steps>
      </section>
      
      <section>
        
        <title>Dynamic Choices</title>
        <description>Using the Dynamic option it is possible to create a list of checkbox choices from 
          existing DBF and AlphDAO data sources. Here is an example:
        </description>
        <steps>
          <step>
            <description>Add a [CheckBox] control to the component and highlight it. In the control properties list under the 
              CheckBox Properties section click the [...] button next to the Choices property.</description>
            
          </step>
          <step>
            <description>The Define Choices dialog will open. Select the Dynamic option.</description>
            <figure><link>images/dyn.png</link></figure>
          </step>
          <step>
            <description>Under the Data Source section of the Define choices dialog click the dropdown next to the "Data source type" property. 
            Select AlphaDAO.</description>
           <figure><link>images/dyn1.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
            <description>Click the [...] button next to the AlphaDAO Connection string name. </description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn2.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
            <description>Choose "Use a names connection string" and click the Select button. Connect to the Northwind database and click OK and OK again.</description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn3.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
            <description>Click the [...] button next to the AlphaDAO SQL SELECT statement.</description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn4.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
            <description>Click the Select button. Choose the Customers table from the list of tables and click OK.</description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn5.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
            <description>Select the Countries field as the Field to display. Click OK and OK again.</description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn6.png</link></figure>
          </step>
        <step>
            <description>Run the component in Live Preview.</description>
              <figure><link>images/dyn7.png</link></figure>
              <note>This image was displayed after setting the Orientation property to vertical.</note>
          </step>
       
        </steps>
        
        
      </section>
      
      
  </sections>
  
  
  
  
  <links>
    <link href="images/open.png">...</link>
  </links>
</page>