<page>
<topic>A5AS::Security Class</topic>
<description>Security properties methods</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Discussion</title>
		<description>The Security object contains properties and methods available for working with the users and roles if a web application uses security. The term "Role" and "Group" are synonymous in this API. The UI in Alpha Anywhere Developer Edition generally uses the term "Group" while the security property and methods use the term "Roles".
</description>
<note>The Security object has a CallResult property. Use this property to see if a method call or property get succeeds before using a method's returned value or property's value. See the following examples: </note>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<example><![CDATA[dim errorMsg as C = "" dim created as L = .F. created = Context.Security.CreateUser("John-
Doe@acme.com", "secret") if Context.Security.CallResult.Success then if .not. created then 
error_generate("User was not created.") end if else error_generate
(Context.Security.CallResult.Text) end if 
dim userName as C = Context.Security.CurrentUser if .not. Context.Security.CallResult.Success then 
error_generate(Context.Security.CallResult.Text) end if if alltrim(userName) = "" then 'Display "no 
user is logged in." else 'Display user name end if 
]]></example>
	</section>
	
</sections>

<properties>
	<property>
		<name>CallResult</name>
		<type>CallResult</type>
		<description>Context.Security.CallResult is used to check the success or failure of a method call or property get in the Security object. See the note in the Security class description above for more details and examples.
Read Only.</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>CurrentUser</name>
		<type>C</type>
		<description>Context.Security.CurrentUser returns the name of the current user if one is logged in. Otherwise a zero length character value is returned. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success, before using the value that is returned. Read Only</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>DefaultRoles</name>
		<type>C</type>
		<description>Context.Security.DefaultRoles returns a crlf delimited list of the default roles to which a new user will be assigned. This value is set in the security settings on the Customize Options tab. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success, before using the value that is returned. Read Only.</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>IsActive </name>
		<type>L</type>
		<description>Context.Security.IsActive returns .T. if the web application is running with security and returns .F. if the web application is not running with security. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success before using the value that is returned.
Read Only.</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>PasswordResetAllowed</name>
		<type>L</type>
		<description>Context.Security.PasswordResetAllowed returns .T. if users are allowed to reset their password. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success before using the value that is returned. Read Only</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>PasswordRetrievalAllowed </name>
		<type>L</type>
		<description>Context.Security.PasswordRetrievalAllowed returns .T. if users are allowed to retrieve their password. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success before using the value that is returned. Read Only</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>RequiresQuestionAndAnswer</name>
		<type>L</type>
		<description>Context.Security.RequiresQuestionAndAnswer returns .T. if users are required to supply an answer to a security question in order to reset or retrieve their password. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success before using the value that is returned. Read Only</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>RolesAreEnabled</name>
		<type>L</type>
		<description>Context.Security.RolesAreEnabled returns a .T. if roles are enabled for the security settings of the application. .F. is returned otherwise. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success, before using the value that is returned. Read Only.</description>
	</property>	
	<property>
		<name>SecurityQuestionList</name>
		<type>C</type>
		<description>Context.Security.SecurityQuestionList returns a crlf delimited string of security questions defined by the security system. Use this list when a user is created or updated and a security question needs to be selected. Check Context.Security.CallResult.Success, before using the value that is returned.</description>
	</property>	
	
</properties>

<!--list:.-->
</page>