<page>
<topic>ControlBar Builder</topic>
<description>The ControlBar Builder is used to define a ControlBar control. </description>


<sections>
<section>
	<title>Finding the ControlBar Builder</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the UX Builder on the Controls page open the 'Other Controls' menu and click on 
				the [ControlBar] option to add a ControlBar control to the UX.
			</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb2.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Highlight the ControlBar control in the tree. In the properties list under 'ControlBar Properties' 
				click on the ControlBar properties property. Alternatively double click on the [ControlBar] control itself.
			</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb3.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>The ControlBar builder will open.</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb4.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>ControlBar Panes</title>
<description>The ControlBar Builder contains the following panes.</description>
<list>
	<item>
		<name>Home</name>
		<description>Gives a general overview of the ControlBar builder</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Data</name>
		<description>The data pane is used to define ControlBar data.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Items</name>
		<description>The Items pane allows developers to define items such as buttons, button-lists, and button-toggles.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Actions</name>
		<description>The Actions pane allows you to define 'actions', i.e. bits of javascript, that are tied to items. </description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Properties</name>
		<description>The 'Properties' pane contains a number of settings. Among these are settings to define Javascript events 
			for the ControlBar, specify animation times, and set docking preferences.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>ControlBar Layout</name>
		<description>This pane is where the visual appearance of the ControlBar is defined.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Disclosures</name>
		<description>Optional. This pane defines disclosures. Disclosures are similar to pop-up windows.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>CSS</name>
		<description>Optional. The CSS pane can be used to define custom CSS to use with the ControlBar.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Javascript</name>
		<description>Optional. The Javascript pane can be used to used by the ControlBar.</description>
	</item>
	
	
</list>
</section>


</sections>

</page>
