<page>
<topic>ControlBar Builder</topic>
<description>The ControlBar Builder is used to define a ControlBar control. </description>

<groups>
	<group>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		
	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Finding the ControlBar Builder</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the UX Builder on the Controls page open the 'Other Controls' menu and click on 
				the [ControlBar] option to add a ControlBar control to the UX.
			</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb2.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Highlight the ControlBar control in the tree. In the properties list under 'ControlBar Properties' 
				click on the ControlBar properties property. Alternatively double click on the [ControlBar] control itself.
			</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb3.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>The ControlBar builder will open.</description>
			<figure><link>images/cb4.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>ControlBar Panes</title>
<description>The ControlBar Builder contains the following panes.</description>
<list>
	<item>
		<name>Home</name>
		<description>Gives a general overview of the ControlBar builder</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Data</name>
		<description>The data pane is used to define ControlBar data.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Items</name>
		<description>The Items pane allows developers to define items such as buttons, button-lists, and button-toggles.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Actions</name>
		<description>The Actions pane allows you to define 'actions', i.e. bits of javascript, that are tied to items. </description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Properties</name>
		<description>The 'Properties' pane contains a number of settings. Among these are settings to define Javascript events 
			for the ControlBar, specify animation times, and set docking preferences.
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>ControlBar Layout</name>
		<description>This pane is where the visual appearance of the ControlBar is defined.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Disclosures</name>
		<description>Optional. This pane defines disclosures. Disclosures are similar to pop-up windows.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>CSS</name>
		<description>Optional. The CSS pane can be used to define custom CSS to use with the ControlBar.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Javascript</name>
		<description>Optional. The Javascript pane can be used to used by the ControlBar.</description>
	</item>
	
	
</list>
</section>



</sections>
</group>



<group>
	<title>Data</title>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Adding Data</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>In the Control Bar Builder open the Data pane</description>
					<figure><link>images/cb5.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the 'Add Data Item' button.</description>
					<figure><link>images/cb6.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>A dialog named 'Setting' will open. In the 'Setting name' textbox give the item a name, like 'setting1'.</description>
					<figure><link>images/cb7.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the 'Value' text area give the named item a value. Click OK</description>
					<figure><link>images/cb8.png</link></figure>
					<note>The value can be in the form of a string, a JSON object, or a function that returns a value. </note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>The new value should appear in the Data pane.</description>
					<figure><link>images/cb9.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				
				
			</steps>
			
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Defining Data</title>
			<description>The Data pane allows you to define ControlBar data. 
You can define as many data items as you want. Each data time has a unique name and a value.
The value can be a string, a JSON object, or a function that returns a value.
For example
</description>
			<example><![CDATA[setting1 = 'value of setting 1'
setting2 = {address: '123 main st.', city: 'boston'}
]]></example>
		</section>
		<section>
<description>In the second example the data item's value is a JSON object.
	 To refer to one of the properties in the object you use the full path. For example:</description>			
<example><![CDATA[setting2.city]]></example>			
		</section>
		<section>
<description>The primary purpose (although by no means their only purpose) is to provide content to be displayed on the ControlBar, or to be used in Enable/Disable expressions for controls that are placed on the ControlBar.
For example, you might have an HTML ControlBar item whose html text is set to:
</description>			
<example><![CDATA[{setting1}]]></example>			
		</section>
		<section>
<description><p>A powerful option when defining Data items is to specify that the value of the data item should be updated automatically when a 'watch' event fires. When you define a watch event you can specify which controls you want to watch. For example, if you specify that you want to watch the FIRSTNAME and LASTNAME controls, then whenever the value in one of these controls changes, the watch event will fire.
</p><p>Watch events also fire when the state of the UX changes. For example, when the UX goes from a 'clean' state to a 'dirty' state.
</p><p>You can also manually fire watch events using this method:</p>
</description>			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
</group>
	
</groups>
</page>
