<page>
    <shortlink>howto allformshidden</shortlink>
    <topic>What does "All Forms Hidden" mean?</topic>
    <description>If forms have been downloaded to the TransForm App but none of them can be viewed, the message "All Forms Hidden" will be shown.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>There are cases where TransForm forms will be downloaded to the mobile app but cannot be viewed by the user. If none of the forms can be accessed by the user, the message "All Forms Hidden" will be displayed in the List of forms.</p>
        <p>A form may not be viewable for the following reasons:</p>
        <p>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>You do not have permissions to view the form(s).</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The Form Type definition has been removed by the TransForm Account administrator.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Preventing Existing Forms from Downloading when the Form Design has been Deleted</title>
            <description>
                <p>If you delete a form design without deleting any existing forms created with that design, the form instance may still be downloaded to the TransForm App. The form will be included in total forms in the List of Forms. Because the form no longer has a form design, however, you cannot select, edit, or delete the form.</p>
                <p>To remove the forms from the device, you must either delete the form instances or prevent the forms from downloading to the device. In order to do this, however, you must create a form design with the same Form ID as the deleted form. The form design does not need to include any fields.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/deletedForms1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>After creating the form design, use the Management Console to delete or prevent the form instances from downloading.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/deletedForms2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>After you have updated the form instances to they no longer download to the TransForm app, you can either delete the form instance again or [set the form design permissions to prevent users from accessing it].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Deleting a Form</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the form you want to delete in the form list.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Delete Selected Form]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Click to save changes]* at the top of the form list to save the changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <warning>
                        <p>There is no undo for this action.</p>
                    </warning>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Deleting Multiple Forms</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the checkbox for each form instance you want to delete.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Delete Checked Forms Only]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Click to save changes]* at the top of the form list to save the changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <warning>
                        <p>There is no undo for this action.</p>
                    </warning>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Preventing a Form from Downloading</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the form you want to change in the form list.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the *[ui:Yes]* option for the *[ui:Prevent Filler from downloading]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/preventDownload.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Click to save changes]* at the top of the form list to save the changes.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Giving Users Permissions to View and Edit Forms</title>
            <description>
                <p>Access to view and edit forms is controlled using permissions. Alpha TransForm creates some basic permission roles for controlling access to various features in TransForm, including the form designer, dashboards, web filler, management console, and mobile filler.</p>
                <p>The features users in a specific role can access are managed on the Permissions tab in TransForm Central.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Permissions tab</title>
                <alt>Permissions tab</alt>
                <link>/images/permissions1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Viewing and editing forms in the form filler application, both the mobile app and web filler, are defined in the Form Filler settings for a selected Role in the *[ui:Combined Group/Status/Role/Permissions List]* column.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Form Filler settings</title>
                <alt>Form Filler settings</alt>
                <link>/images/permissions2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Permissions for roles are defined for each form Status for a permissions Group. Permission Groups are assigned to Form Types. By default, all Form Designs use Simple Group permissions unless you explicitly set the form's [Status/Role Permissions Group] in the Designer.</p>
                <p>To give a user permission to view forms with a specific status in the filler app, locate the permission group used by the Form Type the user needs to see, then, for each status listed in the permission group you would like to grant access, select the Role, then check the *[ui:Permissions]* you want to grant users with the selected role.</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Permissions</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>List</name>
                            <description>Users with this role can view form instances in the form filler.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit</name>
                            <description>Users with this role can edit form instances in the form filler.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Delete</name>
                            <description>Users with this role can delete form instances in the form filler.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>If you are granting Edit permissions to the selected Role, you can optionally choose the *[ui:New Status Allowed]* that the user can give a form instance. If a status is checked and the user has permission to *[ui:Edit]* form instances, the user will be allowed to change the status for a form instance in the filler application to one of the allowed statues.</p>
                <p>Once you have updated the Roles to grant access to view or edit forms in the Form Filler, click *[ui:Click here to save changes.]* to save your changes. The next time your users log out and log in to the filler app, they should be able to see the forms they've been granted access.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Save your changes</title>
                <alt>Save your changes</alt>
                <link>/images/permissions3.png</link>
            </figure>
            <important>
                <p>After editing Permissions, you must log out and log in to the filler app for the permissions to take effect.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>I don't have permissions to add Form Designs or access the Management Console. What should I do?</title>
            <description>
                <p>If you do not have permissions to access the Designer or Management Console, contact your TransForm account administrator.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="Form%20Type%20Properties%20Screen#section1_Status/Role%20Permissions%20Group">Status/Role Permissions Group</link>
        <link link="transform%20central%20permissions">set the form design permissions to prevent users from accessing it</link>
    </links>
</page>