<page>
    <shortlink>howto get form field list</shortlink>
    <topic>How do I get a list of every field and it's corresponding field name for a form?</topic>
    <description></description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>There are several ways to get a list of field names for a Form Type. In the Designer, on the Management Console, or using the Alpha TransForm API.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">In the Designer</title>
                    <description>Select the Form Type from the list in the Designer and click 'Edit Form Commands'. In the left-most column, you will see a list of every command in the form including "field" commands. Each field command lists a summary of information here, including the field type, it's field name, the field Title, and it's preview value (if one is specified) in the following format:</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <content><![CDATA[
<strong>field</strong> <em>fieldType</em> fieldName / "fieldTitle" (fieldPreviewValue)
                    ]]></content>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>For example, in the Pumpjack Inspection sample form, the Pumpjack ID field appears as shown below in the command list (the field name has been highlighted):</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <content><![CDATA[
<strong>field</strong> <em>list</em> PumpjackID / "Pumpjack ID" (value2)
                    ]]></content>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>To reference the field, it is expressed as *[tpl:#fieldname]*. For example:</description>
                    <example code="tpl"><![CDATA[#PumpjackID]]></example>
                    <important>*[Case matters.]* The field name must match case exactly as it is defined in the Field property for a field command.</important>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>Field can be used in [Heading Templates] and [Listing Templates] to display additional information (such as a customer's name) in the form lists. They can also be used in expressions (such as IF commands) to add dynamic behaviors  to a form.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">On the Management Console</title>
                    <description>You can get a list of form fields from the Quick Input editor. In the Management Console, select the Form Type you wish to get a list of fields for. Then, click the *[ui:+]* Add Form button. Click the "Quick Input" option when prompted. This opens the Quick Input editor. Clicking the "Fields" button at the bottom of the editor will insert a list of all fields for the form using the following format:</description>
                    <example><![CDATA[fieldTitle (fieldname):]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>You can copy-paste the inserted fields to a text editor such as notepad to use as reference where needed.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/mcInsertFields.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Using the Alpha TransForm API</title>
                    <description>The GetFieldsInForm API method can be used to retrieve a list of form fields for a specified Form Type from an Alpha TransForm account. See the [GetFieldsInForm method] documentation for more information.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Heading%20Template">Heading Templates</link>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Listing%20Template">Listing Templates</link>
        <link link="transform%20getfieldsinform%20method">GetFieldsInForm method</link>
    </links>
</page>