<page>
   <topic>table.SUMMARIZE Function</topic>
    <description>Summarize the records of the table into a specified output table.</description>
 
   <syntax><![CDATA[V Summarize(), Specify the required values in the Sum dot variable, then use the following command: <TBL>.SUMMARIZE()]]></syntax>
<sections><section>
<list>
<item>
<name>sum.db
</name>
<description>Type "C". The name of the resulting table.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>sum.order
</name>
<description>Type "C". A character order expression that sorts selected records.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>sum.filter</name>
<description>Type "C". A character filter expression that selects records to process.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>sum.options</name>
<description>Type "C". Options used when ordering the Result table records. This string can contain one or more of the following index codes:
</description>
<list>
<item>
<name-title>Code</name-title>
<description-title>Description
</description-title>
</item>

<item>
<name>D</name>
<description>The Descending Order option puts the records in the Result table in descending alphabetical order or, for a numeric field, from highest to lowest value.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>U</name>
<description>The Unique option uses only unique records in the summary.
</description>
</item>

</list>

</item>

<item>
<name>sum.fields</name>
<description>Type "N". Indicates how many fields are to be summarized. Each field to be included in the Summary operation is declared through a pair of parameters that indicate the field name and summary operator for that field.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>sum.field1 ... 
  C sum.fieldN</name>
<description>Type "C". Fields (1 ... N) containing the names of the field(s) to be summarized.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>sum.code1 ... 
  N sum.codeN
</name>
<description>Type "N". Fields (1 ... N) containing the operation codes for the fields to be summarized. The following codes may be used:
</description>


<list>
<item>
<name-title>Code
</name-title>
<description-title>Details</description-title>
</item>

<item>
<name>
SUM_OP_TOTAL (1)
 
 </name>
<description>Operation: Total. Returns: The sum of values for the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_COUNT (2)
</name>
<description>Operation: Count. Returns: A count of the number of records included in the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_MIN (3)
</name>
<description>Operation: Min. Returns: The minimum (smallest) value for the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_MAX (4)
</name>
<description>Operation: Max. Returns: The maximum (largest) value for the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_AVERAGE (5)
</name>
<description>Operation: Average. Returns: The average of values for the specified field or expression.
.</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_FIRST (6)
</name>
<description>Operation: First. Returns: The first value for the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>


<item>
<name>SUM_OP_LAST (7)
</name>
<description>Operation: Last. Returns: The last value for the specified field or expression.
</description>
</item>

<item>
<name>NULL (15)
</name>
<description>Returns: Adds a column label in the output table for the specified field.
</description>
</item>
</list>
</item>
</list>

</section></sections>
  

 <sections><section><title>Discussion</title>
   <discussion><![CDATA[
The <TBL>.SUMMARIZE() method is a high-level utility used to summarize the records of a specified table, creating a new table to store the result. Most parameters passed to <TBL>.SUMMARIZE()through the summary function variable correspond directly with the prompts appearing on the Summarize Builder which is accessed by defining a new summary operation from the Control Panel.
]]>   </discussion></section></sections>
  
   <sections>
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>This script counts the number of customers who live in each state. The result will be put in the specified output table.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
output_tbl = ui_get_file("Result Table","Tables(*.DBF)","","N")
if output_tbl = "" then
    end
end if
tbl = table.current()
sum.db = output_tbl
sum.order = "STATE_PROV"
sum.filter = ""
sum.options = "I"
sum.fields = 2
sum.field1 = "STATE_PROV"
sum.code1 = 0
sum.field2 = "LAST_NAME"
sum.code2 = 2
tbl.summarize()
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Document Types/DBF/Table Functions/Table Functions and Methods.html">Table Functions and  Methods</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Objects/Table/Table Operation Methods.html">Table Operation  Methods</ref>
      <ref href="/Server/Guide/Design/Platform/Xbasic/Writing Expressions.xml">Writing Expressions</ref>
   </see>
   
<terms>table,column,contains,expressions,field,filter,function,index,label,number,operation,record,script,string,summarize,writing</terms>
   
</page>