<page>
    <shortlink>alphadao cannot connect to database</shortlink>
    <topic>Cannot Connect to Database</topic>
    <description>
        <p>If drivers are missing or are not properly configured, a connection to a database can fail.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Incorrect or missing drivers can manifest as a "cannot connect to database" error from Alpha Anywhere when establishing a connection. To resolve the issue, you must update the drivers for your database system.</p>
        <p>Specific solutions for some database systems are listed below. Alpha Anywhere ships some database drivers, which can be found in the installation folder.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <note>
                <p>If you do not see your database vendor below, contact your database vendor for driver information.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Microsoft Access</title>
            <description>
                <p>Failure to connect to Microsoft Access may be the result of a 32-bit/64-bit compatibility issue with Microsoft Office or Microsoft Office 365. If you have installed a 64-bit version of Microsoft Office, you will need to uninstall that version and install the 32-bit version.</p>
                <p>You can temporarily repair Office by reinstalling the 32-bit engine, however updates will overwrite those changes.</p>
                <p>To correct this issue, install the Access 2010 Database Engine Redistributable. The redistributable can be downloaded and installed from Microsoft's website (*[extlink:https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=13255]*). Be sure to select the *[32-bit version]*.</p>
                <p>When installation completes, restart Alpha Anywhere and try to connect to your Microsoft access database.</p>
            </description>
            <important>
                <p>*[You must install the 32-bit version of the redistributable.]* Alpha Anywhere is not compatible with the 64-bit drivers. If 64-bit Office is installed, uninstall it and install the 32-bit version of Microsoft Office.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>DB2</title>
            <description>
                <p>Failure to connect to a DB2 database may be the result of a configuration problem or because the DB2 client software is not installed. To install the DB2 client software, download and install the DB2 client software from IBM's website (*[extlink:http://www-01.ibm.com/support/docview.wss?uid=swg21418043]*). When installation completes, restart Alpha Anywhere and try to connect to your DB2 database again.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <!-- 
        <section>
            <title>EnterpriseDB</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
                <p>Locate the install folder for Alpha Anywhere. If you do not remember where Alpha Anywhere was installed, you can run the following script on the command line to get the location of the folder:</p>
            </description>
            <example code=""><![CDATA[]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Locate the EnterpriseDB installer. It can be found in the installation directory in SQLDatabases &gt; ClientInstallers &gt; EnterpriseDB</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>PostgresPlus</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
        </section>
        -->
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref href="http://db2express.com/en/" target="_blank">DB2 Express (external page)</ref>
    </see>
</page>