<page>
    <shortlink>function request is not supported</shortlink>
    <topic>SQL Server - Function request not Supported</topic>
    <description>The "Function request not supported" error is a SQL Server error that occurs when the SQL Server drivers are missing or the wrong SQL Server drivers are installed on the system.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>If the server does not have the correct drivers when querying a SQL Server database, the following error can occur:</p>
        <p>
            <example><![CDATA[Function requested is not supported]]></example>
        </p>
        <p>This error occurs when the required drivers for SQL Server are not installed. This often occurs when the drivers that are installed are older than the version of SQL Server that is running. For example, the Date type does not exist in any version of SQL Server prior to SQL Server 2008. If the ODBC drivers installed on a system are older than the version of SQL Server installed, an error can occur when doing a SQL query that includes Date fields. This issue manifests as a "Function request is not supported" error in a Grid or UX Component populated from a SQL Server database.</p>
        <p>To correct the problem, the drivers for communicating with the SQL Server database need to be updated on the server running the Alpha Anywhere Application Server:</p>
        <p>1. Download the ODBC driver for your database from Microsoft. As of this writing, the following drivers are available:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>SQL Server Version</name-title>
                    <description-title>Client Driver</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2017,2019</name>
                    <description>ODBC Driver 17 for SQL Server</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2016</name>
                    <description>ODBC Driver 13 for SQL Server</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2014</name>
                    <description>ODBC Driver 11 for SQL Server</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2012</name>
                    <description>SQL Server Native Client 11.0</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2008</name>
                    <description>SQL Server Native Client 10.0</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2005</name>
                    <description>SQL Native Client</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Older Versions</name>
                    <description>SQL Server</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>2. Install the drivers on the server running Alpha Anywhere.</p>
        <p>3. Test your application.</p>
        <p>It is recommended to install the ODBC drivers Microsoft recommends for your version of SQL Server.</p>
    </discussion>
    <see>
        <ref href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/connect/odbc/windows/microsoft-odbc-driver-for-sql-server-on-windows">Microsoft ODBC Driver for SQL Server on Windows (external)</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>sql server, function request not supported,grid component</terms>
 </page>