<page>
	<shortlink>Grid Builder Page Menu</shortlink>
	  <topic>Page Menu</topic>

   <description>The page menu allows you to select different sets of menus. </description>

<sections>
	<section>
		<description>Different menus will appear or disappear, depending on the options that you select. Most of these Dependencies are determined under the Component Type page. If you click Grid is: Updateable under component type, for example, the ' Update Settings ' Page will appear under the Grid tree. However, setting your grid to this will prevent you from checking off the ' Grid contains a 'Detail View' part ' check box; that is also located on the Component Type page. Without this box checked the Detail View options, show below, will not appear under the Component Type tree menu.  </description>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Page_menu.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	
		<section>
			<title>Menu Options</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Component Type</title>
					<description>Defines the style of the grid and whether it will have search and/or detail parts.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Data Source</title>
					<description>Defines the type of database connection that you require.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Query (DBF)  
Grid > Query (AlphaDAO)
</title>
					<description>Specifies the database, table, filter expression, and order expression.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the grid and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Properties</title>
					<description>Sets properties for the grid, including style.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Update Settings</title>
					<description>Appears if the grid is updateable. Sets add, edit, and insert properties.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Search > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the search part and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Search > Properties  </title>
					<description>Sets properties for the search part.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Detail View > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the detail view part and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Detail View > Properties</title>
					<description>Sets properties for the detail view part.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Events  </title>
					<description>Allows you to create scripts to respond to grid events.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Information  </title>
					<description>Allows you to record information about the grid.  </description>
				</case>
				
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		
		
</sections>
	
	
	
</page>