<page>
   <topic>EMAIL_CLIENT Function</topic>
    <description>Display the Alpha Anywhere e-mail client.</description>
   <syntax>result as C = email_client([C send_to [,C subject [,C message [,C attachments [,C cc [,C bcc [,L modal [,C text_type [,C profile [,C parent_dlg_title [,C msg_id [,L mdi ]]]]]]]]]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>result</name>
         <description>"Send" = if the Modal flag is set to .T.
"" = in all other casesCharacter</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>send_to</name>
         <description>Optional. One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>subject</name>
         <description>Optional. The subject of the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>message</name>
         <description>Optional. The contents of the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>attachments</name>
         <description>Optional. A CR-LF or comma-delimited list of filenames to attach to the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>cc</name>
         <description>One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>bcc</name>
         <description>One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>modal</name>
         <description>Logical. Optional. Default = .F. (FALSE),
 .T. = The dialog opens as a modal dialog box, .F. = The dialog opens as modeless dialog box. </description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>text_type</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "". The options are: "Plain Text" and "HTML" </description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>profile</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "". The email profile to use. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>parent_dlg_title</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "". The title of an Xdialog to display when the send, reply, or forward events occur.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>msg_id</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "". A user defined value to identify the message.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>mdi</name>
         <description>Logical. Optional. Default = .T. When false, converts the window in a modeless dialog.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
  
   <discussion><![CDATA[
EMAIL_CLIENT() opens the Alpha Anywhere email client allowing you to compose, edit, and send an email message. All arguments are optional. If any of the arguments is specified, Alpha Anywhere fills in the email client with the default value.
In the case of a modal dialog box, if the user closes the email client by pressing the Send button, then Result is set to "send". If the user presses the Cancel button, Result is set to "Cancel". Otherwise, Result is set to a NULL value.
If the email client is opened up from a button on a form, the email client will have additional buttons at the bottom of the window: 
]]></discussion>
<sections><section>
<figure><link>images/FU_EMAIL_CLIENT.GIF</link></figure>
</section></sections>

<sections><section>
<description>
<![CDATA[
These buttons allow you to insert fields and expressions into the body of the email message so that your email can include fields from the current record. You can also include conditional statements so that different text is included in the body of the email based on conditions, and you can also include text in the body of the email that is retrieved from saved template.
 ]]></description>
   </section></sections>
   
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>Open the Alpha Anywhere email client as a modeless dialog and fill in the default email address.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[email_client("president@alphasoftware.com")]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
   <see>
      <ref>Email Functions and Methods</ref>
      <ref><![CDATA[<EMAIL> Pointer Properties]]></ref>
      <ref link="EMAIL_CLIENT_EXTERNAL Function">EMAIL_CLIENT_EXTERNAL()</ref>
   </see>
   <terms>email,defaults,display,events,filename,function,list,set,users,window,xdialog</terms>
</page>