<page>
   <topic>UI_DLG_PANEL Function</topic>
    <description>Create an xdialog panel - this is an xdialog that lives in a panel - and doesn't need to exist to honor automation.</description>
   
   <syntax>V UI_DLG_PANEL(C title,C dialog format[,C code])</syntax>
   <arguments>
   	<argument>
         <name>Result</name>
         <description>The value returned by the dialog. This is typically  the name of the BUTTON that was pressed to close the dialog.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>title</name>
         <description>The title of the dialog. The title may also be specified  dynamically using the syntax: Title = "@=" +  Title_Var_Name.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>dialog</name>
         <description>Format_StringA series of Xdialog commands that describe the appearance  of the dialog box. The basic structure of the Format section is:
</description>
         <list>
         <item><name><![CDATA[
         <<%dlg%]]>
         </name></item>
         <item><name>
		 Xdialog_Code
		 </name></item>
		 <item><name>
		 %dlg% 
		 </name></item>
         
         
         <item>
         <name-title>Argument</name-title>
         <description-title>Description</description-title>
         </item>
         
          <item>
         <name><![CDATA[<<%dlg%]]></name>
         <description>The only optional part of this argument is the "dlg"  sequence of characters (the marker), which can be any string of characters, as long as it  is unique within this instance of the UI_DLG_BOX() function. The character  sequence  is specifically recommended  because it is supported by bubble help.
</description>
         </item>
         
          <item>
         <name>Xdialog_Code</name>
         <description>Xdialog_CodeOne or more statements, each of which must  be on a separate line from the  and %dlg% arguments.
</description>
         </item>
         

          <item>
         <name><![CDATA[%dlg%]]></name>
         <description>The marker characters can be any string of characters, as long as they  match those in the first argument (  ).
</description>
         </item>
         </list>
         
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>code</name>
         <description>Optional. Xbasic code that describes what should happen  when various events happen when the user is interacting with the dialog  box. For example, what should happen when the user presses a button, or  when the user tabs out of a field. The basic structure of the Event Handling  section is:
</description>
<list><item>
<name>
<![CDATA[<<%code%]]>
</name>

</item>
<item><name>
Xbasic_Code
</name>

</item>
<item><name><![CDATA[%code%]]>
</name>

</item></list>

     </argument>
   </arguments>
  
   <discussion>
The UI_DLG_PANEL() function creates an Xdialog box.
   </discussion>
  <limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
   
   <see>
      <ref>UI_DLG_BOX()</ref>
   </see>
<terms>xdialog,ui,button,event handling,events,function,marker,string,tabs,xbasic</terms>
</page>