<page>
    <shortlink>ux list fields client side properties control type</shortlink>
    <topic>Control type</topic>
    <description>Specify the control type to use to display the data in the List. If you choose 'RawData' then the data is not wrapped in any HTML tags (such as span or img) and you must add your own html markup to the template. Use 'CSSIcon' if the data in the field is the name of a CSS font icon (such as Font-Awesome) or an SVG icon.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Fields in a List can be rendered as different control types, such as switches, maps, or button lists.</title>
                <link>images/listcolumntypes.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Control type choices include the following:</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Label</title>
                    <description>Displays the value using the label control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Image</title>
                    <description>Displays the value as an image.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Video</title>
                    <description>Displays the value using a video control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Audio</title>
                    <description>Displays the value using an audio control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>RawData</title>
                    <description>Displays the raw data int he field.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>CSSIcon</title>
                    <description>Displays the value as a CSS icon.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Ink</title>
                    <description>Displays the value using the Ink control.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Star Rating</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Displays a value using a star rating control. Tapping on one of the stars in the control will update the value in the List.</p>
                        <p>For example, in the image below, the selected row in the List (which has an associated Detail View) was edited by tapping on a star and the List row is shown as dirty.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/liststarrating1.jpg</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Switch</title>
                    <description>Displays a value using a two state switch control.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Integer</title>
                    <description>Displays an integer value with buttons to the left and right of the value to increment/decrement the value. You can display buttons that change the value by 1, 10, or 100.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Radiobuttons</title>
                    <description>Displays a value using a button list. The control behaves like a radio button because only one value in the button list can be selected.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Checkbox</title>
                    <description>Displays a value using a button list. The control behaves like a checkbox control because multiple values in the button list can be selected. The selected values are stored as a comma delimited list. For example, if the user selects the Red and Green buttons, the value stored in the List is *[js:Red,Green]*</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Map</title>
                    <description>Display a value using a Map. The value (which must be a comma delimited string with a latitude and longitude value) is shown as a marker on the map.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="4582">
                    <title>Javascript</title>
                    <description>Allows you to define a Javascript function that returns HTML that is displayed in the List. The Javascript must be defined as a List method (i.e. it must be defined in the List builder on the Javascript pane). The method must take these input parameters:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[js:value]*</name>
                            <description>The value of the field.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[js:data]*</name>
                            <description>The array of data for all rows in the List.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[js:rowNumber]*</name>
                            <description>Row number of the row being rendered (zero based).</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[js:fieldName]*</name>
                            <description>The name of the field being rendered.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>For example, the following JavaScript outputs the field name in bold followed by a colon and the field value:</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/javascriptFunc.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[var html = "";

html = "<b>" + fieldName + ":</b> " + value;

return html;]]></example>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>'RawData' Control Type</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The "RawData" control type returns the data "as-is" from the data source. No HTML mark up is automatically added, as is the case when you choose the "Label" or "Image" control type. Use the "RawData" control type when you want complete control over how the HTML for the field should be created. When you use the "RawData" control type, you must put the HTML markup in the template.  </p>
                    <p>For example, say you have a field called "MyImage" that contains an Image URL. If you set the control type to Image, then in the template you would simply place this placeholder: *[cst:{MyImage}]*</p>
                    <p>But if you set the control type to "RawData", the template would then be: *[html:&lt;img src="{MyImage}" /&gt;]* </p>
                </description>
                <date>2013-08-16</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/d81fe398</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Displaying Data in a List using a StarRating Control</title>
                <description>
                    <p> Many applications allow you to rate something by tapping on a star in a StarRating control. The UX component has a stand-alone StarRating control (accessed by selecting [More...] in the UX Builder Controls toolbox), but in some cases you might want to display data in a List control using a StarRating control.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how this is easily done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2017-08-18</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/2d6bad13</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_List_starRatingColumn.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Displaying Data in a List using Switch, Radio Button, Checkbox, Integer Increment and Map Controls</title>
                <description> The UX offers several different control types that can be used to display data in the List.  In this video we demonstrate several of the control types that can be used in a List.</description>
                <date>2017-09-02</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/96e8f94e</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ListColumnTypes.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>