<page>
    <shortlink>transform designer commandproperties</shortlink>
    <topic>Command Properties Screen</topic>
    <description>An explanation of the properties for a command shown on the right side of the screen.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Command Properties Screen displays properties associated with the currently selected row in the Commands List. The particular properties displayed, and their meaning, depend upon the type of command.</p>
                <p>Some of the common properties shared by more than one command type are listed here.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Command Type</title>
            <description>
                <p>The first property displays the type of the command. This is not editable. To change the command type you will need to insert a new command and delete the unwanted one.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Comment</title>
            <description>
                <p>The comment property is a textbox that lets you enter optional information that will appear in the Commands List. This may be used to leave explanations and other information that may be helpful to a person modifying the Form Type Definition at a later time.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Field Name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The field property is used to specify particular items in the form instance data that are given values.</p>
                <p>In colloquial terms, this is the "name of the field". It is different than the Title of a field, which is what is shown to the person reading or filling out the form. In technical terms, these values specify a particular "attribute/value pair" in the JSON data, giving the attribute name that will appear in the JSON.</p>
                <p>These property values correspond to "field names" in a database, but may have hierarchy (a parent-child relationship) as allowed by JSON data and the Data Group functionality. (See the [Terminology] topic for more information about Form Instance Data JSON and Data Groups.)</p>
                <p>In the common case of data fields all at the same level in a hierarchy (that is, no parent-child or one-to-many relationships), you just refer to a field in the data with a simple name in the Field property. This is also the case for data fields that are all on the same "level" in a hierarchy.</p>
                <p>The name should be made up of letters and numbers and be relatively short (1-30 characters). The name may have meaning if you want (such as "quantityOrdered") or not ("field2"). The name choices may depend upon whether or not you are creating JSON data for use with an existing application. While uppercase and lowercase characters should be considered distinct, it is  best to not use names that differ only by case.</p>
                <p>Names must be unique within a level in the parent-child hierarchy. That is, you may usually use a particular name as a field name for only one field; however, a child field may have the same name. For example: A literal "Parent-Child" form may have a "name" field for the parent, as well as a "name" field in each set of fields for each child.</p>
                <p>The Field property knows which level it is referring to by the position of the command using it within the Commands List. If the command is within a Data Group, then it refers to the fields within that "sub-array" of the form instance data that correspond to the contents of the Data Group. If the command is at top level (not within a Data Group), then it knows that a Field property refers to the top level value in the JSON.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="transform designer terminology">Terminology</link>
    </links>
</page>