<page>
    <shortlink>transform designer previewscreen</shortlink>
    <topic>Preview Screen</topic>
    <description>An explanation of the form preview shown on the right side of the screen.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description><p>
  The right side of the app window displays a preview of the currently selected form type. 
 </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Form Tab</title>
            <description><p>
  At the top of the preview is the Form Tab, showing the form Display Name as well as icon with 
  the background color specified for the form type. 
  This is similar to the tab that will be displayed when a form is being filled out in the Form Filler
  app, as well as the tab making up the row in the Form Filler for selecting a particular form instance 
  in the list of forms, and is also displayed at the top of each instance of the form in the Management Console.
 </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Form body</title>
            <description><p>
  The rest of the Preview Screen shows the fields, headings, etc., defined for the form type. 
  The names for fields, and the text of headings come from the commands that define the form type. 
  The values displayed come either from the Preview Values defined for each field, or, if it's present,
  from the Preview Data property for the form type itself.
 </p>
 <p>
  Clicking on most parts of the form preview will switch the left part of the app window to show the Commands List 
  if it is not already being displayed, and will select a command line that corresponds to what you clicked on, 
  showing the appropriate properties for that command. 
  The selected part will be displayed in the Preview with a light gray background.
 </p>
 <p>
  Alternatively, if you are viewing the Commands List on the list, when you select a command the 
  corresponding part of the Preview will be scrolled into view and selected.
 </p></description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>