<page>
	<topic>Add Text to RTF Memo Field</topic>
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Add Text to RTF Memo Field action adds text at any location in an RTF memo field. You may specify the font, style, size, and color. You can also insert new lines before or after the inserted text.</description>
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Insert text into an RTF memo in which window? field. This field will be grayed out unless this action is based on a Form or Browse. The choices are:</description>
				
				<list>
					<item>
						<name>"Current Form or Browse Window".</name>
					</item>
					<item>
						<name>"Another Form or Browse Window".</name>
					</item>
				</list>
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Window Name field select either:</description>
						
				<list>
					<item>
						<name>"Forms"</name>
					</item>
					<item>
						<name>"Browses"</name>
					</item>
				</list>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the form or browse that you wish to use from the list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Object Name field select an RTF field on the form or browse.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Text to Insert field enter either a text string or use the Expression Builder to create an expression that evaluates to a text string.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Start new line before text check box to insert a blank line before the new text.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Insert new line after text check box to insert a blank line after the new text.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Specify the insertion point for the new text.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally specify a new font or point size for the display. Either enter the font name and point size separated by a comma, or click the black triangle on the Font list to display the Select Font dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally check the Bold, Italics, and/or Underline check boxes to set these attributes.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally specify a new font color. Click the black triangle on the Font color list to select a color.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
			
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Working with RTF Data</ref>
		<ref>Rich Text Overview</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>