<page>
	<topic>Branch Command</topic>
	<description>The Branch Command Action can be used to change the execution of your script based on an expression or the value of a control. Note that this action references an open form or browse.</description>

	<sections>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>On the first page of the Script Genie select a value from the Branch Expression is based on list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "The Value in a Control on the current Form or Browse", choose a control from the Control Name list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Branch Choices text box enter a list of choices, separated by line breaks.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Check the Include a default branch check box if you want to have default branch if the expression does not evaluate to any of your choices.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter a unique name for the branch test in the Branch Name field.</description>
		<note>For each choice, specify whether you want to play a script or set a variable to TRUE (.T.). By default, the Action is to set a variable to true. The variable name is a combination of the branch name and the option name. For example, if the branch is branch1 and the choice is New York, the variable will be called branch1_new_york and it will be set to .T. (TRUE). To play a script when a choice is TRUE, you must also specify the name of the script.</note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>For each entry in the If the expression evaluates to list select a value in the then ... list.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected Include a default branch on the previous page of the genie, in the Default Action field specify what you would like to happen for the default branch. If a variable is set to TRUE, it will be called, branchname_else where branchname is the name of your branch.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>On the next page of the Script Genie optionally modify the default comment which describes the action.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
					
				</step>
				
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>A5_EVAL_EXPRESSION()</ref>
		<ref>SELECT ... CASE</ref>
		<ref>How to Use Branches in Your Scripts</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>