<page>
	<topic>Disable Object(s)</topic>
	<description>The Disable Object(s) action renders objects unable to receive focus. A user cannot switch focus to a disabled object.

This action, when used with the Enable Object(s) action, is useful when either user interaction is required for accessing objects, or user interaction indicates that specific objects are unimportant/important for the task at hand. In either case, use the Disable Object action to restrict objects from receiving focus, and use Enable Object to allow focus.
</description>
	<sections>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Disable object(s) in which window? field. This field will be grayed out unless this action is based on a Form or Browse. The choices are:</description>
				<list>
					<item><name>"Current Form or Browse Window". </name></item>
					<item><name>"Another Form or Browse Window". </name></item>
				</list>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Another Form or Browse Window", in the Window Name field select either:</description>
						<list>
					<item><name>"Forms" </name></item>
					<item><name>"Browses" </name></item>
				</list>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select one of the listed forms or browses.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Add Object to List for a pop-up list containing the names of available objects on the specified form or browse.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the object to show and press OK. Repeat the process to show multiple objects.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>To remove an object from the list, highlight the object to be removed, and click Remove Object from List.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref><![CDATA[<OBJECT>.DISABLE()]]></ref>
		<ref><![CDATA[<OBJECT>Enable Object(s)]]></ref>
	</see>
	
</page>