<page>
	<topic>Display a Message Box</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Display a Message Box action automates the process of creating message boxes. Message boxes are a great way to communicate with users, allowing them to accomplish tasks using a simple, specialized interface for the task at hand.</description>
			
		</section>
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>On the first page of the Script Genie select the buttons to include in the message box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Initial Focus field optionally select a different button to have initial focus (becomes the default selection).</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>On the second page of the Script Genie optionally select an image to display on the dialog box. </description>
				<figure><link>images/UG_Dialog_box_display_a_message_box_2.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter a Title for the dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Check Use HTML in message text.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you did not check Use HTML in message text, enter a message to appear in the Message box. It is possible to use static text or an expression that resolves to a character string. To use the Expression Builder press the 'x-y' button.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you did check Use HTML in message text.
</description>
<list>
	<item>
		<name>1. Click Specify HTML Message to display the Edit Message Box Text dialog.</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>2. Enter your message and click Save.
</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>3. Optionally, change the Message width and unit of measurement, which may be: "inches", "cm", or "characters".
</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>4. Optionally, change the Message height and unit of measurement, which may be: "inches", "cm", or "characters".
</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>5. Optionally, select the Dialog background color.
</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>6. Optionally, clear Use Win3D background color. The background of the HTML component of the message will be set by the HTML code.
</name>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>7. Optionally, check Indented to place an indent around the HTML component of the message. 
</name>
	</item>
	<figure><link>images/HTML_Message_Box.gif</link></figure>
	
</list>
				</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Preview to display your message box.
</description>
	</step>		
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.
</description>
	</step>		
	<step>
		<description>Enter a name for the dialog box in the Dialog Name field. The name should be unique so that when referenced, Alpha Anywhere won't confuse it with any other objects.
</description>
	</step>	
	<step>
		<description>Select each button in the If the user selects the list and make a selection in the then... field to specify what happens when you press the button. You can attach a previously defined script, or have it do nothing.
	"Play a Script". Use this option to attach a script to a button. When you select this option, you'll be prompted to select the script you wish to attach. A drop-down box appears, listing available scripts. Pressing the button runs the script.
	
		"Do Nothing - just set a Flag Variable to .T.". Use this option if you do not want the button to play a script. When the button is selected, the message box will close, and set a Flag Variable.
	In both cases, Alpha Anywhere automatically creates and names Flag Variables. In this case: "Error_Handler_YES_button", "Error_Handler_NO_button", and "Error_Handler_CANCEL_button".
</description>	
	</step>	
	<step>
		<description>Finally, Alpha Anywhere asks you set the scope of the variables created on this dialog. A variable's scope refers to where the variable can be "seen". The following options are available:</description>
	<list>
		<item>
			<name>Shared: Variables are available throughout the current form.</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Global: Variables are available anywhere in Alpha Anywhere.</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Local: Variables are available only in the current script.
</name>
		</item>
	</list>
	
	
	</step>	
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
				
			</steps>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>UI_MSG_BOX()</ref>
		
	</see>
	
	
</page>