<page>
	<topic>Exporting and Importing Scripts and Functions</topic>
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			
			<description>You can share scripts or transfer them to other databases by exporting and importing them.</description>
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>To export a script</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Display the Code tab of the Control Panel.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select Code > Export... or Function > Export... or Script > Export... to display the Export Scripts and/or Functions dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the Scripts, Functions, or Scripts and Functions radio buttons.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the name of the file to export in the Filename field or click  to navigate to and select a file to replace.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Export All to display the Export Scripts and Functions to ASCII File dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Export Selected... to display the Select Scripts and Functions dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Place checkmarks to the left of each script or function that you want to export.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click the Select All or UnSelect All buttons to make your choices.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click OK.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>To import a script</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Display the Code tab of the Control Panel.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select Code > Import... or Function > Import... or Script > Import... to display the Import Scripts and/or Functions dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click  to navigate to and select the file to import.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Import to display the Import from dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Place checkmarks to the left of each script or function that you want to import.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, select a script or function and click Preview to display the Preview dialog box.</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>Select the script and click Preview Script.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>Select the function and click Preview Function.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>Click 'X' to exit.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click the Select All or UnSelect All buttons to make your choices.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Import.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Printing Scripts and Functions</ref>
		<ref>Compiling Scripts and Functions</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>