<page>
	<topic>Get Properties of Object(s)</topic>
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Get Properties of Object(s) action retrieves specified properties of one or more object(s) on a form or browse.</description>
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Select the window that contains the text data. There are two options:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Current Form or Browse Window" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Another Form or Browse Window"</description>
					</case>
				</cases>
				
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Another Form or Browse Window", select an open form or browse in the Window Name list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click  to the right of the Get properties of the following objects list to display a list of objects on the window. Select an object and click OK to add it to the list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click  to remove the currently selected item on the Get properties of the following objects list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>For each object in the Get properties of the following objects list, click  to the right of the Get the following properties list to display a list of properties for the object. Select an object and click OK to add it to the Get the following properties list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click  to remove the currently selected item on the Get the following properties list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>For each property value, enter the name you would like to use for the variable.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>For each object in the list, specify the Variable scope. There are two options:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Shared". Means that the variable can be used only by other scripts on the window. </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Global". Means that all scripts can access the variable. </description>
					</case>
				</cases>
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
	<see>
		
		<ref>Get 'Text' Property of Object(s)</ref>
		<ref>Get 'Text' Property of Object(s)</ref>
	</see>
</page>