<page>
	<topic>Run Custom Query</topic>
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Run Custom Query action queries records based on custom filter and order expressions. This query can include parameters prompted for at run-time. If you choose to prompt for parameters at run-time, you can customize the prompts, title, and buttons on the parameters dialog.</description>
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Query records in which Form/Browse window? field. This field will be grayed out unless this action is based on a Form or Browse. The choices are:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Current Form or Browse Window". </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Another Form or Browse Window". </description>
			</case>
		</cases>
		
		
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Another Form or Browse Window", in the Window Name field select either:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Forms" </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Browses" </description>
				</case>
			</cases>
			
			
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select one of the listed forms or browses.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check Prompt for Parameters at run-time? to display the Define Parameters button. The resulting  Define Parameters dialog box lets you define the parameters that the user will be prompted for. When you add parameters, you are creating a dialog box to collect variables from the user at run-time. Once you have created the parameters for the query, you will then create an expression using the parameters on which the query will be based.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, enter a character filter expression that selects records from the table in the Filter Expression field, or click the 'funnel' icon to open the Filter Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, enter an character order expression that sorts the number of records returned in the Order Expression field, or click the 'A..Z' button to open the Order Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Query Options tab.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check the Combine filter with existing filter (if any) check box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check the Exclude records selected by filter check box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click the Tips on Parameters tab.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref><![CDATA[<OBJECT>.QUERYRUN()]]></ref>
	</see>
	
</page>