<page>
	<topic>Using the "Same Condition as Previous" Setting</topic>
	<description>If an Action uses the same condition as the action before it, there is a simple technique to copy the condition.
Add a third Action to your Action Script that opens the Default Form for the Customer table. This action will be conditional, using the same condition as the "Display a Message Box" Action.
</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		<section>
			
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>If you're not already editing the Lesson1 script, open it in the Code Editor.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the "Display a Message Box" Action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Add New Action button.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the "Form/Browse" category and the "Open Default Form or Browse" Action. Click OK to select this Action. Alpha Anywhere displays the Open Default Form or Browse Genie. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/Open_default_form_or_browse_1.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>To open the default form for the Customer table, select "customer" in the For which Table/Set? list and click Next >. 
</description><figure><link>images/Open_default_form_or_browse_3.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>We want the default form to show all records. Select "No additional selection criteria" then click Next > and Finish to complete the Action.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Check the Action is conditional and Same as Previous condition fields. Note that the icon to the left of "Open Default Form or Browse" is now a "ditto" mark, indicating that the action's condition is the same as the previous Action's condition. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/Conditional_action_6.gif</link></figure>
<note>The Same as Previous condition field only appears when the action immediately above it is conditional. If you select the "Display a Message Box" action, the prompt disappears.</note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Save your script and run it to test it. You will see the form is only opened if you enter a non-null value at the first prompt.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the View Xbasic button again to see all the work Action Scripting has automated for you.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
	
</page>