<page>
	<topic>Xbasic Enter Record</topic>
	<description>The Xbasic Enter Record action adds a record without opening a form or browse. The user never has to be aware that changes were made.</description>
		
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Choose an operating mode from the Select Action list. The options are:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Enter a new record" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Edit an existing record" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"View existing record" </description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
				
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the table that contains the record from the Specify name of Table to edit list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Edit an existing record" or "View existing record" in step 1, make a selection from the Specify how Record to edit should be selected list. Otherwise, continue with step 8. The options are:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"By record number" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"By key value" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"By filter expression" </description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
				
				
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "By record number" in step 3, enter the record number, or -1 for the last record, or an expression that evaluates to a record number in the Record number field. Optionally, click the x-y button to open the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "By key value" in step 3, enter an expression in the Key Expression field. Optionally, click the 'x-y' button to open the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "By key value" in step 3, enter an expression in the Key Value field. Optionally, click the x-y button to open the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "By filter expression" in step 3, enter an expression in the Filter Expression field. Optionally, click the 'funnel' icon button to open the Filter Builder.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Click Add Fields to display the Add Fields to List Dialog Box and select the fields you want to update.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, select a field in the Fields to enter/edit list and click Remove Field to eliminate it from the list.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>For each field in the Fields to enter/edit list, make a selection in the Update field to a list. The options are:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Value specified now" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Value contained in a variable" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Result of an expression" </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Prompt at runtime" </description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
				
				
				
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Value specified now" in step 10, enter a value in the Value field.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Value contained in a variable" in step 10, enter a value in the Variable Name field.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Result of an expression" in step 10, enter a value in the Expression field. Optionally, click the x-y button to open the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check Include error checking code to include the Xbasic code to handle errors when opening the table.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Xbasic Change Record</ref>
		<ref>Xbasic View Record</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>