<page>
    <shortlink>form layout multistate switch settings properties</shortlink>
    <topic>FormView Multi-state Switch Settings Properties</topic>
    <description>Multi-state Switch Settings Properties</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Data type</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the data type of the multi-state field.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Character</name>
                    <description>Data is stored as characters.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Number</name>
                    <description>Data stored is a number.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Define switch states</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Define switch states]* property is used to configure the switch states for a multi-state switch control. The multi-state switch control cycles through each state when clicked or tapped.</p>
                <p>When clicked, the [...] smart field button opens the *[ui:Multi-state Switch Settings]* dialog. The states for the switch are managed using the Multi-state Switch Settings dialog. States can be added, modified, reordered, or deleted.</p>
                <p>Every switch has a &lt;Default&gt; state. The &lt;Default&gt; state is required, cannot be deleted, and is always the last state listed in the list of States.</p>
                <p>If the *[ui:Multi-state switch type]* is set to "HTML", the Multi-state Switch Settings dialog can be used to define the HTML shown when a state is selected.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/stateHTML.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If the *[ui:Multi-state switch type]* is set to "Icon", the Multi-state Switch Settings dialog can be used to define the image or icon shown when a state is selected. The icon can be an SVG image, a font icon, an image from the project, or a built-in Alpha Anywhere image.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/stateIcon.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Multi-state Switch Settings Tools</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Tool</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Add state</name>
                    <description>Add a new state.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Delete state</name>
                    <description>Delete the selected state. The &lt;Default&gt; state cannot be deleted.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Up</name>
                    <description>Move the selected state up. The &lt;Default&gt; state cannot be moved.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Down</name>
                    <description>Move the selected state down. The &lt;Default&gt; state cannot be moved.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Select icon</name>
                    <description>If the *[ui:Multi-state switch type]* is set to "Icon", the Select icon button is used to pick an icon from the project, an icon font, or a built in SVG or Alpha image.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>HTML</name>
                    <description>If the *[ui:Multi-state switch type]* is set to "HTML", the HTML box is where HTML can be entered to define the displayed content when the switch state is selected.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Insert image</name>
                    <description>If the *[ui:Multi-state switch type]* is set to "HTML", the Insert image link can be used to insert an image from the project, an icon font, or built-in SVG or Alpha image.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Multi-state switch type</title>
            <description>
                <p>Each 'state' of the switch can be represented by an icon, or some custom HTML.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Icon</name>
                    <description>Each state is represented by an icon.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>HTML</name>
                    <description>Each state is rendered with HTML. HTML can include an icon. Use this option if you would like to display text with an icon.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Defining States as HTML</title>
                <link>images/stateHTML.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Defining States as Icons</title>
                <link>images/stateIcon.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Switch Control</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Most fields in a FormView control are edited in an associated 'editor'. When the user taps on the field in the Form, the associated editor is opened, the user edits the form field value and then saves the edited value back to the form. This is called 'indirect editing'. </p>
                    <p>There are cases, however, where 'immediate' editing of a value would be more convenient than having to go to a separate editor to edit the value. A good use case for an 'immediate' editor is a toggle field that has two states, such as 'Yes' or 'No' for a 'Married' field. A 'switch' control is ideal for this use case. </p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can add a switch control to a FormView. The switch control acts as an 'immediate' editor.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2015-08-10</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/593c1828</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/FormViewSwitch.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
</page>
