<page build="">
    <shortlink>getting started installing</shortlink>
    <topic>Installing</topic>
    <description title=""></description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Install Alpha Anywhere</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[extlink:Download the Alpha Anywhere Universal Installer@https://download.alphasoftware.com/Installer/InstallAlphaAnywhereCommunityEdition.exe]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>Request a free *[link:Alpha Anywhere Community Edition@https://www.alphasoftware.com/build-apps-for-free-community-edition-download]* license if you do not have one.</p>
                    </note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>When the download completes, run the installer. You may be prompted to update the installer. Click the *[ui:Update]* button to apply the update.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Windows User Account Control may ask you if you want to run the installer. Click "Yes" to continue.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the *[ui:Available]* tab, locate the Developer Edition and click the *[ui:Install]* button.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/installCE1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Run the installer to completion. This typically takes 5 minutes.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>

                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If prompted to reboot, reboot your computer and rerun the installer. You may see this prompt if you have pending Windows Updates or have installed another product that requires a reboot. A pending reboot may prevent the Alpha Anywhere installation from completing.</p>
                        <p>You can optionally click *[ui:Continue]*, however it is strongly recommended that you reboot your system before continuing with the installation.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Enter your License</title>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere requires a license number to run. You will be prompted to enter your license the first time you run the software.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Launch Alpha Anywhere. This can be done by clicking the *[ui:Launch]* button on the *[ui:Installed]* tab in the Universal Installer or by opening the app from the Windows Start Menu.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Locate your license number. If you do not have a license, you can *[extlink:request a free Community Edition license@https://www.alphasoftware.com/build-apps-for-free-community-edition-download]*. If you purchased an Alpha Anywhere subscription and cannot locate your license, contact custserv@alphasoftware.com.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Enter your Alpha Anywhere license number and click OK.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The registration screen is shown when you launch Alpha Anywhere for the first time.</title>
                        <link>images/license.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Great! Now that Alpha Anywhere is installed and registered, we can start building an app.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <next>
        <link link="getting started building">Building</link>
    </next>
</page>