<page build="6838">
    <shortlink>ionicAppflow</shortlink>
    <topic>PhoneGap / Ionic Appflow</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere now includes an Ionic Appflow build option in the PhoneGap App Builder Genie. Support is provided for Android and iOS builds using Ionic Appflow.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Ionic Appflow is a cloud based service that allows an Alpha mobile app developer to build PhoneGap / Cordova apps for iOS or Android in the cloud, similar to PhoneGap Build.</p>
        <p>As described on the Ionic Appflow welcome page, "Appflow is a continuous integration (CI) and continuous deployment (CD) platform for Ionic development teams. Appflow helps development teams continuously build and ship their Cordova and Capacitor apps faster than ever."</p>
        <p>Appflow can be used as an alternative to PhoneGap Build which is in "maintenance mode" per Adobe. PhoneGap Build is no longer available as a subscription offering for paid accounts and is not expected to support versions of iOS beyond iOS 12. If you want to build your PhoneGap / Cordova apps with a cloud based service, Ionic Appflow is a good alternative to PhoneGap Build.</p>
        <figure>
            <link>images/appflow_dashboard.png</link>
        </figure>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Ionic Appflow Subscription and Setup</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Setup an Ionic Appflow paid Account</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Go to *[extlink:https://ionicframework.com/pricing/compare]* and purchase an account. Compiling native iOS or Android apps requires a paid Ionic Appflow account. At a minimum, you must purchase a Launch plan.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appfLow_intro1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Setup a GitHub Account</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Go to *[extlink:https://github.com/]* and create a GitHub account if you do not already have one.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Install GitHub Desktop</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Download and install *[extlink:GitHub Desktop@https://desktop.github.com]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Build your PhoneGap Project</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>From within Alpha Anywhere, open the PhoneGap App Builder Genie and select Ionic Appflow as the *[ui:App Build Target]*.</p>
                        <p>Use the PhoneGap App Builder as you normally would to build your PhoneGap App. When you are finished configuring the properties for your app, click *[ui:Save and Build For Ionic Appflow]*.</p>
                        <p>Next, Alpha Anywhere will ask where you want to save the generated files. The files will be saved in a folder named *[em:ProjectName]* within the selected directory. The location where the files are saved will be passed to GitHub Desktop, which will be used to create the git repository.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/alpha_pgbuilder.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Create a git Repository</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once all of the files are transferred and created, GitHub Desktop will launch. Click *[ui:create a repository]* to create a git repository.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_create_git_repo.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title nested="2">Publish the Repository to GitHub</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>After the repo is created, click *[ui:Publish repository]* to publish the repository to your GitHub account. You are now ready to create a new app in Ionic Appflow</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/github_publish_repo.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating an App in Ionic Appflow</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Go to *[extlink:https://dashboard.ionicframework.com/]* and login.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Create a new app. Click *[ui:Apps]* and select *[ui:Add App]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_create_new_app.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Enter your app name. It can be anything you want. This app will be linked to the project GitHub repo in a later step.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_add_new_app.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once the app is created, click *[ui:Commits]*. You will notice that no commits are listed. The next step is to connect this app to your project GitHub repo.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_no_commits.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Settings]* to link the app to your GitHub repo.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_settings.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, click *[ui:Git]* and select *[ui:GitHub]* from the top menu. If it isn't already connected, connect Ionic Appflow to your GitHub account. Once you connect to your GitHub account, all of your repositories will be shown.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_showing_repos.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the GitHub repository for this app.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_connect_repo.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>You will now need to make a new commit to the linked GitHub repo in order for Appflow to pick up the commit. To do that, go to your Alpha Anywhere project, make a simple change to the component to make it dirty and save. Then, open the PhoneGap Builder and click *[Save and Build For Ionic Appflow]*.</p>
                        <p>To initiate an iOS or Android build, click on the isometric grey box on the right side of the screen.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_commits.png</link>
                    </figure>
                 </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating an iOS Build</title>
            <description>
                <p>Select iOS Xcode 11 as the build *[ui:Target Platform]*. Select the development *[ui:Build Type]* for testing. </p>
                <p>When you first create an iOS build, you will need to create a *[ui:Security Profile]* that will contain your Apple development credentials which are required to sign and run the app on a device. This step is repeated for every iOS project you create to make sure to keep your signing certificate P12 and provisioning profile in a directory that is easy to remember and access.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_create_new_build.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the *[ui:security profile]* link, give the profile and name and select a Production or Development type as appropriate. Then, click *[ui:Create]*</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_add_security_profile.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, click the iOS tab. Upload your *[ui:Apple Development/Store Certificate]* P12 file, *[ui:Provisioning Profile]* file, and enter your *[ui:Certificate Password]*.</p>
                        <p>When you are done, click *[ui:Save]* to save the profile.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_edit_security_profile.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>
                        <p>This step is the same as the iOS signing process in PhoneGap Build.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>iOS Security Profile</title>
                        <link>images/appflow_show_security_profiles.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_create_new_build_with_profile.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <description>
                        <p>The security profile will be added to the project, and you can now click *[ui:Build]* to start the iOS build process.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_build_progress.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appflow_show_builds.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <description>
                        <p>For iOS builds, Ionic Appflow will fire up a Mac OS Virtual Machine and progress will be displayed as the build progresses. Once the process is completed, a link to the .ipa file is displayed to the right of the console screen. The .ipa file is also listed in the App Builds list.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/diawi.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <description>
                        <p>iOS .ipa files cannot be loaded directly onto an iOS device. The easiest way to load the app .ipa file onto a device is using a third-party service like Diawi.com. .ipa files can be uploaded to Diawi.com and then installed on your iOS device. See *[extlink:https://www.diawi.com/]* for more information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating an Android Build</title>
            <description>
                <p>The process of creating an Android .apk file on Appflow is very similar to the process of creating an iOS app. The only difference is specifying Android as the target platform.</p>
                <p>The generated .apk file can be loaded directly on an Android device.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/appflow_create_android_build.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Video Overview: Using Ionic Appflow with Alpha Anywhere To Build PhoneGap Apps</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Ionic AppFlow is a service offered by Ionic for building iOS and Android PhoneGap application. It is tightly integrated in the Alpha Anywhere PhoneGap Genie.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we'll walk you through the process of building Alpha Anywhere applications with Ionic Appflow.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mzeO0ENXGcU</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>