<page build="6838">
    <shortlink>ionicAppflow</shortlink>
    <topic>PhoneGap /Ionic Appflow  </topic>
    <description>
        Alpha Anywhere now includes an Ionic Appflow build option in the PhoneGap App Builder Genie. Support is provided for Android and iOS builds using Ionic Appflow. 
    </description>
    <discussion>
      <p>Ionic Appflow is a cloud based service that allows an Alpha mobile app developer to build PhoneGap / Cordova apps for iOS or Android in the cloud, similiar to PhoneGap Build.</p>
      <p>
        As described on the Ionic Appflow welcome page, "Appflow is a continuous integration (CI) and continuous deployment (CD) platform for Ionic development teams. Appflow helps development teams continuously 
      build and ship their Cordova and Capacitor apps faster than ever."
      </p>
      <p>Appflow can be used as an alterntive to PhoneGap Build which is in "maintenance mode" per Adobe. PhoneGap Build is no longer available as a subscription offering for paid accounts and 
      it is not expected to support versions of iOS beyond iOS 12. If you want to build your PhoneGap / Cordova apps with a cloud based service, Ionic Appflow is a good alternative to PhoneGap Build.</p>
       <figure>
          <link>images/appflow_dashboard.png</link>
       </figure>
    </discussion>
 
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Ionic Appflow Subscription And Setup</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>*[Setup An Ionic Appflow Paid Account]*</description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <figure>
                               <link>images/appflow_intro1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                               <link>images/appflow_pricing.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                     <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>In order to compile native iOS or Android apps you need to subscribe to the Launch Plan at $42.00 per month.</p>
                                <p>a. See: *[extlink:https://ionicframework.com/pricing/compare]* </p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Setup A GitHub Account]*</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                           <figure>
                               <link>images/setup_github_acct.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                           <description>
                              <p>a. See *[extlink:https://github.com/]*</p>
                           </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Install GitHub Desktop]*</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                         <case>
                           <figure>
                               <link>images/github_desktop.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>a. Follow the installation instructions *[extlink:https://desktop.github.com]*.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>*[Build Your PhoneGap Project]*</description>
                    <cases>
                      <case>
                         <figure>
                               <link>images/alpha_pgbuilder.png</link>
                           </figure>
                      </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                              <p>From within Alpha Anywhere, open the PhoneGap App Builder Genie and select Ionic Appflow as the App Build Target.</p>
                              <p>Use the PhoneGap App Builder as you normally would to build your PhoneGap App. When all of the numerous properties, features, plugins, images, etc. required for your app 
                              have been entered, modified and selected, click the *[Save and Build For Ionic Appflow]* button at the bottom of the panel. 
                              </p>
                              <p>
                                All of the app files and assets are copied to a folder named ionicAppflowRepo in the Alpha workspace PhoneGapProjects/ProjectName root directory. GitHub Desktop will be passed
                                this path to allow you to easily create the required Ionic Appflow repository.
                              </p>
                              <p>
                                Once all of the files are transferred and created, GitHub Desktop will launch.
                              </p>
                           </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>*[GitHub Desktop]*</description>
                    <cases>
                      <case>
                         <figure>
                               <link>images/github_desktop.png</link>
                           </figure>
                      </case>
                      <case>
                          <p>Once the repo is created, publish the repositiry to your GitHub account. You are now ready to connect the GitHub repo you just created to a new app in Ionic Appflow</p>
                      </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating An App In Ionic Appflow</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>*[Login To Your Ionic Appflow Dashboard]*</description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                          <description>
                            <p>
                              a. See *[extlink:https://dashboard.ionicframework.com/]*
                            </p>
                            <p>
                              b. To create a new app, click on the App menu button and click the blue Add App button on the upper right corner of the screen.
                            </p>
                          </description>
                          
                        </case>
                        <case>
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_create_new_app.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                         
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_add_new_app.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                           <description>
                            <p>
                              Enter your app name. It can be anything you want. This app will be linked to the project GitHub repo in a later step.
                            </p>
                          </description>
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_no_commits.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                           <description>
                            <p>
                              Once the app is created, click on the Commits menu button. You will notice that no commits are listed. The next step is to connect this app to your project GitHub repo.
                            </p>
                          </description>
                         
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_showing_repos.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_connect_repo.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                       <case>
                          <description>
                            <p>
                              Click on the Settings menu button to link the app to your GitHub repo. Next, click on Git and select GitHub from the top menu. Once you connect to your GitHub account all of
                              your repos will be displayed. Select the repo for this app. 
                            </p>
                          </description>
                         
                          <figure>
                              <link>images/appflow_commits.png</link>
                           </figure>
                        </case>
                      <case>
                        <description>
                           <p>
                             You will now need to make a new commit to the linked GitHub repo in order for Appflow to pick up the commit. To do that, go to your Alpha project, make a simple change to the component or make it dirty and save. Then open the PhoneGap
                             Builder and  click the *[Save and Build For Ionic Appflow]* button at the bottom of the panel. 
                           </p>
                          <p>
                            To initiate an iOS or Android build, click on the isometric grey box on the right side of the screen.
                          </p>
                         </description>
                      </case>
                    </cases>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating an iOS Build</title>
            <description>
                <p>Select iOS Xcode 11 as the build target platform. Select the development build type for testing. </p>
                <p>When you first create an iOS build, you will need to create a security profile that will contain your Apple development credentials which are required to sign and run the app on a device. This step
                is repeated for every iOS project you create to make sure to keep your signing certificate P12 and provisioning profile in a directory that is easy to remember and access.</p>
            </description>
          <cases>
            <case>
                <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_create_new_build.png</link>
                </figure>
             </case>
              <case>
                 <description>
                      <p>Click the blue Security Profile link, give the profile and name and select a Production or Development type as appropriate. Next click the iOS tab.</p>
                </description>
                <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_add_security_profile.png</link>
                </figure>
             </case>
              <case>
                 <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_edit_security_profile.png</link>
                </figure>
             </case>
            <case>
              <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_show_security_profiles.png</link>
                </figure>
                 <description>
                  <p>
                    Select your Apple Development certificate P12 file and enter the certificate password. Next select the provisioning profile and click the blue Save button. This step is exactly the same as the iOS signing process in PhoneGap Build. 
                  </p>
                </description>
            </case>
              <case>
                <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_create_new_build_with_profile.png</link>
                </figure>
                <description>
                  <p>
                    The security profile will be added to the project and you can now click the blue Build button to start the iOS build process.
                  </p>
                </description>
             </case>
              <case>
                <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_build_progress.png</link>
                </figure>
             </case>
             <case>
                <figure>
                  <link>images/appflow_show_builds.png</link>
                </figure>
                <description>
                    <p>
                      For iOS builds, Appflow will fire up a Mac OS VM and progress will be displayed. Once the process is completed, a link to the ipa file is displayed to the right of the console screen and it is also listed in the App Builds list. 
                    </p> 
                </description>
             </case>
            <case>
              <figure>
                  <link>images/diawi.png</link>
                </figure>
              <description>
                 <p>
                      iOS ipa files cannot be loaded directly onto an iOS device. The easiet way to load the app ipa file onto a device is to drag and drop the file to Diawi.com. See: *[extlink:https://www.diawi.com/]*
                 </p>
              </description>
            </case>
          </cases>
          
        </section>
        <section>
           <title>Creating an Android Build</title>
            <description>
                <p>The process of creating an Android apk file on Appflow is very similar to the process of creating an iOS app. The only difference is specifying Android as the target platform.
                </p>
              <p>
                The generated apk file can be loaded directly on an Android device.
              </p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/appflow_create_android_build.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
      <section>
        <title> Video Overview: Using Ionic Appflow with Alpha Anywhere To Build PhoneGap Apps</title>
        <description>
          <p>
           *[extlink:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PMxBa7cR-Ys]*
          </p>
        </description>
      </section>
    </sections>
</page>