<page>
    <shortlink>server ref Google Map Properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Google Map Properties</topic>
    <description>The Google Map Component's properties are used to configure the component, including it's initial view, SSL support, custom styling and more.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Google Map Properties Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Initial Map Type</title>
                    <description>The type of Google Map to display. This can be changed by the user using the displayed controls. Choices include *[ui:HYBRID]*, *[ui:ROADMAP]*, *[ui:SATELLITE]*, *[ui:TERRAIN]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Use Google Maps Premier</title>
                    <description>Check this if you have a Google Maps Premier client ID and want to use it</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Google Maps Premier Client ID</title>
                    <description>Enter your Google Maps Premier client ID</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Use SSL</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want to call Google Maps using SSL (HTTPS:)</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Use Sensor</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want to use a GPS or other geolocation method for any reason, or if this map is intended to be used on a mobile device.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Set Initial Position from Sensor</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want to use a GPS or other geolocation method to set the initial map center. This works best on mobile devices.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Initial zoom factor</title>
                    <description>The initial zoom factor on the map. This can be changed by the user using the displayed controls. 0 shows the whole world; 20 shows a few square yards. Displaying a circle will override this setting.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Create marker at initial center</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want a push pin and/or polygon vertex created at the initial map center</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Initial marker is draggable</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want the initial push pin to be draggable by the user</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show markers</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want push pins displayed.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Added markers are draggable</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want any user-added push pins to be draggable by the user</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show polygon</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want a polygonal area displayed</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Polygon color</title>
                    <description>The color used for displaying the Polygon, as hex RGB, e.g. #FF0000</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Maximum number of points</title>
                    <description>The maximum number of markers or vertices to display</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show circle</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want a circle displayed</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Circle color</title>
                    <description>The color used for displaying the circle, as hex RGB, e.g. #00FF00</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Circle radius</title>
                    <description>The radius of the circle to display, in meters. 1 mile is roughly 1609 m. Note that displaying a circle resets the map size.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Geocoding source</title>
                    <description>The service to use for geocoding addresses. Choices include *[ui:Google]*, *[ui:Nominatim]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Reinitialize on Geocode</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want to reinitialize the map if the user geocodes an address. Otherwise, the geocoded point will be added to the map.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Cluster bulk markers</title>
                    <description>Check this if you want to display bulk markers in clusters (useful if you have a lot of markers to display)</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>HTML Properties Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Map Width</title>
                    <description>The width of the map, e.g. "400px" or "3in"</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Map Height</title>
                    <description>The height of the map, e.g. "500px" or "4in"</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Toolbar HTML</title>
                    <description>HTML that defines the controls for the toolbar</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Toolbar position</title>
                    <description>Specify whether the HTML toolbar is above or below the map. Choices include *[ui:Below]*, *[ui:Above]*.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Other Component Properties Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Style name</title>
                    <description>Click the button to select a new style, or edit the existing style.  You can also use &lt;ProjectStyle&gt; or &lt;Session:varname&gt;</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Class map</title>
                    <description>Specify how the abstract CSS class names used in this component map to physical CSS class names in your style sheets.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Resolve abstract CSS class names</title>
                    <description>Replace abstract CSS class names with physical CSS class names. This should only be un-checked if you are in development mode and you want to determine what the abstract CSS class name is for a particular element in the component.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Font size</title>
                    <description>Specify if the fonts in the Component should be scaled to make the component larger or smaller. Select 'Medium' for no scaling (i.e. the fonts shown will match those defined in the style sheet). Choices include.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Font scaling option</title>
                    <description>Specify which CSS classes should be scaled. If you choose All, the fonts in these classes will be scaled, in addition to the fonts in the CSS classes specific to the Style that you selected: BODY, TABLE, TH, TR, TD, UL, OL, LI, P, A, BLOCKQUOTE. Choices include *[ui:All]*, *[ui:GridStyleClassesOnly]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Master template</title>
                    <description>Specify an optional Master Template. This allows you to place arbitrary HTML surrounding the component.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Page title</title>
                    <description>Specify the page title for the .a5w page that renders this component.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>CSS/SVG Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Local CSS definitions</title>
                    <description>Define any local CSS classes. NOTE: You can include SASS syntax in your CSS definition. For more information on SASS syntax see *[extlink:http://sass-lang.com/]*</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Additional component styles</title>
                    <description>Specify if any other styles (in addition to the primary style for the component) must be included. Enter a comma delimited list of style names. e.g., GlassOlive,Airport</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">CSS Linked files</title>
                    <description>Specify any CSS files that should be linked (in addition to the primary style for the Component). Enter a comma delimited list of filenames.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Local SVG definitions</title>
                    <description>Specify any local SVG  image definitions you want to include in this component.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">SVG Linked files</title>
                    <description>Specify any SVG files that should be linked. Enter a comma delimited list of filenames. Only relative filenames can be specified. Files must be in a folder relative to the webroot.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Arguments Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Arguments</title>
                    <description>Define arguments. Arguments can be bound to page, session and cookie variables. Argument values are passed into all server-side Xbasic event handlers in the component.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Javascript Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Javascript Linked files</title>
                    <description>Specify any Javascript files that should be linked. Enter a comma delimited list of filenames.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Xbasic Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Xbasic Linked files</title>
                    <description>Specify any Xbasic Function Library files that should be linked. Enter a comma delimited list of filenames. Defining Xbasic functions in a Function Library (that can be shared among multiple components) is an alternative to defining your Xbasic functions in this component (see 'Xbasic functions' on the toolbox).</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Other Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Language definitions</title>
                    <description>Define strings for different languages.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Text dictionary tags</title>
                    <description>Show Text Dictionary tags (&lt;a5:t&gt;...&lt;/a5:t&gt;) used in this component.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Active language</title>
                    <description>Specify the active language to use for translating strings tagged with &lt;a5:r&gt;..&lt;/a5:r&gt; tags. Setting the property here is useful for testing purposes. In a real application you can set the 'session.__protected__activeLanguage' variable to specify the active language. To select the default language, enter &lt;Default&gt; or leave this property blank.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Remove un-consumed language tags</title>
                    <description>Should any language tags that were not replaced (because they were not defined in the Language Definition) be removed from any output sent to the browser?</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Head section tags</title>
                    <description>Specify any tags you want to appear in the HEAD section of the page that hosts this component.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Component must run in IFrame</title>
                    <description>Specify if this component must run in its own IFrame.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">IFrame inline style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the IFrame. You should set a height and width for the IFrame. e.g. width: 6in; height 4in;</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Advanced Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Other properties</title>
                    <description>Specify other properties of the component</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Save component format</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify if the component should be saved as a binary file or as formatted JSON.</p>
                        <p>Formatted JSON saves the properties in clear text. This is useful if you are using some type of source or version control system and the system has a method to show differences between versions. Choices include *[ui:Binary]*, *[ui:Formatted JSON]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>