<page>
	  <topic>Alternate View Type</topic>

   <description>There are three types of Alternate Views that you can add to your grid; Chart, Custom, and Google Map. </description>
	   
<sections>
	<section>
<title>Selecting an Alternate View:</title>
		
<steps>
<step>
	<description>From the Web Projects Control Panel open the Grid Builder. On the Design tab open the Data Source page and choose either .dbf or SQL.</description>
</step>	
<step>
	<description>Under Query(DBF) or Query(AlphaDAO) choose a table to connect to that contains fields that can be applied to an alternate view.</description>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>On the Fields page move a number of fields from the Available fields: list into the Selected fields list. Select fields that can be used for your alternate view. For example if you are doing a map choose fields that contain records for Addresses, Cities, Latitudes, Longitudes, and/or Countries.</description>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>On the Properties page find the Alternate View properties and check Has Alternate View property checkbox.</description>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>Click the button [...] next to the Alternate Views definition property. This will open the Alternate View Builder. At first you will see no properties</description>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>On the Alternate Views tab click the Add Alternate View button.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_AlternateView3.png</link></figure>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>The Add New Alternate View dialog will open. Click the Select button next to the Alternate View Type: box.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_AlternateView4.png</link></figure>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>This will open the Alternate View Type dialog. Select the Alternate View you want to use and click OK.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_AlternateView5.png</link></figure>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>You will see the Alternate View Type you selected appear in the Add New Alternate View dialog. Now type in an ID: and Label: for your Alternate View, these can be any string.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_AlternateView6.png</link></figure>
</step>	

<step>
	<description>Click OK. Your selected Alternate View should appear in the Alternate View Builder's  Alternate Views: menu. You should also now see an Alternate View Properties list.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_AlternateView7.png</link></figure>
</step>	

	
	
	
</steps>
		
		
		
	</section>
	
	
	
	
	
</sections>
	
	<links>
		<link href="images/open.png">...</link>
	</links>
	
	
</page>