<page>
    <topic>Time picker customization</topic>
    <description>Customize the choices for the hours, minutes, and seconds in the time picker.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Time picker customization]* property can be used to customize the hours, minutes, and seconds shown in the time picker. Clicking the [...] smart field button for the property opens the *[ui:Customize Time Picker]* window.</p>
        <p>To customize the options for hours, minutes or seconds, check the appropriate box to display the options.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/timePickerCustom.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Setting Columns</title>
            <description>
                <p>The choices for hours, minutes, and seconds are displayed as a table that is shown when the user selects the column. The *[ui:Number of columns]* property can be used to specify how many columns to display. By default (a value of "-1"), Alpha Anywhere displays 12 columns for hours and 10 columns for minutes and seconds.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The hours configured to display 6 columns.</title>
                <link>images/timePickerHours.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Using a Step</title>
            <description>
                <p>An interval or *[ui:Step]* can be used to define what options are available for the Time picker. The "Step" option for the *[ui:Method for determining available choices]* property can be used to define an interval between each choice. For example, if you wanted to display Minutes in 15-minute intervals, you would set the *[ui:Step]* to 15. The user will be presented with the following options in the time picker when selecting the minutes: 0, 15, 30, and 45.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Minutes configured with a Step of 15.</title>
                <link>images/timePickerMinutes.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Explicitly Defining Choices</title>
            <description>
                <p>Time options can also be explicitly defined to a static list of choices. Set the *[ui:Method for determining available choices]* to "Explicit" and specify the choices as a comma-delimited list of values in the *[xb:Explicit]* property.</p>
                <p>If defining choices for hours, you can define the hours as 12 hour time using the "am" and "pm" prefix. If no prefix is supplied, 24 hour time is assumed.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Seconds configured with an explicit list of choices. The only choice is '0'.</title>
                <link>images/timePickerSeconds.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Choices with a JavaScript Function</title>
            <description>
                <p>Time picker choices can also be defined using a JavaScript function. The function must return options as an array.</p>
                <p>For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[function getSeconds() {
    return ["0","10","25","33","59"];
}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The hours can be specified using 24 hour time or 12 hour time. For example, both functions below return the values 1am and 1pm. The *[js:getHours12]* returns the hours using 12 hour format while *[js:getHours24]* uses 24 hour format:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[function getHours12() {
    return ["1am","1pm"];
}

function getHours24() {
    return ["1","13"];
}
]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Hours can be specified as 12 hour format using the "am" and "pm" prefix.</title>
                <link>images/timePickerHours2.png</link>
            </figure>
            <note>The "am" and "pm" prefix is not case-sensitive.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
</page>