<page>
    <topic>PhoneGap-  Modified The Default Location For Persistent Files</topic>
   <description>Previous versions set the Persistent File Location property to "Compatibility" mode on both Android and iOS devices. It has now been changed to "Internal" for Android and "Library" for iOS. 
</description> 
<sections>
    <section>
      <description>This is the recommended setting on Android to ensure the files are contained within the app folder and that the files are deleted when the app is deleted. Under iOS, the files are always in the app folder, however, files in the Library folder are not available to iTunes nor are they synchronized to iCloud.

When "Compatibility" mode is set as the persistent file location for an Android PhoneGap app:</description>
<cases>
    <case>
        <description>The files are written to the devices root directory
</description>
    </case>
    <case>
        <description>The app has full access to the devices files
</description>
    </case>
    <case>
        <description>The media files are indexed by the Gallery app
</description>
    </case>
    <case>
        <description>The files are NOT deleted when the app is un-installed from the device.
</description>
    </case>
    
</cases>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>When "Compatibility" mode is set as the persistent file location for an iOS PhoneGap app:
</description>
        <cases>
    <case>
        <description>The files are written to the apps sand-boxed Documents directory
</description>
    </case>
    <case>
        <description>The files may be accessed via iTunes
</description>
    </case>
    <case>
        <description>The files may be synchronized to iCloud
</description>
    </case>
 
</cases>
    </section>
    
<section>
    <description>In general "Compatibility" mode is NOT the recommended setting.

If you have used the PhoneGap file plug-in in previous versions, the default setting will make your app files inaccessible. The setting will not change for existing PhoneGap apps because the previous "Compatibility" setting will remain within the configuration file. Your app will only be affected if you delete the previous PhoneGap project and create a new one. You can change this setting by enabling Show Advanced Options in the Configuration Options settings of the PhoneGap App Builder Genie. Once the Show Advanced Options is enabled, you can change the persistent file location as required 
</description>
</section>    
    
    
</sections>
    
    
</page>