<page>
    <topic>User Included PhoneGap Plugins</topic>
    <description>The PhoneGap Builder includes a User Included Plugin Manager that allows the developer to include any PhoneGap plugin that is publicly available through NPM or GitHub.
	</description>
	
	<sections>
        <section>
			<description>
				<p>While Alpha Anywhere includes the ability to add most of the major PhoneGap plugins to any project from within the PhoneGap App Builder, the list of available PhoneGap plugins is extensive and dynamic. You may find that you need to use a PhoneGap plugin that is not listed in the PhoneGap App Builders' 3rd Party Plugins section. With the User Included Plugin Manager, you can build a library of user included plugins for use within any Alpha Anywhere PhoneGap App. It's easy to add any PhoneGap plugin that you'd like to use with the User Included Plugin Manager. </p>
			</description>
		</section>
		
		 <section>
            <description>The PhoneGap User Included Plugin Manager is accessed by clicking the button labled *[Manage My PhoneGap Plugins]* from within the PhoneGap App Builder.</description>
            <figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img1.png</link>
			</figure>
        </section>
		
		<section>
			<title>The PhoneGap User Included Plugin Manager</title>
            <description>The PhoneGap User Included Plugin Manager allows you to add, edit or delete any publicly available 3rd party PhoneGap plugin for use within the PhoneGap App Builder.</description>
            <figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img2.png</link>
			</figure>
        </section>
		
		<section>
            <description><p>The New button allows you to insert a new PhoneGap Plugin definition. Required fields include the plugin name, a resource or URL link (for GIT installed plugins) and the required repository which may be GIT, NPM or PGB. The PGB (PhoneGap Build) repository has been deprecated and should not be used for new projects. </p>
			<p>Optional fields include the help field which shows up in the help text area of the PhoneGap App Builder and the plugin version> If the version field is left blank, the latest plugin version is always loaded with the project.</p>
			</description>
            <figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img3.png</link>
			</figure>
        </section>
		
		<section>
            <description><p>The Edit button allows you to edit an existing PhoneGap Plugin definition. If you make a change to the resource or url link and have installed the older definition of the plugin in any PhoneGap Build project, the older plugin resource will remain referenced in the PhoneGap config.xml file. If you need to remove the reference in the PhoneGap Build config.xml file, you'll need to do that manually. See the instructions below. </p>
			</description>
            <figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img4.png</link>
			</figure>
        </section>
		
		<section>
            <description><p>If you define a plugin resource/url that already exists within the PhoneGap App Builder 3rd Party Plugins list, the user referenced plugin will take the highest priority. Assuming the resource/url link is exactly the same as the resource/url link within the PhoneGap App Builder 3rd Party Plugins list, then the user included plugin will appear with the user included plugins and the built in 3rd party plugin will not appear within the 3rd Party Plugin List. </p>
			<p>This allows the developer to easily specify a preferred specific plugin version or repository. In the example below, including a definition for the printer plugin, which is included within the PhoneGap Builder 3rd Party Plugins list however the repo has been changed from PGB to NPM.
			</p>
			</description>
            <figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img5.png</link>
			</figure>
        </section>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img6.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img7.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img8.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/pluginManager_img9.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</page>