<page>
    <shortlink>how to display a three state checkbox on a grid</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Display a Three State Checkbox on a Grid Component</topic>
    <description>Logical values stored in a database can have three states: true, false, or NULL. Representing these three values can be done using checkboxes.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A checkbox is often used to display logical fields in an application. An unchecked box represents a false value while a checked box represents a true value. If the logical field can be NULL in the SQL database that stores the records, however, a two-state checkbox is not adequate. Both NULL and false are by default represented with an unchecked checkbox.</p>
        <p>HTML checkboxes have a third state that can be used to represent NULL values in logical fields: "indeterminate". The indeterminate state is typically represent using a solid fill or dashed line in the checkbox. HTML does not directly support setting a checkbox to indeterminate. To set a checkbox to the indeterminate state, you must use JavaScript. For example:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var checkbox = $('{grid.componentName}.V.R{grid.rowNumber}.SHIP_SAME');
checkbox.indeterminate = true;]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>JavaScript can be executed when a Grid row is rendered using the server-side [onExistingRowRender] event, allowing you to set NULL logical checkboxes to the indeterminate state when rendered:</description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[dim flag as l 
flag = e.rowData.dataIsNull("ship_same")
if flag then
    dim js as c 
    js = "var checkbox = $('"+e.tmpl.alias+".V.R"+e.rowNumber+".SHIP_SAME');"+crlf()+\
    "checkbox.indeterminate = true;"
    e.javascript = js
end if]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For full step-by-step instructions on how to add support for three state checkboxes to a Grid Component with logical fields that support NULL values, watch the video below:</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Three-State Logical Checkboxes</title>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/3s9m3HE2HE1yFpdpn2drQs?</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="grid onexistingrowrender event">onExistingRowRender</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="corejs dollar">$ Function</ref>
    </see>
</page>