<page>
	<topic>Integrated Local Help and WebHelp</topic>
	<description>When you click F1 in the Xbasic Editor or Action Script Editor, Alpha Anywhere will display help for the function, method, or language element under the cursor. You can customize help so that clicking F1:</description>

<sections>
	<section>
				<cases>
			<case>
				<description>displays a topic from the help files on your PC
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>displays a topic from the Alpha Software WebHelp through an Internet connection
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>lets you choose between the two alternatives
</description>
			</case>
			
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<description>You can set the primary and secondary sources of help to be either local help files or Internet WebHelp. If, for any reason, the primary source is unavailable, Alpha Anywhere will retrieve help from the secondary source.
Both help systems include help for all the following topics.
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Xbasic functions and methods
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Xbasic variables and objects
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Xbasic language and syntax
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Xdialog functions, controls, and syntax
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Programming utilities
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Action Scripting functions and usage
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Theory of operation
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Programming tips
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<description>Plus the full contents of the following books:
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Alpha Anywhere User Guide
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Introduction to Action Scripting
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Learning Xbasic
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Learning Xdialog
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>When working in the Code Editor, pressing F1 when your cursor is over an Xbasic function or method will display the appropriate help from the Xbasic Reference help file.
The following example shows an instance where there is only one reference to a function. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/help_function_single_reference.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>The following picture shows the result when a function has multiple references. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/help_function_multiple_references.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>Clicking on the desired reference brings up the topic. The following pictures shows the result when a method has multiple references. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/help_method_multiple_references.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>If you are looking for information about a method, but are unsure of the object name. The Xbasic Reference help index will show you your options, as illustrated with the .SIZE() methods in the following picture. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/help_multiple_methods.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Linking to a External Help File Topic">Linking to a External Help File Topic</ref>
	</see>
</page>