<page>
    <shortlink>Dynamically Compute Values for Added Rows in a Repeating Section</shortlink>
    <topic>Dynamically Compute Values for Added Rows in a Repeating Section</topic>
    <description>Create generated expressions for new rows in a repeating section using an Ajax callback.</description>
   
   <sections>
       <section>
           <description>You can use an expression in order to generate a GUID for a field in a repeating section. 
        This can be done by defining the expression inside a function and then calling the function using the 
        'Default value' property on the control that contains the field in question.  
         The expression can then be used to populate the rows associated with that control dynamically.
          </description>
           <figure><title>Three added rows generate the same GUID, unlike the five initially loaded rows above them.</title><link>images/dcv14.png</link></figure>
       </section>
        <section>
           <description>When the server initially renders the repeating section the default value expression
        is automatically executed and then populates each existing row in the repeating section. 
        However, if the user clicks on the 'Add row' button at the bottom of the 
        repeating section, to add a new row, then the generated GUID for each added row will be exactly the same. 
        This is because the default value expression is not rendered on the server when new rows are added to a repeating section.
        One way to resolve this problem is to define an ajax callback that fires when the user clicks the add new row button.
        The default value for the new row can then be evaluated on the server and sent back to the client
         to populate the new row.</description>
           
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>This process is described in [this video]. You can also follow the guide below for more detail.</description>
           
       </section>
       <section>
           <title></title>
           <steps>
               <step>
                   <description>In the UX Builder on the UX Controls page open the 'Data Controls' menu. Click on 
                       on the [TextBox] option to add a textbox control to the component. Give the textbox the 
                       name and label 'Address'. 
                   </description>
                   <figure><link>images/dcv2.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Add a second textbox control to the component with the name and label 'City'.</description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv3.png</link></figure>
               </step>
                <step>
                   <description>Highlight the 'City' textbox control. In the properties list on the right set the 
                       'Default value' property in the 'Field Properties' section to this:
                   </description>
                   <example><![CDATA[=api_uuidcreate()]]></example>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv4.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>From the 'Data Controls' menu add a third [TextBox] control to the component with the name and label 'Country'.</description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv5.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Highlight all of the textbox controls in the controls tree. Open the Containers menu 
                       click on the [Container] option.
                   </description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv6.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>From the 'Container Type' list seclect the 'RepeatingSection' option. Click OK</description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv7.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>From the 'Events' section on the main menu open the 'Client-side' events page. 
                       Highlight the 'afterRptSectionRowAdd' event in the Client-Side Events list.
                   </description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv8.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Add the following definition to the afterRptSectionRowAdd event:</description>
                   <example><![CDATA[var r = {dialog.Object}.getRepeatingSectionActiveRow(e.sectionName);
var data = 'rowNum=' + r;
{dialog.object}.ajaxCallback('','','xb','',data)]]></example>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv9.png</link></figure>
                    <note><![CDATA[Here we are getting the row number of the repeating section row that was just added 
                        by using the getRepeatingSectionActiveRow method. We then construct a name value pair, 
                        ("var data = 'rowNum=' + r;")that will be sent back as part of an Ajax callback. This 
                        name value pair becomes this last parameter in the Ajax callback. The Ajax callback also 
                        calls an Xbasic function called 'xb', that is described in the next step.]]> 
                        
                    </note>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>From the main menu's 'Code' section open the 'Xbasic functions' page. 
                       Add the following definition:
                   </description>
                   <example><![CDATA[function xb as c (e as p)
	dim js as c
	js = "{dialog.object}.setValue('Address:"+e.rowNum+"','"+js_escape(remspecial(api_uuidcreate()))+"');"
	xb = js
end function ]]></example>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv10.png</link></figure>
                     <figure><link>images/dcv11.png</link></figure>
                     
                     <note>This function generates the javascript to set the value on the 'Address' field. The address 
                         will be set on the row number for each row using 'e.rowNum'. This is the row number value 
                         that is being passed using the Ajax Callback defined in the step before this. A new GUID 
                         is then generated for that row on the server. The 'xb = js' simply sends the javascript 
                         contained inside this Xbasic function as the response to the Ajax callback.
                     </note>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Run the component in Live Preview. The initial rows should all be dynamically populated.</description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv12.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Click the 'Add row' button at the bottom of the repeating section. Now a custom 
                       expression value should appear for all of the rows in the 'Address' column. 
                   </description>
                    <figure><link>images/dcv13.png</link></figure>
               </step>
           </steps>
           
           
           
           
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   
   
   <links>
       <link href="https://share.vidyard.com/watch/h6aMZUBj7tJDJxkKHC3wLD?">this video</link>
       
       
   </links>
   
    
    <see>
        <ref link="repeatingsection">RepeatingSection</ref>
        <ref link="repeating section">Repeating Section Properties</ref>
        <ref link="ux clientside afterRptSectionRowAdd">afterRptSectionRowAd</ref>
    </see>
    
    <terms>container,repeating section</terms>
    
    
    
</page>