<page>
   <topic>UI_GET_LIST_ARRAY Function</topic>
   <prototypes><prototype>Result_String as C = UI_GET_LIST_ARRAY(C title,N default_choice,C array_name)</prototype>
   <prototype>Result_String as C = UI_GET_LIST_ARRAY( Title as C, Default_Choice as N, Array_Name as C [, Sizeable as L [, Xpos, Ypos [, Xsize, Ysize ]]] )
</prototype>
   
   </prototypes>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>title</name>
         <description>The title of the dialog box.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>default_choice</name>
         <description>Determines which list box entry is selected when the dialog box first appears. This parameter is a numeric value indicating which item is to be selected (from 1 to the last element of the array). For example, if the Default_Choice is 5, the fifth list box entry is highlighted when the dialog box appears.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>array_name</name>
         <description>A character string containing the name of a defined array. You must declare this array as an array of character strings. For example, the following statement displays the contents of the Company array:
ui_get_list_array("Choose a Company Name", 1, "Company").
</description>
     </argument>
     
     
      <argument>
         <name>Sizeable</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .F. Determines if the dialog can be resized by the user.
</description>
<list>
<item><name>.T. = sizeable</name></item>
<item><name>.F. = not sizeable</name></item>
</list>


     </argument>
     
      <argument>
         <name>Xpos and Ypos</name>
         <description>Optional. Parameters that determine where on the screen the dialog is displayed. Both parameters must be between 0.0 and 1.0, where 0 represents the top (or left) corner of the screen, and 1 represents the bottom (or right) corner. Xpos and Ypos values of 0.5 and 0.5, for example, represent the center of the screen.

</description>
     </argument>
     
      <argument>
         <name>Xsize and Ysize</name>
         <description>Optional. Parameters that determine the size of the dialog. Both parameters must be between 0.0 and 1.0, where 1 represents the full width or height of the screen.  Xsize and Ysize values of 0.25 and 0.25, for example, represent a dialog that fills one quarter of the screen.

</description>
     </argument>
     
     
     
     
   </arguments>
   <description>Prompt user for selection from list.</description>
   <discussion>
UI_GET_LIST_ARRAY() displays a dialog box with a list box filled with the contents of a character array. Your response is returned as a Result_String that contains the contents of the listbox entry that you either double-clicked or highlighted before you clicked the dialog box's OK button. This function is useful for selecting a value from the contents of an array.
The Result_String will be empty ("") if the Cancel button is selected.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
     
        <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>Populate an array with all the fields in the current table.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim fields[1024] as C
tbl = table.current()
number_of_fields = tbl.fields_get()
for i = 1 TO number_of_fields
    fld = tbl.field_get(i)   'get a pointer to field I
    name = fld.name_get()   'get the name of this field
    fields[I] = name
next i
]]></example>
       </section>
        <section>
            <description>Let user select a field.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
fld_name = ui_get_list_array("Choose a field", 1, "fields")
]]></example>
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>User Interaction Functions</ref>
      <ref>Array Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
  
</page>