<page>
   <topic>UI_Get_Time Function</topic>
   <syntax>C Time = ui_get_time(C dlgTitle ,C time [,L useCalendarDropdowns [,L connectClockHands [,N hourSnap [,N minuteSnap ]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
      <argument>
         <name>Time</name>
         <description>Returns the date time value as a character string. Use ctodt() to  convert result to a time value if necessary
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>dlgTitle</name>
         <description>The dialog title</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>time</name>
         <description>Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>useCalendarDropdowns</name>
         <description>Specify if month and year are selected from drop down boxes (as shown in the image), or by clicking on the title bar to change the calendar display from days to month, and then from months to years.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>connectClockHands</name>
         <description>If .t., then when you move the minute hand, the hour hand will also move and vice versa. For example, if you move the minute hand (say) by 180 degrees, the hour hand will be positioned between hours. If .f. then moving the minute hand does not cause the hour hand to move.

If .f., the hour hand can only snap to full hours (i.e. it can't be positioned between two hours as an analog clock can) .</description>
 </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>hourSnap</name>
         <description>If, for example, hourSnap is set to 15 and connectClockHands is .t., then there will be 4 positions that the minute hand can snap to when the hour hand is moved (e.g. 0, 15 minutes, 30 minutes and 45 minutes after the hour). 
If connectClockHands is .f. then hourSnap is ignored.
The default value for hourSnap is 5
hourSnap can be set to any number between 1 and 60.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>minuteSnap</name>
         <description>When you are moving the minute hand, you can specify what minute interval the hand should snap to. The default value for minuteSnap is 0 (no minute snap).

     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Prompts for a full time value (date and time).</description>
   <discussion>
      ...put discussion here....
   </discussion>
   
   <sections>
       <section>
           <figure><link>images/What's5.jpg</link></figure>
       </section>
   </sections>
   



</page>