<page>
	<topic>Request Object</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
	<description>A5W pages have access to a system object named Request. This object represents the parsed HTTP request that was received by the Application Server and has a number of properties available.</description>
		<note>The Request object is local to the page (script) and must be passed to any functions that need access to it.</note>	
			
		</section>
	</sections>
	
<properties>
	<property>
		<name>Request.Accept
</name>
		<description>
 
The value of the Accept HTTP header, which indicates the MIME types that the client can accept. This property was optionally created in versions 6-9, but will always exist in version 10.
 </description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.AcceptCharset
</name>
		<description>The value of the Accept-Charset HTTP header, which indicates the character sets that the client can accept.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.AcceptEncoding
</name>
		<description>The value of the Accept-Encoding HTTP header, which indicates the types of transfer encoding accepted by the client. This replaces the optional Accept_Encoding property in versions 6-9.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.AcceptLanguage
</name>
		<description>The value of the Accept-Language HTTP header, which indicate the languages that the client is configured to accept. This replaces the optional Accept_Language property in versions 6-9.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.ApplicationRoot
</name>
		<description><![CDATA[The path to the root of the current application, as  seen from the server. For example, if you publish an application to c:\a5webroot\app1 on your server, Request.ApplicationRoot will contain the value c:\a5webroot\app1 for all requests for anything in that application, even if it is in a subfolder. So http://server/app1/page1.a5w would see the same value as  http://server/app1/subfolder1/page2.a5w.
 ]]></description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Body
</name>
		<description>The full body of the HTTP request. This will be empty for a GET request, as a GET does not include a body.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Browser.CookiesEnabled
</name>
		<description>A logical value that indicates whether or not the client browser accepts cookies.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Connection
</name>
		<description>The value of the Connection HTTP header, which contains the connection type requested by the client, such as "Keep-Alive". This property was optionally created in versions 6-8, but will always exist in version 9.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.ContentType
</name>
		<description>A string that describes any encoding applied by the client before sending the request.  It is typically blank, but some HTML forms may use a type of "multipart/form-data".
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Cookie
</name>
		<description>
 
The value of the Cookie HTTP header, which is a string containing all cookies sent by the client. This property was optionally created in versions 6-9, but will always exist in version 10.
 </description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Cookies
</name>
		<description>An object containing all of the variables created from the cookie(s) included in the HTTP request sent from the client.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Headers
</name>
		<description>The headers of the request in a CR or CR-LF delimited list.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.HTTP_Request
</name>
		<description>The first line of the request headers, which tells the server what file to retrieve and how to retrieve it.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Host
</name>
		<description>The hostname that this request was sent to. Request.Host will always exist if the client uses HTTP/1.1, but it may not if the client uses HTTP/1.0.
</description>
	</property>
	<property>
		<name>Request.IfModifiedSince
</name>
		<description>The value of the If-Modified-Since HTTP header, which a client may include to ask the server to compare a client cached version of the resource with the resource on the server.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.IfUnmodifiedSince
</name>
		<description>The value of the If-Unmodified-Since HTTP header, which a client may include to ask the server to compare a client cached version of the resource with the resource on the server.
</description>
	</property>
	<property>
		<name>Request.Query_String
</name>
		<description><![CDATA[The query string of a GET request, such as "foo=bar&this=that". 
NOTE: As of V12, this is deprecated. Instead use:
context.request.queryString.toString() ]]></description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Raw
</name>
		<description>
 
The complete raw request received by the server.
 </description>
	</property>
	<property>
		<name>Request.Referer
</name>
		<description>
 
Contains the URL of the page from which the user came. NOTE: Request.Referer is extremely unreliable for any type of run-time decision making. It is really only useful for statistical analysis of your logs, for example to determine whether your traffic came from a search engine or another site's recommendation.
 </description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Remote_Addr
</name>
		<description>The IP address of the remote client making the request. Do not attempt to use Request.Remote_Addr as a unique identifier for the session. All users behind a firewall or proxy server typically show up as a single IP address.
</description>
	</property>
	<property>
		<name>Request.Request_Method
</name>
		<description>
 
The request method, such as "GET" or "POST".
 </description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Request_URI
</name>
		<description><![CDATA[
 
The requested file including any GET query string, such as " /index.html?foo=bar&this=that ".
 ]]></description>
	</property>
	<property>
		<name>Request.Script_Name
</name>
		<description>
 
The requested file, such as " /index.html " (the currently running page).
 </description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Server_Protocol
</name>
		<description>The protocol used by the request, such as "HTTP/1.1" or "HTTP/1.0".
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.UserAgent
</name>
		<description>The value of the User-Agent HTTP header, which is a string identifying the software used on the client to send this request. Replaces the Request.User_Agent property in versions 6-9.
</description>
	</property>
	
	<property>
		<name>Request.Variables
</name>
		<description>A dot variable containing all variables sent from the client. This is a combination of GET variables, POST variables and cookies.
</description>
	</property>
	
</properties>	
	
<see>
	<ref>Sessions</ref>
	<ref>Status Codes</ref>
	<ref>Configuring Internet Explorer</ref>
	<ref>Request Object V10</ref>
</see>
</page>