<page>
   <topic>{dialog.object}..refreshDropdownBoxChoices Method</topic>
   <syntax>{dialog.Object}.refreshDropdownBoxChoices(controlName [[,dynamicFilter [[,dynamicFilterArguments [[,selectedValue [[,currentRowOnly]]]]);</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>dynamicFilter</name>
         <description>(optional) dynamic filter to apply when recomputing the choices in the DropdownBox.</description>
     </argument>
     
      <argument>
         <name>dynamicFilterArguments</name>
         <description>(optional) if a dynamic filter is specified, and the filter uses arguments, this parameter contains the argument values.
The format for this argument is a CRLF delimited string in this format: argumentValue|||dataType|argumentName
</description>
     </argument>
     
      <argument>
         <name>selectedValue</name>
         <description>(optional) - the value in the DropdownBox to select after it has been repopulated.</description>
     </argument>
     
      <argument>
         <name>currentRowOnly</name>
         <description>(optional) - if the control is in a Repeating Section by default when you refresh the Dropdownbox choices, the choices in all rows in the Repeating Section are updated. If this parameter is false, then only the choices in the Dropbownbox in the current row are updated.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
 
 
   <description>Recompute and repopulate choices in a DropbownBox for the specified controlName.</description>
  
  <discussion>Does an Ajax callback to recompute the choices in a DropdownBox and repopulates the choices in the DropbownBox for the specified controlName. Applies only if the choices in the Dropdownbox are based on a SQL or .dbf query. 
</discussion>
  
  <example><![CDATA[ ]]></example>
  
  <sections>
    <section>
      <title>Example</title>
      <description>Refresh the choices in the DropdownBox for the 'products' control.</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.refreshDropdownBoxChoices('PRODUCTS');
 ]]></example> 
    </section>
    
     <section>
      
      <description>Refresh the choices and set the select to 'PRODUCT_X'</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.refreshDropdownBoxChoices('PRODUCTS',,,'PRODUCT_X'); ]]></example> 
    </section>
    <section>
      
      <description>Refresh the choices and filter choices to only show items where the 'type' field is 'a' and 'code' field is 'x'</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.refreshDropdownBoxChoices('PRODUCTS','type=:whatType and code = :whatCode','a|||c|whatType\nx|||c|whatCode'); ]]></example> 
    </section>
    
    <section>
      
      <description>Note that in the above example the dynamicFilterArguments is a crlf delimited string (\n is the CRLF code in javascript) of the form</description>
      <example><![CDATA[value|||datatype|argumentname ]]></example> 
    </section>
    
  </sections>
  
  
   <see>
      <ref>{dialog.object}</ref>
   </see>




</page> 
