<page>
	<topic>IIS Getting Started Guide</topic>
    <description>A guide to getting started with the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Getting Started Guide</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Preface</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>This document is one of a group of documents on using the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS. The documents are:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <description>
                                [Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Overview]
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <description>
                                [Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Installation Guide]
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <description>
                                [Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Getting Started Guide] (this document)
                            </description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
             <title>Notes on Deprecated Features</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Alpha Five Version 11 introduced changes that removed, deprecated, or added features for coding a web application. The [Server Programming Changes for Version 11] document lists these changes. These changes were made so a web application can run under the stand-alone web application server and the IIS application server without needing to be modified. Review the linked document for changes you may need to make to your web application so that it will run under IIS. Here is a link to documentation for the [Context object] that is referred to in the Server Programming Changes for Version 11 document.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The [Publishing - A More Typical Web Application] instructions use the Application Server Demosample workspace to demonstrate publishing to an IIS server. Alpha Anywhere supports direct publishing. Direct publishing means Alpha Anywhere will connect directly to an IIS server. Refer to the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Installation Guidefor details on the requirements for direct publishing.</p>
                        <p>Please forward questions, comments, and other feedback to [iisbeta@alphasoftware.com].</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>IIS Publish Feature Pack Key</title>
                    <description>Even though Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS is still in beta, the feature pack key requirement has been removed and a publish profile to publish to IIS can be created without it.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description></description>
                </section>         
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Publishing - Simple Web Site</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>These instructions are a guide for publishing a one page web site without security in order to verify publishing to IIS is configured correctly.</p>
                    </description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Create a new, empty workspace named IISHello.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/newworkspaceA.png</link>
                                <title>Create new workspace.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Create a new, blank a5w page.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/create-a5w-pageA.png</link>
                                <title>Create new a5w page.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>

                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Type Hello from IIS! in to the a5w page and then save as hello.a5w.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/hello-a5wA.png</link>
                                <title>Save hello.a5w page.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Close editing hello.a5w and then click on the "Project Properties" button on the Web Projects Control Panel to set the default page.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/project-properties.png</link>
                                <title>Project properties button.</title>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/set-default-page.png</link>
                                <title>Set default page.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Click on the "Profiles" button on the main toolbar to show the publish profiles and then click on the "Add New Profile" button to create a new publish profile.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/profile-button.png</link>
                                <title>Profiles button.</title>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/new-profile.png</link>
                                <title>Add new profile.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Select "IIS" to create a publish profile for publishing to IIS.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/create-iis-profile.png</link>
                                <title>Create IIS publish profile.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                For this guide it is assumed that IIS is located on the same machine as Alpha Anywhere Developer Edition so the IIS management service URL is "localhost". If your IIS server is on a different machine enter that machine's host name or IP address. Since publishing is being done to localhost, integrated Windows authentication can be used for publishing. If your IIS server is on a different machine and it is not in your Active Directory domain, uncheck "Use integrated Windows authentication" and enter the credentials of a user that has local administrator access on the IIS server machine. You will also most likely need to Ignore HTTPS certificate errors for the purpose of this test publish.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/publish-profile-page-1.png</link>
                                <title>Create IIS publish profile page one.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Click the Next button at the bottom of the genie. Keep the defaults that are set for the Site and Application Details and click on the Finish button.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/publish-profile-page-2.png</link>
                                <title>Create IIS publish profile page two.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Enter the name "Simple IIS" and then click the OK button.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/save-simple-iis.png</link>
                                <title>Save IIS publish profile with name Simple IIS.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the OK button on the Web Project Profiles dialog. Now it is time to publish.
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Click on the "Publish" button on the Web Projects Control Panel to bring up the publish dialog.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/publish-button.png</link>
                                <title>Publish button.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                Select the "Simple IIS" profile and then click on the "Publish" button.
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/do-publish.png</link>
                                <title>Do Publish.</title>
                            </figure>
                            <note>A trace of the publish to IIS is logged to the Trace Window. If an error occurs this log will help diagnose what happened. To get to the the trace log, go to the View menu on the main menubar and then the Trace Window sub menu. Then select the tab labelled "IISPublish".</note>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/trace-window-menu.png</link>
                                <title>Trace window menu.</title>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/trace-window.png</link>
                                <title>Trace window.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Now bring up a browser and type "localhost/IISHello" to see the page that was published.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/simple-publish-running.png</link>
                                <title>Display IISHello site.</title>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Publishing - A More Typical Web Application</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>These instructions are a guide for publishing a more complex web application that more closely resembles a typical web application which has security and accesses databases.</p>
                        <p>Create a new workspace using the Application Server Demosample workspace.</p>
                        <p>To publish to an IIS server create a new web project profile and select the new IIS type.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image07.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you are developing on the same machine that the IIS server is on, you can use "localhost" as the IIS management service URL. If your IIS server is in the same active directory domain as your user account or is in a domain with cross domain trust and your user account is a local administrator on the IIS server machine you can can use integrated Windows authentication. Otherwise you will need to set up a local user on the IIS server machine that has local administrator access and use that user's credentials in the Alpha Anywhere publish profile setting.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        In order to publish using integrated Windows authentication you must run Alpha Anywhere Developer Edition as administrator. Running it under a local administrator account is not enough. You must either right click on the program icon and choose "Run as administrator" or go into the program icon's properties and set it to be Run as administrator.
                    </note>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image02.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image16.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>In general, you will want your application to run in its own application pool (i.e. "Private") to isolate it from other applications running under IIS.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image03.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify the location of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS installation. Selecting "Default" assumes installation in C:\Program Files (x86)\A5V12 Application Server for IIS. If you installed to a different location you will need to select "Custom" and then enter the path to the installation.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image00.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image12.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image06.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the Security Store Configuration genie page select the "web.config (for testing only)" option. This stores the user and group data in the web.config file.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/security-provider.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/image18.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Profile Settings Specific to the Application Server Demo workspace</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Application Server Demosample workspace uses files and databases that are local to the development machine. These resources need to be made available to the IIS server.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title>Workspace Files</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>There one workspace file that needs to be published" flowers.dbf. To add this file to what gets published, check the Publish data filesoption and then click on the ... button in the Files to publishrow.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image01.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Check the flowers.dbf file and then click the OK button. This will include flowers.dbf along with its supporting files in the publish.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>In order for your app to locate the flowers.dbf file after it is published you will have to update the Aliases for the profile. Click on the ... button for the Aliasesrow.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image15.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Now add the following expression as the value for the [PathAlias.ADB_Path] = entry:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[=a5_default_path + chr(92) + "App_Data"]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Note that this value starts with and = sign to denote that it is an expression so as you see in the image below there are two equal signs. The first is for "equals" a space and then the second is for "the following is an expression".</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image04.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title>Named AlphaDAO connection strings</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The Application Server Demosample workspace uses local .mdb databases. These databases need to be published to a database server accessible from the IIS server machine. This can be done through the web project publish profile settings.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image14.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Make sure the IIS publish profile is selected and then click on the Publish Local Databasesbutton. If you have local databases you will be prompted to enter a connection string to a database server that is accessible from the IIS server machine. If there are no local databases a message box will display saying there are no local databases.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image05.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Enter the connection string to a database server. You can use the "Create SQL Connection String" dialog by clicking the smart field button on the right of the edit box.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image17.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>When publishing the local databases to a database server is finished the connection strings will be updated to point to the new databases.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image08.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Now you are ready to publish to IIS. Goto the Web Projects Control Panel, select Publish and then select the IIS profile that you just created.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/image13.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Showing Error Information During Publishing</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Error details can be shown when a remote request fails while publishing to IIS. Normally a limited amount of detail is returned in a remote request when an error occurs on the server. This is done in order to reduce the likelihood of inadvertent information disclosure. To allow returning error detail to be returned from a remote request edit the publish profile and check the *[ui:Show error detail in remote responses]* property.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/iis_detail_error_info.jpg</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Alternatively, check the *[ui:Show error detail in remote responses]* checkbox when creating a new IIS publish profile.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/iis_error_detail2.jpg</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="../Overview.xml">Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Overview</link>
        <link href="../Installation/index.xml">Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Installation Guide</link>
        <link href="#">Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Getting Started Guide</link>
        <link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index/ServerProgrammingChangesVersion11">Server Programming Changes for Version 11</link>
        <link href="http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v12Download/ReleaseNotes/ContextObject/context.html">Context object</link>
        <link href="#group_Publishing%20-%20A%20More%20Typical%20Web%20Application">Publishing - A More Typical Web Application</link>
        <link href="mailto:iisbeta@alphasoftware.com">iisbeta@alphasoftware.com</link>
    </links>
</page>




		
