<page build="6348">
    <shortlink>ux drag and drop control</shortlink>
    <topic>Drag and Drop File Upload Control</topic>
    <description>
        <p>The Drag and Drop File Upload Control (Drag and Drop Control) adds the ability to upload files by dragging and dropping files from the filesystem onto a designated location in your app. When the files are dropped, Alpha Anywhere uploads the files to the the specified location -- either Amazon S3 or the Alpha Anywhere Application Server.</p>
    </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to drag and drop, this control also supports tapping or clicking the drag and drop area to open a File picker to select files from the device for upload. See [Click on Drag and Drop area to select files] below for more details.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding the Drag and Drop File Upload Control</title>
            <description>
                <p>To add drag and drop file upload to a component, add a *[ui:Drag&amp;DropArea]* control to your UX component.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dragdrop1.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Next, click on the smart field to configure the *[ui:Drag and Drop area properties]* and *[ui:File upload properties]* for the control:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dragdrop2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When the UX component is run, the *[ui:Drag&amp;Drop]* control will be rendered as shown in the image below:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dragdrop5.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can control various aspects of the appearance and behavior of the Drag and Drop control. For example:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>The text that appears in the area</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The vertical and horizontal alignment of the text</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The size of the area</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The style of the area</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Whether clicking on the area (as opposed to dropping files into the area) opens the file picker</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring the Drag and Drop Area</title>
            <description>
                <p>The drag and drop area is the area where uses can drop files for upload. You can customize the look and feel of the drag and drop area with the *[ui:Drag and Drop area properites]*. These properties include:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Text to display</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The text shown in the drag and drop area where files can be dropped. This text should suggest what the user should do.</p>
                        <p>Default message is "Drag one or more files here to upload."</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Text position - vertical</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The veritcal position of the text shown in the drag and drop area. The message can be positioned *[ui:Top]*, *[ui:Center]*, or *[ui:Bottom]*.</p>
                        <p>Default value is *[ui:Center]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Text position - horizontal</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The horizontal position of the text shown in the drag and drop area. The message can be positioned *[ui:Left]*, *[ui:Center]*, or *[ui:Right]*.</p>
                        <p>Default value is *[ui:Center]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Style</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Inline CSS styling applied to the drag and drop area. The CSS specified here will override any style information definined in classes assigned to this control.</p>
                        <p>Default style is:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="css"><![CDATA[border: solid 1px #c1c1c5; border-radius: 10px;]]></example>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Class name</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>One or more CSS classes containing styling information for the drag and drop area.</p>
                        <p>Default value is blank.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Click on Drag and Drop area to select files</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, the user can click on the drag and drop area to open a file picker to select one or more files to upload in addition to dragging and dropping files on the control.</p>
                        <p>By default, this property is unchecked.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining the File Upload Properties</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:File upload properties]* specify where files will be stored when they are uploaded. Files can be stored on the Alpha Anywhere Application Server or Amazon S3.</p>
                <p>File Upload settings are identical to those specified in the File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere Action Javascript action. See [File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere] for more information about specific upload properties.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Drag and Drop Control Properties</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Drag and Drop control has the following properties:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control Id</title>
                    <description>The Drag and Drop control's Id. This id can be used with the *[js:{dialog.object}.getPointer()]* method to get a pointer to the HTML DOM Element for the Drag and Drop control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Drag and Drop area properties</title>
                    <description>Settings for configuring the look and feel of the drag and drop area. See [Configuring the Drag and Drop Area] above for more information.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">File upload properties</title>
                    <description>File upload properties property. See [File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere] for more information.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Width</title>
                    <description>Specify the control width. Use CSS syntax for the width (e.g. 100px, 100%, etc.)</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Height</title>
                    <description>Specify the control height. Use CSS syntax (but not %)  for the width (e.g. 100px, etc.). TIP: It is generally not necessary to set the height of a ControlBar as it is computed automatically.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Break</title>
                    <description>Force a column break before, after, or both before and after this control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Break height</title>
                    <description>Specify the vertical distance between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Horizontal spacer</title>
                    <description>Specify the horizontal space between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Horizontal spacer</title>
                    <description>Specify the horizontal space between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control container class name</title>
                    <description>Controls in a UX Component are wrapped in a DIV with the class 'A5CWLayout' or 'A5container', unless the has been placed in a 'NoFloat' or 'Alignment' container. The *[ui:Control container class name]* allows you to add one or more additional CSS classes to the DIV for the Drag and Drop control.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control container prevent float</title>
                    <description>The class applied to the DIV wrapped around the Drag and Drop control applies a 'float' to the control so that controls render automatically from left to right until a control with a 'break after' is encountered. The class used to apply the float includes a fixed width padding. If you do not want the padding or float behavior applied to the Drag and Drop control, check the *[ui:Control container prevent flaot]* property to prevent the class (either 'A5CWLayout' or 'A5container') from being assigned to the DIV wrapper for this control.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Methods</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Drag and Drop control has no methods or properties. It is not a data control, so UX methods such as *[js:{dialog.object}.getValue()]* and *[js:{dialog.object}.setValue()]* cannot be used with the control.</p>
                <p>You can get a pointer to the HTML DOM element for the Drag and Drop control area using the *[js:{dialog.object}.getPointer()]* method:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[// Get a pointer to the Drag and Drop control's HTML Element:
var ele = {dialog.object}.getPointer('DRAGDROPFILEUPLOAD_1');

if (ele) {
    // ...
}]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>File Upload using Drag and Drop	</title>
                <description>
                    <p>You can upload files to either Amazon S3 or to your Alpha Anywhere server by dragging and dropping files onto a 'drag drop area' on your UX component.</p>
                    <p>This video shows how to configure drag and drop file upload.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2019-12-11</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/db5a8457</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <terms>dragdropfileupload,uploading files,amazon s3,*[ui:Drag&amp;Drop]*,drag and drop</terms>
    <links>
        <link link="file%20upload%20amazon%20s3%20storage%20or%20alpha%20anywhere%20server">File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere</link>
        <link href="#section1_Configuring%20the%20Drag%20and%20Drop%20Area">Configuring the Drag and Drop Area</link>
        <link href="#section2_Click%20on%20Drag%20and%20Drop%20area%20to%20select%20files">Click on Drag and Drop area to select files</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="howwto%20configure%20s3%20bucket">How to Configure an Amazon S3 Bucket</ref>
        <ref link="named%20storage%20connection%20strings">Storage Connections</ref>
        <ref link="ux controls other controls file upload download">File Upload/Download Control</ref>
        <ref link="file%20upload%20amazon%20s3%20storage%20or%20alpha%20anywhere%20server">File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere</ref>
    </see>
</page>