<page>
	<topic>Defining and Running Operations</topic>
<description>From the Control Panel, Alpha Anywhere allows you to do define and run several different types of operations such as Copy, export, update, delete etc. You can save the settings for these operations. Once you have saved settings for an operation, you can run the operation from the Control Panel, or using an Xbasic command. For example, to run a saved export operation called "Export Sales Data", you would use this command: Export.Run("Export Sales Data"). See the following topics for details:
</description>

<sections>
	
	<section>
		
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>APPEND.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>COPY.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>EXPORT.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>IMPORT.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>JOIN.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>MARK.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>POST.RUN()
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>In addition to running saved operations, Alpha Anywhere also allows you to use low level Xbasic commands that perform operations without requiring that you first define a saved operation. The advantage of using low level Xbasic commands to run operations is that you have much more flexibility. For example, in an export operation, you could use the UI_GET_FILE() command to prompt for the name of the file to create. You could not dynamically change the name of the export file if you ran a saved operation.
</description>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>More Information:
</title>
		<description><![CDATA[For information on delete and mark operations, see the following methods:
<TBL>.DELETE_RANGE(), <TBL>.DELETE_DUPS(), <TBL>.MARK_RANGE(), <TBL>.UNMARK_RANGE(), <TBL>.MARK_DUPS(), <TBL>.UNMARK_DUPS()
The OPERATION TYPE.RUN()topic describes the syntax for running append, copy, crosstab, export, import, intersect, join, post, subtract, summarize and update operations.
]]></description>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Viewing the Xbasic of Operations">Viewing the Xbasic of Operations
</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>