<page>
   <topic>{dialog.object}.setValue Method</topic>
 <description>Set the value of a control in the Dialog.</description>
  
   <syntax>{dialog.Object}.setValue(name,value ,honorChangeEvent )</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>honorChangeEvent</name>
         <description>Default = T. Causes the onChange event for the control to fire when the value is set. </description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
 
 
  <sections>
<section>
<title>Discussion</title>


<description>If the field you want to set is in a Repeating Section, use 'name:rownumber' for the field name, otherwise the row with focus will be updated. 
By default honorChangeEvent is true. This causes the onChange event for the control to fire when the value is set. </description>


<note>IMPORTANT: Unlike standard Javascript techniques to set the value of a control, the .setValue() method sets the control's state in the Dialog Object to be dirty (in the same way that the control becomes dirty if the user types a value into the control). 
Checkbox and Multi-value Dropdownbox Controls - See the example for information on how to set the value of a multi-valued control (e.g. Checkbox or multi-line Dropdownbox).</note>

</section>




    <section>
      <title>Example</title>
      <description>Set value in 'LASTNAME' field.</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.setValue('LASTNAME','Smith');
 ]]></example>
      
      
    </section>
     <section>
      <description>Set value in 'LASTNAME' field in the 3rd row of a Repeating Section.</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.setValue('LASTNAME:3','Smith'); ]]></example>
    </section>
     <section>
      <description>Set the value in 'FAVORITECOLOR'. Assume that 'FAVORITECOLOR' is a multi-valued field 
        (e.g. a Checkbox control or a Dropdown control configured to allow multiple values):

      </description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.Object}.setValue('FAVAORITECOLOR[]','alpha','beta','gamma');
 ]]></example>
    </section>
     <section>
      <description>Notice that the fieldname has a trailing [] - to indicate that it is an array of values, and the 
values you want to set are passed in in the form of a Javascript array.</description>
     
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
      <title>Additional Options</title>
     <description>Several additional options are available with the List control's .setValue() method. The options allow</description> 
     <cases>
       <case>
         <description>select all records in a List that has been configured to allow multiple selections
</description>
       </case>
       <case>
         <description>select all records in one or more Groups in a List that has been configured to show client-side group breaks and to allow multiple selections.
</description>
       </case>
       <case>
         <description>select all of the currently rendered records in a List that that has its 'Virtualization type' property set to 'Dynamic' and has been configured to allow multiple selections.
</description>
       </case>
       
     </cases> 
      
      
    </section>
    
    <section>
      
      <description>Examples:
Select all records in a List:
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('MYLISTNAME');
lObj.setValue({select: 'all'});]]></example>
      
    </section>
    
      <section>
      
      <description>Select records by Group name (deselecting any existing selections):</description>
      <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('MYLISTNAME');
lObj.setValue({ 
    select: 'group',
    groups: ['CA','MA'],
    additive: false
})]]></example>
      
    </section>
    
      <section>
      
      <description>Select records by Group name (preserving any existing selections):</description>
      <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('MYLISTNAME');
lObj.setValue({ 
    select: 'group',
    groups: ['NY'],
    additive: true
})]]></example>
      
    </section>
    
      <section>
      
      <description>Select all rendered records in a 'Virtualized' list (if there are 100 records per 'page' and the List has (say) 2,000 records then there are 100 rendered records that will be selected):
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('MYLISTNAME');
lObj.setValue({ 
    select: 'view',
    additive: false
})]]></example>
      
    </section>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </sections>
  
  
   <see>
      <ref>{dialog.Object}</ref>
   </see>

<terms>ux component,array,checkbox,checkbox control,control,defaults,dropdown,dropdown control,events,field,forms,javascript,object,users</terms>


</page> 
