<page>
    <shortlink>transform faq</shortlink>
    <topic>Frequently Asked; Frequently Answered</topic>
    <description>You got questions? We got answers.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>How do I invite users to my account?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Log in to TransForm Central. Then click the Home tab at the top. From the list of choices, choose Invite Users To Join a TransForm Account. On screen instructions will show you what to do.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>I Forgot My Password. What Should I Do?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Go to alphasoftware.com/transformCentral. (Click the logout button if you are already logged in.) Click the Forgot Your Password link to reset your password. The new password is used both by TransForm Central and the TransForm mobile application.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where Do I Find the Mobile Application?</title>
            <description>
                <p>To get the TransForm Mobile Application, you first need to install an application called Alpha Launch, which is available for both iOS and Android. Do a search for "Alpha Launch" in either the Apple App Store or on Google Play - or scan one of the codes below.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <link>images/</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Once Alpha Launch is installed, follow these directions.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open Alpha Launch. You will be prompted to install one or more apps to run.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click Show List. You will then be prompted to select a server from which to install.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click Use Default. You will receive a message welcoming you to the Alpha Software Demo Server.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click OK to clear the message.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Scroll down the list to TransForm and click Install. The TransForm app installs and a message appears letting you know that TransForm has been downloaded.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click OK to clear the message.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click TransForm to open TransForm. You will be prompted for your login name and password.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Login to TransForm and get started</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To open TransForm next time, click the Alpha Launch icon on your phone, and when Launch opens, choose TransForm.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>What Account Privileges Can I Give to Other Users?</title>
            <description>
                <p>As the owner of your account, you can decide who gets to design forms, who gets to fill in forms, which forms a particular user has access to, and who gets to view the data. You can also assign someone else to be the Account Administrator. These privileges are called "roles," and you can assign them by logging to to TransForm Central. Click the Home tab, then click Manage User Roles.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where do I Enter My License Number?</title>
            <description>
                <p>The license number(s) you buy from the Alpha Software store are entered in TransForm Central. Click the Home tab, then click Account License Keys.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where do I Buy I License Number?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha TransForm licenses are available in the *[link:Alpha Software Store@https://server.alphasoftware.com/transform-quick-start-trial?hs_preview=tmeKiRgS-5492907918]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Design and Deploy a New Form?</title>
            <description>
                <p>To create and deploy new forms, log in to TransForm Central and click the Designer Tab at the Top of the page. Then click the + button to add a new Form Type. Choose either Copy Shared to start with a predefined template or click Add Blank to create a new form design from scratch. Follow the on screen prompts.</p>
                <p>When you are done, click the link labeled "Click To Save Changes" to save the form to the server. To use the new form on a mobile device, you will need to download it. See [How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Open the TransForm Mobile App and Log In. Click the Add Form tab, then click Refresh Definitions.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Review the Data Submitted in TransForm?</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can view the data collected in the TransForm app by logging into TransForm Central. One you have logged in, click the Management Console tab.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App?">How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App</link>
        <link link=""></link>
    </links>
</page>