<page>
    <shortlink>ux data controls customcontrol</shortlink>
    <topic>CustomControl</topic>
    <description>Data Bound Custom Controls are a powerful technique for creating custom controls on a UX component.</description>
   

<sections>
    <section>
         <!--list:.-->
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <note>Contrast  'Custom Controls' in the 'Data Controls' section of the UX toolbox (discussed here) 
            with 'Custom Controls' defined in the 'Other Controls' section of the 
            UX toolbar - search for 'UX Component - CustomControl - 'Other Controls' for more information.</note>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>'Data controls' are controls that have the concept of a control 'value'.
             These controls have a [{dialog.object}.setValue()] and [{dialog.object}.getValue()] method 
              and when the UX is 'submitted' the value in these controls are submitted and are 
              available in the [e.datasubmitted] object in your Xbasic event handlers.

</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Custom data controls are built using the ViewBox control. 
            An understanding of how the ViewBox control works is essential before you can create a custom data 
            bound control. For more information on the ViewBox control, click [here].</description>
        <figure><link>images/cust.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>To add a data bound Custom Control to a UX cpmponent, select the [CustomControl] item in the UX toolbox.
To define the properties of the Custom Control click the smart field for the control properties. This will bring up the builder as shown below:
</description>
          <figure><link>images/cust2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>When you define a custom control you can specify the properties for the control 'now' (i.e. at design time), or you can generate the property settings at run-time using Xbasic.
The 'Specify Now' option is rarely used because a Custom Control that uses the 'Specify Now' option is really no different than a ViewBox control and so there is little reason to use the Custom Control rather than the ViewBox.
However, the option to generate the custom control definition at run-time using an Xbasic function is extremely powerful. and allows you to generate highly customized controls on your UX component.

</description>
    </section>
</sections>



<links>
    <link link="ux component setValue Method">{dialog.object}.setValue()</link>
    <link link="ux component getValue Method">{dialog.object}.getValue()</link>
    <link link="">e.datasubmitted</link>
    <link href="http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/A5V12Download/ReleaseNotes/ViewBoxControl_Concepts.html">here</link>
</links>

<see>
    <ref link="ux controls other controls custom control">Other Controls Custom Control</ref>
    <ref link="ux control properties custom control data bound custom control">Control properties - Data Bound Custom Control</ref>
    
    
</see>



</page>