<page>
    <shortlink>guides login component</shortlink>
    <topic>Login Component</topic>
    <description>The Login Component is used with the Alpha Anywhere Web Security System. It provides an interface for users to enter their credentials (i.e. user name and password) as well as optional options for password reset.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>When you create a new Login component, the following dialog is shown asking what type of Login component to create: a Login UX component or a Legacy Login component.</p>
        <p>The Legacy Login component is the Login component that has been in Alpha Anywhere for decades and provides basic authentication functionality. Using the Legacy Login component in web and mobile applications is not recommended.</p>
        <p>The Login UX is a newer component added in the release of Alpha Anywhere 4.6.3.2 and is the recommended Login component to use. The Login UX has numerous advantages over the Legacy Login component:</p>
        <p>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>The Login UX is fully customizable</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The Login UX supports two-factor authentication</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The Login UX includes built-in support for password reset and new account creation</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The Login UX includes built-in support for two different after login behaviors - redirect to a target page, or set focus to a Panel Card that represents the starting point of your application</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The Login UX includes built-in support for 'persistent login' -- the user will be automatically logged in if they have previously logged in provided the login has not expired (you can customize the persistent login duration)</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </discussion>
    <!--list:.-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>New Login Component Prompt</title>
                <alt>New Login Component Prompt</alt>
                <link>images/newLoginDlg.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using a UX Component as your Login Dialog</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you enable the Security Framework for your project you will need a login dialog where users will log into your application. A UX component can be used as the Login component and can be configured to allow password reset and new account creation.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how to use a UX component as your Login dialog.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch video - Configuring a UX as a Login Component</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_uxlogincomponent.mp4</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch video - Using a UX as a Login Component</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_uxlogincomponentinaction.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Reset Password</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in any Security Framework is the ability for the user to reset their password if they have forgotten it. The typical pattern for this is to send an email to the user. The email has a link that the user can click to bring up a dialog where they can change their password.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how this is done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_forgotpassword.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Create new account</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in any Security Framework is the ability for a user to create a new account.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how the user can create a new account.</p>
                    <p>In addition, if the Web Project has defined an Extended User-information table, then at the same time that the user creates their new account, they can choose to enable two-factor authentication.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how this is done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_createaccount.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>After Login Behavior</title>
                <description>
                    <p>After the user has logged into your application using a UX component, configured as a Login dialog, the "after login behavior" can either redirect the user to another page in your application, or to another Panel in the UX component.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how the "after login behavior" is configured.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_afterlogin.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Persistent Login</title>
                <description>
                    <p>	A common requirement when building an application with the Security Framework is to enable 'persistent login'. With 'persistent login' a user will not need to log into the app again after they have successfully logged in once.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how 'persistent login' is enabled.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_persistentLogin.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Password reset when userid is a value (not an email address)</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The password reset feature can be used when the userid in the security framework is a value (rather than an email address).</p>
                    <p>This video shows how this is done and how the extended user-information table must be configured.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-07-08</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/passwordreset_useridisvalue.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using the password reset feature in a Cordova mobile application</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The password reset feature can be used in Cordova applications running on mobile devices. The behavior of the component is slightly different than when running in a browser.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how password reset work in a Cordova application.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-07-08</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/resetpassword_cordova.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Webinar: Intro to The New Alpha Anywhere Security Genie</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Dion McCormick presents an introduction to Alpha Anywhere's new Security Genie.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-10-20</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXoB9Jy8Fqs</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux template SecurityFramework LoginComponent">UX Component Login Template</ref>
        <ref link="ux template SecurityFramework LoginComponentMobileApp">UX Component Mobile Login Template</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20template%20securityframework%20logincomponent">SecurityFramework-LoginComponent</link>
    </links>
</page>