<page>
  <topic>No record in List is selected action</topic>
  
  <description>This property allows you to specify the action if no record is currently selected (which can happen if the List's 'Allow null selection' property is not checked).</description>
  
  <sections>
    <section>
         <figure><link>images/norecordinlistiselected.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    <section>
      <description>The options are:

</description>
<cases>
  <case>
    <title>None</title>
    <description>do nothing. (Default action) When the UX is rendered no record in the List will be selected. The Detail View will be enabled and the user will be able to enter data into the Detail View. When the user clicks the 'Save' button, a new record will be added to the List. However, since the List's .NewDetailViewMethod() was not called, any default values for fields in new records will not be displayed in the Detail View.</description>
  </case>
  <case>
    <title>NewRecord </title>
    <description>The List's .NewDetailViewMethod() method will be called. If this method does not prevent the new record being shown, the Detail View will be enabled and the user can enter a new record. The default values for any fields in the Detail View will be shown. (Detail Values for fields in the Detail View are defined in the Fields pane of the List builder.)</description>
  </case>
  <case>
    <title>DisableDetailView </title>
    <description>The DetailView will be disabled. The user will have to either click on an existing row (in which case the Detail View will then be enabled, showing data from the selected row). or click the New Record button (in which case the Detail View will then be enabled, showing default values for fields).</description>
  </case>
  
</cases>
    </section>
    <section>
      <note>If you have not defined any default values for fields then there is little difference between the 'None' option and the 'NewRecord' option because in both cases the Detail View will be enabled and will not have any default values filled in. If the user edits data in the Detail View and then clicks the Save button, a new row will be added to the List.</note>
   
    </section>
    
    
  </sections>
</page>