<page>
    <shortlink>grid google maps alternate views javascript method</shortlink>
    <topic>Alternate View Google Map JavaScript Methods</topic>
    <description>Methods can be called directly on the JavaScript object for the Grid Map object in the Grid Component.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>These are method of the Grid map object, which is *[not]* the same as the Google map object. To get a pointer to the Grid map object, use this syntax:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js">
                <![CDATA[var mapId = {grid.object}.googleMap_mapId;]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The map id is defined in the Alternate View properties.</p>
                <p>So, for example, if the map Id is 'VIEW1', the pointer to the Grid map object is:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js">
                <![CDATA[var view1Id = {grid.object}.googleMap_VIEW1;]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To get a pointer to the underlying Google map object you add .map to the Grid map object. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js">
                <![CDATA[var mapObj = {grid.object}.googleMap_VIEW1.map;]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Once you have a pointer to the Google map object, you can refer to the Google Maps API documentation to see what methods are available.</description>
            <example code="js">
                <![CDATA[//callback from Google Maps startup
//Geocode or otherwise set the initial map center,
// then chain to initialize2
.initializeGoogleMap()

//Try to Geocode the supplied address, then chain to initialize2
.encodeAddress(address)

//This function is chained from initialize or encodeAddress
//Set map options, create map object, add map click listener,
// mark initial position if wanted, and create bulk loaded markers
.initialize2(myLatLng)

//addBulkMarkersCallback: add contents of markerArray argument to bulk markers
// API exposed for use by Ajax callbacks; called by initialize2
.addBulkMarkersCallback(markerArray, fClearAllMarkers, fClearBulkMarkers,
 fRecenterMapNew, fRecenterMapAll)

//doGeocode: address into LatLng, if we can
// Note that geocoding is asynchronous
.doGeocode(address, title, infotext, icon, rowNumber, layer, animation,
 duration, callback, [opt]circleObj)

.doGeocode2(address, canDrag)

.openInfoWindow)index) //index is Xbasic 1-based row number

.addBulkMarker2(lat, lng, title, infotext, icon, rowNumber, layer, animation,
 duration, callback, [opt]circleObj)


//addBulkMarker: Add the LatLng marker, with infotext, title, icon, layer,
// animation, duration, callback, and optionally a circle
// Also update bounds
//rowNumber can be used by a defined bulkMarkerClickAction
.addBulkMarker(latlng, title, infotext, icon, rowNumber, layer, animation,
 duration, callback, [opt]circleObj)

//reset map bounds to fit all markers if wanted
.autoScaleMap()

.addMarker2(lat, lng, canDrag)

//Add a marker to the map with a title and InfoText box
//Add a listener for marker drag events
//Show updated polygon if wanted
//Show circle for the first marker if wanted
.addMarker(location, canDrag)

//Attach an InfoText ballon to a specified marker
//Add a listener to the marker to show the InfoText
.attachInfoText(marker, num)

//Geocode the address in the address input box or optional address argument
//If successful, make this the new map center, reinitialize
// the markers, and add this as a new first marker
.encodeAddressField([opt]address)

//Hide bulk markers in a given layer
.hideLayer(layer)

//Show bulk markers in a given layer
.showLayer(layer)

.bounceLayer(layer, seconds, action)

.bounceBulkMarker(index, seconds, action)

//Remove the markers from the map, but keep them in the array
.clearOverlays()

//Show any markers currently in the array
.showOverlays()

//Turn marker displays on or off
.toggleMarkers()

.deleteBulkMarkers()

//Delete all markers in the arrays
//also calls .deleteBulkMarkers()
.deleteOverlays()

//Create and show the polygon defined by the markers
.showPoly()

//Hide the polygon
.clearPoly()

//Turn the polygon display on or off
.togglePoly()

//Show a circle on the map around the center point if wanted
//Fit the map to the bounding box of the circle
.setRadius(value)

//Create a URL-encoded string containing the values to post back to the server
.computePostValues()

//Perform an Ajax callback to the Xbasic function 'TakeLatLng'
// using computePostValues() to do the heavy lifting
.SubmitLatLng()

//Ajax callback to do Geocoding
.geoCodeCallback(arg, callback)
]]>
            </example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
