<page>
    <shortlink>xbasic working with dotnet arrays</shortlink>
    <topic>Working with .Net Arrays</topic>
    <description>Arrays in Xbasic use one-based indexing. In other programming languages, arrays are zero-indexed. In this guide, you will learn how to work with .Net arrays in Xbasic.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Zero-based versus One-Based Indexing</title>
            <description>
                <p>By default, Xbasic arrays are indexed using one-based indexing. This means that the items in the array are referenced using indexes beginning with one (1) for the first entry and continuing on with 2, 3, 4 and so on.</p>
                <p>Other environments, including .Net arrays and collections, use zero-based indexing. This means that the first item in the array is referenced with an index value of zero (0) and continues on with 1,2,3 and so on.</p>
                <p>When accessing an array or collection in .Net from Xbasic, Alpha Anywhere automatically maps one-based indexes in Xbasic array references (square brackets – "[]") to zero-based indexes. This removes the need to remember whether an array reference is for an Xbasic array or a .Net array or collection.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Xbasic Square Bracket References</title>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Xbasic square bracket references ("x[1]" for example) to.Net collections and indexed properties assumes one-based indexing on the Xbasic side and maps to zero-based indexing on the .Net side. </name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>This is consistent with the default behavior of Xbasic arrays.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Xbasic Function Calls</title>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>If a .Net collection or class uses a function to access items, the Xbasic function syntax ("x.Item(0)" for example) does not map any parameters, as it does not know if they are indexes or simple values.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>If you call a .Net function, consult the documentation as to appropriate values. In general, indexing functions will require that you use zero-based indexing.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example Usage</title>
            <description>
                <p> The interactive window session below now shows accessing the *[xb:System::Data::DataSet]* Tables collection using the Item property with a numeric or string index:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[dim ds as system::data::dataset
t1 = ds.Tables.Add("Fred1")
?t1.TableName
= "Fred1"
t2 = ds.Tables.Add("Fred2")
?t2.TableName
= "Fred2"
Tables = ds.Tables.Count
for i = 1 to Tables ; ? ds.Tables.Item[i].TableName + crlf(); next
Fred1
Fred2
?ds.Tables.Item["Fred1"].TableName
= "Fred1"
?ds.Tables.Item["Fred2"].TableName
= "Fred2"]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>