<page>
    <shortlink>Javascript Actions Editor</shortlink>
    <topic>Javascript Actions Editor</topic>
    <description>Opens the Javascript Actions Editor which allows for the creation of unbound events.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Opening the Javascript Actions Editor on the UX Controls page</title>
                <link>images/jae5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>A standard way to access the Javascript Actions Editor is to first add a control to the controls tree, on the UX Controls page, and then define an javascript event for that control, for example 'onClick' or 'down'. Doing this automatically opens the Javascript Editor where you can define an action, or some free-form javascript, for the specified event on the specified control. Because these events are tied to a specific event they can be referred to as a 'bound event'.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>It is also possible to define 'unbound events' in the UX Builder. It is not necessary to have an event in place before creating a Javascript Action that defined what will happen when some javascript code is executed. You can create unbound events by opening the Javascript Actions Editor in the Additional Options Menu even before you have added a single control to the component.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Because the action javascript created for unbound events is not yet tied to anything, it is necessary to create a name for the action before it is defined. When you access the Javascript Actions Editor directly from the 'Additional Options Menu' you will need to press an 'Add' button.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/jae.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Editor will then prompt you to name the action.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/jae2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To define the action, highlight the new action and click the Edit Action button.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/jae3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Edit Unbound Event editor will open allowing you to create an unbound action.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/jae4.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you are using the Action Javascript option you can visit the '[Action Javascript]' page to see a list of all of the actions available in Alpha Anywhere. For a list of actions specific to the UX Component visit the '[Action Javascript for the UX]' page.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="action javascript for the ux">Action Javascript for the UX</link>
        <link link="Action Javascript">Action Javascript</link>
    </links>
</page>