<page>
    <topic>PhoneGap Shell QR Codes</topic>
    <description>Generate QR Codes for the UX Component name or Server Address for loading and testing Cordova applications in the PhoneGap-Shell-V2 (Cordova shell).</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/phonegapqrcode.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>When testing an app using the PhoneGap-Shell-V2 template, both the UX Component name and the URL for Ajax callbacks are required in order to load and test the application. Both the component name and Ajax callback URL can be loaded using a QR Code generated using the PhoneGap Shell QR Codes menu option. Codes for a UX Component's name and URL for Ajax Callbacks for an application can be generated. These codes can then be scanned in the Cordova shell application for testing on a mobile device.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Generating a QR Code for a UX Component Name</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>On the *[ui:Controls]* pane in the UX Builder, open the *[ui:Show additional options]* menu and select *[ui:PhoneGap Shell QR Codes...]* from the list of options.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/shellv2_qr1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>When prompted, choose *[ui:Component name]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/phonegapqrcode_component.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Alpha Anywhere will generate a QR Code that contains the component's name. Scan the QR Code using the QR Code scanner in the Cordova Shell app installed on a mobile device. Close the *[ui:UX Component Name]* QR Code dialog when you are finished.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/phonegapqrcode_componentqr.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Generating a QR Code for a Server Address</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>On the *[ui:Controls]* pane in the UX Builder, open the *[ui:Show additional options]* menu and select *[ui:PhoneGap Shell QR Codes...]* from the list of options.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/shellv2_qr1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>When prompted, choose *[ui:Server Address]* from the popup menu.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/shellv2_qr2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If generating a QR Code for a Server Address, enter the URL and a short description of the URL in the *[ui:URL for Ajax Callbacks]* dialog. The URL is the URL to the server where the published application resides. For example:</description>
                    <example><![CDATA[https://www.myapp.com/folderWhereAppWasPublished/]]></example>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/shellv2_qr3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to generate the QR Code. Scan the QR Code using the QR Code scanner in the Cordova Shell app installed on a mobile device.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/shellv2_qr4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="phonegap shell v2 template">PhoneGap-Shell-V2 UX Template</ref>
    </see>
</page>