<page build="4307">
    <shortlink>howto persistent login</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Build a Mobile Application with Persistent Login</topic>
    <description>Persistent login can be added to mobile applications, allowing users to log in to an application once and not requiring the user log in again, even if the application is closed.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A common pattern in mobile applications is to not require the user to login to the application after they have successfully logged in for the first time.  The login should be persistent until it is explicitly revoked by the action of an Administrator, or until the end of the persistent login period is reached.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <note>The [canAjaxCallback] server-side event previously would only emit user-defined Javascript if the event denied permission for the callback. Now, user defined Javascript can be emitted even if the Ajax callback is allowed. This change was made to support the Mobile Application with Persistent Login pattern.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>For more information on the approach used to implement this pattern, please [view this document].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Mobile Applications with Persistent Logins</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common pattern in mobile applications is to not require the user to login to the application after they have successfully logged in for the first time.  The login should be persistent until it is explicitly revoked by the action of an Administrator, or until the end of the persistent login period is reached.</p>
                    <p>Unlike a traditional Web application built using the Alpha Security Framework, the user will not have to log in again once their session expires, or when they restart the application.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how this pattern is achieved.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2017-04-29</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/Ei2D9uP1dn3s2AQShVLRTe</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>components/sampleMobleAppWithPersistentLogin.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="http://aadocuments.s3.amazonaws.com/misc/MobleAppsWithPersistentLogin.pdf">view this document</link>
        <link link="ux ssevents canAjaxCallback">canAjaxCallback</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux template persistent login">SecurityFramework-LoginComponentMobileApp-Persistent Login UX Template</ref>
    </see>
</page>