<page>
    <shortlink>capture images and audio in phonegap app</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Capture Media Files in an Offline Mobile Application</topic>
    <description>Learn how to build an offline-capable PhoneGap application that can be used to capture images and audio in a disconnected environment.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Many offline enabled mobile applications require the ability to capure rich media, such as images or audio recordings. The application must be able to capture and store images, video, and audio files with or without a network connection. The List control, which is the primary control used to create mobile applications, stores its data in Local Storage. Unfortunately, due to the size of rich media files - images, video, and audio - storing this information in Local Storage is not feasible. Instead of using Local Storage, the device's file system can be used to store images and audio files in mobile application built using PhoneGap.</p>
        <p>In the videos below, we explain how to build a PhoneGap application that can record audio and capture images in an offline environment. We show how to configure a List Control with a Detail View to capture data and media files and then sychronize the data with a server when a connection is available.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <note>The final video, "Part 6 - Running the app on a Device", is a large video file and may take longer to download.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 1 - Configuring the Data Source</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_1_sqldatabase.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 2 - Building the List Control and its associated Detail View</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_2_buildingTheUX.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 3 - Building the List Control and its associated Detail View</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_3_buildingTheUX.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 4 - Building the List Control and its associated Detail View</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_4a_buildingTheUX.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 5 - Building the List Control and its associated Detail View</name>
                    <link>www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_4b_buildingTheUX.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Part 6 - Running the app on a Mobile Device</name>
                    <link>www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/phonegap_mediaFilesTutorial_5_runningInPhoneGapShell.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>[Click here] to download the component shown in the videos above.</description>
            <note>See the component's *[ui:PhoneGapDefaultSettings]* property for a list of plugins used by the PhoneGap application.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/mediaFiles.zip">Click here</link>
    </links>
</page>