<page source="Xbasicaddins/ajax_webcomponents.a5lib/scripts/web_socket_server_sendmessage.a5udf" api="xb">
    <shortlink>api web socket server send message function source</shortlink>
    <topic>web_socket_server_sendmessage Function</topic>
    <description>Send a message to the web-sockets server. All clients that are listening to the web-sockets server will receive the message and the webSocketOnMessage client side event in each client will fire.</description>
    <prototype>P web_socket_server_sendMessage(C messageJSON)</prototype>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>messageJSON</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>A JSON string that contains the data to send. The JSON should be in the format expected by the client.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <returns>
        <return>
            <name>result</name>
            <types>
                <type>P</type>
            </types>
            <description>Returns a dot variable with the following properties:</description>
            <properties>
                <property>
                    <name>error</name>
                    <type>L</type>
                    <description>Indicates whether or not an error occurred.</description>
                </property>
                <property>
                    <name>errorText</name>
                    <type>C</type>
                    <description>If an error occurred, contains information about the error. *[xb:errorText]* will be blank if no error occurred.</description>
                </property>
            </properties>
        </return>
    </returns>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[xb:]* sends a message to the web-sockets server. The message is sent to all clients that are listening for messages.</p>
        <p>The message must be defined as a JSON string. The JSON format is dictated by the client(s) listening for the message. For example, if the client is expecting to receive a text string in a property called "newMessage", you must include this property in your JSON string.</p>
        <p>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[dim pm as p
pm.newMessage = "Hello!"
dim json as c
messageJSON = json_generate(pm)
callResult = web_socket_server_sendMessage(messageJSON)
]]></example>
        </p>
        <p>If *[xb:messageJSON]* is not a JSON string, you may see the following error message on the client when a message is sent:</p>
        <p>
            <example><![CDATA[Received a message that was not in correct format. Messages must be JSON strings]]></example>
        </p>
        <p>*[xb:web_socket_server_sendMessage()]* is not supported in Working Preview.</p>
    </discussion>
    <see>
        <ref link="web socket server">Web Socket Server</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>web-sockets,client side,function</terms>
</page>