<page>
	  <topic>Cell in-line Style</topic>
<description>The appearance of a control and the grid cell that contains it are set by the style sheet attached to the grid component.</description>
  
<sections>
	<section>
		<description>In the Grid or UX Component Builders, two properties can override these style sheet settings. These are the In-line style property found in the control's properties settings (i.e. Label Properties, Dropdown Properties, etc..) and the Cell in-line style property found in the Column (or Row) Properties section of the Field Properties list. The picture shows what this can look like. Here is a grid component with four field rows, Company Name, Contact Name, City, and Country. The last field, Country, has had its Cell in-line style properties modified so that the background and the border are green. </description>
	</section>
	<section>
		<figure>
			<title>Cell in-line style for Country field.</title>
			<link>images/02_Incellstyle.png</link>
			</figure>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Change the Cell in-line Style:</title>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Open the Grid Builder. On the Design tab in the Component Type page select Grid is: Read Only.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Open the Data Source page and select either dbf or SQL. </description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>On the Query(DBF) or Query(AlphaDAO) page select a table you want to use, click Select Primary Key to choose field you will use.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>On the Fields page move a number of fields from the Available Fields: list to the Selected: fields list using the arrows between the two lists.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select one of the fields in the Selected: fields list. In the Field Properties list scroll down to either the Column Properties section or the Row Properties section depending.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>In this section find the Cell in-line style property. Click the button next to it. This will open the  Style Editor.</description>
				<figure><link>images/02_Styleeditor.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>In the Style Editor set the Background color, border style and color, font type and size, and other style attributes to your liking. </description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Now go to Live Preview and see how your styling looks.</description>
				<figure>
					<title>Cell in-line style on Contact Name field</title>
					<link>images/02_Styleeditor2.png</link>
					</figure>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
			
		
	</section>
	
</sections>
  
	
</page>