<page>
	<topic>Changing the Case of Words
</topic>
	<description>Transformation Rules automatically change entries to uppercase or lowercase, and define shortcut abbreviations for entering commonly used words and phrases.  
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<figure><link>images/UG_Field_Rules_Transformations_tab.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>You can automatically change words in a character field to uppercase, lowercase, proper case, or initial capitals. You can also define special cases when the rule should not be applied.
</description>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Creating a Case Conversion Rule
</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the Control Panel select the table and click Table > Edit Field Rules.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Display the Transformations tab.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select an entry from the Case convert list. 
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>The options are:</description>
				<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Upper"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Lower"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"First"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Word"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description><![CDATA["Low & First"]]></description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description><![CDATA["Low & Word"]]></description>
						</case>
				</cases>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>This table shows the different effects of the case conversion options.</description>
				<figure><link>images/fieldtable.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
			
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Case Conversion Exceptions</title>
			<description>Alpha Anywhere lets you define words that do not conform to any pre-defined case conversions, such as a name with mixed upper and lowercase letters.
</description><cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Check the Check exceptions check box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Decide at what level you want to examine the user's input. Choose either Lookup Entire Field or Lookup Each Word.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click Edit Exceptions to add items to display the Special Case Conversions dialog box and update its entries.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Defining Word Substitutions</title>
			<description>You can also use the Speed Glossary to define field rule transformations.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>1. Check the Use speed typing glossary check box.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>2. Click Edit glossary... to add items to display the Speed Glossary dialog box and update its entries.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
<section>
	
	
	
</section>


	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>