<page>
	<topic>Creating and Using a Summary Field</topic>
<sections>
<section>

	<description>The Summary Genie assists you in creating calculated fields that summarize various aspects of a field over a group of records or over the whole table. The Summary Genie will summarize over the child records for a given parent record if you select a field or expression based on a child record. It will summarize over the whole table if you select a field or expression based on a parent record. The following functions are supported:</description>
</section>	

<section>		
	<title>Summary Functions</title>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Total
</title>
			<description>Total of a group of number values.</description>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Average</title>
			<description>Average of a group of number values.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Count</title>
			<description>Count of records for a group of records.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Minimum value</title>
			<description>Minimum character or number value for a group of records.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Maximum value</title>
			<description>Maximum character or number value for a group of records.</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>	
<section>		
	<title>Other functions</title>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Count duplicates
</title>
			<description>A summary function that returns the number of Duplicate records for the expression evaluated for a group of records.
</description>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>First in group
</title>
			<description>
 
A summary function that returns the First value of the expression evaluated for a group of records.
 </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Last in group
</title>
			<description>
 
A summary function that returns the Last value of the expression evaluated for a group of records.
 </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Standard deviation
</title>
			<description>
 
Returns the Standard Deviation of the field's expression evaluated for a group of records.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Standard deviation for population
</title>
			<description>Returns the Population Standard Deviation of the field's expression evaluated for a group of records.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Variance
</title>
			<description>Returns the Variance of the field's expression evaluated for a group of records.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Variance for population
</title>
			<description>Returns the Population Variance of the field's expression evaluated for a group of records.
</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>		
	<section>
<title></title>		
<description></description>		
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Click the following to display a list of table fields.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Drag_and_Drop_List_button.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the Genie button so that it is depressed.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Genie_button.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Drag a field with a number value, such Invoice_Items->Extension onto the form.</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the Total of the field option button when the Summary Field Genie appears.</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Finish. </description>
		<figure><link>images/AL_summary_field_genie_2.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>		
		
		
	</section>
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>The Invoice Form</ref>
	</see>
</page>