<page>
	<topic>Define a View Query</topic>
<sections>
	<section>
		<description>This procedure is part of the procedure for building a grid component.
A view is similar to an Alpha Anywhere set or SQL join. It combines selected fields from two or more tables that are linked in one-to-one or one-to-many relationships. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Table_View.gif</link></figure>
	<note>When you are displaying data from two tables linking in a one-to-many parent-child relationship, you have two alternatives when designing the view.</note>
	</section>
<section>
	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"One" table as parent, "Many" table as child - creates as many records as there are in the "One" table.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Many" table as parent, "One" table as child - creates as many records as there are in the "Many" table. This is essentially the same as flattening a set.
</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Select the Tables to Use
</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select Grid > Query (DBF).
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Tables in View to display the Add Table dialog box.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the table from the Table Name list.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, provide an alternative name for the table in the Alias field.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to add the table or Cancel to discard your inputs.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>After the first table has been added, the Define Join dialog box appears.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the parent table in the relationship and click Add Table to display the Add Table dialog box.
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Steps:</title>
			<description>1. Select the new child table from the Table Name list.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>2. Optionally, provide an alternative name for the table in the Alias field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>3. Select the Link Type. The options are:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"One-to-first"
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"One-to-last"
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"One-to-closest"
</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<description>4. Select a value from the Include Parent list:
</description><cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Always"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Only if Matching Child Exists"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Only if Matching Child Does Not Exist"
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Click OK to add the child table or Cancel to discard your inputs.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Select the child table in the Define Join dialog box.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Optionally, select a different field from the Link Expression list. The Link Expression defines how to associate the parent with the child. You may click Build </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Expression to use the Expression Builder to help you define the expression.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Optionally, select a different field from the Parent Link Expression list. The Parent Link Expression defines how to associate the child with the parent. You may </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>click Build Expression to use the Expression Builder to help you define the expression.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>If you made any changes the to the properties of the child table, click Apply Edits to save your changes or Cancel Edits to discard your changes.
</description>
		</case>
	</cases>



		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Repeat step 7 for each additional child table that you want to include in the view.
</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>Click OK to continue or Cancel to discard your inputs.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Select the Fields to Retrieve
</title>
			<description>In the Grid Builder click Fields in View to display the Select Fields in View dialog box.
</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Use the >, >>, <, and << buttons to add and remove fields from the available fields list.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, use the 'AZ up' and 'AZ down' buttons to sort the list of fields.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, use the following buttons to reorganize the sequence of fields.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Move_First_button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Up_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Down_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Last_button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to continue or Cancel to discard your inputs.
</description>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<title>Define Arguments
</title>
			<description>Optionally, if you want to provide a value for use in the grid's filter expression, click Define Arguments to display the Define Arguments dialog box.
</description>
			
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<title>Enter a Filter Expression</title>
			<description>Optionally, enter a logical expression that selects records from the table into the Filter field. You may click 'xy' to use the Expression Builder to help you define the expression. A blank filter expression retrieves all records in the table.</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Unique records only to eliminate records with duplicate values.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<title>Enter an Order Expression</title>
			<description>Optionally, enter a character expression that orders selected records into the Order field. You may click the 'up and down arrows' icon to use the Order Builder to help you define the expression. A blank order expression retrieves records in record number order.</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Ascending or Descending to change the sequence of records.
</description>
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<title>Enable Editing of Records</title>
			<description>Optionally, check Read only to indicate that you do not need to define a primary key.</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Define Primary Key(s) to define the field or character expression that will uniquely identify records.</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Limitations: Web publishing applications only.
</description>
	
</section>
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Selecting the Fields to Display</ref>
</see>
	
</page>