<page>
	<topic>Placing a Calculated Value on a Form</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>This example shows how to place a calculated value on a form. The example is based on the invoice_items table of the AlphaSports sample database.
</description>
	<note>Alpha Anywhere documentation and software has traditionally referred to the values that you calculate and place on a layout as "calculated fields". However, these values are not fields, because they are not stored in a table record. They are temporary variables that are created and calculated on demand. If you want to calculate a value for a table field, refer to Calculated Fields.</note>
	
</section>	
	<section>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Display the Forms tab of the Control Panel.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click New, select the invoice_items table, and click Next >.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select Custom Form and Next >.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select "Price" in the Available Fields list and click '>'.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select "Quantity" in the Available Fields list and click '>'.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click Next > and Finish. The Form Editor will now display a form that looks something like this: 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Calculated_Field2.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select and drag the "" entry from the Drag Drop list onto the form. This will display the New Calculated Field dialog.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Enter "Total" into the Name control.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click the 'xy' icon in the Expression control to display the Expression Builder.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Double click Field Name in the upper left corner of the dialog. Select "Price" and click Insert.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Place a multiplication symbol after "Price", so the expression is "Price*".
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Double click Field Name in the upper left corner of the dialog. Select "Quantity" and click Insert, so the expression is "Price*Quantity".
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click OK to return to the New Calculated Field dialog.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click OK to return to the Form Editor.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click to switch to form view.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Enter a value into the Price field, then the Quantity field. Alpha Anywhere will calculate the value of the Total field. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Calculated_Field2b.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>The labels and controls clearly need formatting. For more information, see Setting Field Properties.</description>
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Placing Type-In Objects</ref>
		<ref>Editing Objects on the Form</ref>
		<ref>Calculated Values</ref>
	</see>
</page>