<page>
	<topic>Placing Bitmap and JPEG Image Fields</topic>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere lets you add images to your database in two ways.</description>
	
<sections>
<section><cases>
		<case>
			<title>Bitmap and JPEG Image fields </title>
			<description>store Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) images in the database. The images are stored in .FPT memo files.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
				<title>Image File Reference fields</title>
			<description>store the paths and filenames of Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) images in the database, while the images are stored independently in Windows folders. For many applications this is a more efficient way of storing images, and it can result in much smaller databases.</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Creating a Bitmap Image Field</title>
	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Display the Table/Sets tab of the Control Panel.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the table that will contain the field and select Design > Table Structure.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the resulting Restructure Table dialog box create a field of type "Bitmap". Its width automatically defaults to 10 characters.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
	
	<title>Creating a JPEG Image Field</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Display the Table/Sets tab of the Control Panel.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the table that will contain the field and select Design > Table Structure.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the resulting Restructure Table dialog box create a field of type "JPEG Image". Its width automatically defaults to 10 characters.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Placing a Bitmap or JPEG Image Field</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the image file reference field on the Drag and Drop List.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Drag the field onto the form.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Resize and reposition the field (which will display the image) as necessary.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click on the field and select Properties > Setup.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the image display mode to use. The options are:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Absolute" - the image is not stretched or scaled and may be bigger or smaller than the form field. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Best Fit" - the image is scaled without distortion to fit the form field </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Stretch" - the image is scaled with possible distortion to fit the form field </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Tiled" - the image is repeated as many times as necessary both vertically and horizontally to fill the form field </description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Adding an Image to the Table</title>
	<description>When you insert a picture into a .JPG Picture field, you are not restricted to selecting only .JPG files. For example, you can select a .BMP file and insert it into the .JPG field. Alpha Five will automatically convert the .BMP format file to a .JPG format and store the picture in the field.
The same is true of storing a .JPG format file in a .BMP field. Alpha Five automatically converts from the .JPG format to the .BMP format.
</description>
	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image file reference field and select Import Image.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the resulting Filename dialog box, optionally enter the path and filename of an image file in the File name field.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally,</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>1. Click the 'open folder' icon to select a disk drive and directory in the Look in field.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>2. Select the file from the File Names list.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>3. Optionally, click the 'heart' icon to save the current folder as the default folder when adding other images.</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the preview display mode by clicking Best Fit, Absolute, or Stretch. This does not affect the form's image's display properties.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Absolute" - does not stretch the image. This option may cause the image to appear as a different size when printed. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Stretch" - stretches the image both horizontally and vertically to cover the form's background. This option may distort the image. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Best fit" - scales the image to the maximum size that will fit on the form background without clipping the image. </description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to select the image or Cancel to quit.</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>



<section>
	<title>Adding Data to a Bitmap or JPEG Image Field with Xbasic</title>
	<description>The following script was placed under the OnPush event of a button on a form. The form displays a field named thumbnail, which is a Bitmap Image field. This script works equally well for JPEG Image fields.</description>
	<note>There is no automatic format conversion, so you must select a Windows Bitmap for a bitmap image field and a JPEG image for a JPEG image field.</note>
</section>
<section>
	<example><![CDATA[dim img as C
dim tbl as P
tbl = table.current()
img = ui_get_image_filename()
tbl.enter_begin(.t.)
tbl.thumbnail.memo_read_from_file(img, MEMO_APPEND)
tbl.enter_end(.t.)
thumbnail.refresh() ]]></example>
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Deleting an Image</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image field and select Delete Image.</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Exporting the Image</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image field and select Export Image.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, in the resulting Save As dialog select Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) from the Save as type list.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Navigate to the target folder, enter a filename in the File name field, and click OK.</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Using the Toolbox</ref>
	<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
	<ref>Creating an Image File Reference field</ref>
	<ref>Creating Wallpaper for Your Application</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>