<page>
	<topic>Placing Image File Reference Fields</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere lets you add images to your database in two ways.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Bitmap and JPEG Image fields</title>
			<description>store Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) images in the database. The images are stored in .FPT memo files.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Image File Reference fields</title>
			<description>store the paths and filenames of Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) images in the database, while the images are stored independently in Windows folders. For many applications this is a more efficient way of storing images, and it can result in much smaller databases.</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>An image file reference field in a table stores the path and filename of a JPEG (.JPG) or Windows Bitmap (.BMP) image. The field on a form displays the image.</description>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Creating an Image File Reference Field</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Display the Table/Sets tab of the Control Panel.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the table that will contain the field and select Design > Table Structure.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the resulting Restructure Table dialog box create a field of type "Image File Reference". Its width automatically defaults to 10 characters.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Placing an Image File Reference Field</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the image file reference field on the Drag and Drop List.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Drag the field onto the form.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Resize and reposition the field (which will display the image) as Necessary.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>


<section>
	<title>Adding an Image to the Table</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image file reference field and select Change Image Filename.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the resulting Filename dialog box, optionally enter the path and filename of an image file in the File name field.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally,</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Click the 'open folder' to select a disk drive and directory in the Look in field.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Select the file from the File Names list.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Optionally, click the 'heart' icon to save the current folder as the default folder when adding other images.</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the display mode by clicking Best Fit, Absolute, or Stretch.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Absolute" - does not stretch the image. This option may cause the image to appear as a different size when printed. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Stretch" - stretches the image both horizontally and vertically to cover the form's background. This option may distort the image. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Best fit" - scales the image to the maximum size that will fit on the form background without clipping the image. </description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to select the image or Cancel to quit.</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Adding Data to an Image File Reference Field with Xbasic</title>
	
			<description>The following script was placed under the OnPush event of a button on a form. The form displays a field named picture, which is an Image File Reference field. The IMAGE_FILENAME_ENCODE() function replaces any part of the file path for which there is an alias.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim img as C
dim tbl as P
tbl = table.current()
img = ui_get_image_filename()
tbl.enter_begin(.t.)
tbl.picture = image_filename_encode(img)
tbl.enter_end(.t.)
picture.Refresh()]]></example>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
			<description>To read the image filename, use:</description>
		<example><![CDATA[a5_eval_expression(tbl.picture)]]></example>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Deleting an Image File Reference</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image file reference field and select Delete Image Filename.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Viewing the Image Filename</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Put the form into view mode.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the image file reference field and select Show Image Filename.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to continue.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>


	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Using the Toolbox</ref>
		<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
	</see>
</page>