<page>
	<topic>Types of Field Rules</topic>
	<description>The following list includes a brief description of each field rule in its own respective category.</description>

<sections>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Field Types
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Calculated Fields
</title>
				<description>Alpha Anywhere automatically calculates field values.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Auto-increment
</title>
				<description>Assigns incrementing field values as records are entered.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Default Descriptive Name
</title>
				<description>Changes the default field name; for example, "F_Name" to "First Name".
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Field Description
</title>
				<description>Provides the status bar text that appears when a field is selected.
</description>
			</case>
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Data Entry
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>
 
Required
 </title>
				<description>Specifies that a field must contain data.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Masks/Templates
</title>
				<description>
 
Inserts formatting characters, like dashes and spaces, and determines whether a number or letter can be entered in a particular location in the field.
 </description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Auto-Advance
</title>
				<description>Moves the cursor to the next field, when the current field is full; for example, after you enter both characters in a two-character state abbreviation field, the cursor moves to the next field.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Default Mode
</title>
				<description>Fills in a constant value that you provide, or the result of a default expression.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Skip
</title>
				<description>Causes the cursor to skip over the field, when you press the Tab or Enter keys.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Position Cursor
</title>
				<description>Places the cursor at the beginning or end of selected or non-selected text, when the field gets focus.
</description>
			</case>
			
		
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>
Transformations
 

 </title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Case Convert
</title>
				<description>Converts values to uppercase, lowercase, or a combinations of both.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Speed Typing Glossary
</title>
				<description>Fills in a longer word or phrase, when you enter a user-defined keyword.
</description>
			</case>
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Validations
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Double Entry
</title>
				<description>Requires that a field value be entered twice, to ensure data entry accuracy.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Min/Max Value
</title>
				<description>Specifies the minimum and maximum field values.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Uniqueness Test
</title>
				<description>Prohibits a field value from being entered in the same field for another record.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Cross-file Validation
</title>
				<description>Cross-checks a field value to a field value in another table.
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Custom Validation
</title>
				<description>Checks the validity of a field value using a validation expression or user-defined function.
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Lookups
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>
 
Simple List
 </title>
				<description>Presents a pre-defined list of values for field entry.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Cascading List
</title>
				<description>Presents a pre-defined list, which can include multiple sub-lists, for field entry.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Table Lookup
</title>
				<description>Presents selections from an existing table, for field entry.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Conditional Table Lookup
</title>
				<description>Presents values for data entry, based on a conditional expression.
</description>
			</case>
				<case>
				<title>Previous Values
</title>
				<description>Presents values from a list of previously entered values.
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Posting
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>
 
Posting
 </title>
				<description>Posts data from the current field to a target field, thus, you can add to, subtract from, or replace the target field value. Useful for keeping a running total, by using the Add Operation, or for tracking inventory levels, by using the Subtract Operation.
</description>
			</case>
			
		
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>Events
</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>
 
Field Event
 </title>
				<description>Xbasic code executed for a field.
</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Record Event
</title>
				<description>Xbasic code executed for a record.
</description>
			</case>
			
		
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
	
</page>