<page>
<topic>Icon</topic>
<description>The 'Icon' property specifies the icon that will appear on a button. 
	In order to access the Icon property you must fisrt select an option from the 'Button layout' property that contains an 'Image'.</description>


<sections>
	<section>
		<description>Clicking the [...] button next to the Icon property opens the 'Specify Image' dialog. There are five 
			general options for specifying an image. These are:
		</description>
		<list>
			<item>
				<name>SVG Icon</name>
				
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>CSS Icon</name>
				
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Image in Web Project or Style</name>
				
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Built-in Image</name>
				
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>URL for external image</name>
				
			</item>
			
		</list>
	</section>
	
	
	<section>
		<title>SVG Icon</title>
				<description>Unlike regular images, which are bitmaps, SVG Icons are rendered as vectors. The advantage 
			of SVG Icons is that they can be smoothly scaled to any size and can be rendered in any color. Some of the 
			component styles use SVG Icons and if you are using one of these styles, then you can choose an icon from the style. 
			You can also add your own SVG icons to a component in the 'Local SVG definitions' and 'Linked SVG files' property.
		</description>
		<figure><title>Built-in SVG icons using the 'Alpha' style.</title><link>images/svgicons.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>CSS Icon</title>
		<description>Unlike regular images, which are bitmaps, CSS Icons are rendered using a special font that is loaded by a CSS stylesheet. 
			Some of the component styles use CSS Icons and if you are using these styles, then you can choose an icon from the style. 
			You can also select the icon from any of the 3rd-party CSS Icon libraries that you have specified should be loaded 
			(for example, the 'Font-Awesome' icon library).
		</description>
		
			</section>
	<section>
		
		<figure><title>Built-in CSS icons using the 'Alpha' style and 'font-awesome' Image source.</title><link>images/cssicons.png</link></figure>

	</section>
	<section>
		<description>The Color: control in the corner of the Icon Picker opens the Color Picker. This allows you to alter the color of the icons.</description>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>Checking the 'Spin' checkbox causes icons to spin.</description>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Image in Web Project or Style</title>
		<description></description>
		
	</section>		
		
	<section>
		<description>Choosing the 'Select From Web Project Folder' option opens a dialog that allows you to add images to a project. 
			This can be done by clicking the 'Add Image to Project' button in the lower left-hand corner of the dialog. Doing this 
			will open a file navigator that will let you select an existing image on your computer's desktop and add it to the project. 
			
		</description>
		<figure><title>A project image imported from the desktop.</title><link>images/project icon.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Built-in Image</title>
		<description>You can access Alpha Anywhere's built-in images for use in an application by selecting the Built-in Image option. 
			There are options for using System Images, Addin Images, Windows Images, and Current Workspace Images. The Built-in Image 
			feature is an old one and works with almost all styles. The System Images option contains the largest number of built-in 
			icons.
		</description>
		<figure><link>images/builtin.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>

</page>
