<page>
   <topic>A5WS_Get_Groups Function</topic>
   <syntax>Group_List as C = a5ws_Get_Groups([* Localrequest [,L FlagWeb ]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>Group_List</name>
         <description>A list of security groups in the current web project.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>Localrequest</name>
         <description>Optional. The Request system variable. This variable explicitly passes all request variables  to the function. Required if run from a web page.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>FlagWeb</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .F. . 

 .T. = Format suitable  for use in a list, checkbox, or radio control on a web page

.F. = CR-LF delimited  list </description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Show a CR-LF list of web groups  for the current project.  FlagWeb default value is .F.  FlagWeb = .T. will output list in a format used in web components for checkboxes, radio buttons, list boxes and dropdowns.  'Request' pointer must be provided if run in web page.</description>
   <discussion>
The A5WS_Get_Groups() function returns a list of security groups defined for the current web project. 
 It can be used without parameters to return a list of groups defined for the current selected web project. 
It can be used on a web page or in a web componetn event to retrieve a list of user security  groups for use in a check box control, a dropdown list, a radio lbutton list, or a listbox control in a dialog component. Typically  used in the Server Activate event of a dialog component.

   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
    <section>
            <list>
            <item><name>
            1. Display the Form > Properties menu page of the Dialog  Builder.

            </name>
            </item>
            <item>
            <name>
            2. Click  in the Server Events > Activate property. 
            </name>
            </item>
            </list>
          
       </section>
       <section>
            <description>Limitations: Web applications only.</description>
          
       </section>
   </sections>
   
   <sections>
       <section>
            <title>Example</title>
            <example><![CDATA[
? A5WS_Get_Groups()
= Accounting
Administrators
Marketing

'on web page or in component event
grouplist = a5ws_get_groups(request,.T.) 

]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   
   <see>
      <ref>a5ws_GetGroupsDialog Function</ref>
      <ref>Web Application Functions</ref>
      <ref>Returns a list of security groups defined for the current web project</ref>
   </see>
   
<terms>web application,security,a5w,box,click,components,control,default value,display,dropdown,events,function,list,menu,pointer,system,variable</terms>
   
   
</page>