<page>
	<topic>The Record List Control</topic>
<description>A record list control displays data in a combo box, edit-combo box, or a list box. Unlike combo boxes or list boxes, however, the record list is populated dynamically with data from records in a table. The advantage of this over a combo box or list box is that there is no limit to the number of entries that can be displayed in a record list. In addition, record lists have other advantages over combo boxes in that they can be multi-columned.</description>	
<sections>
<section>
	<description>If you are familiar with the Table Lookup Field Rule, you can think of the record list control as being loosely equivalent to a table lookup.
The record list control gives you a great deal of control over various aspects of the data in the drop-down list or list associated with the record list control. For example, you can control how many columns of data are displayed, column widths, what data is displayed in each column, which records are displayed in the list, and what value is returned when the user makes a selection.
</description>
	<note>While this lesson will teach you the syntax of the record list commands (which frankly can get quite tricky), the easiest way to create a record list control on an Xdialog box is to let Alpha Anywhere do it for you automatically using Action Scripting. Use the "Display an Xdialog Box" action to create the Xdialog box, and then view the underlying Xbasic code.</note>
</section>	
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>[Simple Record Lists]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Simple List Box-Record List Control]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Advanced Record Lists]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Syntax of the KEYLIST_BUILD function]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Advanced List Box-Record List Control]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Formatting Record Lists]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Optimizing Performance of Advanced Record Lists]</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>[Record List Events]</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Learning Xdialog">Learning Xdialog</ref>
	</see>
	<links>
		<link href="/Desktop/Guide/Design/Data/DBF/Simple Record Lists.xml">Simple Record Lists</link>
			<link href="/Guides/Desktop/Xdialog/Controls/Simple List Box-Record List Control.xml">Simple List Box-Record List Control</link>
			<link href="/Desktop/Guide/Design/Data/DBF/Advanced Record Lists.xml">Advanced Record Lists</link>
			<link href="/Ref/Api/Functions/Document Types/DBF/Index Functions/KEYLIST_BUILD Function.xml">Syntax of the KEYLIST_BUILD function</link>
			<link href="/Guides/Desktop/Xdialog/Controls/Advanced List Box-Record List Control.xml">Advanced List Box-Record List Control</link>
			<link href="/Desktop/Guide/Design/Data/DBF/Formatting Record Lists.xml">Formatting Record Lists</link>
			<link href="/Desktop/Guide/Design/View/Database/Optimizing Performance of Advanced Record Lists.xml">Optimizing Performance of Advanced Record Lists</link>
			<link href="/Desktop/Guide/Design/Data/DBF/Record List Events.xml">Record List Events</link>
		
	</links>
</page>