<page>
    <shortlink>transform app editornumeric</shortlink>
    <topic>Numeric Field Editor</topic>
    <description>Used for capturing numeric values.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description><p>
        The Numeric Field Editor is used to enter text values made up of numeric characters (0 through 9, and optionally "." and
        "–"). It displays a box at the top with the current value and a large keypad below for entering and editing
        the value. There are several configurations for different types of values.
      </p>
      <p>
        All input and editing is done using the keys on the keypad. The digit buttons (
        *[0]* through
        *[9]*) add digits to the right of the current value.
        *[AC]* button (All Clear) clears the current value (to a blank field for phone numbers and zero for all other configurations).
        The [bspace] *[backspace]* button deletes the rightmost character from the value. The
        *[+/-]* toggles the value between positive and negative. The
        *[Done]* button confirms the value and returns to the form details screen. The
        *[–]* button adds a "–" to the value, such as for a phone number.
        The *[00]* button adds two zeroes, such as for a currency value. 
      </p>
      <p>
        The configurations are:
      </p></description>
        <cases>
            <case>
                <title nested="2">Number</title>
                <description><p>
              A numeric value with an optional decimal point. It includes keypad buttons for the digits as well as ".".
            </p></description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <title nested="2">Integer</title>
                <description><p>
              A numeric value with no decimal part nor a sign. It includes keypad buttons for the digits only.
            </p>
            <p>
              On the
              *[form details]* screen, just under the value displayed,
              *[additional buttons]* are provided to quickly change the value without needing to bring up an editor. There
              are buttons to
              *[add]* 1 or 10 to, or
              *[subtract]* 1 or 10 from, the value.
            </p>
            </description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <title nested="2">Signed</title>
                <description><p>A numeric value with an optional decimal point and it may also optionally be negative. It includes keypad buttons for the digits as well as "." and "+/-". </p></description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <title nested="2">Currency</title>
                <description><p>A numeric value with two decimal places. It includes keypad buttons for the digits as well as "00". Numbers are entered with an implied decimal point. That is, if you enter just "2", you get "0.02", and "1.00" would be entered with either "100" or "1" followed by "00".</p></description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <title nested="2">Phone</title>
                <description><p>
              A text value made up of digits and any number of optional "–" dashes.
            </p></description>
            </case>
        </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/backspace.svg">bspace</link>
    </links>
</page>