<page>
    <shortlink>transform app editoraudio</shortlink>
    <topic>Audio Editor</topic>
    <description>Used to record or play audio.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description><p>
        The Audio Editor lets you access the device's microphone and audio recording functionality to make a recording for use as
        the field's value. Once recorded, it may also be used to play that recording.
      </p>
      <p>
        The Audio Editor has two main mode: Recording and Playback.
      </p>
      <p>
        If the field does not already have a recording as a value, accessing the Audio Editor will start in Record Mode. If the field
        already has a recording as a value, accessing the Audio Editor will start in Play Mode.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Record Mode</title>
            <description><p>
        In record mode, the editor screen starts out almost entirely filled with a single, large gray, rectangular button with a
        red circle icon in the middle. Tapping anywhere on the button will start recording.
      </p>
      <p>
        While the device is recording, the editor screen will display two large buttons with a time display above them. The time
        display will show both the elapsed time and the maximum time allowed for a recording (60 minutes). The gray button
        with a red [redPause] Pause icon may be tapped to pause the recording. The red button with a white [stop] Stop icon must be tapped to finish the recording.
      </p>
      <p>
        While paused, the gray rectangle will have a red circle icon. Tapping that button will resume recording. The red rectangle
        may be used to end recording without resuming.
      </p>
      <p>
        Once recording has been ended, the editor will switch to Play Mode.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Play Mode</title>
            <description><p>
        In play mode, the editor screen starts out almost entirely filled with a single, large, green, rectangular button with a
        white [play] Play icon in the middle. Tapping anywhere on the button will start playback.
      </p>
      <p>
        While the device is playing the recording, the editor screen will display two large buttons with a time display above them.
        The time display will show both the current time position in the recording (starting out at 0:00.0) and the total
        length of the recording. The gray button with a white [pause] Pause icon may be tapped to pause the playback. The red button with a white [stop] Stop icon may be tapped to stop the playback completely.
      </p>
      <p>
        While paused, the gray rectangle will be replaced by a green Play button. Tapping that button will resume playback. The red
        rectangle may be used to end playback without resuming.
      </p>
      <p>
        Below the large buttons, both a [rewind] Rewind button and a [forward] Forward button will be displayed.
      </p>
      <p>
        Tapping these buttons will move the playback an increment in the corresponding direction. Pressing and holding on either
        of these buttons will repeatedly move the playback.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Deleting the recording</title>
            <description>An existing recording may be deleted (setting the field to blank) by tapping the [delete] *[Delete]* button at the bottom-left of the screen. Confirmation will then be requested to make sure that you indeed
        wish to delete the recording.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/play.svg">play</link>
        <link href="/images/redPause.svg">redPause</link>
        <link href="/images/pause.svg">pause</link>
        <link href="/images/stop.svg">stop</link>
        <link href="/images/rewind.svg">rewind</link>
        <link href="/images/forward.svg">forward</link>
        <link href="/images/deleteFilled.svg">delete</link>
    </links>
</page>