<page>
    <shortlink>transform app editorphoto</shortlink>
    <topic>Photo Editor</topic>
    <description>Used to capture and annotate photos.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Photo Editor lets you access the device's camera capabilities and photo album to obtain an image for use as the field's value. Optionally, you can also draw annotations on the image (explained in the [Ink Drawing Screen] help).</p>
                <p>If the field does not already have a photo as a value, accessing the Photo Editor will bring up the device's camera screen. You can then use the camera to capture an image as you normally would and confirm that you wish to use that photo as the field value. The Photo Editor screen will then be displayed, showing the image. Alternatively, instead of taking a photo, you may cancel taking a photo and go directly to the Photo Editor screen (for example, in order to obtain a photo from the device's photo album or to set the image resolution before taking the photo, or to draw on a blank image of plain, lined, or graph "paper"). </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Previewing the image</title>
            <description>
                <p>When a photo is displayed on the Photo Editor, you may zoom in and out using a two-finger pinch gesture. Double-tapping on the photo will restore it to "fit to screen".</p>
                <p>You may also use the [fit], [zoomIn], and [zoomOut] buttons at the bottom of the screen to fit to screen, zoom in, and zoom out, respectively.</p>
                <p>If the preview is zoomed in, you may pan the image by dragging with one finger. If the preview is set to fit to the screen (the initial state) such that panning has no meaning, swiping right or left will switch to the next or previous field's editor just as with other editors. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Drawing or writing on the image</title>
            <description>
                <p>The [draw] button at the bottom of the screen switches to the Ink Drawing Screen. See the [Ink Drawing Screen] help for more information about writing on an image. (This button may optionally not be available at the discretion of the form designer.) </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Photo Menu</title>
            <description>
                <p>The [menu] Photo Menu button at the bottom of the screen brings up a menu to access this help topic as well as to replace or delete the existing image. The replacement may be a photo taken with the camera, an image copied from the device's photo album, or an automatically-created image of blank plain, lined, or graph "paper" on which to write. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Deleting the image</title>
            <description>
                <p>An existing image may be deleted (setting the field to blank) by tapping the [delete] *[Delete]* button at the bottom-left of the screen. Confirmation will then be requested to make sure that you indeed wish to delete the image.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Capturing an image (camera or photo album)</title>
            <description>
                <p>To capture an image (which will replace an existing image, if any, without confirmation if not canceled), tap the *[New Photo]* [camera] button at the bottom-right of the screen. This will bring up a menu with the following parts: </p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Resize New]* checkbox on the left. If checked, the new image being obtained will be resized to the size specified by the designer of the form type. (This is done by default to keep the image file sizes small.) If not checked, then the original, full-resolution size of the new image will be preserved. Tap the checkbox or words to toggle the check off and on.</p>
                        <p>If there is an existing image, the size, in pixels, of the image will be displayed below the Resize New checkbox.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>*[Album]* [album] button on the right. Tapping this will allow you to access the device's photo album to select an existing photo in the album. A copy will be used for the field value.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>*[Camera]* [camera] button on the right. Tapping this will allow you to access the device's camera to take a new photo for use as the field value.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To cancel the photo menu, tap above or below the menu.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a new blank image on which to draw </title>
            <description>
                <p>To create a blank "piece of paper" on which to draw (which will replace an existing image, if any, without confirmation when saved), tap the *[New blank image for drawing]* [page] button on the Photo Menu. (This button may optionally not be available at the discretion of the form designer.) This will bring up a menu with the following parts: </p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Portrait / Landscape]* choice buttons. Tapping one of these lets you specify whether the new image will be taller than wide, or wider than tall. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Plain / Lined / Graph]* choice buttons. Tapping one of these lets you specify whether the new image will be all white, have light horizontal lines, or have both horizontal and vertical lines. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Preview]* showing a simple representation of the new image. Tapping this will create the image and start editing. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Create New]* [page] button to actually create the image and start editing. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description> To cancel this menu, tap above or below the menu.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/fit.svg">fit</link>
        <link href="/images/zoomIn.svg">zoomIn</link>
        <link href="/images/zoomOut.svg">zoomOut</link>
        <link href="/images/deleteFilled.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/camera.svg">camera</link>
        <link href="/images/pen.svg">draw</link>
        <link href="/images/menu.svg">menu</link>
        <link href="/images/page.svg">page</link>
        <link href="/images/album.svg">album</link>
        <link link="transform app ink">Ink Drawing Screen</link>
    </links>
</page>