<page>
    <shortlink>transform app editorlist</shortlink>
    <topic>List Editor</topic>
    <description>Used to select an option from a list of choices.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description><p>
        The List Editor displays a list of items from which to choose. Tapping on an item selects that item. Tapping again deselects
        the item. Double-tapping will either select or deselect as if it was a single tap; however, if it selects it also
        will advance to the next field.
      </p>
      <p>
        The List Editor has several different variations which are determined by the person who designed the form type.
      </p>
      <p>
        In some variations only one item may be selected at a time. In other variations any number of items may be selected.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Row-oriented List and Button Lists</title>
            <description><p>
        There are two main types of lists: Row-oriented Lists where items are mainly chosen on a separate editor and the items are
        listed vertically one per row, and Button Lists where items are listed horizontally as separate buttons and choosing
        may be performed directly on the form details.
      </p>
      <p>
        The determination of whether a given field is a Row-oriented List or a Button List is made by the form type designer.
      </p>
      <p>
        Button Lists also have an associated editor which has the same buttons listed horizontally. Normally you may set the field
        value directly on the form details without calling up the editor just by tapping on a button. However, if you are
        traversing through fields with editors using the [moveLeft] or [moveRight]  buttons or swiping across the editor body, you will encounter the editor form of button lists. You can go to the editor from
        the form details by pressing and holding on the buttons in the Button List for the field.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search</title>
            <description><p>
        Another aspect of the editor that varies is whether or not you may type in a search value. (This only applies to Row-oriented
        lists.) If searching is enabled, then an extra control bar will be shown above the list with a textbox in which to
        type text. Only rows that contain that text will be shown – all others will be hidden. The filtering of the
        list will occur immediately as you type each character. A match may be anywhere in the row's text – it need
        not be just the start (e.g., "al" matches both "Alabama" and "California").
      </p>
      <p>
        If, after typing into the textbox, you press the Return key on the keyboard, and the search has resulted in finding just
        one item, that item will be selected. If the search resulted in finding no items, and the field has been set by the
        designer to allow the addition of new items, then an item with that value will be added to the list and selected.
        In all cases, the keyboard will be dismissed.
      </p>
      <p>
        The control bar will include (grayed out if not applicable):
      </p></description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>A [clear] *[Clear]* button to clear text in the textbox without closing the on-screen keyboard.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>A [delete] *[Cancel]* button to clear the textbox and close the on-screen keyboard.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Either a [check] *[Confirm]* button or an [add] *[Add]* button. The Confirm button will select the row that was found. The Add button will add the typed value
          as a new item.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description><p>
        Note that list items may have optional display text that is displayed instead of the actual value being stored in the field.
        For example, the display text may be "Pennsylvania" but the value stored in the field may be "PA". When searching,
        the displayed value is searched. When determining whether to add a new item, the value being typed will be compared
        to the value for saving of existing items in the list. The new, added item will have that value for both the saving
        value and the displayed value. Searching is not case sensitive (e.g., "Pennsy" and "pennsy" will both match "Pennsylvania")
        but determining whether or not to add a value is case sensitive (e.g., "pa" does not match "PA").
      </p></description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/clear.svg">clear</link>
        <link href="/images/add.svg">add</link>
        <link href="/images/check.svg">check</link>
        <link href="/images/moveRight.svg">moveRight</link>
        <link href="/images/moveLeft.svg">moveLeft</link>
    </links>
</page>