<page>
    <shortlink>transform app ink</shortlink>
    <topic>Ink Drawing Screen</topic>
    <description>Used to annotate a photo or blank image.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p> The Ink Drawing Screen lets you write on an image with "ink" drawn on the screen with a finger or stylus. This can be used to annotate a photo or other image, or to put handwriting or drawings on a "blank" image created by the app for this purpose. </p>
                <p>When done, the result of the drawing on this screen (the original image plus the newly drawn lines) will be saved as a new image, replacing the original image, if any.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Zoomed and unzoomed writing</title>
            <description>
                <p>Writing with a finger, or even a stylus, on a smartphone screen does not give you the fine control that you are used to with something like a pencil on paper. You normally only have room for just a handful of words written with your finger unless you have small fingers and a lot of patience. Detailed markup on an image can also be very difficult. The Ink Drawing Screen, though, has an option to make it easy to create small, readable text or annotations. It can *[automatically shrink your writing]* and drawing so that you can comfortably write with larger letters and symbols yet end up with normally-sized ones placed exactly where you intended. This is done with "*[Zoomed Writing]*". </p>
                <p>The [zoomIn] and [zoomOut] buttons in the upper-right of the Ink Drawing Screen *[toggle]* between Zoomed and Unzoomed Writing. </p>
                <p>In *[Unzoomed Writing]* the entire image fills the screen and lines will appear wherever you draw with your finger. "Pinching" does not change the magnification. The screen has *[two parts]*: The image on which to write and an *[Ink Editing Button Bar]* with a button to set the "pen" color and thickness, a button to turn on an "eraser" to erase parts of the ink, and undo/redo buttons.</p>
                <p>In *[Zoomed Writing]* the screen usually has *[three parts]*: A small *[Full View]* of the entire image at the top, the *[Ink Editing Button Bar]* with a few additional buttons for navigation, and a *[Close-up View]* at the bottom showing just a magnified portion of the image on which to write.</p>
                <p>When you *[write]* with large letters in the *[Close-up View]*, those letters will be echoed much smaller on the Full View. This lets you "write big" but end up with text or annotations that are much smaller. </p>
                <p>Inside the Full View is a small, blue and gray rectangle called the *[Zoom Box]*. The Zoom Box indicates which part of the Full View is displayed in the Close-up View. *[Moving the Zoom Box changes what is shown in the Close-up View.]* You can move the Zoom Box by dragging it or by tapping elsewhere on the Full View. </p>
                <p>There are buttons in the Ink Editing Button Bar to move the Zoom Box left or right, or down to the start of the "next line" when tapped. You can also *[drag from those buttons]* to move further smoothly to the left, right, up or down. </p>
                <p>You can *[change the size of the Zoom Box]* to change the magnification shown in the Close-up View by using the [collapse] and [expand] buttons at the top of the screen. Making the Zoom Box bigger will show a larger amount of the image in the Close-up View and thereby shrink any new writing less. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Ink Editing Button Bar </title>
            <description>
                <p>These are the buttons that may appear on the Ink Editing Button Bar: </p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[left] *[Move Left button]*: Tapping this moves the Zoom Box to the left a fixed amount. Dragging starting on this button will move the Zoom Box smoothly as if you were dragging the content of the Close-up View directly. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[inkLine] *[Set Pen button]*: Tapping this brings up a menu for choosing the color and thickness of the ink that will be written. The top row sets the ink thickness. The last thickness item also makes the ink transparent like a highlighter. The next two rows set the color. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[eraser] *[Eraser button]*: Tapping this starts Ink Erasing. The next time you drag on the Close-up View your finger will erase ink until you take it off of the screen. Lines will be split if you erase through the middle. This operation is subject to undo/redo. </p>
                        <p>Only current ink may be erased. The image being annotated, and any ink previously added to it, are not erased. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[redo] [undo] *[Redo and Undo buttons]*: Tapping the Undo button will undo the last stroke of ink written or erasure. The Redo button lets you reverse an undo. Dragging on the buttons moves forward and backward through the undo/redo steps. </p>
                        <p>The number of steps of operation that are stored for undo/redo is limited to about 100 of the most recent steps. All undo/redo information is cleared when you exit editing through the Save or Cancel button at the top of the screen. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[return] *[Return button]*: Tapping this moves the Zoom Box to the start of the line and down a fixed amount. Dragging starting on this button will move the Zoom Box just up and down in fixed steps as if you were dragging the Zoom Box directly. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[right] *[Move Right button]*: Tapping this moves the Zoom Box to the right a fixed amount. Dragging starting on this button will move the Zoom Box smoothly as if you were dragging the content of the Close-up View directly.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Buttons at the top of the screen</title>
            <description>
                <p>These are the buttons at the top of the screen: </p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Save]*: The result of the drawing on this screen (the original image plus the newly drawn lines) will be saved as a new image, replacing the original image, if any, as the value of the form field. It also returns to the screen showing the full image without editing. This clears the undo/redo information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Cancel]*: Returns to the screen showing the full image without editing, but does not make any changes to the previous image, if any, in the form field. This clears the undo/redo information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[collapse] [expand] *[Zoom Box Shrink and Grow buttons]*: These buttons change the size of the Zoom Box to change the magnification shown in the Close-up View. Making the Zoom Box bigger will show a larger amount of the image in the Close-up View and thereby shrink any new writing less. Making the Zoom Box smaller will show a smaller amount of the image in the Close-up View and thereby shrink any new writing more. There are three different sizes available. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[zoomIn] [zoomOut] *[Switch to Unzoomed Writing and Switch to Zoomed Writing buttons]*: One of these buttons will be shown in the upper-right of the Ink Drawing Screen to toggle between Zoomed and Unzoomed Writing. In Unzoomed writing the entire image is available for writing while in Zoomed Writing only the part of the image that is enclosed by the Zoom Box is available for writing. </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Landscape Orientation</title>
            <description>
                <p>Smartphones are usually operated in a portrait (vertical) orientation. When operating with Zoomed Writing, and rotated into a landscape (horizontal) orientation, on most phones there isn't enough room to display a useful Full View. </p>
                <p>In this case, the Full View will be hidden and only the Ink Editing Button Bar and Close-up View will be shown. The Close-up View will still be zoomed in. Movement on the image may only be done using the navigation buttons on the button bar.</p>
                <p>This is especially useful for writing long strings of text because of the extra space horizontally. *[Moving by dragging left from the right [right] button]*, or tapping on the [return] Return button, make it possible to quickly write larger amounts of text than you would expect on such a small screen. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/fit.svg">zoomIn</link>
        <link href="/images/unzoom.svg">zoomOut</link>
        <link href="/images/collapse.svg">collapse</link>
        <link href="/images/expand.svg">expand</link>
        <link href="/images/moveLeft.svg">left</link>
        <link href="/images/inkLine.svg">inkLine</link>
        <link href="/images/eraser.svg">eraser</link>
        <link href="/images/redo.svg">redo</link>
        <link href="/images/undo.svg">undo</link>
        <link href="/images/return.svg">return</link>
        <link href="/images/moveRight.svg">right</link>
        <link href=""></link>
    </links>
</page>