<page>
    <shortlink>transform app editors</shortlink>
    <topic>Form Editors</topic>
    <description>Screens for entering different types of data.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <description><p>
        "Editors" is the term used for the screens that allow you to enter field data. For example, when a number field in the form
        contents is tapped an editor will be displayed with a keypad for entering the value for that field.
      </p>
      <p>
        There are many different editors with a variety of configurations, one of which is used for any given field. For example,
        there is an editor configuration for entering text on a single line which automatically advances to the editor for
        the next field when you tap the Return key on the keyboard, and there is an editor configuration for entering multiple
        lines of text which inserts a line break into the text when you tap the Return key on the keyboard.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Common characteristics</title>
            <description><p>
        There are common characteristics shared by all editors.
      </p>
      <p>The top of the screen on all editors displays a description for the field. If the description is too wide to fit on the screen, tap it to display a popup with more text.</p>
      <p>
        The left side of the top has a [check] button to
        *[confirm]* the value entered and return to the form details display. It also has a [delete] button to
        *[cancel]* the change of value and return to the form details display.
      </p>
      <p>
        The right side of the top has a [moveRight] button to confirm the value entered and advance to the editor for the next field. It also has a [moveLeft] button to confirm the value entered and advance to the editor for the previous field. If there are no next or previous field
        when advancing, the button will be treated as confirmation of the value and then the form details display will return.
      </p>
      <p>
        *[Swiping from right to left]* or left to right anywhere on the body of the editor below the top will also
        *[confirm and advance]* to the next or previous field.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Descriptions of editors</title>
            <description>The currently available editors are as follows:</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:.-->
            <!--order:
editorText
editorNumeric
editorList
editorDate
editorStopwatch
editorTimeNow
editorLocation
editorPhoto
editorScanner
editorSignature
editorAudio
-->
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/check.svg">check</link>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/moveRight.svg">moveRight</link>
        <link href="/images/moveLeft.svg">moveLeft</link>
    </links>
</page>