<page>
    <shortlink>Submit a Bug Report</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Submit a Bug Report</topic>
    <description>Instructions for submitting a bug report to Alpha Software.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Before you Send a Bug Report Checklist</title>
            <description>
                <p>Before submitting a bug report, you need to verify a few things first:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Check the documentation.]* It's possible the problem you're experiencing is expected behavior. An error message may be occuring due to an improperly formatted Javascript function or missing parameter. Review the documentation. Search the *[extlink:Alpha Anyhwere Documentation@www.alphasoftware.com/documentation]* to see if any information is avaliable for the behavior you are seeing.</p>
                        <p>The *[extlink:Alpha Anywhere Users Forum@http://www.alphasoftware.com/alphaforum/]* is also an excellent resource. Search the forum to see if anyone else is experiencing the same issue. If your searches come up empty, try posting a new thread on the forum.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[Test the Pre-Release Build.]* We are constantly improving Alpha Anywhere. Before you submit a bug report, you should verify the problem can be reproduced using the latest Pre-Release of Alpha Anywhere. Check the Pre-Release Notes to see if the issue you are experiencing is documented and fixed. If you do not see any fixes related to the issue you are experiencing, download and install the latest Pre-Relase of Alpha Anyhwere and test your application before proceeding futher.</p>
                        <p>To view the Pre-Release notes and install the Pre-Release build, follow the instructions below:</p>
                    </description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Launch Alpha Anywhere. Click on *[ui:View Release Notes]* in the *[ui:Help]*  menu to open the Release notes.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title></title>
                                <link>images/bugReport_preRelease1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the Release Notes, find the *[The 'Pre-Release' Build]* section and click on the link to open the pre-release page.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title></title>
                                <link>images/bugReport_preRelease2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Check the Pre-Release notes for the issue you are experiencing. If the issue is listed as fixed, downloading and installing the Pre-Release will fix your problem. If your issue is not listed, it doesn't necessarily mean it has not been fixed. Download the Pre-Release Build.</p>
                                <p>Select the full installer, *[a5v12_full_DL.exe]*, for Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When the download is complete, run the installer. You can install the pre-release version of Alpha Anywhere to a directory that is not the default destination folder. To do this, select a different installation directory by clicking the *[ui:Browse]* button on the *[ui:Destination Location]* page and typing the new destination folder name for the Destination Directory. Finish the installation.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Destination Location defines where Alpha Anywhere is installed</title>
                                <link>images/bugReport_preRelease3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>You can install multiple versions of Alpha Anywhere by changing the Destination Directory</title>
                                <link>images/bugReport_preRelease4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>You must type in the destination folder name. Selecting another folder may not change the installation directory.</note>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Once the Pre-Release is installed, test your component using the Pre-Release. Before testing, make a backup of your project. Alpha Anywhere components are not backwards compatible with older versions of Alpha Anywhere. The easiest way to make a backup is to copy your entire Alpha Anywhere project to another folder for safe keeping.</description>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you are able to unable to reproduce the issue in the Pre-Release, the issue is likely fixed. If problems still persist, create a reproducible test case to submit to Alpha Software.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Reproducible Test Case</title>
            <description>
                <p>If we can't reproduce your problem, we can't fix the bug. In order for us to understand the issue you're experiencing, you must send us a reproducible test case, complete with components and sample database, if required.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <title>Isolate the Problem and Create a Test Case</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>A complex component is difficult to diagnose. Your test case should contain the minimum amount of code to reproduce the issue. This can be accomplished by either removing all code and controls from your component that are unrelated to the problem or rebuilding the component from scratch, adding only the controls necessary to reproduce the issue.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title>Create a Database Backup</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If your component references tables in a database, you need to include a sample of the tables and data in your test case. We don't need a full backup of your entire SQL database, only the tables and views that your component uses.</p>
                        <p>If the issue you are experiencing happens with specific records in a database, submit those records as part of your test case.</p>
                        <p>See [How to Create a Database Backup] for information on how to create a SQL database backup. If you are using DBF tables, submit the DBF tables with your bug report.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <title>Create Detailed Steps to Reproduce the Issue</title>
                    <description>The steps to reproduce your issue should be as detailed as possible. *[Do not omit any steps.]* Create a step-by-step guide explaining how to recreate your issue. </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Sending a Bug Report</title>
            <description>
                <p>Once you have a simplified component that reproduces the issue, a backup of any SQL tables required to run your component, and a set of detailed steps to reproduce the issue, you are ready to send your bug report.</p>
                <p>In addition to the reproducible test case, we also need to know what version of Alpha Anywhere that produces the problem you are expriencing as well as the operating system you are running. This information is automatically generated for you using the Send a Bug Report feature in Alpha Anywhere. Send a Bug Report will also give you the email address to send the report.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In Alpha Anywhere, open the *[ui:Sending a Bug Report]* dialog by clicking *[ui:Send a Bug Report]* under the *[ui:Help]* menu.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Sending a bug report from the Alpha Anywhere Help Menu</title>
                        <link>images/bugReport_send1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>If you use a browser-based email client, such as Gmail, to send email, check the *[ui:Use browser based e-mail account]*. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/bugReport_send2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you are using a browser-based email client, a popup containing the email address, subject, and body will appear. Copy this information to the clipboard and paste it into your email client.</p>
                        <p>If you are using a built-in email client, such as Thunderbird or Outlook, your email client should open with the to, subject, and email body pre-populated with the appropriate information.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/bugReport_send3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Attach the reproducible test case to the email. If you are sending multiple files, combine them into a single zipped archive.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the email body, describe the problem and the behavior you expect to see. Include detailed, step-by-step instructions for reproducing the problem.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Send the email.</description>
                    <note>If zipped archive too large to send via email, click the *[ui:Instructions on how to create a dump file]* link in the *[ui:Sending a Bug Report]* dialog. At the end of the instructions on how to create a dump file, you will find instructions on how to FTP your reproducible test case to us.</note>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/HowTo/Export Tables from a Database.xml">How to Create a Database Backup</link>
    </links>
</page>