<page>
    <shortlink>Submit a Bug Report For a Web Project Report</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Submit a Bug Report for a Report, Letter, Layout, or Label</topic>
    <description>When you report a bug to Alpha Software, a test case is required. For issues with Reports, both the Project Report file and data the report is based on need to be submitted. The *[ui:Create Bug Report Files...]* tool makes it easy to create a test case to submit with a bug report about an issue you're experiencing with a Project Report.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Bug Report Zip File for a Report</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Create Bug Report Files...]* tool can be used to easily package up the information needed by the Alpha Software team when reporting a bug with a Report. In most cases, the default settings will generate the information needed.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the Web Projects Control Panel, right-click the Report to open the Context Menu.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Under the *[ui:DataSource]* menu, select *[ui:Create Bug Report Files...]*</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/createreportbug_1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select a *[ui:Location]* to save the .zip file.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Dialog to create a bug report zip file</title>
                        <link>images/createreportbug_2.PNG</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If the issue with your report is related to the data, check *[ui:Include Sample Tables]*. Otherwise, you can leave this option unchecked.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>Generated sample tables can be very large if the tables your report is based on have a lot of records.</p>
                    </note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Finally, click *[ui:Create]* to generate the .zip file.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>After the .zip file is created, send the .zip file along with an explanation of the issue you're experiencing to bugs@alphasoftware.com.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/index?search=submit%20a%20bug%20report">How to Submit a Bug Report</ref>
    </see>
</page>
