<page>
    <topic>OpenSSL and TLS/SSL protocols used by Alpha Anywhere</topic>
    <description>OpenSSL and TLS/SSL protocols supported by current and past versions of the Alpha Anywhere web server products.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Current Versions of Alpha Anywhere</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Alpha Anywhere and Alpha Anywhere Classic Application Server</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Use OpenSSL 1.0.2</p>
                        <p>OpenSSL will support 1.0.2 until December 31, 2019. Alpha Software provides updates to Alpha Anywhere subscribers whenever OpenSSL makes a new release. Currently, Alpha Software is shipping OpenSSL 1.0.2h (accurate as of 8/1/2016).</p>
                        <p>The exact protocols and ciphers used can be precisely configured using an OpenSSL cipher list. The following cipher list is the default cipher list used (updated 8/1/2016) and results in an A- rating using the Qualsys SSL Server test at *[extlink:https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/]* (tested 8/1/2016)</p>
                        <p><![CDATA[ECDHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-GCM-SHA384:DHE-RSA-AES128-GCM-SHA256:DHE-DSS-AES128-GCM-SHA256:kEDH+AESGCM:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA256:ECDHE-RSA-AES128-SHA:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES128-SHA:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-AES256-SHA:ECDHE-ECDSA-AES256-SHA:DHE-RSA-AES128-SHA256:DHE-RSA-AES128-SHA:DHE-DSS-AES128-SHA256:DHE-RSA-AES256-SHA256:DHE-DSS-AES256-SHA:DHE-RSA-AES256-SHA:AES128-GCM-SHA256:AES256-GCM-SHA384:ECDHE-RSA-RC4-SHA:ECDHE-ECDSA-RC4-SHA:AES128:AES256:HIGH:!aNULL:!eNULL:!EXPORT:!DES:!3DES:!MD5:!PSK]]></p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS does not use OpenSSL for serving TLS/SSL-secured applications, and instead leverages the TLS/SSL support built-in to the Windows operating system. Protocol and cipher support varies based on the operating system version, but does not include TLS 1.1 and 1.2 before Windows 2008 R2. (*[extlink:https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/kaushal/2011/10/02/support-for-ssltls-protocols-on-windows/]*)</p>
                        <p>Window's TLS/SSL settings are all configured through registry entries and Group Policy. IIS Crypto from Nartac Software (*[extlink:https://www.nartac.com/Products/IISCrypto]*) is a very useful third-party product for configuring Windows settings that control protocols and ciphers with a graphical interface.</p>
                        <p>OpenSSL is still used for client functionality within the Alpha Five Application Server for IIS, such as secure database drivers and outbound HTTP access using the [http_* Xbasic functions].</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Older Versions of Alpha Anywhere</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Alpha Five V11 and Alpha Five Application Server V11</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Use OpenSSL 1.0.1</p>
                        <p>OpenSSL will end support for 1.0.1 on December 31, 2016. No further releases of 1.0.1 will be made after that date. Security fixes only will be applied to 1.0.1 until then. Additionally, Alpha Software is no longer making OpenSSL updates available for Alpha Five v11 and the Alpha Five Application Server v11 as these are no longer supported by Alpha Software. Alpha Software Customers are strongly encouraged to upgrade to Alpha Anywhere before December 31, 2016.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Alpha Five v10 and prior, and Alpha Five Application Server v10 and prior</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Use OpenSSL 0.9.8</p>
                        <p>OpenSSL ended support for the 0.9.8 release on December 31, 2015. This means that no security issues have been addressed since that time, and will not be addressed by OpenSSL. As such, no SSL sites using these older releases can be considered secure. Customers are strongly encouraged to upgrade to Alpha Anywhere at the earliest time possible.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=http functions">http_* Xbasic functions</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=http functions">HTTP Functions</ref>
        <ref href="https://www.openssl.org/">OpenSSL</ref>
        <ref href="https://www.openssl.org/policies/releasestrat.html">OpenSSL Release Strategy</ref>
        <ref href="https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/">QualSys SSL Labs SSL Server Test</ref>
        <ref href="https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/dn786418(v=ws.11).aspx">Windows TLS/SSL Settings</ref>
        <ref href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/kaushal/2011/10/02/support-for-ssltls-protocols-on-windows/">Support for SSL/TLS protocols on Windows</ref>
        <ref href="https://www.nartac.com/Products/IISCrypto">IIS Crypto from Nartac Software</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>application server,ssl,tls/ssl,openssl,encryption standards,ssl version,ciphers,IIS</terms>
</page>