<page>
	<topic>Define an AlphaDAO SQL Query</topic>
	<groups>
		<group background="true">
			<sections>
				<section>
					<description>This procedure is part of the Grid Builder procedure for building a component. You can click on the Create a new grid component button at the top of the Web Projects Control Panel (between the 'New' and 'Add File' buttons).</description>
					<figure><link>images/Grid_Button.png</link></figure>
				</section>
						<section>
					<description>This will bring you to the Select Grid Component Template Dialog. Here you have the option of working with a blank grid component or choosing from a list of pre-existing templates; to construct a grid component. Choose what you wish to work with and click OK. This will bring you to the Grid Builder Dialog. Web publishing applications only.</description>
					
				</section>
			</sections>
			
		</group>
		<group>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<title>Establishing the Connection</title>
					
					<steps>
						<step>
							<description>Select Grid > Query (AlphaDAO).</description>	
						</step>
						
						<step>
							<description>Select the Connection type. The options are:</description>	
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>"Used Named Connection String"</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>"Specify Connection String"</description>
									<figure><link>images/Query AlphaDAO.png</link></figure>
									
								</case>
								
							</cases>
			
						</step>
						<step>
							<description>If you selected "Used Named Connection String" in step 1.
</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Optionally, select a saved connection from the Connection Name list.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Optionally, click Add/Edit Saved Connections to display the Connections dialog.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Click Connect. If the Grid Builder was able to open the database, additional fields will appear on the dialog box.
</description>
								</case>
							</cases>
							
						</step>
						
						<step>
							<description>If you selected "Specify Connection String" in step 1.
</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Optionally, click '...' and enter the connection string, then click OK to return to the Grid Builder.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Optionally, click Build.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Enter the parameters necessary to connect to your database.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Click Test Connection.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>If the connection succeeded, click OK to continue.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Click Connect. If the Grid Builder was able to open the database, additional fields will appear on the dialog box.
</description>
								</case>
								
								
							</cases>
							
						</step>
						
						
					</steps>
					
					
					
				</section>
				
<section>
	<title>Retrieving Your Data From a Table or View</title>
	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select how to retrieve data. The options are:
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Table or View</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>SQL Select Statement</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you selected "Table or View", click the 'down arrow' icon to select a table or view from the Table/View list.
</description>
<note>A table alias can make your grid portable, by separating it from direct reference to a table name. as long as a table has the same structure and the same alias, it can use a grid originally built for another table.</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, enter an alias for the table into the Table/View alias field. If you do not enter an alias, it will default to the name of the table.
</description>		
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Define Arguments to display the Define Arguments dialog. You use arguments to provide run-time values for filter and order expressions.
</description>		
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, specify a filter expression in the Filter field that selects records from the table. Click '...' to display the Specify Filter dialog. Refer to Specifying a Filter Expression.
</description>		
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, specify a ordering expression in the Order by field that sequences selected records. Click '...' to display the Specify Order dialog. Refer to Specifying an Order Expression.</description>		
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Read only to prevent user updates. If you are in the process of creating a grid, continue with Selecting the Fields to Display.
</description>		
		</step>
		
		<step>
			<description>Click Select Primary Key(s) to display the Specify Primary Keys dialog. Select the field(s) that uniquely identify each record and click OK.
</description>		
		</step>
	</steps>
	
</section>				
<section>
	<title>Retrieving Your Data with a SQL Statement
</title>
	<description>If you want to retrieve your data with a "SQL Select Statement":
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select SQL Select Statement.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Edit SQL to display the SQL Builder to define the table(s) and fields that you want to work with. Continue with SQL Builder.
</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
	
	
</section>				
				
				
				
				
			</sections>
<see>
	<ref>Selecting the Fields to Display</ref>
</see>			
		</group>
		
	</groups>
	
</page>