<page>
	<topic>SQL Command Window</topic>
	<groups>
			<group>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<description>The SQL Command Window provides a mechanism for testing SQL statements. There are several ways to open the SQL Command Window: </description>
				</section>
				
			</sections>
			
		</group>
		
		
		
		<group background="true">
			<sections>
				<section>
					<steps>
						<step>
							<description>From the Control Panel, select Tools > External Databases > SQL Command Window.</description>	
						</step>
						<step>
							<description>From the Control Panel, select Tools > External Databases > Database Explorer, select a back-end database listing, right click, and select Open SQ Command Window.</description>	
						</step>
						<step>
							<description>From the Web Projects Control Panel, select Tools > SQL Command Window.</description>	
						</step>
						
						
					</steps>
				</section>
				
			</sections>
			
		</group>
		
		
		<group>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<title>Open SQL Command Window from Database Explorer
</title>
					<figure><link>images/Database Explorer.png</link></figure>
				</section>
				
				<section>
					<title>SQL Command Window
</title>
					<figure><link>images/SQR_SQL_Command_Window.png</link></figure>
				</section>
				<section>
				
<section>
	<description>The SQL Command Window requires that you have defined one or more named connection strings. </description>
	<figure><link>images/SQR_SQL_Command_Toolbar.png</link></figure>
	
</section>				
			<section>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select a named connection string from the Connection list.
</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select the SQL Type you wish to use. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Portable" - use the multi-database Portable SQL dialect
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Native" - use the dialect specific to a database product
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter SQL in the SQL Command window.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you need to insert a table or column name into a SQL statement:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click Insert... to display the Database Explorer.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Select the item and click Insert.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Click the 'lightning' icon Execute SQL to run the SQL statement.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>If the statement was a SELECT statement, you will see a sample of records in the Result window.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>If the statement was an INPUT, DELETE, or UPDATE statement, you will see the number of affected rows reported in the Result window.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>If you executed another type of SQL command, the Result window will show a success or failure message.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>If the statement could not be processed by the back-end database (for example, because of invalid SQL syntax), you will see an error message in the Result window.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>

	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>You may revert to previous versions of your SQL statement:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click SQL History to display the SQL History dialog.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Select a previous statement (from this session).
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click Select.
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click the 'x window' icon shown below to clear the SQL Command window.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Clear_All_Button.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click to display the Connections dialog, where you can edit or create connection strings.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>				
				
				
				
			</section>	
				
				
				
				
				
			</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>SQL Native Syntax Dialog Box</ref>
	</see>		
		</group>
		
		
		
		
	</groups>
	
	
</page>