<page>
    <shortlink>ux Creating a Spin List using Static Data</shortlink>
    <topic>Creating a Spin List using Static Data</topic>
    <description>A Spin List control can be based on Static data or a Data Series. When a Spin List control is populated with static data, the values are set at design time in the UX Builder.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Spin List Control with Static Data</title>
            <description>
                <p>The easiest way to specify values in a spin list control is using Static Data. Static spin list data is defined at design time.</p>
                <p>To specify the data in the Spin List control, click the [...] smart field for the *[ui:Static data]* Spin List Property to open the "Spin List - Static Choices" dialog.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/static1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Define the list of choices in the *[ui:Spin List - Static Choices]* dialog with each option listed on its own line. An optional stored value can be specified separately from the text shown in the Spin List control. To specify a stored value that is different from the displayed value, use this format:</description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[DisplayValue|StoredValue]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>For example, the image below shows a list of months.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/static2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description> If you wanted to store the month as a number starting with January = 1, you could define the list of static choices as follows:</description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[January|1
February|2
March|3
April|4
May|5
June|6
July|7
August|8
September|9
October|10
November|11
December|12]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The buttons along the bottom of the *[ui:Static List - Static Choices]* dialog can be used to sort the list, insert a predefined List of choices, or save the list of choices. You can also manage saved lists by clicking the *[ui:Manage Lists]* button.</p>
                <p>Saved lists can not only be used to populate Spin Lists, they can also be used to populate Checkboxes, RadioButtons, Dropdownboxes, and the list of options for TextBox controls configured to include an Edit-Combo or Auto-Suggest lookup.</p>
             </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/staticTools.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Once the static choices are defined, the Spin List will display the options in the order defined in the *[ui:Static List - Static Choices]* dialog.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/static3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
    
    <see>
        <ref link="ux Creating a Spin List using Data Series">Creating a Spin List using Data Series</ref>
    </see>
    
</page>