<page>
	<topic>Send an Email Message</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<title>Overview</title>
<description>The Send an Email Message action allows the user to send email using either the built-in Alpha Anywhere email client, or the user's default email client (e.g. Eudora, Outlook etc.). This is an extremely versatile function that lets you send an email message that includes data from the current record.</description>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Procedure</title>
<steps>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select the email client you wish to use. The options are:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client" </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Default email client (e.g. Eudora, Outlook, etc.)" </description>
			</case>
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check the Load message header check box. This causes three fields to appear.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Template source field select the library file that contains the template.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Prompt for template when? list, select either:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Specify template name now" </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Prompt for template name at run time" </description>
			</case>
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>If you selected ""Specify template name now", select the template from the Template name field. You may click the 'xy' button to launch the Expression Builder to define the template with an expression.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, if you did not check the Load message header check box, enter a character string or an expression that evaluates to a character string in the Subject field.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter one or more email address(es) or an expression that evaluates to one or more email address(es) in the Send to field.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter email address(es) into the CC and Bcc fields.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Attachments to display the Select Files dialog box or enter an expression to select attachments.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check the Put attachments into a Zip file? check box. If you select multiple files to attach, Alpha Anywhere automatically zips the files for you.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check the Load message body from a saved email template check box. If you checked it, continue with step 13. Otherwise, continue with step 17.</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally check the Use same template as for message header check box. If you did not check the Use same template as for message header check box, continue with step 14. Otherwise, continue with step 17.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select the library that contains the template from the Template source field.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Prompt for template when? list, select either:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Specify template name now" </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Prompt for template name at run time" </description>
			</case>
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>If you selected ""Specify template name now", select the template from the Template name field. You may click the x-y button to launch the Expression Builder to define the template with an expression.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter a text message in the Message window, or use the Expression Builder. The window contents appear as the default message in the email. Unless you specify that the email should not open for the user, the user will be able to edit this message at run-time.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, select the message type. The options are:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"HTML"</description>
			</case>
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>If you choose to use the Alpha Anywhere email client in step 1, you have the option to further specify the behavior of the action. You can select the type of interaction that results from the user initiating the action. The following options are available:</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"Open Alpha Anywhere email client as a modal dialog box" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Open Alpha Anywhere email client as a modeless dialog box" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Don't open the Alpha Anywhere email client - just send message then display confirmation" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Don't open the Alpha Anywhere email client - just send message without confirmation dialog" </description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Choosing not to display the Alpha Anywhere email client means that the user can't edit the message before it's sent, so choose the option that best corresponds with the action's needs.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Finish.</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>EMAIL_CLIENT()</ref>
	<ref>Email Client</ref>
	<ref>Inserting Commands in Email</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>