<page>
	<topic>Send Selected Files</topic>
<description>The Send Selected Files action lets you select files to send by email as attachments. You can specify specific files in the Genie, or prompt the user at run-time. 
 Send Selected Files options.</description>	
<sections>
	
<section>
	<title>Procedure</title>
<steps>
<step>
	<description>In the first list box select either:</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"Prompt for file names at runtime". Allows the user to specify the files to send using the Select Attachments Dialog Box. </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Specify the file names now". Allows you to specify the files to send using the Select Attachments Dialog Box. </description>
		</case>
	</cases>
</step>	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter the message subject into the Subject field. You can also use the Expression Builder to create an expression that generates one or more email addresses.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter the recipient's email address or a comma delimited list of email addresses. You can also use the Expression Builder to create an expression that generates one or more email addresses.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, fill in the CC and Bcc fields. Email addresses in the CC field will receive a copy of the email. Their addresses will appear in the email header. Recipients in the Bcc field will also receive a copy, but their addresses will not appear in the header. You can also use the Expression Builder to create an expression that generates one or more email addresses.</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>In the Send using field select either:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client" </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Default email client (e.g. Eudora, Outlook, etc.)" </description>
			</case>
		</cases>
		<note>If you select "Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client", the user has the opportunity to make edits before sending the. Otherwise, the email is sent automatically without further user interaction.</note>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>If you selected "Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client", you have the option to further specify the behavior of the action. You can select the type of interaction that results from the user initiating the action.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"Open Alpha Anywhere email client as a modal dialog box" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Open Alpha Anywhere email client as a modeless dialog box" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Don't open the Alpha Anywhere email client - just send message then display confirmation" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Don't open the Alpha Anywhere email client - just send message without confirmation dialog" </description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
	<note>If you selected "Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client", the user has the opportunity to make edits before sending the. Otherwise, the email is sent automatically without further user interaction.</note>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Finish.</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>
	
</section>		
	
</sections>	
	<see>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=EMAIL_CLIENT Function">EMAIL_CLIENT()</ref>		
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Email Client">Email Client</ref>		
<ref>Inserting Commands in Email</ref>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Receive an Email Message">Receive an Email Message</ref>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Integrated Email HTML Editor">Email HTML Editor</ref>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Emailing an HTML Report">Emailing an HTML Report</ref>
	
	</see>
</page>