<page>
    <shortlink>how to mark records deleted without deleting them</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Mark Records Deleted Without Physically Deleting Them</topic>
    <description>In some applications, you may want to allow users to mark records as 'deleted' without physically deleting the record from the database. this can be done using a logical field to flag a record as deleted.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Records can be "logically" deleted in a table by using a logical or bit field to track whether or not a record has been deleted. Using JavaScript, you can mark a record as 'deleted' by setting the value of the isDeleted field in the record to true. For example, the code below sets the deleted state for a row to *[js:true]*. The delete state is tracked by the field called "isDeleted":</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{grid.object}.setValue('G','ISDELETED',rowNum,true);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You can take this a step further and include the ability to "undelete" a record. This is done by first checking if the record has been deleted and then setting the value of the isDeleted field to the appropriate value:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[function toggleDelete(rowNum) {
    var isDel = {grid.object}.getValue('G','ISDELETED',rowNum);
    if (isDel) {
        {grid.object}.setValue('G','ISDELETED',false);
    } else {
        {grid.object}.setValue('G','ISDELETED',true);
    }
}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The JavaScript method defined above can be called from the click event for a button in the same row as the record delete or undelete a record:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[toggleDelete({grid.rowNumber});]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For additional information and an explanation of how to add the "isDeleted" field to your database records, watch the video below:</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Marking Records as 'Deleted' without Physically Deleting Them</title>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/2pMz1p48JdoDVAWuu5CTGs?</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>