<page build="8000">
    <shortlink>cordovacli filetransfer dependency error</shortlink>
    <topic>Cordova CLI Build fails with Unable to Resolve Dependency Error for File Transfer plugin</topic>
    <description>
        <p>On build 8000 of Alpha Anywhere, an error can occur when doing a Cordova CLI build for Android that includes the File Transfer plugin when using Cordova Android 10.x.x </p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Version 1.5.1 of the cordova-file-transfer-plugin hosted on NPM is not compatible with Cordova Android 10.x.x. Cordova Android 10.x.x is the version installed with Cordova CLI 11.x.x. The cordova-file-transfer-plugin hosted on NPM is the version downloaded in Alpha Anywhere build 8000. To work around this issue, you can manually include a version of the cordova-file-transfer-plugin hosted on GitHub that contains a fix for the issue.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <important>
                <p>*[This article applies to Alpha Anywhere build 8000.]* Newer releases of Alpha Anywhere use a version of the File Transfer plugin that has been updated to work with Cordova Android 10.x.x. It's strongly recommended that you upgrade to a newer release of Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <important>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere build 8000 is compatible with Cordova CLI 10.x.x, which installs Cordova Android 9.x.x. If you wish to use Cordova Android 10.x.x, which includes Android API Level 30 support, it's best to upgrade to a newer version of Alpha Anywhere. Alpha Anywhere build 8099 and newer include support for Cordova CLI 11.x.x, which installs Cordova Android 10.x.x. See [Cordova CLI Builder] for more information.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open "Manage My Cordova Plugins".</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Cordova Project Settings</title>
                        <alt>Cordova Project Settings</alt>
                        <link>images/managePlugins.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click New to add a new plugin.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>User Defined Corodva 3rd Party Plugins</title>
                        <alt>User Defined Corodva 3rd Party Plugins</alt>
                        <link>images/addPlugin.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Enter the following information and save the plugin.</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Value</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Plugin name</name>
                                    <description>cordova-plugin-file-transfer</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Plugin resource/url</name>
                                    <description>https://github.com/remoorejr/cordova-plugin-file-transfer</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Plugin source</name>
                                    <description>GIT</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Plugin version</name>
                                    <description>1.5.2</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Add a new plugin</title>
                        <alt>Add a new plugin</alt>
                        <link>images/newPlugin.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Close the Manage My Cordova Plugins dialog to return to the Cordova Builder.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>In the *[ui:Required Core Plugins]* section, uncheck *[ui:File Transfer]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Uncheck File Transfer</title>
                        <alt>Uncheck File Transfer</alt>
                        <link>images/uncheckFileTransfer.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>In the *[ui:Required User Included Third Party Cordova Plugins]* section, check *[ui:cordova-plugin-file-transfer]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Include new cordova-file-transfer-plugin</title>
                        <alt>Include new cordova-file-transfer-plugin</alt>
                        <link>images/checkNewPlugin.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, click *[ui:Save &amp; Launch Cordova CLI Builder]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Verify the correct file transfer plugin is included and that only one plugin is listed in the config.xml. Click *[ui:View / Edit Config.xml File]*</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Cordova CLI Project Build Properties dialog</title>
                        <alt>Cordova CLI Project Build Properties dialog</alt>
                        <link>images/verify1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Scroll to the bottom of the config.xml file and look for the specification for the file transfer plugin. Verify the plugin name, spec (URL), source, and version match. Verify no other entries exist in the config.xml.</p>
                        <p>If you find another entry for the cordova-plugin-file-transfer in the config.xml with a different version, delete the entry from the file. Verify only the cordova-plugin-file-transfer plugin you created is listed. Click *[ui:Save]* to save any modifications and build you app.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Verify plugin is included</title>
                        <alt>Verify plugin is included</alt>
                        <link>images/verifyPlugin.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="phonegap%20cli%20builder">Cordova CLI Builder</link>
    </links>
</page>