<page>
    <shortlink>transform central home</shortlink>
    <topic>TransForm Central Home</topic>
    <description>The Home Tab in TransForm Central is where you manage your TransForm account, including inviting and managing users, configuring your password and account, and generating a TransForm API Key.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/transformCentralHome.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>My Information</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Display name</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Your display name is shown in the header when you are logged into TransForm Central.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/header3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>To change your display name, enter the new name in the *[ui:Display name]* text box and click *[ui:OK]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/changeDisplayName.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Change Password</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Use the *[ui:Change Password]* option to change your TransForm password.</p>
                        <p>To change your password, enter the new password in the *[ui:New password]* and *[ui:Confirm password]* text boxes and click *[ui:Submit]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/changePassword.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>User Preferences</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Users can specify their preferred method of receiving notifications by changing their preferences in TransForm Central.</p>
                        <p>To configure your User Preferences:</p>
                    </description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Log into TransForm Central.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>On the Home tab, click "Change Preferences" under the My Information section.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Configure your notification preferences. The options available are described below</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>/images/tfUserPreferences.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Setting</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Send notification when a form is dispatched to you</name>
                                    <description>Enable or disable notifications.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Send notification via e-mail</name>
                                    <description>Enable or disable email notifications. If enabled, your TransForm User Name will be used as the email.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Send notification via SMS</name>
                                    <description>Enable or disable SMS (text) notifications. If enabled, you also need to specify the phone number where notifications will be sent.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Mobile phone number</name>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>The number to send the SMS message. The number must begin with a + and contain only numbers in the following format. Replace *[[Country Code]]* and *[[Phone_Number]]* with the country code and phone number for the mobile device:</p>
                                        <p>
                                            <example><![CDATA[+[Country Code][Phone Number]]]></example>
                                        </p>
                                        <p>The example below shows how to specify the USA phone number (617) 555-1234:</p>
                                        <p>
                                            <example><![CDATA[+16175551234]]></example>
                                        </p>
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Account Settings</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>License keys</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[ui:License keys]* is where you enter your TransForm license(s) to activate The number of authorized users for a TransForm account is determined by the license key(s) entered in the *[ui:License keys]* box. If no licenses are provided, your account will run in Trial mode until the trial period expires.</p>
                        <p>Multiple licenses can be entered for a single TransForm account. Licenses are cumulative. This means, if you enter a 5 user license key and a 10 user license key for a single TransForm account, up to 15 users can log in to the account. If you unsure how many users are authorized for you licenses, *[ui:Show License Information]* can be used to find out how many users are authorized and when the license expires.</p>
                        <p>To activate one or more licenses for a TransForm account, specify each license on a separate line and click *[ui:Save]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/accountLicenseKeys.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Contact the Alpha Software sales team] if you have questions about existing licenses or to purchase additional TransForm license keys.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Account Name</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Account Display Name is the name of your TransForm account. When you are logged into TransForm Central, the Account Display Name is shown in parentheses at the top of the page next to your Display Name.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/header2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Account Display Name is also shown when you log in to TranForm. If you are a member of multiple TransForm accounts, you will be prompted to select the TransForm account you wish to log into after entering your username and password in TransForm Central or the TransForm mobile application.</p>
                        <p>To change your Account Display Name,  enter the new name in the *[ui:TransForm account display name]* text box and click *[ui:OK]*. Choose an Account Display Name that is easy for you to remember or recognize as your account (for example, the name of your company or simply "Sarah's Account"):</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/changeAccountName.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Create New Account</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you do not have a TransForm account or wish to create another one, *[ui:Create New Account]* can be used to create another TransForm account associated with your user name.</p>
                        <p>A TransForm Account is not required to use Alpha TransForm. You must, however, be a member of an existing TransForm account or have your own TransForm account to use Alpha TransForm.</p>
                        <p>If you are a member of more than one TransForm Account, a list of accounts will be shown when you log in to TransForm Central or the TranForm mobile application. The Account Name is what will be shown in the list.</p>
                        <p>To create a new TransForm account, enter the "Account name" in the text box provided and click *[ui:OK]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/createTransFormAccount.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>When you click *[ui:OK]*, TransForm Central will create a new account with the specified Account Name and log you into the new account.</p>
                        <p>You can also use the *[ui:Don't have a username/password?]* link on the TransForm Central login screen to create a new TransForm account.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/login2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Account Notifications</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Notify your users when a form is dispatched with Notifications. Notifications can be sent via email, text message, or both. A Twilio, SparkPost, or SendGrid account is required in order to send notifications. If you do not have an existing account, you can sign-up for a Trial or purchase an account from the desired service:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>Twilio: *[extlink:https://www.twilio.com]*</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>SparkPost: *[extlink:https://www.sparkpost.com]*</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>SendGrid: *[extlink:https://sendgrid.com]*</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>Notifications for a TransForm account are configured in the Account Preferences. To setup Notifications:</p>
                    </description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Log into TransForm Central.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>On the Home tab, click "Change Preferences" in the Account Settings section.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Configure Notifications for your account. Details about each option are described below.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>/images/tfAccountPreferences.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Setting</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Twilio Account SID</name>
                                    <description>The Account SID for your Twilio SMS project.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Twilio Authorization Code</name>
                                    <description>The Auth Token for your Twilio SMS project.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Twilio Phone Number</name>
                                    <description>The Phone Number for your Twilio SMS project.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>SMS Message Template</name>
                                    <description>The template used to send the SMS message.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>SparkPost/SendGrid API Key</name>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>Your SparkPost or SendGrid API key. If you specify an API key from SendGrid, you must prefix the key with "sendgrid:". EG:</p>
                                        <p>
                                            <example><![CDATA[sendgrid:SG.Y3G9_NFwQm6IOtzqaKg.pHepuLrTdHdWxW24M02cAJQ5-nkX2nLCXmW4]]></example>
                                        </p>
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Send from</name>
                                    <description>The email address to include in the "From" field.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Email subject</name>
                                    <description>The email subject.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Email message template</name>
                                    <description>The template used to send an email notification. The message can use the [metadata.formid] placeholder to include the Form ID in the message.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>User Management</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Add Users to Account</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Users can be added to your TransForm account using *[ui:Add Users]*. When added, if a user does not have an existing TransForm account, they will be sent an email invitation inviting them to create a TransForm User Account.</p>
                        <p>To add a user, enter their email address in the text area. Each email address must be specified on a separate line. Once you have entered the list of users to add, click the *[ui:Add Users]* button.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>Users who do not yet have TransForm User Accounts will be sent an email invitation to create their own TransForm User Accounts.</p>
                    </note>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/addUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Delete / Reorder Users</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Users can be deleted from your TransForm account using *[ui:Delete/Reorder Users]*. To delete a user, set the Select mode to *[ui:Delete Users]*. Then, select the user to delete and click the *[ui:Delete Users]* button below the user box. Use the Shift or Ctrl keys to select multiple users to delete from the account.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/deleteReorderUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The order in which users are listed in the *[ui:Delete/Reorder Users]* text area is important. If you are using a demo account only the first five users listed below will be able to login. If you have a paid TransForm account, your account will authorize a certain number of TransForm users. If, for example, your TransForm account authorizes up to 5 users, then only the first five users listed will be able to login. You may want to re-order the list of users so that a particular user falls within the first five users shown in the list.</p>
                        <p>To reorder users, set the Select mode to *[ui:Re-order Users]*. Then, select the move icon next to the user you wish to move and click-and-drag the user to the new position. When you are satisfied with the order, click the *[ui:Save List Order]* button below the list of users to save your changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/reorderUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Manage User Roles</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Access to your TransForm account is controlled using Roles. Users can be assigned one or more roles using *[ui:Manage User Roles]*. Alpha TransForm includes a set of pre-defined roles, listed below. You can modify roles on the [Permissions] tab.</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Role</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>User</name>
                            <description>Person who fills in forms on a mobile device.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Account Administrator</name>
                            <description>Controls the TransForm account.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Form Designer</name>
                            <description>Creates and updates form type definitions.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Management Console</name>
                            <description>Uses Management Console to examine and process forms.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Supervisor</name>
                            <description>Processes forms needing approval.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>To modify the roles for a user, select a user in the User list, then select the roles for that user in the Available Roles list. Use Ctrl+Click to select multiple roles. After you have selected the roles for the user, click the *[ui:Set Roles]* button to save your changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/manageUserRoles.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Invite Users (advanced)</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can invite other users to join your TransForm account using *[ui:Invite Users (advanced)]*. Invite users is different from adding users in that an invited users is not added to your account until they have accepted the invitation or if you explicitly set their password and role(s).</p>
                        <p>Invited users are assigned the "User" role if no role is specified, allowing them to fill in TransForm forms. If an invited user does not yet have a TransForm User Account, they will be able to sign-up for a TransForm User Account. If the invited user already has a TransForm User Account, they will be added as a member of your TransForm Account.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/inviteUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>To invite users, enter their email addresses - one per line - in the text box. For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[fred.smith@company.com
molly.richter@company.com]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Setting the Display Name for Invited Users</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>When the user accepts the invitation, they will be added to your TransForm account. Their display name will be the email address as it as written in the invite text box.</p>
                                <p>If desired, you can specify the display name for a user when they are invited. To include the display name, use the following format:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[Display name (email address)]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>For example:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[Fred Smith (fred.smith@company.com)
Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Assigning Roles to Invited Users</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>By default, all users are assigned the "User" role when they accept an invitation to join a TransFrom account. You can optionally specify the user roles to assign a user when they accept the invitation to your TransForm account. Roles are defined as a pipe followed by a comma delimited list of user roles.</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[|role1,role2,role3]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>You can define as many roles as you want for a user. The example below assigns roles to 2 users: fred.smith@company.com will be assigned the "user" and "FormDesigner" roles while molly.richter@company.com will be assigned the "user", "AccountAdmin", and "ManagementConsole" roles. TransForm will assign users the "user" role if no role is specified.</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[fred.smith@company.com|user,FormDesigner
Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)|user,AccountAdmin,ManagementConsole
dave.smith@company.com
janice.reed@company.com]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>When you specify a role, you must use the Role ID. Be aware that *[Role IDs are case-sensitive.]* If the specified role cannot be found or does not exactly match, Alpha TransForm will default to assigning the user to the "user" role.</p>
                                <p>The avaiable roles and their corresponding Rold IDs can be found on the [Permissions] tab in the "Roles" section. Alpha TransForm has the following pre-defined roles. Roles can also be assigned to a user after they have joined your account using [Manage User Roles].</p>
                            </description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Role ID</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>user</name>
                                    <description>User role - Person who fills in forms on a mobile device.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>AccountAdmin</name>
                                    <description>Account Administrator - controls the TransForm account.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>FormDesigner</name>
                                    <description>Form Designer - creates and updates form type definitions.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>ManagementConsole</name>
                                    <description>Management Console - can access Management Console to examine and process forms.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>supervisor</name>
                                    <description>Supervisor - processes forms needing approval.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Advanced Usage</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Users are not added to your account until the accept an invitation and create their own TransForm account. If preferred, you can automatically create TransForm user accounts for users to add to your account.</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[Display name (email address)|comma delimited roles|noinvite|password]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>For example:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example>
                                <![CDATA[Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)|user,AccountAdmin,ManagementConsole|noinvite|mrichter]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Developer Options</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>API Keys and events can be created for your TransFrom account using the Developer Options.</p>
                        <p>Here, you can do the following:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Get a TransForm API Key</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Revoke a TransForm API Key</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Define an onSubmit Event</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Define On Device Assets</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Each of these options is detailed below.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Get API Key</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>TransForm can be integrated into external applications using the TransForm API. In order to access the TransForm API, an API key is needed. When an API key is created, the scope for the key needs to be defined. The APK Key scope defines what operations are permitted when accessing the TransForm API. Multiple scopes can be defined for an API key by using the select key when choosing the scopes from the list.</p>
                        <p>The available scopes for a TransForm API key are below.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Scope</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>All</name>
                            <description>All possible scopes</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read data</name>
                            <description>Read data for forms in your account from the TransForm database</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit data</name>
                            <description>Edit data for forms in your account in the TransForm database</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create Forms</name>
                            <description>Create new form types</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Create new form from an existing form type in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Delete Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Delete forms in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Edit data in an existing form in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit roles</name>
                            <description>Edit the roles in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Invite users</name>
                            <description>Invite users to your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create users</name>
                            <description>Add users to your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Account Membership</name>
                            <description>Add or remove a user from your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read Account Membership</name>
                            <description>Read which users are members of your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read User Roles</name>
                            <description>Read the roles for a user in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Set User Roles</name>
                            <description>Set roles for a user in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Account Information</name>
                            <description>Edit your TransForm account information</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create/Revoke API Key</name>
                            <description>Create or revoke an API Key</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                    <tip>
                        <p>If you are unsure what roles you need for your API Key, visit the [TransForm API documentation] and check what permissions are required for the API methods you would like to use.</p>
                    </tip>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once you have selected the scope(s) for the TransForm API key, click the *[ui:Get API Key]* button to generate the key.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/getApiKey.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>After an API Key has been created, it can be used until it has been revoked. To revoke an API Key, see [Revoke TransForm API Key] below.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Revoke API Key</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An API key can be revoked for a TransForm account using the *[ui:Revoke TransForm API Key]* tool. Enter the API key to revoke in the text box with the text "API Key to revoke" then click the *[ui:Revoke API Key]* button. Once revoked, the API Key can no longer be used to access TransForm.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/revokekey.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Define onSubmit Event</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The onSubmit event can be used to define a series of actions that should occur when data is submitted from a TransForm form. The actions can include sending an email with the submitted form data or posting the data to a REST endpoint.</p>
                        <p>The event is defined as a JSON definition. This definition can be created using the [TransForm onSubmit Genie] in Alpha Anywhere or by manually specifying the event using JSON.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/defineOnsubmitEvent.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">onSubmit Event Definition Syntax</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The event is specified using JSON. The JSON string is an array of actions that should be performed after that data has been submitted. Each action has a number of properties (defined as a JSON object). Two actions are supported: *[js:SendEmail]* (sends an e-mail message with the form data that was submitted) and *[js:PostData]* (posts the form data that was submitted to a URL).</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[js:SendEmail]* action supports these properties:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:sendTo]* - a comma delimited list of e-mail addresses.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:subject]* - e-mail subject.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:sendFormat]* - options are *[js:json]*, *[js:html]*, or *[js:excel]*.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:formIds]* - (optional) a comma delimited list of form Ids for which the action should be executed. Use *[js:"*"]*, *[js:""]* (a blank list of formIds) or omit the property to execute the action for all forms.</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[js:PostData]* action supports these properties:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:url]* - the URL to which the data should be posted. The URL can include placeholders for form data. </name>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>Available placeholders include:</p>
                                        <p>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>
                                                    <name-title>Placeholder</name-title>
                                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                                </item>
                                                <item>
                                                    <name>*[js:{formdata.formid}]*</name>
                                                    <description>Inserts data from a form field. Replace formid with the ID of the form field that includes the data.</description>
                                                </item>
                                                <item>
                                                    <name>*[js:{metadata.fieldname}]*</name>
                                                    <description>Inserts data from a form metadata field. Replace fieldname with the name of the metadata field.</description>
                                                </item>
                                            </list>
                                        </p>
                                        <p>For example, PostData action shown below includes the form instance's ID in the URL:</p>
                                        <p>
                                            <example code="json"><![CDATA[{
    "action": "PostData",
    "url": "http://mywebhook.data.com/{formdata.formid}",
    "variableName": "formdata",
    "formIds": "*",
    "headers": "",
    "actionId": "55ca0dce-75db-411a-96b9-585be3da132e"
}]]></example>
                                        </p>
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:variableName]* - the variable name for the data that is posted. If not specified, the variable name defaults to *[js:data]*. The data (form data and meta data) are posted as a JSON string.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:formIds]* - (optional) a comma delimited list of form Ids for which the action should be executed. Use *[js:"*"]*, *[js:""]* (a blank list of formIds) or omit the property to execute the action for all forms.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:headers]* - (optional) a comma delimited list of headers in the format *[js:headername: headervalue]* to add to the REST call. For example: *[js:header1: value of header1,header2: value of header2,header3: value of header3]*</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The example below defines two actions:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example code="json">
                                <![CDATA[[

    {
        "action":"SendEmail",
        "sendTo":"fred.smith@company1.com,john.jones@company1.com",
        "subject":"TransForm Data",
        "sendFormat": "html",
        "formIds" : "*"
    },

    {
        "action" : "PostData",
        "url" : "http://www.company1.com/transformwebhook",
        "variableName" : "postBody",
        "formIds" : "form1,form2,form3"
    }

]]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Define On Device Assets</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>On Device Assets are files (e.g. images, videos, PDFs, etc.) and SQLite databases that should be loaded onto the device.</p>
                        <p>These assets can be used when filling in a form to lookup data, etc.</p>
                        <p>You specify the assets to load on the device by specifying either a JSON string that defines a manifest, or by providing a URL from where the manifest file can be downloaded.</p>
                        <p>On Device Assets are defined at the TransForm account level. That means that all of the forms you define for a particular account can access the same On Device Assets.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/onDeviceAssets.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <important>
                        <p>You must define an [On Device Assets Policy] in order for assets to be downloaded to the device.</p>
                    </important>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">Manifest Syntax</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The manifest is defined by a JSON string that specifies an array of objects where each object in the array defines a particular file that should be downloaded and stored on a device.</p>
                                <p>The example below defines a manifest with three assets:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <example><![CDATA[[
    { 
        "url": "http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/transform/SQLiteNorthwind.zip",
        "type": "sqlite",
        "version": 1
    },
    {
        "url": "http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/transform/allimages.zip",
        "type": "folder",
        "targetFolder": "images",
        "version": 1
    },
    {
        "url": "http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/transform/snow.JPG",
        "type": "file",
        "targetFolder": "images",
        "version": 1
    }
]]]></example>
                                </p>
                                <p>The "type" property in each object defines the type of the asset. The available options for "type" are:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>"sqlite"</name>
                                            <description>A SQLite database - can either be compressed into a .zip file, or uncompressed - recommend that you zip the file to reduce download time.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>"folder"</name>
                                            <description>A folder that contains one or more files. The folder must be compressed into a single .zip file.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>"file"</name>
                                            <description>An individual file. The file must NOT be compressed into .zip file. *[TIP:]* If you want to compress the file, use the "folder" option.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">Target Folders</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>For each "folder" or "file" type you can also specify an optional "targetFolder" property. This defines the folder on the device where the files will be loaded. If you do not define the "targetFolder", the files are loaded into the root folder for your TransForm account.</p>
                                <p>Multiple "folder" assets can specify the same "targetFolder" property.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">Versions</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Each item has an (optional) "version" property. If the "version" property is not defined, then the asset is always downloaded, regardless of whether it has been previously downloaded. If the "version" is defined, the asset is only downloaded if the "version" number in the manifest is higher than the version of the downloaded asset.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="3">Manifest URL</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Instead of defining the manifest as a JSON string, you can specify the URL of a file that contains the manifest definition. For example</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="html"><![CDATA[https://myamazons3bucket.s3.amazonaws.com/mytransformaccount/manifest.json]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>You can also define (optional) options for the On Device Assets that control how often the On Device Assets are refreshed.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Integrations</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Zapier</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Alpha TransForm integrates directly with Zapier. The *[ui:Zapier]* section lists a set of common integrations using Alpha TransForm with Zapier. See [Getting Started with Zapier] to learn more about Zapier integration.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link link="transform api reference">TransForm API documentation</link>
        <link link="transform central permissions">Permissions</link>
        <link href="#section1_Manage User Roles">Manage User Roles</link>
        <link href="mailto:sales@alphasoftware.com">Contact the Alpha Software sales team</link>
        <link href="https://www.alphasoftware.com/using-transform-with-zapier">Getting Started with Zapier</link>
        <link link="ondevice assets policy">On Device Assets Policy</link>
        <link href="https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/index?search=tranformapi%20explorer">TransForm onSubmit Genie</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="https://www.alphasoftware.com/transform-tutorial-part1" target="_blank">Getting Started with TransForm</ref>
    </see>
</page>