<page>
    <shortlink>transform central home</shortlink>
    <topic>TransForm Central Home</topic>
    <description>The Home Tab in TransForm Central is where you manage your TransForm account, including inviting and managing users, configuring your password and account, and generating a TransForm API Key.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/transformCentralHome.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Account license keys</title>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:Account license keys]* is where you enter your TransForm license(s) to activate The number of authorized users for a TransForm account is determined by the license key(s) entered in the *[ui:Account license keys]* box. If no licenses are provided, your account will run in Trial mode until the trial period expires.</p>
                <p>Multiple licenses can be entered for a single TransForm account. Licenses are cumulative. This means, if you enter a 5 user license key and a 10 user license key for a single TransForm account, up to 15 users can log in to the account. If you unsure how many users are authorized for you licenses, *[ui:Show License Information]* can be used to find out how many users are authorized and when the license expires.</p>
                <p>To activate one or more licenses for a TransForm account, specify each license on a separate line and click *[ui:Save]*.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/accountLicenseKeys.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>[Contact the Alpha Software sales team] if you have questions about existing licenses or to purchase additional TransForm license keys.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Invite users to join a TransForm account</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/inviteUsers.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To invite users, enter their email addresses - one per line - in the text box. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[fred.smith@company.com
molly.richter@company.com]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Setting the Display Name for Invited Users</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>When the user accepts the invitation, they will be added to your TransForm account. Their display name will be the email address as it as written in the invite text box.</p>
                        <p>If desired, you can specify the display name for the users when they are invited. To include the display name, use the following format:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[Display name (email address)]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[Fred Smith (fred.smith@company.com)
Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Assigning Roles to Invited Users</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>By default, all users are assigned the "User" role when they accept an invitation to join a TransFrom account. You can optionally specify the user roles to assign a user when they accept the invitation to your TransForm account. Roles are defined as a pipe followed by a comma delimited list of user roles.</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[|role1,role2,role3]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can define as many roles as you want for a user. The example below assigns roles to 2 users. TransForm will assign users the "User" role if no role is specified:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[fred.smith@company.com|user,FormDesigner
Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)|user,AccountAdmin,ManagementConsole
dave.smith@company.com
janice.reed@company.com]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>The roles available for assigning to the user can be found on the Permissions tab in the "Roles" section.  Alpha TransForm has the following pre-defined roles.</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Role</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>user</name>
                            <description>User role - Person who fills in forms on a mobile device.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>AccountAdmin</name>
                            <description>Account Administrator - controls the TransForm account.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>FormDesigner</name>
                            <description>Form Designer - creates and updates form type definitions.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>ManagementConsole</name>
                            <description>Management Console - can access Management Console to examine and process forms.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>supervisor</name>
                            <description>Supervisor - processes forms needing approval.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can add additional roles or modify existing roles on the [Permissions tab].</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Advanced Usage</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Users are not added to your account until the accept an invitation and create their own TransForm account. If preferred, you can automatically create TransForm user accounts for users to add to your account.</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[Display name (email address)|comma delimited roles|noinvite|password]]></example>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[Molly Richter (molly.richter@company.com)|user,AccountAdmin,ManagementConsole|noinvite|mrichter]]></example>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Manage users</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/manageUsers.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Add users</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Delete/Re-order users</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Manage user roles</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Each of these options is detailed below.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Add users</title>
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/addUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Delete/Re-order users</title>
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/deleteReorderUsers.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Manage user roles</title>
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/manageUserRoles.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Change your display name</title>
            <description>
                <p>Your display name is shown in the header when you are logged into TransForm Central.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/header3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To change your display name, enter the new name in the *[ui:Display name]* text box and click *[ui:OK]*.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/changeDisplayName.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Change your password</title>
            <description>
                <p>Use the *[ui:Change your password]* option to change your TransForm password.</p>
                <p>To change your password, enter the new password in the *[ui:New password]* and *[ui:Confirm password]* text boxes and click *[ui:Submit]*.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/changePassword.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Change your account display name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Account Display Name is the name of your TransForm account. When you are logged into TransForm Central, the Account Display Name is shown in parentheses at the top of the page next to your Display Name.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/header2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Account Display Name is also shown when you log in to TranForm. If you are a member of multiple TransForm accounts, you will be prompted to select the TransForm account you wish to log into after entering your username and password in TransForm Central or the TransForm mobile application.</p>
                <p>To change your Account Display Name,  enter the new name in the *[ui:TransForm account display name]* text box and click *[ui:OK]*. Choose an Account Display Name that is easy for you to remember or recognize as your account (for example, the name of your company or simply "Sarah's Account"):</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/changeAccountName.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Create new TransForm account</title>
            <description>
                <p>If you do not have a TransForm account or wish to create another one, *[ui:Create new TransForm account]* can be used to create another TransForm account associated with your user name.</p>
                <p>A TransForm Account is not required to use Alpha TransForm. You must, however, be a member of an existing TransForm account or have your own TransForm account to use Alpha TransForm.</p>
                <p>If you are a member of more than one TransForm Account, a list of accounts will be shown when you log in to TransForm Central or the TranForm mobile application. The Account Name is what will be shown in the list.</p>
                <p>To create a new TransForm account, enter the "Account name" in the text box provided and click *[ui:OK]*.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/createTransFormAccount.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When you click *[ui:OK]*, TransForm Central will create a new account with the specified Account Name and log you into the new account.</p>
                <p>You can also use the *[ui:Don't have a username/password?]* link on the TransForm Central login screen to create a new TransForm account.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/login2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Developer Options</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/developerOptions.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Get TransForm API Key</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Revoke TransForm API Key</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Define onSubmit Event</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Each of these options is detailed below.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Get TransForm API Key</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>TransForm can be integrated into external applications using the TransForm API. In order to access the TransForm API, an API key is needed. When an API key is created, the scope for the key needs to be defined. The APK Key scope defines what operations are permitted when accessing the TransForm API. Multiple scopes can be defined for an API key by using the select key when choosing the scopes from the list.</p>
                        <p>The available scopes for a TransForm API key are below.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Scope</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>All</name>
                            <description>All possible scopes</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read data</name>
                            <description>Read data for forms in your account from the TransForm database</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit data</name>
                            <description>Edit data for forms in your account in the TransForm database</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create Forms</name>
                            <description>Create new form types</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Create new form from an existing form type in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Delete Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Delete forms in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Form Instances</name>
                            <description>Edit data in an existing form in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit roles</name>
                            <description>Edit the roles in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Invite users</name>
                            <description>Invite users to your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create users</name>
                            <description>Add users to your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Account Membership</name>
                            <description>Add or remove a user from your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read Account Membership</name>
                            <description>Read which users are members of your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read User Roles</name>
                            <description>Read the roles for a user in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Set User Roles</name>
                            <description>Set roles for a user in your account</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Account Information</name>
                            <description>Edit your TransForm account information</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Create/Revoke API Key</name>
                            <description>Create or revoke an API Key</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                    <tip>
                        <p>If you are unsure what roles you need for your API Key, visit the [TransForm API documentation] and check what permissions are required for the API methods you would like to use.</p>
                    </tip>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once you have selected the scope(s) for the TransForm API key, click the *[ui:Get API Key]* button to generate the key.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/getApiKey.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>After an API Key has been created, it can be used until it has been revoked. To revoke an API Key, see [Revoke TransForm API Key] below.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Revoke TransForm API Key</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An API key can be revoked for a TransForm account using the *[ui:Revoke TransForm API Key]* tool. Enter the API key to revoke in the text box with the text "API Key to revoke" then click the *[ui:Revoke API Key]* button. Once revoked, the API Key can no longer be used to access TransForm.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/revokekey.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Define onSubmit Event</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The onSubmit event can be used to define a series of actions that should occur when data is submitted from a TransForm form. The actions can include sending an email with the submitted form data or posting the data to a REST endpoint.</p>
                        <p>The event is defined using a JSON definition.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/defineOnsubmitEvent.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">onSubmit Event Definition Syntax</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The event is specified using JSON. The JSON string is an array of actions that should be performed after that data has been submitted. Each action has a number of properties (defined as a JSON object). Two actions are supported: *[js:SentEmail]* (sends an e-mail message with the form data that was submitted) and *[js:PostData]* (posts the form data that was submitted to a URL).</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[js:SendEmail]* action supports these properties:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:sendTo]* - a comma delimited list of e-mail addresses.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:subject]* - e-mail subject.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:sendFormat]* - options are *[js:json]*, *[js:html]*, or *[js:excel]*.</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[js:PostData]* action supports these properties:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:url]* - the URL to which the data should be posted.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>*[js:variablName]* - the variable name for the data that is posted. If not specified, the variable name defaults to *[js:data]*. The data (form data and meta data) are posted as a JSON string.</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The example below defines two actions:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example code="json">
                                <![CDATA[[

    {
        "action":"SendEmail",
        "sendTo":"fred.smith@company1.com,john.jones@company1.com",
        "subject":"TransForm Data",
        "sendFormat": "html"
    },

    {
        "action" : "PostData",
        "url" : "http://www.company1.com/transformwebhook",
        "variableName" : "postBody"
    }

]]]>
                            </example>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="transform api reference">TransForm API documentation</link>
    </links>
    <links>
        <link href="mailto:sales@alphasoftware.com">Contact the Alpha Software sales team</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="https://www.alphasoftware.com/transform-tutorial-part1" target="_blank">Getting Started with TransForm</ref>
    </see>
</page>