<page build="4499">
    <shortlink>uxcontrols date range selector control</shortlink>
    <topic>Date Range Selector</topic>
    <description>
        <p>The *[ui:Date Range Selector]* control is a Dropdown Box control with pre-defined date ranges that can be used to populate controls containing a Start Date and End Date.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Date Range Selector]* control is useful if your UX component has controls where the user must enter a start date and an end date.</p>
        <p>In the image below, the *[ui:Date Range Selector]* shows the list of date ranges. The user has selected the 'This Year-to-date' range and the two input controls (one for date start, the other for date end) have been filled in.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dateSelector1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To add a *[ui:Date Range Selector]*, select the control from the *[ui:Defined Controls]* section of the UX toolbox:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dateSelector2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Connecting the Start Date and End Date Controls</title>
            <description>
                <p>After inserting the *[ui:Date Range Selector]* into the UX Component, you must update the JavaScript in the *[ui:onChange]* event with the ID for the Start Date and End Date controls. The Start Date and End Date controls should be text boxes with a *[ui:Type]* of 'date'.</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[//fill in the name of the controls where the start date and end date should be inserted
*[highlighter:var idStartDate = '';]*
*[highlighter:var idEndDate = '';]*
if(idStartDate == '' || idEndDate == '') { 
	alert('Error: You have not specified the Ids of the start and end date controls. Edit this control\'s onChange event and define the ids.');
	return false;
};

//...]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating the Start Date and End Date Controls</title>
            <description>
                <p>If the UX does not contain controls for the start and end date, you can quickly add them using the 'Create multiple new controls at once' option when inserting a *[ui:[TextBox]]* control:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dateSelectortb1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Field syntax can be used to define the data type of each textbox in the *[ui:New Control]* dialog. The following will create two date controls named "StartDate" and "EndDate" on the same line:</p>
            </description>
            <example code=""><![CDATA[StartDate|D,EndDate|D]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Once the controls have been added, the *[ui:onChange]* event for the *[ui:Date Range Selector]* can be updated with the controls for the Start Date and End Date:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[//fill in the name of the controls where the start date and end date should be inserted
*[highlighter:var idStartDate = 'StartDate';]*
*[highlighter:var idEndDate = 'EndDate';]*
if(idStartDate == '' || idEndDate == '') { 
	alert('Error: You have not specified the Ids of the start and end date controls. Edit this control\'s onChange event and define the ids.');
	return false;
};

//...]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>