<page>
    <shortlink>ux defined controls delete record</shortlink>
    <topic>Delete Record</topic>
    <description>Deletes a record in a component that has been bound to one or more tables.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Delete Record]* button adds the ability to delete a record from a data bound UX component. The button can be placed on the UX component by selecting it from the list of pre-defined control in the *[ui:Defined Controls]* section of the UX Builder.</p>
        <p>The *[ui:Delete Record]* button has a client-side *[ui:Enable expression]* that will disable the control if the current record is a new record.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/deleteRecord.png</link>
            </figure>
            <important>
                <p>This control can only be used if you have loaded primary keys for the primary table. You can load primary keys using the 'Load Primary keys for Parent Table' server-side action in the onDialogInitialize event, or in an Ajax callback, using the 'Get Primary Key values for Records in a Query' Action Javascript.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The button calls the [{dialog.object}.deleteRecord()] JavaScript method when clicked. You can customize this action by passing additional parameters to the deleteRecord() method. For example, you could specify that the component should display a new record after deleting the current record:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[
var deleteOptions = { nextRecordToShow : 'newrecord' };

{dialog.object}.deleteRecord(deleteOptions);]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>Or, you could suppress the confirmation message:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[
var deleteOptions = { confirmation : false };

{dialog.object}.deleteRecord(deleteOptions)]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>See [{dialog.object}.deleteRecord()] for more information about available parameters.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Deleting a Record in a Data Bound Component</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In a UX component that has been bound to one or more tables, you can delete a record from the primary table to which the UX component has been bound using the Delete Record button.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/c6e39bf7</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20component%20deleterecord%20method">{dialog.object}.deleteRecord()</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux%20component%20deleterecord%20method">{dialog.object}.deleteRecord()</ref>
    </see>
    <limitations>Data bound UX Component Only</limitations>
</page>