<page build="4294">
    <shortlink>ux editor timespinlists</shortlink>
    <topic>Editor-TimeSpinLists</topic>
    <description>Inserts an Editor for editing a value ina  time control using Spin List controls for the hour, minute, and AM/PM values.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:[Editor-TimeSpinLists]]* control adds an Editor to the UX Component that can be use to edit a time value.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <important>This control must be placed inside an *[link:EditorSet@ux container editorset container type]* container.</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To select the time value editor, select *[ui:[Editor-TimeSpinLists]]* from the list of controls in the Defined Controls section.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/selecttimeeditor.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The image below shows a form control on the left with a time value and a time value editor on the right. The time value editor is implemented using three spin lists - one for hours, one for minutes and one for AM/PM.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/showtimeeditor.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring the Editor</title>
            <description>
                <p>To configure the Time value editor, click the smart field for the *[ui:Editor configuration genie]* property in the FormView builder on the Fields tab.</p>
                <p>The configuration genie allows you to specify if the 'Now' button should be shown.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/formvieweditor-editorconfiggenie.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Customizing the Spin Lists</title>
            <description>
                <p>The values in the hours, minutes, and am/pm Spin Lists are defined as static choices. You can modify the values in the spin lists to customize the choices displayed. For example, minutes can be changed to display multiples of 5, 10, 15 minutes, etc.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Values in the Spin Lists can also be populated dynamically at run-time using the Spin List control's JavaScript *[link:populate Method@api client api a5 spinlist populate method]*. This is useful if the Time Spin List editor will be used to edit multiple fields that may have different time restrictions - such as half-hour increments only or hours limited to between 8AM and 5PM. See *[link:Dynamically Repopulating a Spin List Control@ux spinlist dynamic repopulate]* to learn more.</p>
                <p>To add data validation, use the *[ui:Validate editor]* event for the Editor.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux formview builder editor settings Editor configuration genie">Editor configuration genie</ref>
    </see>
</page>