<page build="4417">
    <shortlink>ux editor alphanumerickeypad</shortlink>
    <topic>Editor-AlphaNumericKeyPad</topic>
    <description>Displays a customizable alphanumeric keypad for enterning number and character values.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:[Editor-AlphaNumericKeyPad]]*, as shown in the two images below, display the AlphaNumeric keypad editor in its two possible configurations. In the first image, the keypad is shown as it would be displayed on a phone.</p>
        <p>In the second image, the keypad is shown as it would be displayed on a tablet.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <important>This control must be placed inside an *[link:EditorSet@ux container editorset container type]* container.</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>AlphaNumeric keypad as shown on a mobile device with a small screen, such as a phone.</title>
                <link>images/alphakeypadsmall.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>AlphaNumeric keypad as shown on a mobile device with a larger screen, such as a tablet.</title>
                <link>images/alphakeypadlarge.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding the Editor to a UX Component</title>
            <description>
                <p>To add the editor to a UX Component, select *[ui:[Editor-AlphaNumericKeyPad]]* from the list of controls in the Defined Controls section.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/alphanumericdefinedcontrols.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring the Editor</title>
            <description>
                <p>The keypad is configured using the *[ui:Editor configuration genie]* property in the FormView Builder.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/editorconfiggenieproperty.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The genie can be used to configure the editor, allowing you to define the keys shown, add custom keys, and configure how the keypad is displayed.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/alphanumerickeypadconfiggenie.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Editor Settings</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum number of characters</name>
                    <description>The maximum number of characters the user can enter. Set to *[ui:-1]* for no limit.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Align</name>
                    <description>Defines the alignment of value in the display area. Can be *[ui:left]*, *[ui:center]*, or *[ui:right]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Scale</name>
                    <description>If the value is longer than can fit in the display area, the text can be automatically scaled so that the full value can be seen. If unchecked, the text can be scrolled.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Initial keypad</name>
                    <description>Defines the initial set of keys shown. The keys shown can be Numeric or Alpha keys. Options are *[ui:a]* (Alpha) or *[ui:1]* (Numeric).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Initial Alpha keypad case</name>
                    <description>If checked, the initial character case for the keypad is set to lower case. Otherwise, initial case is set to upper case. This option is only available if *[ui:Allow lower case]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Allow lower case</name>
                    <description>Defines whether or not upper and lower case values can be entered. If unchecked, only uppercase values are allowed.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Allow space</name>
                    <description>If checked, spaces can be entered using the AlphaNumeric keypad.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Show insertion point</name>
                    <description>If checked, an insertion point will be displayed in the text area to indicate where characters will be entered.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Initial cursor position</name>
                    <description>The initial position of the insertion point. Set to *[ui:-1]* to place the insertion point at the end of the value.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Keypad size</name>
                    <description>Defines the size of the keypad shown. Can be one of the following values:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>auto</name>
                            <description>Automatically choose the keypad layout that best fits the available space.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>full</name>
                            <description>Displays a full keypad with one key per character. Ideal for large devices such as tablets.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>compact</name>
                            <description>Displays a compact keypad with multiple letters per key. Ideal for small devices such as phones.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Has custom keys</name>
                    <description>If checked, up to two additional custom keys can be added to the keypad.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Show primary custom key</name>
                    <description>If checked, the primary custom key will be shown in the keypad. This option is only available if *[ui:Has custom keys]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Primary custom key label</name>
                    <description>The label shown for the Primary custom key. This option is only available if *[ui:Show primary custom key]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Primary custom key value(s)</name>
                    <description>Enter one or more values in a comma delimited list. If you enter more than one value, a pop-up menu showing all custom values will be shown when the key is tapped. This option is only available if *[ui:Show primary custom key]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Show secondary custom key</name>
                    <description>If checked, the secondary custom key will be shown in the keypad. This option is only available if *[ui:Has custom keys]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Secondary custom key label</name>
                    <description>The label shown for the Secondary custom key. This option is only available if *[ui:Show secondary custom key]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Secondary custom key value(s)</name>
                    <description>Enter one or more values in a comma delimited list. If you enter more than one value, a pop-up menu showing all custom values will be shown when the key is tapped. This option is only available if *[ui:Show secondary custom key]* is checked.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux formview builder editor settings Editor configuration genie">Editor configuration genie</ref>
    </see>
</page>