<page build="0">
    <shortlink>ux defined control listdataexplode</shortlink>
    <topic>List data explode</topic>
    <description>Inserts a button for displaying all the data in a list, including any nested array data.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:List data explode]* control is a button that can be used to update a List's layout to display all data in the List. This control can be used to explore the data stored in a List control. If the List displays a subset of List data fields, it adds all fields to the layout. If the List data contains nested arrays, a checkbox will be included in the dropdown shown for the *[ui:List data explode]* button. You can include the nested array data in the List layout by checking the checkbox for the nested data and clicking "Explode".</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>An exploded list that contains a nested array, "Children" (*[link:download component@components/listExplode_Simple.zip]*)</title>
                <link>images/explodedList1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:List data explode]* can be used with any List regardless of the List's layout. Exploded data is displayed using a Columnar layout. If the List only has one layout, *[ui:List data explode]* replaces the List's layout. If the List has multiple layouts, *[ui:List data explode]* will replace the Default layout.</p>
                <p>In addition to the fields in the data source, the *[ui:List data explode]* button may also add internal List data fields to the layout. These are used internally by Alpha Anywhere to track record-dependent information, such as the record's primary key (*[_primaryKey]*) or if the record has been modified (*[IsDirty]*). The internal fields shown are dependent on how the List is configured. It is strongly recommended that you do not directly modify these internal use only fields.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>An exploded editable List based on a SQL data source with a multi-field Primary Key (*[link:download component@components/listExplode_SQL.zip]*)</title>
                <link>images/explodedList2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>