<page>
	  <topic>CheckBox Properties</topic>
<description>Check boxes are appropriate when you want to set a True/False value into a logical field. The most important property for a check box control is the definition of its choices.</description>

<sections>
<section>
	<title>Choices</title>
	<description>Click [...] to define the true and false choices set by the check box. Refer to Defining Choices for Check Boxes, Radio Buttons, and Drop Down Listsfor details.  </description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Orientation</title>
	<description>The orientation of the label. The choices are:  
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"Horizontal" </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Vertical"  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]       
.CheckBox.Orientation as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>
<section>
	<title>In-line style</title>
	<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click [...] to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
	<cases>
	
		<case>
			<description>code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]       
.CheckBox.InLineStyle as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>
<section>
	<title>Not in list rule</title>
	<description></description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>"First Entry" - use the first entry in the list  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Null" - set the field to NULL  
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>"Do Nothing" - accept the user input  
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]      
.CheckBox.NotInListRule as C 
]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>
<section>
	<title>Style control if error  </title>
	<description>Legacy (v6). Specifies whether to apply a second style to the field if a validation error occurs.  
</description>
	<cases>
		
		<case>
			<description>code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]      
.CheckBox.StyleFieldIfError as L ]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>
<section>
	<title>In-line style for errors</title>
	<description>Legacy (v6). Specifies style attributes that are used when a validation error occurs. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
	<cases>
		
		<case>
			<description>code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]      
				.CheckBox.ErrorInLineStyle as C 
 ]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Date Picker Properties 
</title>
	<description>A date picker is a variation on a TextBox control. The date picker option appears in a TextBox control if the grid is updateable.  
</description>
	<note>Pop-up blockers will prevent the Calendar Picker from appearing and will sometimes generate an error message.</note>
</section>
<section>
	<note>User grids and the server hosting the Application Server can use different date formats like yy-mm-dd or yy/mm/dd, as opposed to the US date format mm/dd/yy.  In the Grid Component Builder set Grid Properties > Advanced > Date format on client does not match server to TRUE and enter the client date format in the following field. You may use different separators between the YY, MM, and DD parts of the date format. This property informs the Application Server that it needs to translate dates entered through this grid component.</note>
</section>	
	
</sections>




 
</page>