<page>
	<topic>[Frame Begin]</topic>
	<description>When designing a grid component with Columnar formatting, you may position controls by placing them into frames. A frame has a label and places a box around selected fields. You can use the frame feature in columnar layouts, such as columnar grids, search forms, and detail view forms. This example shows how to create a columnar grid with 2 frames.  
</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Using Frames for Control Positioning:  </title>
		
		<steps>
<step>
	<description>Open the Grid Builder and create a new blank grid. On the Component Type page select Form (Columnar) under the Grid Layout menu. 
		
	</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe8.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Under Data Source select either .dbf or SQL. </description>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>On the Query(DBF) or Query(AlphaDAO) page connect to the table that you will use to extract data. If using SQL make sure to set the primary key to a field you will use from your table. </description>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Go to the Fields page. There should be a number of fields in the Available Fields: list. Highlight a field </description>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Click the right arrow to move fields from the Available fields: list to the Selected: fields list. </description>
<figure><link>images/01_fframe9.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Add three more fields to the Selected: fields list. Next, check the editable? checkbox next to the Selected: fields title.  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe10.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>The Notice dialog will appear. Select all fields and click OK .  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe11.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>The fields you selected should now appear as textbox controls. Highlight the first two fields in your Selected fields: list by holding down the Shift key and clicking on each field.</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe12.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Click the Insert.. hyperlink underneath the Available fields: list.  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe13.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>The Insert Special Control dialog will open. Select a [Frame begin] control and click OK .  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe14.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>An Insert Frame dialog will appear. Give the frame a Label name that describes the two fields you selected. For example, Customerfor a Firstand a Lastnamefield or Locationfor an Addressand a Cityfield.  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe15.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>You should now see a [Frame:] control and a [Frame End] Control around the first two field controls in the Selected: fields list.  
</description>

</step>			
<step>
	<description>Add a second [Frame] control around the last two fields in your Selected fields list using the same steps.  

</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Go to Live Preview . You should see something like this:  </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe2.png</link></figure>
	<note>On the Grid > Properties page, under the Layout Options section, there is a  Number of 'Layout' Columns    property that specifies the number of columns inside each record column. By default this is set to 1. Below you can see how changing this property will alter the look of your [Frame] control.</note>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Go to the Layout Options section on the Grid> Properties page. Change the  Number of 'Layout' Columnsproperty to  2. Go back to Live preview :  </description>
	<figure>
		<title>Framed fields now appear next to each other on the same row.  </title>
		<link>images/01_fframe3.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>On the Grid Properties page go to the Layout Options section and set the Repeating Columnsproperty to 1 and the Rows of Data property to 2. Go to Live Preview :  

</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe4.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>On the Fields page add a third field to your second [Frame] control. You can use the Up and Down arrows to the right of the Selected: fields list to position the field vertically. Check field is editable? .    </description>
	<figure><link>images/01_fframe7.png</link></figure>
</step>			
<step>
	<description>Layout Options > Number of "Layout" Columnsproperty to 3.  </description>
	<figure>
		<title>The three framed fields appear in the same row. </title>
		<link>images/01_fframe5.png</link></figure>
</step>			
			
			
		</steps>
		
		
			</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>