<page>
	  <topic>Link Properties</topic>
<description>An essential decision about a link control is what it will display. The options are:  Value in field, Value from other field(s), Static text, Static image, Image in another control </description>


<groups><group background="true">

<sections>
	<section>
		<description>Link controls have choices for the Link address type. The link could be:  a URL (presumably also a field value), an email address (presumably also a field value), a link to the detail view form, a value that is computed (see Link Address Builder ), a value that specifies filter, order, and/or linking informationfor the records in a second grid   
</description>
	</section>
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group><title>In-line style</title>
		<sections>
	
	<section>
		
		<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
	</section>
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group><title>Display what in link? </title>
		<sections>
		
	<section>
		
		<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details. Specifies what is displayed in the link. The options are:"Value in field", "Value from other field(s)", "Static text", "Static image", "Image in another control"  </description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Field(s) to display - Specify the HTML to display in the link. Use field placeholders to include values from other fields in the grid. Typically, the fields that you reference will have the Hide row or Hide column properties checked. </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Static text - Specify the text to display in the link. 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Static image - Specify the image to display in the link. 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Dynamic image control - Specify the control that contains the image to display. 
Link address type 
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Using Images in Link Fields:</title>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Open the Grid Builder . On the Design tab click on the Component Type  page and select Tabular  in the Grid Layout menu.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Open the Data Source  page and select either .dbf or SQL .</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>On the Query(DBF) or Query(AlphaDAO)  page select the table you will work from. </description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Open the Fields  page. Select several fields and move them from the Available Fields:  list into the Selected:  fields list; using the arrows between the two list.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select the field that you want to contain the linking data.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Go to the selected field's Field Properties  list. Under the Display Settings  section find the Control type  property. Set the control type to 'link '.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Now go to the Link Properties  section of the Field Properties. Find the Display what in link?  property and select "Image in another control ".</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>While in Link Properties set the Dynamic image  control property to the name of the image field you wish to display. For the Link address type  property select "DetailView link ".</description>
				<figure>
					<title>Preview of the grid showing both ID and Thumbnail fields before modification.</title>
					<link>images/WP_Image_before_link.gif</link></figure>
					<note>Images may be used in hyperlinks and in link fields to detail view forms.</note>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Adding an Image in Hyperlink and Link Fields to a Detail Form</title>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>For the field that contains the linking data:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>a. In Display Settings > Control typeset the control type of the field to "link".
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>b. In Link Properties > Display what in link?select "Image in another control".
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>c. In Link Properties > Dynamic image controlselect the name of the image field that you wish to display.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>d. In Link Properties > Link address typeselect "DetailView link".
</description>
					</case>
				</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>For the field that contains the image you wish to display:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>a. In Column Properties > Hide columncheck the check box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<figure>
			<title>Preview of the grid after modification showing the Thumbnail image in the ID field.
</title>
			<link>images/WP_Image_as_link.gif</link>
			</figure>
		
	</case>
</cases>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Static Text:</title>
		<description>You use the Link Display Valuedialog box to compose the HTML code that will be displayed in a link. The link may contain references to any of the fields on the grid.</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select the field placeholders in the Available Fieldslist that you want to use in the link expression.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Arrange the field placeholders in the order that you want to see them in the expression.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, add any text that you want around the fields.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, click HTML Editorto use it to format the expression.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click OK to save your work or Cancelto discard it.
</description>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
	</section>
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group><title>Link address type </title>
		<sections>
	
	<section>
		
		<description>You can specify that the link address type is 'Javascript'. Any Javascript function call or command can be added to the 'onclick' event. The Javascript will be executed when the link is clicked.  "Field Value is a Link address" , "Field Value is an email address" , "DetailView link"  , "Computed from fields in the grid" , "Javascript"   
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_flink.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	<section>
		<figure><title>Javascript link with an onClick event opening an alert box. 
</title>
			<link>images/01_aa.png</link>
			</figure>
		
	</section>
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group><title>Link Address </title>
		<sections>
		
	<section>
		
		<description>When the Link address type is "Computed from fields in the grid", this field appears. Click to define the link address in the Link Address Builder .  
</description>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Link Address Builder  </title>
		<description>A common requirement is to open a page that contains a grid component, showing just records that match certain values.
For example, assume that when you click the hyperlink, you want to open a page named CustomerInfo.A5w. We will make the following assumptions about this page:
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>The page contains a Grid component named customers.
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>The table has a field named Customer_ID.
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Alpha Anywhere .DBF Syntax </title>
				<description>If the data is coming from an Alpha Anywheretable, the filter expression that we want to apply to the customersgrid on the CustomerInfo.A5wpage is therefore:</description>
				<example><![CDATA[customer_id="{customerID}"]]></example>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>where {customerID}is the value in field for which we are defining the Link control.
Grid components understand two special parameters: _Filterand _Order. So, to open the CustomerInfo.A5wpage showing just the records that we want, the computed link address is:</description>
				<example><![CDATA[CustomerInfo.A5w?customers_filter=customer_id="{customerID}"]]></example>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Other example computed link address are:</description>
				<example><![CDATA[CustomerInfo.A5w?customers_filter=firstname="{firstname}".and.lastname="{lastname}"?customers_order="{lastname}"
OrderInfo.A5w?orders_filter=orderid="{orderid}"]]></example>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>SQL Syntax </title>
				<description>The syntax for the "Filter" and "Order" parameters must be appropriate for the database on which the Grid component is based. SQL syntax typically uses single quotes for character values and "AND" and "OR" to join conditions (as opposed to .AND.and .OR.which Alpha Anywhere uses for querying local tables). So the above examples would become:
</description>
				<example><![CDATA[CustomerInfo.A5w?customers_filter=customer_id='{customerID}'
CustomerInfo.A5w?customers_filter=firstname='{firstname}' AND lastname='{lastname}'?customers_order={lastname}
OrderInfo.A5w?orders_filter=orderid='{orderid}']]></example>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Composing a Link Address:</title>
				<description>If you have a field in your grid where the Display Settings > Control Type is "Link": 
</description>
				<steps>
					<step>
						<description>Click or in the Link Properties > Link Address field to display the Link Address Builder. </description>
					</step>
					<step>
						<description>Select a page from the Pages in Project list and click Insert Page. </description>
					</step>
					<step>
						<description>Position the cursor in the Link Address text box, select a field placeholder from the Grid Fields list, and click Insert Field. Repeat as Necessary. </description>
					</step>
					<step>
						<description>Add additional syntax elements as Necessary to the Link Address text box. </description>
					</step>
					<step>
						<description>Click OK to save your inputs or Cancel to discard them. </description>
					</step>
				</steps>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group><title>Target frame or window </title>
		<sections>
		
		
	<section>
		
		<description>The default is "Explicit". Defines where to display the linked page. The default is Null. The options are: Blank (opens in a new window) "Explicit", "WindowName" (e.g. "Window2"), "_blank", "_parent", "_self", "_search", "_top"  
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Clear Parameters - The default is .F. . Specifies whether the target URL preserves existing parameters.  </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Scroll to Detail View - The default is .T. . Specifies that the page should scroll down to display the detail view form when a record is selected.  </description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<figure>
			<title>An example of a displaying multiple field values as  a link expression </title>
			<link>images/wp_Expression_as_Detail_View_Link.gif</link></figure>
		
		
	</section>
	
	
	
	
	
	</sections>
	</group>
	<group>
		<sections>
		
	<section>
		
		
		
		<description>code reference:</description>
		<example><![CDATA['In-line style  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .link.InLineStyle as C 
'Display what in link?  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .link.DisplayType as C 
'Field(s) to display  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .link.DisplayExpression as C 
'Static text  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .StaticText as C 
'Static image  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .StaticImage as C 
'Dynamic image control  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .link.AlternateImageControl 
'Link address type   
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .Link.Type as C 
'Link Address  
with tmpl.field_info[N]        .link.ComputedAddress 
'Target frame or window  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]              .Link.targetFrameOrWindow as C 
'Clear Parameters  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]              .Link.ClearParameters as L 
'Scroll to Detail View  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]              .Link.ScrollToDetailView as L 
]]></example>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>
</group></groups>


</page>