<page>
	<shortlink>api a5storage datacontainer class</shortlink>
	<topic>A5Storage::DataContainer Class</topic>
	<properties>
		<property>
			<name>CallResult</name>
			<type>CallResult</type>
			<description>When using a static method, the CallResult property will hold information for the result of calling the static method.</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>ConnnectionProperties</name>
			<type>P</type>
			<description>ConnectionProperties property</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>ConnectionString</name>
			<type>C</type>
			<description>The Storage Connection String used to open the connection. E.g. *[xb:"Provider='Disk';Container='C:\A5WebRoot';"]*</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>Exists</name>
			<type>L</type>
			<description>.T. if the container exists, otherwise .F.</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>Name</name>
			<type>C</type>
			<description>The name of the DataContainer. For example, for 'Disk' Storage container, the name may be *[xb:"C:\A5WebRoot"]*.</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>StorageType</name>
			<type>C</type>
			<description>The type of storage. Storage types include 'Azure', 'AmazonS3', and 'Disk'.</description>
		</property>
	</properties>
	<description>Used to access and manage data in a Storage container. A container can be an Azure Blob Storage account, an Amazon S3 Storage bucket, or a folder on disk located on the server or a machine on the same network as the server.</description>
    <!--list:.-->
	<discussion>
		<p>An *[xb:A5Storage::DataContainer]* acts as a reference point from which other objects can be accessed. An object is a file. Object references can include paths as part of the object name.</p>
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<important>Do not share *[xb:A5Storage::DataContainer]* objects across threads!  Connection strings and item names can be shared, but a new object must be created every time you want to access the Storage container. Many functions save the error state as a member variable (*[xb:CallResult]*) and return a Boolean .T. or .F. to indicate success or failure. If an object is shared across threads, two different users may make overlapping calls, causing the *[xb:CallResult]* to be overwritten.</important>
			<description>
				<p>If a DataContainer references objects stored on disk, a path can be specified that defines the "root" path to other objects. The complete path to an object on disk is a combination of the Container path (defined as part of the connection string) and object name.</p>
				<p>To create a *[xb:A5Storage::DataContainer]*, use the [A5Storage::DataContainer::Open] static method.</p>
			</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<links>
		<link link="api a5storage datacontainer open method">A5Storage::DataContainer::Open</link>
	</links>
    <see>
        <ref  link="api a5storage namespace">A5Storage</ref>
    </see>
</page>