<page>
    <topic>Images in Reports</topic>
    <description>Images stored in a database can be displayed in a report. This includes images stored as blob, base64, or image file reference fields as well as SVG and Ink data. Composite images can also be generated from picutre and ink data and shown in a report.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Displaying Image Fields in Reports</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you have images stored in a table as blob data, an image file reference, ink, or svg, you can display them in a report by overriding the Field Definition for the field.</p>
                        <p>In the *[Specify Data Source]* dialog, click on *[Advanced Options]* near the bottom of the dialog. On the Advanced Options dialog check *[Override field definitions of selected fields]* and press the *[Field Definitions]* button. In the Field Definitions dialog, select the image field and click the *[Edit field definition]* button. Select the desired type from the *[Data type]* dropdown. Supported data types for images are listed below:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Data type</name-title>
                            <description-title>Usage</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Bitmap</name>
                            <description>For fields that contain binary bitmap image.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Jpeg Image</name>
                            <description>For fields that contain binary jpeg image.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>PNG Image</name>
                            <description>For fields that contain binary png image.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Image File Reference</name>
                            <description>For fields that are image file references. An image file reference is the path to where the image is stored.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>SVG Image</name>
                            <description>For fields that contain SVG data.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Ink Image</name>
                            <description>For fields that contain Ink data. </description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Displaying Images Annotated with Ink</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Images can be annotated with Ink. The annotation is stored separately from the image. In order to display the image with annotations in the report, the two fields need to be combined into a composite image. The *[link:a5_composite_picture_and_ink@a5_composite_picture_and_ink Function]* Xbasic method can be used to create a composite image. The composite image can be stored in a calculated field, which can be placed in the Report.</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[annotatedPicture = a5_composite_picture_and_ink(imageField, inkField)]]></example>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
</page>