<page>
    <topic>Create a new Alpha Anywhere Workspace</topic>
    <description>Every Alpha Anywhere application begins with a Workspace. Learn how to create a new workspace for a mobile or web application by following this step-by-step guide.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>    
        <section>
            <description>
                To create a new mobile application with Alpha Anywhere, you must create a new workspace. A workspace contains all of the files that your application needs, including files such as components, javascript libraries, images, HTML or .a5w pages, or css stylesheets. Let's create a new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Launch Alpha Anywhere. Under the *[ui:File]* menu, select *[ui:New Workspace...]* to create a new Alpha Anywhere project.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Create a New Workspace from the File menu.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Create a new directory. This directory is where you will save your project. Give the directory a name that will make sense for the project you are building.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Create a new directory where your workspace will be saved.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Navigate inside the directory you created. In the *[ui:File name:]* text box, type in the same name you gave the directory. A good naming convention for Alpha Anywhere projects is to give the workspace the same name as its parent directory. Click the *[ui:Save]* button to create your new workspace.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Naming your workspace.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>When the *[ui:Startup Control Panel]* appears, check the box for *[ui:Open the Web Control Panel when this Workspace is opened]* if you plan to use this workspace to create a Web or Mobile application. The Web Control Panel is where all of the resources for a web or mobile application are listed. Click *[ui:OK]* to finish creating your new workspace.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Specifying the Web Control Panel should be opened when the Workspace is opened.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Now that you have created a workspace, you can start building your application.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For a a step-by-step guild on building a web or mobile appliction, check out one of our tutorials listed in the See Also section below.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref href="Build a Mobile App/index.xml">Build Your First Mobile App</ref>
        <ref href="Build the Sample Mobile App/index.html">Build the Sample Mobile Application</ref>
        <ref href="Build a Web App/index.xml">Building Your First Web Application</ref>
    </see>
</page>