<page>
    <topic>Getting Started with Alpha Anywhere Tutorials</topic>
    <description>Experience how simple it is to go from Install to Deploy with Alpha Anywhere. These tutorials are geared towards new users.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Installing and Registering Alpha Anywhere</title>
            <description>
                <p>*[Installing Alpha Anywhere]*</p>
                <p>Don't have Alpha Anywhere installed? No problem. The [Installation Guide] describes how to install Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>*[Registering Alpha Anywhere]*</p>
                <p>Once you have Alpha Anywhere installed, the next step is to register the product and learn about the IDE. [Alpha Anywhere Developer Environment: First Launch] describes what to expect when you first launch Alpha Anywhere as well as walks you through registering the product and creating an Alpha Anywhere workspace.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Building Your First Application</title>
            <description>
                <p>After you have installed and registered Alpha Anywhere, you are ready to begin building your first application. Choose one of the tutorials below to start building your first Web or Mobile Application.</p>
                <p>Our Getting Started Tutorials are broken into two tracks: Mobile and Web. If you need to build applications that will be used in the field and need to work with or without an internet connection, start with our [Build Your First Mobile App] tutorial. If your users will always have a connection and will typically be working on a laptop, start with our [Build Your First Web App] tutorial.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[[Build Your First Mobile App]]*</p>
                        <p>Build a Mobile Application that interacts with the Northwind database, an Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. You will learn how to build connection strings to interact with SQL databases and the basic building blocks of mobile applications in Alpha Anywhere. When you complete this tutorial, you will have a mobile application that is ready to deploy using PhoneGap Build.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[[Build Your First Web App]]*</p>
                        <p>Get a flying start to building your first web application with Alpha Anywhere's Flying Start Genie. In this tutorial, you'll build a web application with a Tabbed UI interface that can be used to manage data in the Northwind database, an Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. You will learn how the Flying Start Genie can be used to quickly get started building web applications.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Alpha Anywhere Basics</title>
            <description>Learn some of the basic concepts in Alpha Anywhere that are key to building mobile and web applications. If you are new to Alpha Anywhere, you can dive straight into one of our Building Your First Application tutorials listed above. They will explain everything you need to know from launch to finish.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Creating a New Workspace] - Every Alpha Anywhere application begins with a new workspace. Learn how to create a new workspace for creating a web or mobile application.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Creating an AlphaADO Connection String] - Nearly every business application needs to interact with a database. Alpha Anywhere appliactions can communicate with a wide variate of databases using AlphaDAO connection strings. AlphaDAO stands for "Alpha Anywhere Data Access Object". Using AlphaDAO connection strings, you can perform Create, Read, Update, and Delete (CRUD) on a wide variety of SQL databases. Follow this tutorial to learn how to create an Access, MySQL, or SQL Server connection string.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[The Development Server] - The Development Server is required to view an application published to the local webroot. It is also required if you wish to perform a Live Preview or Remote Test. This guide walks you through setting up the Alpha Anywhere Development Server to run in your development environment.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Publishing to the Local Webroot] - A publishing profile defines where your web application is published. This guide teaches you how to create a publishing profile to publish your project to the local webroot. When you complete this tutorial, you will know how to publish and test your web projects on your develompent machine.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Working and Live Preview] - Components can be tested and viewed using the Working Preview and Live Preview. Learn the difference between these two tools and how they can help you design and build Alpha Anywhere applications.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Remote Testing] - Remote Test allows you to run your application on another device, such as a smartphone or tablet, that is connected to the same network as your computer. This step-by-step guide walks you through creating a Remote Test.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Other Tutorials</title>
            <description>These tutorials require you to have some initial experience with Alpha Anywhere. They explain how to perform more complex tasks using Alpha Anywhere.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Build the Sample Mobile Application] - This tutorial is a step-by-step guide on how to create the sample mobile application that ships with Alpha Anywhere. You will need to install the "Demo Mobile Application" that ships with Alpha Anywhere to follow along with tutorial.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>[Photo App Tutorial] - In this 90 minute video, Dan Bricklin walks you through the process of building a web and mobile application that can capture and store images in a SQL database. You will need to [Create a New Workspace] before you begin this tutorial.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="../Installation/index.xml">Installation Guide</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/First Launch/index.xml">Alpha Anywhere Developer Environment: First Launch</link>
        <link href="Build a Mobile App/index.xml">Build Your First Mobile App</link>
        <link href="Build a Web App/index.xml">Build Your First Web App</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/Create a Workspace.xml">Creating a New Workspace</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/Create a Workspace.xml">Create a New Workspace</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/Create a Connection String.xml">Creating an AlphaADO Connection String</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/DevelopmentServer/index.xml">The Development Server</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/PublishLocalhost.xml">Publishing to the Local Webroot</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/PreviewComponent.xml">Working and Live Preview</link>
        <link href="Basic Tutorials/RemoteTest.xml">Remote Testing</link>
        <link href="Other Tutorials/Build the Sample Mobile App/index.html">Build the Sample Mobile Application</link>
        <link href="Other Tutorials/Photo App Tutorial.xml">Photo App Tutorial</link>
    </links>
</page>