<page>
	  <topic>Define Named Layouts</topic>

   <description>The Defined named layouts property gives you access to the Named Layouts Builder.</description>
	   
<sections>
      <section>
            <description>Clicking the [...] button next to the 'Define named layouts' property will open the builder.</description>
          <figure>
                <title>The Named Layout Builder</title>
                <link>images/namedlayout1.png</link></figure>
      </section>
      <section>
           <title>Create a Named Layout</title> 
            <steps>
                  <step>
                        <description>Open the grid builder, define a Data Source and Query, and select four fields to use with the grid in the Fields page.
                              This example uses for fields from the Northwinds database's Customers table.
                        </description>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>Find the 'Multiple Named Layouts'' section in Grid Properties.</description>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>Check the 'Has named layouts'' checkbox and then click the [...] button next to the Define named layouts property.
                              The Named Layout Builder will open.
                        </description>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>Click the 'Add New Layout' button under the 'Named Layouts:' menu. The New Named Layout dialog will open.</description>
                <figure><link>images/phone.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>Give the layout the name 'Phone' and click OK.</description>
                           <figure><link>images/phone2.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>In the 'Named Layout Properties' section find the Layout type and select SingleColumn from the dropdown.</description>
                  <figure><link>images/phone3.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>In the Grid Templates section of the Named Layout Properties, click the [...] button next to the Row template property.</description>
                  <figure><link>images/phone4.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                   <step>
                        <description>The 'Named Layout - Row Template' editor will open. On the left side of the editor is a list of available fields.
                              Double click on each available field to add it to the layout definition. 
                        </description>
                           <figure><link>images/phone5.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>These are the fields that will appear in the layout. The result should look something like this:</description>
                          <figure><link>images/phone6.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>Optionally you can add some html breaks between the field placeholders so that the fields will stack vertically. Click OK to close the editor.</description>
                        <figure><link>images/phone7.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>In the 'Named Layout Builder' click on the [...] button next to the Title template property.</description>
             <figure><link>images/phone8.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>This will open the 'Named Layout - Column Titles' editor. This is where you can define how the layout will sort, if there will be sorting options, and what field will be used.</description>
                        <figure><link>images/phone9.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <description>Select a placeholder starting with "{grid.columnSorterLink:Field=" from the Available fields list that uses a field that you want the layout to sort by.
                              Double click on the placeholder to add it to the field definition. This example will sort based on the ContactName field. </description>
                  <figure><link>images/phone10.png</link></figure>
                  </step>
                  
            </steps>
            
      </section>
      
</sections>	
<links>
      <link href="images/open.png">...</link>
</links>

</page>