<page>
    <topic>Quick Panels Dialog</topic>
    <description>The Quick Panels Dialog allows you to define a complex Panel layout quickly.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can add multiple Panels (Panel Navigators, Panel Cards and Panel Layouts) at once using the Quick Panel Genie. Panels can have an optional header and/or footer. You can also add static text objects and buttons.</p>
                <p>Double-click the placeholder listed in the left-hand column to insert it in the Quick Panel editor. For a Panel Card, Panel Layout, or Panel Navigator, you will be prompted to choose whether or not the panel should also be created with a header and/or footer.</p>
                <p>Items can be placed inside Panels using *[tabs]* (not spaces) to indicate that an object belongs inside a Panel. Panels can be nested inside Panels, as well as buttons and static text objects.</p>
            </description>
            <note>Because indentation is used to indicate containership, there is no need to put in 'ending' directives. For example, there is no need for a *[xb:{PanelCard}]* to be followed by a *[xb:{PanelCardEnd}]* directive.</note>
            <figure>
                <title>Inserting a Panel Card</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_InsertPlaceholder.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The *[xb:{PanelCard}]* is used to create a Panel Card. In the following example, a Panel Card with a Static Text Object will be generated.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{PanelCard}
    {StaticTextObject}
]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Controls generated from Quick Panels using the {PanelCard} placeholder</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_Panel.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The *[xb:{PanelCard-H}]*, *[xb:{PanelCard-F}]*, and *[xb:{PanelCard-HF}]* can be used to create a Panel Card with a Header, Footer, or Header and Footer. For example, the following creates a Panel Card with a header and a static text object:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{PanelCard-H}
    {StaticTextObject}]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Controls generated from Quick Panels using the {PanelCard-H} placeholder</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_PHeader.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>This example creates a Panel Card with a header, footer and static text object:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{PanelCard-HF}
    {StaticTextObject}]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Controls generated from Quick Panels using the {PanelCard-HF} placeholder</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_PHeaderFooter.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Here is a more complex example showing a Panel Navigator with 3 child Panel Cards. Note that one of the Panel Cards has a header and footer.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{PanelNavigator}
    {PanelCard}
    {PanelCard-HF}
    {PanelCard}]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Controls generated for 3 Panel Cards nested inside a Panel Navigator</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_3Panel.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Here is the same layout but with the addition of static text objects to help identify the current Panel Card when testing the component.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{PanelNavigator}
    {PanelCard}
        {StaticTextObject:some text1}
    {PanelCard-HF}
        {StaticTextObject:some text2}
    {PanelCard}
        {StaticTextObject:some text3}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Predefined Layouts</title>
            <description>
                <p>There are several pre-defined layouts available. To insert a pre-defined layout, click the *[ui:Insert pre-defined layout]* link. The pre-defined Layouts dialog lists the layouts availalbe, including a description of the layout and the code that will be inserted into the Quick Panel editor.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Pre-defined Layouts dialog</title>
                <link>images/quickPanels_preDefinedLayouts.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Quick Panel Placeholders</title>
            <description>Placeholders used to define the panel layout in the Quick Panel Genie are listed below.</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Placeholder</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelCard}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Card</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelCard-H}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Card with a Header</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelCard-F}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Card with a Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelCard-HF}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Card with a Header and Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelLayout}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Layout</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelLayout-H}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Layout with a Header</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelLayout-F}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Layout with a Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelLayout-HF}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Layout with a Header and Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelNavigator}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Navigator</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelNavigator-H}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Navigator with a Header</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelNavigator-F}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Navigator with a Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{PanelNavigator-HF}</name>
                    <description>Creates a Panel Navigator with a Header and Footer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{StaticTextObject}</name>
                    <description>Creates a static text object. Use a colon ':' to define the text to be displayed in the text object. EG: *[xb:{StaticTextObject:This is a static text object}]*</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{ButtonObject}</name>
                    <description>Creates a button. Use a colon ':' to define the text in the button. EG: *[xb:{ButtonObject:Click Me!}]*</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{Predefined:Splitview}</name>
                    <description>Creates a split-view layout with a 'menu' Panel and 'master' Panel wrapped in a Panel Layout. If the window size is large enough, the 'menu' Panel is shown. Otherwise, the 'menu' Panel is docked and a button is shown in a Panel Header for displaying the menu.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{Predefined:SplitviewWithIcons}</name>
                    <description>Creates a split-view layout with a 'menu' Panel and 'master' Panel wrapped in a Panel Layout. Generates the same controls as the {Predefined:Splitview} but uses an icon to show/hide the docked 'menu' Panel.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>{Predefined:SplitviewWithIconsAndPanels}</name>
                    <description>Creates a split-view layout with a 'menu' Panel and 'master' Panel wrapped in a Panel Layout. Generates the same controls as the {Predefined:Splitview} but uses an icon to show/hide the docked 'menu' Panel. Icons are included in the menu items and sample Panel Cards for each menu item are also created.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
            <note>Predefined placeholders should be inserted without additional placeholders. Any placeholers added alongside a Predefined placeholder will be ignored by the Quick Panel Genie.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>