<page>
	<topic>How to configure a Postgres connection</topic>
<description>In order to configure a Postgres connection it is necessary to first do the following. </description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>You must install the 32-bit ANSI version of the PostgreSQL client. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>When configuring data sources on 64-bit systems you must use the 32-bit version of the ODBC Data Source Administrator. This is applicable for ALL ODBC drivers we don't wrap directly. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>In order to verify that the driver is properly installed (for all ODBC drivers and extension drivers - meaning everything except for Oracle, DB2, and MySQL) on 64-bit systems, you must use the 32-bit version of the ODBC Data Source Administrator. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>For all servers, clients must also be granted access to the server. Problems with this will be identified in trying to create a DSN using ODBC, but
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>In all cases, the server must open the appropriate firewall port (they vary by database  see the connection string dialog for defaults and they can be overridden, which is often recommended). </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>For PostgreSQL, this also requires editing of the file pg_hba.conf in the server installs data directory (located under PostgreSQL - for example c:\Program Files\PostgreSQL\9.0\data on 32-bit Windows XP). 
</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Example</title>
			
			<description>To be sure that the 32-bit ANSI driver is installed, please look at the drivers tab of the 32-bit ODBC Administrator:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/postgres1.jpg</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>Next test the PostgreSQL driver by creating and testing a DSN using the ODBC Data Source Administrator:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/postgres2.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>Follow the same steps in the Alpha Anywhere Connection String dialog:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/postgres3.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>Result:</description>
			<figure><link>images/postgres4.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</section>
	</sections>
	
</page>