<page>
	  <topic>Control type</topic>
<description>You can pick what type of control you want to represent a given field using the Control Type property.</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Discussion</title>
	<description>If your grid is ' Read only ', then the fields that you put on the grid will be displayed by default using Label  controls. If the grid is Updateable , then the fields initially will be displayed using textbox controls. Label controls  display the value of the field but do not have a width setting. In contrast, Textbox controls always have a specified character width, even if the field is Read only. For some data types, such as  Images  and dates, you will have to manually select the control type. You can select other control type by using the Control Type dropdown under Display Settingsin the Field Properties list.  </description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Label</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_alabel.png</link></figure>
			<description>A read-only control suitable for character, numeric, and date/time data.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Textbox</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol2.png</link></figure>
			<description>An editable control suitable for character, numeric, and date/time data.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>TextArea</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol3.png</link></figure>
			<description>Similar to a text box, but with multiple lines.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Link</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol4.png</link></figure>
			<description>A link that may open another page or select a record to display.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Image</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol5.png</link></figure>
			<description>Displays either embedded or linked images.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DropDownBox  </title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol6.png</link></figure>
			<description>A list box that appears as either a list or combo box. Drop-down boxes present a selection from an existing list of values; that is hard coded or retrieved from a table.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>RadioButton  </title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol7.png</link></figure>
			<description>A circular button that allows users to select from a list of values.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Checkbox</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol8.png</link></figure>
			<description>A square box that allows a selection from a list of values.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Custom</title>
			<figure><link>images/01_acontrol9.png</link></figure>
			<description>You define the data to display and its formatting using Xbasic and HTML.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Hidden</title>
			
			<description>Hides controls without hiding the column that contains them.  
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<figure><link>images/01_acontrol10.png</link></figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>code reference:</description>
		<example><![CDATA[tmpl.Field_Info[N]         .controltype as C]]></example>
	</case>
	
</cases>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>
  
  
	
</page>