<page>
	<topic>Display Format</topic>
	<description>If the control type is Label, Link, TextBox, or TextArea, the Display Format property allows you to automatically change the presentation of your data. </description>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>For example, a money value could be displayed with its currency symbol and commas, and with the correct number of decimal characters. An In-Line style overrides the formatting of the cascading style sheet. If you wanted the text to be bolded, or in a different font, point size, or color, this is where you would define the formatting. </description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>You may want to allow only certain users to see a field. To do this set a minimum user security level required before the field will display. 
You may want to allow the user to see the fields in a grid, but not edit, delete, or insert records. To do this, set three different permission properties that control grid update. 
You may also want to define validation rules to improve the quality of user input. 
   </description>
</section>

<section>
	<description>This expression formats the data after it has been entered into the field. Click to display the Display Format dialog box. This property should be set to one of the following values: 
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[Null (empty) ]]></example>
</section>

<section>
	<description><![CDATA[An Xbasic expression that returns a character value. The expression should use & < value> as Placeholder for the field value, as in the following example:]]></description>
	<example><![CDATA[f_upper(& < value>)]]></example>
</section>
<section>
	<description>Optionally, click Select Pre-Defined Format to select a format from the Pre-Defined Formats dialog box. </description>
	<note>There are no predefined display formats for short time (Y) fields. However, you can write your own.  </note>
</section>
<section>
	<note>If the control type is "TextBox" and the field type is "Date", then a Date Picker will appear. You must set the tmpl.Field_Info[N].DatePicker.DateFormat to the same style. See Date Picker DateFormat.  </note>
</section>

<sections>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>display format code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.Field_Info[N]     .DisplayFormat as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>display unformat code reference</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.Field_Info[N]     .DisplayUnFormat as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</sections>


	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>