<page>
    <topic>UX Component - FlexLayout Containers</topic>
    <description>A new container type in the UX component makes it easy to dynamically size controls when the orientation of the device changes (mobile devices), or the window size changes (desktop browsers).</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_flexLayoutContainer_1.swf</link>
                    </video>
                    <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_flexLayoutContainer_2.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section> 
        <section>
            <description>The purpose of the FlexLayout container is to dynamically size the widths of controls that are on a single line. This container does not size the height of controls.</description>
            <note>FlexLayout containers are not supported in Repeating Sections.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For example in the image below, the device is in portrait mode. The button to the right of the textbox control is set to have a fixed size of 80px. The text box has been set to have a flexible width, so it consumes all of the available space (less the built-in padding between controls, defined by the A5CWLayout class padding property).</description>
            <figure><link>images/flexlayout1.jpg</link></figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Notice in the image below, when the device orientation is changed to landscape, the button size has not changed - it is still 80px wide. But the textbox had grown in width.</description>
            <figure><link>images/flexlayout2.jpg</link></figure> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Here is how the textbox and button control are represented in the builder. Note that the controls are wrapped in a container with a sub-type of 'FlexLayout'.</description>
            <figure><link>images/flexlayout3.jpg</link></figure> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>When you set the container sub-type to FlexLayout, a new property in the Property Grid is exposed.  The image shows that the 'Flexible layout width settings' have been set to:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[flex(1),80px]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>This means that the first control in the FlexLayout container will have relative width of flex(1) (this is the textbox), and the second control (i.e. the button) will have a fixed width of 80px.</description>
            <figure><link>images/flexlayout4.gif</link></figure> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The property has a smart field which brings up a builder to help you set the control widths.</p>
                <p>Notice that the builder also shows the 'Defined Width' for each control. The 'Defined Width' is the width that was defined for each individual control.</p>
                <p>Typically when you wrap controls in a FlexLayout container, you will want to set each control's Defined Width to 100%. The builder will show you at a glance if any of the top-level controls in the FlexLayout container have not been set to 100%.</p>
                <p>The 'Break' column will also show you at a glance if any of the top-level controls in the FlexLayout have breaks after them. You should not have breaks after top-level controls, so the builder will give you a warning to fix this problem.</p>
            </description>
            <figure><link>images/flexlayout5.jpg</link></figure> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In the case where only one control in a FlexLayout container has a 'flex' width, the meaning of the flex setting is simply to fill the available space on the line (after allocating space to the fixed size controls).</p>
                <p>However, if you have two or more controls with a 'flex' setting, then all of the flex controls together will fill the available space (after allotting space to any fixed size controls), and each 'flex' control will have a relative size based on its 'flex' setting.</p>
                <p>For example, if you have two flex controls with settings of flex(1) and flex(2), then the second control will always be twice the width of the first control.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>


</page>