<page>
    <topic>afterCancelBatch</topic>
<description>If the List is being synchronized in batches, fires after the user has clicked the 'Cancel' button to stop sending batches of records to the server to synchronize.</description>
 
<sections>
    
    
    <section>
        <title>What is a Batch?</title>
        <description>In a disconnected application a user might have been disconnected for quite some time, during which they may have done a fair 
            number of edits on their client-side device. When they get their connection back, the user might then click on a synchronize button in order to 
            add their edits back to the server. However, because they made a large number of edits, it is quite likely that the server might take a while 
            to actually process all of the changes that the user made. While the server is processing information it is likely that the user/client would 
            be waiting for a response and, if the server takes to long, might even time out before recieving said response. One way to avoid this 
            problem is to send the edits made in 'batches' to the server, such that the user can get feedback as to what progress has been made. For a complete 
            guide to setting up a detail view that uses batches to synchronize with a server see the [Synchronization using Batches] page.
        </description>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>The Cancel Button</title>
        
        <figure><link>images/cancelsynch.png</link></figure>
      
    </section>
    <section>
          <description>A Cancel button can be used to stop sending batches. This button can easily  be defined on the Detail View pane in the list builder 
            by clicking the [...] button next to the 'Synchronization progress properties' property.</description>
        
           <figure><link>images/cancel2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Tie a Message Box to an afterCancelBatch Event</title>
        <description>Once the Cancel button is defined an afterCancelBatch event can be defined using javascript; to specify what happens 
            after the Cancel button is clicked.
        </description>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <description>Build a detail view that has a synchronization button. The guide on the [Synchronization using Batches] page has instructions on how to do this.</description>
         <figure><link>images/cancel5.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>On the Detail View pane of the List Builder under Client-side Events, click the [...] button next to the 'Events' property.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel3.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Highlight the afterCancelBatch event and click the Action Javascript button.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel6.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Click Create/Edit Javascript Action.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cancel7.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
             <step>
                <description>Click Add New Action. Give the new action a name like cancelMessage and click OK</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel8.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Click the Edit Action Button</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel9.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Click the green '+' or Add New Action button.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel10.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>From the Actions list select 'Message Box' and click OK</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel12.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Check the 'Use advanced message box' property.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel11.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Click the [...] next to the Message box title property to open the HTML editor. Define some HTML for the message box title. Click Save.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel13.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Click the [...] next to the Message box text property to open the HTML editor. Add some text to the message box. Click Save</description>
               
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Click on the OK or Save buttons to get back to the UX Builder. Run the component in Live Preview. Highlight rows in the list control and 
                    make a number of edits in the detail view. Dirty fields will display yellow triangles in the List control.</description>
                <figure><link>images/cancel4.png</link></figure>
            </step>
             <step>
                <description>Click the Save and Synchronize buttons. The status bar at the top of the component should start and the 'Cancel'
                    button should become active. Click the Cancel button before the synchronization finishes. You should see the message box that you defined appear.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/break2.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            
        </steps>
        
        
    </section>
</sections>
<links>
    <link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/pages/Guides/Web%20Components/UX%20Components/UX%20Controls/Data%20Controls/List/Synchronization%20using%20Batches.xml">Synchronization using Batches</link>
    
</links>
</page>