<page>
    <topic>afterCancelBatch</topic>
<description>If the List is being synchronized in batches, fires after the user has clicked the 'Cancel' button to stop sending batches of records to the server to synchronize.</description>
 
<sections>
    
    
    <section>
        <title>What is a Batch?</title>
        <description>In a disconnected application a user might have been disconnected for quite some time, during which they may have done a fair 
            number of edits on their client-side device. When they get their connection back, the user might then click on a synchronize button in order to 
            add their edits back to the server. However, because they made a large number of edits, it is quite likely that the server might take a while 
            to actually process all of the changes that the user made. While the server is processing information it is likely that the user/client would 
            be waiting for a response and, if the server takes to long, might even time out before recieving said response. One way to avoid this 
            problem is to send the edits made in 'batches' to the server, such that the user can get feedback as to what progress has been made. 
        </description>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>The Cancel Button</title>
        
        <figure><link>images/cancelsynch.png</link></figure>
      
    </section>
    <section>
          <description>A Cancel button can be used to stop sending batches. This button can easily  be defined on the Detail View pane in the list builder 
            by clicking the [...] button next to the 'Synchronization progress properties' property.</description>
        
           <figure><link>images/cancel2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Defining afterCancelBatch</title>
        <steps>
            <step>
                
                
            </step>
            
            
        </steps>
        
        
    </section>
</sections>
</page>