<page>
    <shortlink>transform app 5_1_0</shortlink>
    <topic>Version 5.1.0</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Upgraded offline data storage to handle storing more information, added additional metadata fields for user-defined data, enhanced support for HTML markup, and various bug fixes.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The technology through which downloaded and user-input data is temporarily saved ("persisted") on the mobile device before uploading to the server has been changed. These changes should have little user-visible effect, but will allow the app to support a much larger amount of data in a more robust manner. The migration from the previous form of persistence storage to the new is performed automatically.</p>
        <p>Additional form instance metadata fields have been added that the form designer may make use of. This includes a "Due Date" field that may be checked by the forms list filtering. The list filtering was upgraded to enable selecting fields or attributes that do not have a value instead of just those having a value.</p>
        <p>HTML tables (including the colspan and rowspan attributes) can now be included in new forms.</p>
        <p>An On-Device Data Info command was added to Other Actions.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Bug Fixes this release</title>
            <description>
                <p>TF10000128 - Field titles are now truncated if no short title has been defined and the regular title is too long to fit in the header. Appends "..." to the truncated title.</p>
                <p>TF10000129 - Improved support for lists that contain a large number of choices.</p>
                <p>TF10000130 - Fixed issue where pinch/zoom was not enabled in iOS when using inAppBrowser()</p>
                <p>TF10000131 - Fixed issue where images occasionally did not appear in forms when offline and were repeatedly downloaded unnecessarily when refreshed.</p>
                <p>TF10000132 - Support for HTML tables added in new TPL forms: &lt;table&gt;, &lt;tr&gt;,&lt;td&gt;, and the "colspan" and "rowspan" attributes.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>