<page>
    <shortlink>ux control properties panel card properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Panel Card Properties</topic>
    <description>A Panel Card can be added to component through the 'Panels' menu. 
        Panel cards are useful for defining the different screens, or panels, that a user will see as they 
        navigate through an application on a mobile device. If panel cards are 
        being used inside a component, then every control in that component must be inside a specified 
        panel card. Panel card's come with their own set of properties, listed here:</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Panel card type</title>
            <description>
                <p>The panel card type. The type can be either *[Default]* or *[IFrame]*:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Type</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Default</name>
                            <description>The contents of the Panel Card are defined as controls placed within the Panel Card begin and end controls.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>IFrame</name>
                            <description>The contents of the Panel Card are loaded from a URL and embedded in an &lt;iframe&gt; HTML element.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>IFrame URL</title>
            <description>
                <p>If the *[ui:Panel card type]* is *[IFrame]*, the URL to load.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Id</title>
            <description>
                <p>The ID of the panel card.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Sub-theme</title>
            <description>
                <p>A sub-theme (display variant) to use for the Panel Card. Choose from sub-themes included in the web theme or [a sub-theme you created].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Display name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The display name to be used instead of the Id when the panel name is displayed, such as in a header, footer, or tab in a Panel Navigator.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Panel Class name</title>
            <description>
                <p>One or more classes applied to the entire Panel Card.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Panel body class name</title>
            <description>
                <p>One or more classes applied to the body section of the Panel card.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Panel body style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Set the in-line style for the Panel Card body. Typically you can leave this blank, except for the situation where you display an embedded Component in the Card. In this case, you will typically set the style to</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="css"><![CDATA[padding: 0px;]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Center panel contents</title>
            <description>
                <p>If enabled, centers the contents of the Panel Card in the middle of the panel. Contents will be centered horizontally and vertically.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Has background image</title>
            <description>
                <p>An image used as the background of the Panel Card.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The background image name. Shown when *[ui:Has background image]* is enabled.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Pinch to zoom</title>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:Pinch to zoom]* enables the ability for the user to "pinch zoom" the contents of the Panel card. Pinch zooming is useful for manually magnifying content, such as images or text that may be too small to read on the user's device.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pinchtozoom.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Resetting the Zoom Level</title>
            <description>
                <p>To programmatically reset the zoom level, use the [{dialog.object}.unZoomPanelCard()] method:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[// Reset the zoom level for PANEL_1:
{dialog.object}.unZoomPanelCard('PANEL_1');]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux%20controls%20panels">Panels</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link link="ux unzoompanelcard method">{dialog.object}.unZoomPanelCard()</link>
        <link link="howto%20createsubtheme">a sub-theme you created</link>
    </links>
</page>