<page>
	  <topic>Introduction</topic>

   <description>Grids have a property called 'Alternate Views'. An Alternate View is simply another way of displaying the data in the Grid. You can define custom Alternate View (using Xbasic), or you can use one of the built-in Alternate Views. The most commonly used built-in Alternate View is a Google Map. This is used to plot the data displayed in the Grid as markers on a Google Map. </description>
	
<sections>
	<section>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Defining an Alternate View with a Google Map and showing a marker on the map for each record in the Grid. </description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Defining the bubble help for each marker on the Grid so that it shows data from the corresponding record in the Grid.  </description>
	</step>
	
</steps>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<videos>
			<video>
				<name>Watch Video GM1</name>
				<description>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/GoogleMapping_1.swf</description>
			</video>
			
		</videos>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v11download/airport.zip  
</description>
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>New mapping features . grid based on table that has all of the airports in the United States. Have latitude and longitude of the airport. Map of US with a marker on the grid for each airport
Can do a search on California, look at the map, see all the airports listed on the first page of the grid.
</description>
	
	</section>	
	<section>
		<description>Grid with a detail view that pops up in a popup modal window. In order to turn on the map, we will go to Alternate Views. Turn on Has Alternate Views, bring up Alternate View Builder. Select Google Map Alternate View. Give it ID and A Label. Can define properties of this map. Define type, can be address or location (if you have lat and long) If you have address for some lat and long for others you can use the auto feature. Google places no limits on pw many callbacks you can make for latitude and longitude but you can't do this with addresses. Choose location, then specify which field in the table contains latitude and which field contains the longitude and place these next to the latitude and longitude expression properties, Then define the title expression</description>
	</section>
	</sections>	
	
</page>