<page>
	<topic>Add Button Dialog</topic>
<description>The Add Button dialog specifies the characteristics of a button used when setting Advanced Text Properties for a Conditional Expression. 
</description>	

<sections>
	<section>
		
<figure><link>images/UG_Add_Button_Dialog.gif</link></figure>	
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select the Button Style. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Text Only"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap Only"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap-Text"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Text-Bitmap"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Text over Bitmap"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap over Text"
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>If the Button Style uses text, enter it into the Button Text control. You may click 'xy' to use the Expression Builder to compose an expression that returns a text caption.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>If the Button Style uses text, optionally enable Custom Font Attributes to specify additional text formatting options.
</description><cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Optionally, click the 'up' arrow to select a color in the Text Color control.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Optionally, click the 'up' arrow to select a color in the Background Color control.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Optionally, click 'up' arrow to select a font in the Font control.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, select Horizontal Justification. The options are:
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Left"
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Center"
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Right"
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, select Vertical Justification. The options are:
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>"Top"
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Center"
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>"Bottom"
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</case>
	
</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select a Border Style for the button. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Raised"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Flyover"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Modern"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"None" - produces a round cornered button
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>


			</step>
			<step>
				<description>If the Button Style uses a bitmap, click the 'up' arrow to select an image.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, enable Has Flyover Style and display the Flyover Style tab. Assign alternate style attributes for use when the mouse hovers over the button.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, change the Button Width. The measurement is in characters.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, change the Button Height. The measurement is in lines.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, enter Bubble Help that will appear when the mouse hovers over the button.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, check the Enable Expression control. Enter an expression that returns TRUE (.T.) or FALSE (.F.). This expression determines when the button is enabled.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click OK to save your inputs and return to the Advanced Text Properties dialog.
</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
		
		
	</section>
	
</sections>
<limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>


	
</page>