<page>
    <shortlink>transform central permissions roles</shortlink>
    <topic>Roles</topic>
    <description>Distinguishes different classes of users</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Roles help distinguish different classes of users. Each user, for each account to which they have access, is assigned one or more roles. The Roles List enumerates all of the different roles available for an account. Examples of typical roles are "user" and "AccountAdmin".</p>
                <p>The assigned roles are used by TransForm to determine which permissions to use from those specified by a form type's Status/Role Group. These permissions, in turn, help determine for whom and when the form is presented and which operations they may perform on that form.</p>
                <p>The roles are also used to control access to the various tabs on TransForm Central.</p>
                <p>Roles are assigned to users of an account by the Account Administrator. The TransForm Central Home tab has a "Manage users" section, and within that there is a "Manage user roles" sub-section for actually choosing the roles from the list of all possible roles for an account. Changes to roles take effect the next time a user logs in.</p>
                <p>Roles have three values: Role ID, Display, and Description.</p>
                <p>The *[Role ID]* is the actual value that will be used by the system. It must be made up of only letters, numbers, and "_". It must be unique within the account, and is case-sensitive.</p>
                <p>The *[Display]* value will be shown in most cases where the user is shown a role name. This may be a more user-friendly short name for the role and may include spaces and other non-alphanumeric characters. It should be short to fit well in the places where it is displayed. It need not be unique within the account if that makes sense in the situation   (for example, if there are more than one type of "Supervisor" distinguished by Role ID used on totally different types of forms).</p>
                <p>The *[Description]* value, if provided, will be shown in some cases when there is a list of roles from which to   choose to make it easier for the users to understand the meaning or use of a choice for role.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Roles list</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Roles are listed on the left side of the screen. Each row has the information for one type of role, showing the Display value in bold, the Role ID in parenthesis, and the optional Description below.</p>
                <p>Clicking on a row will open that row for editing. There are textboxes for entering and editing each of the three values. New values in a textbox are applied to the current copy when the Set button is clicked, the Enter key is typed on the keyboard, or the textbox loses focus.</p>
                <p>Opened rows also have three buttons: [delete]*[Delete]*, [moveUp]*[Move Up]*, and [moveDown]*[Move Down]*. Delete removes the row. The arrow buttons change the order of the rows. The order is used for most displayed lists of roles.</p>
                <p>Some of the roles and their Role IDs are *[required by TransForm and should not be deleted]*. These are: "user", "AccountAdmin", "FormDesigner", and "ManagementConsole". The last three of these explicitly control access to the TransForm Central tabs and functionality. Any other roles are optional and are used to control Status/Role Group permissions used within the tabs and the Form Filler app.</p>
                <p>On the right side of the header above the Roles list is an [add]*[Add]* button to add a new row. Clicking it will add the new row after the currently selected row, or after the last row if no row is selected.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/moveUp.svg">moveUp</link>
        <link href="/images/moveDown.svg">moveDown</link>
        <link href="/images/add.svg">add</link>
    </links>
</page>