<page>
    <shortlink>transform central permissions statusrolegroups</shortlink>
    <topic>Status/Role Groups</topic>
    <description>Specifies the functionality available to the various combinations of statuses and roles</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>A Status/Role Group specifies the functionality that a user with a particular role attempting to access a form with a particular status has permission to use.</p>
                <p>The permission settings control the ability to:</p>
            </description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Create new forms (form instances) of this type</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>See this type of form in lists of form types</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List, Edit, or Delete forms in the Form Filler app</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Change a form's status to one of a specified list of other status values in the Form Filler App</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List, Edit, or Delete forms in the Management Console</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Change a form's status to one of a specified list of other status values in the Management Console</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Status/Role Groups List enumerates the different available values and their associated permission settings.</p>
                <p>Each type of form has a property that specifies which Status/Role Group controls its permissions. The TransForm Central Form Designer is used to set this value for the form type. The setting is in the Advanced Features part of the form type properties. If a value is not set, the first Status/Role Group in the list is used.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Status/Roles Groups list</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Status/Role Groups are listed in the middle of the screen. Each section of the list has the information for one type of Status/Role Group, showing at the top the Display value in bold red, the Status/Role Group ID in parenthesis, and the optional Description below. Indented below that are the permissions settings.</p>
                <p>On the right side of the header above the Status/Role Group list is an [add]*[Add]* button to add a new section for a new Status/Role Group. Clicking it will add the new section after the currently selected section, or after the last section if no section is selected.</p>
                <p>Clicking on each part of the section for a Status/Role Group will open that part for editing. The place for editing will be on the right side of the screen.</p>
                <p>The parts of each section for a Status/Role Group are:</p>
            </description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>*[ID, Display, and Description]*</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>*[Roles allowed to create new form instances]*</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>*[Roles allowed to browse form type]*</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>*[Status/Role combinations permissions]*</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>ID, Display, and Description</title>
            <description>
                <p>Status/Role Groups have three top-level values: Status/Role Group ID, Display, and Description.</p>
                <p>The *[Status/Role Group ID]* is the actual value that will be used by the system. It must be made up of only letters, numbers, and "_". It must be unique within the account, and is case-sensitive.</p>
                <p>The *[Display]* value will be shown in most cases where the user is shown a Status/Role Group name. This may be a more user-friendly short name than the ID and may include spaces and other non-alphanumeric characters. It should be short to fit well in the places where it is displayed.</p>
                <p>The *[Description]* value, if provided, will be shown in some cases when there is a list of Status/Role Groups from which to   choose to make it easier for the users to understand the meaning or use.</p>
                <p>When this part is clicked, textboxes for entering and editing each of the three values will be shown. New values in a textbox are applied to the current copy when the Set button is clicked, the Enter key is typed on the keyboard, or the textbox loses focus.</p>
                <p>Three buttons will also be shown: [delete]*[Delete]*, [moveUp]*[Move Up]*, and [moveDown]*[Move Down]*. Delete removes the entire Status/Role Group section. The arrow buttons change the order of the sections. The order is used for most displayed lists of Status/Role Groups. The first item in the list is the default Status/Role Group value for form types that have not had that property set.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Roles allowed to create new form instances</title>
            <description>
                <p>This setting specifies which roles are allowed to create new form instances. The setting has an effect in the Management Console and the Form Filler app. When clicked, the list of roles will be displayed along with checkboxes. Users with checked roles will be permitted to create new form instances.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Roles allowed to browse form types</title>
            <description>
                <p>This setting specifies which roles are allowed to see the form type in lists of different types of forms. The setting has an effect in the Management Console and the Form Filler app. When clicked, the list of roles will be displayed along with checkboxes. Users with checked roles will be permitted to see form types associated with the Status/Role Group in lists of available form types.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Status/Role combinations permissions</title>
            <description>
                <p>This part of the Status/Role Group provides the means to set and display   the permissions for each combination of status and role. That is, for each of the possible pairings of a status value and a role value (determined by the current lists of Statues and Roles) a set of permissions properties is displayed. Clicking on the display will open a list of properties on the right of the screen that may be filled in. The pairings are displayed as, at top level, a list of statuses, and then within each status section a section for each of the available roles.</p>
                <p>For each status/role combination, the permission properties let you   control both the Form Filler app and the Management Console tab of TransForm Central. Within each of those, there are checkboxes to provide permission to users with the combination's role to *[List]*, *[Edit]*, and *[Delete]* forms with   the combination's status. So, for example, a person with the role "user" using the Form Filler may be able to list forms with a status of "submitted" but not make changes to the data fields nor delete the forms themselves, while a person with role "supervisor" may have permission in the Management Console to list, edit, and delete them.</p>
                <p>In addition to the List/Edit/Delete permissions, for each combination there is a list of statuses that the form may be changed to, each with a checkbox indicating an allowed new status. For example, a "user" may only be able to change from "open" to "submitted" but not from "submitted" to anything else while a "supervisor" may also be able to change from "submitted" to "open" or "closed".
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/moveUp.svg">moveUp</link>
        <link href="/images/moveDown.svg">moveDown</link>
        <link href="/images/add.svg">add</link>
    </links>
</page>