<page>
    <shortlink>transform central permissions status</shortlink>
    <topic>Statuses</topic>
    <description>Form value to help guide form through life cycle</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>About Statuses</title>
            <description>
                <p>Status values are used to help guide and track forms through their life cycle. Examples of typical status values are "open" and "submitted". Each form (that is, a single instance of a particular type of form along with its current data, if any) has a "status" field. The Status List enumerates of all of the different values that forms in this account may have for this field.</p>
                <p>The Status value is used by TransForm to determine which permissions to use from those specified by a form type's Status/Role Group. These permissions, in turn, help determine for whom and when the form is presented and which operations they may perform on that form.</p>
                <p>The status value is normally set by users as part of working with forms. The initial value is determined by the form type's Initial Status property (set in the Form Designer tab on the Advanced Features section of the Properties). If no Initial Status is provided, the first status in the Status List will be used. Later changes to the status value are made by the user when they use a Change Status button that is part of the form definition or when they use the Change Status menu item on the Form Details Menu. In the Management Console tab of TransForm Central, there is also a Change Status action in the Actions section to let a manager change the status.</p>
                <p>Statuses have three values: Status ID, Display, and Description.</p>
                <p>The *[Status ID]* is the actual value that will be stored in the form status field. It must be made up of only letters, numbers, and "_". It must be unique within the account, and is case-sensitive.</p>
                <p>The *[Display]* value will be shown in most cases where the user is shown a status value. This may be a more user-friendly short name for the status and may include spaces and other non-alphanumeric characters. It should be short to fit well in the places where it is displayed. It need not be unique within the account if that makes sense in the situation (for example, if there are more than one type of "Approval" distinguished by Status ID used on totally different types of forms).</p>
                <p>The *[Description]* value, if provided, will be shown in some cases when there is a list of statuses from which to choose to make it easier for the users to understand the meaning or use of a choice for status.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Statuses list</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Statuses are listed on the left side of the screen. Each row has the information for one type of status, showing the Display value in bold, the Status ID in parenthesis, and the optional Description below.</p>
                <p>Clicking on a row will open that row for editing. There are textboxes for entering and editing each of the three values. New values in a textbox are applied to the current copy when the Set button is clicked, the Enter key is typed on the keyboard, or the textbox loses focus.</p>
                <p>Opened rows also have three buttons: [delete]*[Delete]*, [moveUp]*[Move Up]*, and [moveDown]*[Move Down]*. Delete removes the row. The arrow buttons change the order of the rows. The order is used for most displayed lists of statuses.</p>
                <p>The first status row is also special in that it is the default initial status applied to a new form if none is specified for that type of form.</p>
                <p> On the right side of the header above the Statuses list is an [add]*[Add]* button to add a new row. Clicking it will add the new row after the currently selected row, or after the last row if no row is selected.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
        <link href="/images/moveUp.svg">moveUp</link>
        <link href="/images/moveDown.svg">moveDown</link>
        <link href="/images/add.svg">add</link>
    </links>
</page>