<page build="">
    <shortlink>howto translating report labels</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Translate Labels in Reports</topic>
    <description>The Text Dictionary can be used in reports to automatically translate text, such as labels, when the report is generated.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The labels on Layout Reports can be translated at print-time into different languages by defining a Text Dictionary for the report. The Text Dictionary contains translated values for all of the specially tagged labels in the report definition. For example, you might have a Label on a report with this text:</p>
        <p>
            <example><![CDATA[<a5:t>Report Header</a5:t>]]></example>
        </p>
        <p>At print-time the Text Dictionary is accessed to find a translated string for Report Header in the specified language. In certain cases when the translated string contains certain UTF-8 characters, the labels on the report will not render correctly. This is a limitation that results from the code page of the machine where the server is running.</p>
        <p>To work around this limitation, use the HTML control instead of the Text control on your report.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/report-htmllayoutcontrol.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>For example, add an HTML control to the report then edit the HTML control to add the label text. For example:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="html"><![CDATA[<a5:t>Report Header</a5:t>]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>However, this is not sufficient to work around the problem. You must also add this meta tag to the HTML (in the HTML head section).</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="html"><![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>