<page>
    <shortlink>dynamically adding panels to panel navigator</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Dynamically Add Panels to a Panel Navigator</topic>
    <description>Panels (Panel Cards, Panel Layouts, and child Panel Navigators) can be dynamically added to a Panel Navigator at run-time.</description>
    <discussion>When you create UX component that uses a Panel Navigator, the Panels (Cards, Layouts, and child Navigators) in the Panel Navigator are usually created at design-time. It is not required, however, that the Panels in a Panel Navigator be created at design time.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>You can create Panels at run-time and dynamically add them to the Panel Navigator. The Panel Navigator's *[js:.addPanel()]* method can be called to add Panels. Similarly, you can remove Panels from a Panel Navigator at run-time.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[function addPanel() {
    var id = {dialog.object}.getValue('panelNum');
    if (id == '') {
        alert('Please type a number in the textbox before clicking the button');
        return false;
    }

    //specify a unique name for the new Panel
    var panelName = 'NEWPANEL_' + id;
    var panelTitle = 'Pane ' + id;

    //define a new Panel Card
    var myNewPanelCard = new A5.PanelCard({
        theme : '{dialog.style}',
        body: {
            content: {
                type: 'html',
                src: 'this is my new panel text for: ' + panelName
                }
            }
        });

    //get a pointer to the Panel Navigator where the new Panel will be added
    var pNav = {dialog.object}.panelGet('PANELNAVIGATOR_1');

    //add the new Panel Card to the Panel Navigator

    pNav.addPanel({
        name: panelName,
        title: panelTitle,
        src: myNewPanelCard
    });

    //optionally, set focus to the new Panel
    pNav.setActivePanel(panelName);

}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Watch the videos below to learn more about how to dynamically add Panels to a Panel Navigator.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Dynamically Adding Panels to a Panel Navigator Part 1</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_dynamicallyAddPanels_1.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Dynamically Adding Panels to a Panel Navigator Part 2</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_dynamicallyAddPanels_2.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>[Click here] to download the component shown in the videos above.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/Ux_dynamicPanelsInPanelNavigator.zip">Click here</link>
    </links>
</page>