<page build="5456" api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 u array move method</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.u.array.series" parentType="namespace" elementName="move Method" >A5.u.array.series.A5.u.array.move Method</topic>
	<prototype>A5.u.array.move(array,indexes,location)</prototype>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name>array</name>
			<type>array</type>
			<description>The array to move items in.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>indexes</name>
			<types><type>number</type><type>array</type><type>object</type></types>
			<description>The array of index(es) to move.</description>
		<properties>
			<property>
				<name>start</name>
				<type>number</type>
				<description>When selecting a range of items, the index to start on.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>end</name>
				<type>number</type>
				<description>When selecting a range of items, the index to end on. Either the end or length must be specified.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>length</name>
				<type>number</type>
				<description>When selecting a range of items, the number of items to move. Either the end or length must be specified.</description>
			</property>
		</properties>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>location</name>
			<types><type>number</type><type>string</type></types>
			<description>The location to move the array items to. Can be the index to move them to, or a string with relative movement commands.</description>
		</argument>
	</arguments>
	<returns>
		<return>
			<name>moved</name>
			<type>boolean</type>
			<description>Whether or not items were moved.</description>
		</return>
	</returns>
	<description> Move the items with the given indexes in the array.</description>
	<discussion>
<p>
The A5.u.array.move method moves items in an array.
The indexes can either be specified as a single number, and array of numbers, or an object that specifies the start index and either end index or length.
None contiguous indexes will be clustered into a single continuos group before the move occurs.
</p>
<p>
The location to move the items to can be specified as either an index, or a relative command.
A string of "start" or "top" will move the items to the beginning of the array, while "end" or "bottom" will move the items to the end of the array.
A string of "up" or "back" will decrease the item indexes relative to the first item, while "down" or "forward" will move increase the item indexes relative to the last item.
These relative movements can be adjusted by adding a numeric suffix, for example "down+2" will move the selected indexes 3 down from the last item.
</p>
</discussion>
	<example code="js">
var a = ['a','b','c','d','e','f','g','h','i'];
A5.u.array.move(a,[3,5],6);
// a = ['a','b','c','e','g','h','d','f','i']
A5.u.array.move(a,2,'up');
// a = ['a','c','b','e','g','h','d','f','i']</example>
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/u_namespace/array_namespace/series_namespace/A5.u.array.move Method.xml</annotations>
</page>
