<page>
   <topic>HELP_FILE_VIEW Function</topic>
   <syntax>V help_file_view([C helptable [,C initial_link [,C dialog_title ]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>helptable</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "Help.DBF". The name of the Alpha Anywhere help file. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>initial_link</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = No topic. The chapter and topic in the help file, separated by a colon. For example, " Invoice Form:Lastname " indicates the "Invoice Form" chapter and the "Lastname" topic within that chapter. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>dialog_title</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "Alpha Five Help". The title of the dialog. Character</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description> A popup help viewer.  helptable is the table to be used.</description>
   <discussion>
HELP_FILE_VIEW() displays a topic from the Alpha Anywhere help system.
The Alpha Anywhere help system is an alternative to developers who do not want to purchase a third party help authoring system for creating standard Windows help (.hlp) files. The Alpha Anywhere help system use Rich Text fields in a standard Alpha Anywhere table (.dbf file). It offers the basic features of a help system such as a table of contents, and hyperlinked help topics.
 Help_Filename is the name of the Alpha Anywhere help file. It is a .dbf file that was specially created using the HELP_FILE_EDIT()command.
 NOTE : The help file may also have been created automatically be Alpha Anywhere if you right clicked on an object on a form, selected the Properties command, and then went to the Help Entry tab and defined help for that object.
 Help_Topic is the chapter and topic in the help file, separated by a colon. For example, Invoice Form:Lastname indicates the Invoice Form chapter and the Lastname topic within that chapter. If Help_Topic is blank, Alpha Anywhere opens the help file with no topic open. The user can use the table of contents to navigate to a topic.
 Note : In addition to displaying help topics from an Alpha Anywhere help file you can also display topics from a standard Windows help file using the WINHELP_SHOW()command.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>The following commands display a topic in an Alpha Anywhere help file.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
Help_filename = :a5.get_path() + "\a_invoice_help.dbf"
Help_chapter = "Invoice Form"
Help_topic = "Lastname"
Help_file_view(help_filename, help_chapter + ":" + help_topic)
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Help Functions</ref>
   </see>
   <terms>help,a5,addition,defaults,display,field,file,forms,function,object,popup,system,table of contents,tabs,text,users,window</terms>
</page>