<page build="7947">
    <shortlink>storage sharepoint</shortlink>
    <topic>Connecting to SharePoint</topic>
    <description>Learn how to setup a SharePoint 365 storage connection.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>In order to communicate with SharePoint, you need to create a trusted SharePoint Application for your SharePoint 365 site. Creating a trusted application requires a Client Id and Client Secret, which must be generated. The SharePoint Storage Connection String genie walks you through the process to create a trusted application so that Alpha Anywhere can access your SharePoint data. </p>
        <p>To invoke the genie, click the *[ui:SharePoint Storage Connection String Genie]* hyperlink when you define a new Storage Connection String. Storage connections are defined on the *[ui:Web Projects Control Panel]*. Click *[ui:Tools]* and select *[ui:Storage Connection strings]*.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Add New Storage Connection String dialog</title>
                <alt>Add New Storage Connection String dialog</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This will open the SharePoint Storage Connection String Genie. To begin, enter your SharePoint 365 site URL. The URL is the URL for your SharePoint 365 site that you'd like to access using a storage connection. For example:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[https://mySharepointDomain.sharepoint.com/sites/MySharepointSiteName]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Step 1 - Specify URL for your SharePoint site</title>
                <alt>Step 1 - Specify URL for your SharePoint site</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Next, you need to create a SharePoint Application. Step 2 of the genie walks you through building a SharePoint Application and creating a Client Id and Client Secret.</p>
                <p>In step 2, the Tenant Id is filled in automatically based on your SharePoint 365 URL provided in step 1. If the Tenant Id is empty, the SharePoint site URL is invalid. Return to the previous step and enter a valid SharePoint 365 site URL.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Step 2 - Create a new Application</title>
                <alt>Step 2 - Create a new Application</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Proceed to the next step when you have your Client Id and Client Secret.</p>
                <p>In step 3, register your SharePoint Application. Once you have completed the instructions for step 3, you will have registered your new SharePoint application, given the application necessary permissions, and confirmed the SharePoint can trust the application.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Step 3 - Register your Application</title>
                <alt>Step 3 - Register your Application</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup4.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In the final step, the SharePoint storage connection string is shown. Here, you can copy the connection string to the clipboard using the *[ui:Copy...]* button. Copying your connection string is optional as the connection string will be automatically populated into the *[ui:Connection String]* field of the *[ui:Add New Storage Connection String]* dialog when the builder is closed.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Step 4 - Copy your Storage Connection String</title>
                <alt>Step 4 - Copy your Storage Connection String</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Click *[ui:Close]* to return to the *[ui:Add New Storage Connection String]* dialog. Give the connection string a name and click *[ui:OK]* to save the SharePoint 365 connection string.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Name your SharePoint 365 Connection String</title>
                <alt>Name your SharePoint 365 Connection String</alt>
                <link>images/sharepointSetup6.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>SharePoint connections can be used with all [a5storage* helper functions] to upload, download, delete, and list files stored in SharePoint 365.</p>
                <p>Grid and UX applications can upload files to your SharePoint 365 account using the AmazonS3Indirect option when defining the [image] or [file upload] actions in [Action Javascript].</p>
                <p>See [Storage Connections] to learn more about storage connections.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="named storage connection strings">Storage Connections</link>
        <link link="a5storage%20functions">a5storage* helper functions</link>
        <link link="image%20upload">image</link>
        <link link="file%20upload">file upload</link>
        <link link="ux%20action%20javascript">Action Javascript</link>
    </links>
</page>