<page>
    <shortlink>transform quickstart fieldtypes</shortlink>
    <topic>Quickstart Field Types</topic>
    <description>Available field types in Alpha TransForm</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The following field types can be added in the Quickstart Editor by appending the option below to the field. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[Date of birth*[highlighter::date]*]]></example>
        </section>
        <list>
            <item>
                <name-title>Option</name-title>
                <description-title>Description</description-title>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>(No options)</name>
                <description>If no options are present (i.e., just plain Title text) the field will be treated as a plain text field. Input may be done in the Form Filler using a single-line input box. (A property may be set when doing Commands List Editing after completing Quickstart Text input to specify that a multi-line input box should be used.)</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:number</name>
                <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9 and ".".</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:phone</name>
                <description>This is a field with digits that may include any number of optional "-" characters, entered with a keypad. It can be used for values like phone numbers, Social Security Numbers, serial numbers, and similar values.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:signed</name>
                <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9 and ".". There is also a "+/-" button for toggling the value between positive and negative.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:integer</name>
                <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9. On the main form screen there will also be buttons for "-10", "-1", "+1", and "+10" to facilitate quick input.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:date</name>
                <description>This is a field that will be entered using spinners for Month, Day, and Year. There is also a "Today" button. The value will be stored as text such as "2017-09-15".</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:datetime</name>
                <description>This is a field that will be entered using spinners for Month, Day, Year, Hour, and Minute. There is also a "Now" button. The value will be stored as text such as "2017-09-15 14:04".</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:photo</name>
                <description>This is a field for capturing photos. It will display "Tap to capture image" or a preview of the captured image. The image may be obtained either with the device camera or from stored images.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:audio</name>
                <description>This is a field for recording audio, such as the user making a comment. It will display either "Tap to record" or "Tap to play" on the form. When tapped, large Record/Pause/Stop/Play buttons will be shown, as appropriate.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:signature</name>
                <description>This is a field that will display a "Tap to sign" button that will allow the user to write on the screen to capture a signature. The value will be stored as text specifying the "ink" using the SVG data format usable by browsers. A preview will be displayed once the writing is completed.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>:location</name>
                <description>This is a field that will display a "Get Location" button that will use the device's GPS capability to obtain a "latitude,longitude" value such as "42.480137,-71.203598".</description>
            </item>
        </list>
    </sections>
</page>