<page api="xb" build="8368">
    <shortlink>api debugthread function</shortlink>
    <topic>_debug Function</topic>
    <description>Forces an application thread to break in the Xbasic debugger.</description>
    <prototype>N _debug(N switch)</prototype>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>switch</name>
            <type>N</type>
            <description>Debugger action to take. Can be one of the following values:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Value</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>-2</name>
                    <description>Toggle Debugger</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>-1</name>
                    <description>Ask if Debugger is on</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>0</name>
                    <description>Turn off Debugger</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>1</name>
                    <description>Turn on Debugger</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <discussion>
        <p>When a component is run in Live Preview, you can launch the Xbasic debugger from an Xbasic script using the *[xb:debug()]* function. This is helpful for diagnosing scripts and exploring server-side events. However, some scripts and events cannot be run in Live or Working Preview -- such as Login events. To fully test an application, you need to Live Test the app on an Application Server, such as the local Development Server.</p>
        <p>The *[xb:_debug()]* function can be used to launch the Xbasic debugger when testing an application on the local Development Server. This enables you to test functionality that otherwise cannot be run in a preview environment -- including the security framework.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>To open the Xbasic debugger while testing your app on the Development Server, either using a [Live Test] or [publishing to Localhost], add the following statement to your Xbasic script:</description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[_debug(1)]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When the *[xb:_debug(1)]* statement is encountered, the Xbasic debugger will open in the Alpha Anywhere IDE. The Alpha Anywhere IDE must be open and running in order to use this function.</p>
                <p>The *[xb:_debug()]* function is similar to the *[xb:debug()]* function in that it launches the Xbasic debugger when encountered, however only the *[xb:_debug()]* function will open the debugger when running on the Development Server.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Developer Environment Only</limitations>
    <see>
        <ref link="xbasic%20guide%20debugger">The Xbasic Debugger</ref>
        <ref link="Xbasic ON ERROR GOTO">ON ERROR GOTO</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link link="livetest">Live Test</link>
        <link link="how%20to%20publish%20an%20alpha%20anywhere%20application">publishing to Localhost</link>
    </links>
    <terms>script,debug,display,error,function,logical,trace,Xbasic,troubleshooting,debugging</terms>
</page>