<page>
    <shortlink>server ref Web Project Settings</shortlink>
    <topic>Web Project Settings</topic>
    <description>Different web project settings available in Alpha Anywhere</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Run-time Properties</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Project style</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Project style</title>
                            <description>Specify the name of the style for all components in the project.</description>
                            <note>
                                <p>In each individual component, you must specify the style name as &lt;ProjectStyle&gt;</p>
                            </note>
                            <tip>
                                <p>You can perform a global update of your components to change the style name to &lt;ProjectStyle&gt; by selecting Edit, Bulk operations from the menu when the Web Projects Control Panel has focus.</p>
                            </tip>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">Applying compact and pulse effects</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If you are using a style such as "Alpha" or "Alpha-Green", you can specify that the compact option or pulse effect should be used in the Project style setting. For example:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <example><![CDATA[Alpha-Amber:compact
Alpha:pulse
Alpha-Grey:compact,pulse]]></example>
                                </p>
                                <p>This will apply the compact and/or pulse effect to every component that uses the &lt;ProjectStyle&gt; as its Style name.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Web site defaults (Alpha Cloud and IIS Only)</title>
                    <note>
                        <p>These settings only apply to Alpha Cloud and IIS.</p>
                    </note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default page</title>
                            <description>Select the default page to be returned when no page is specified in the request. This value is only used when publishing to an IIS server. See the Xbasic server settings for its list of default page names.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session lifetime (minutes)</title>
                            <description>Enter the number of minutes a session will remain active on the server without any requests from the user. A session will automatically end on the server if no requests are received from the user in this amount of time. This value is only used when publishing to an IIS server.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Max upload size in MB</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The maximum file upload size. This is specified in MB. The default is 100. This value is only used when publishing to an IIS server.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Authentication cookie name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The name of the cookie that stores encrypted authentication information.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session cookie name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The name of the cookie that stores the user's session ID.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="6382">
                            <title nested="2">Cookie SameSite value</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Cookie SameSite value]* specifies how cookies are served from the Application Server for cross-origin requests. Some third-party embedded services, such as a payment processor, use cookies to perform tasks such as back to your site.</p>
                                <p>Alpha Anywhere mobile applications on iOS and Android use cookies to keep track of the user's session. Because the app is running on the user's device and not on the application server, these cookies are viewed by the device as third-party cookies even though they are part of your application.</p>
                                <p>Third-party cookies will be blocked by default unless the *[ui:Cookie SameSite value]* is configured to allow them. By default, the SameSite value is set to "Strict". This means cookies will not be sent to third-party sites.</p>
                                <p>You can allow third-party cookies by setting the SameSite value to "None" or "Unset". All available settings are listed below.</p>
                                <p>To learn more about Same Site cookies and solutions for common warnings, see *[extlink:SameSite Cookies (MDN)@https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Set-Cookie/SameSite]*</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Mode</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Unset</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is not set and is not sent with requests.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>None</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is set to "None". Cookies are sent in all contexts, including cross-origin. Requires SSL.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Lax</name>
                                            <description>The SameSite attribute is set to "Lax". Cookies are allowed to be sent in top-level navigation and in GET requests to third-party websites.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Strict</name>
                                            <description>(Default) The SameSite attribute is set to "Strict". Cookies are only sent in first-party context. Cookies are not sent to third-party websites.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>You must set the Same Site policy to *[Unset]* or *[None]* if you are deploying Cordova Applications that must communicate with the Application Server.</p>
                            </important>
                        </case>
                        <case build="6655">
                            <title nested="2">Stack options</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Allows you to configure how IIS processes requests. See *[link:Optimizing Memory Usage on IIS@https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/index?search=iis%20stack%20options]* for more information.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="7832">
                            <title nested="2">HTTP to HTTPS redirect</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Allows you to configure how IIS redirects HTTP requests to HTTPS requests. This also lets you configure Strict-Transport-Security (see *[extlink:Strict-Transport-Security (MDN)@https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/Strict-Transport-Security]*), which tells the browser to make all requests to the application using HTTPS, even if HTTP is used in the address.</p>
                                <p>There may be cases when automatic HTTP to HTTPS redirection should not be done. For example, LetsEncrypt can use HTTP-01 Challenge (see *[extlink:Challenge Types (LetEncrypt)@https://letsencrypt.org/docs/challenge-types/]*) to prove domain name control that is done using HTTP. LetsEncrypt sends a request in the form *[html:http://&lt;YOUR_DOMAIN&gt;/.well-known/acme-challenge/&lt;TOKEN&gt;]*. In this case, requests for *[html:.well-known/acme-challenge/]* should be allowed over HTTP. A redirect exclusion needs to be created for files in that path. The following regular expression allows HTTP requests to *[html:.well-known/acme-challenge/]*:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example code="regex"><![CDATA[\.well-known/acme-challenge/.*]]></example>
                            <figure>
                                <title>HTTP to HTTPS automatic redirect exclusion regular expression.</title>
                                <alt>HTTP to HTTPS automatic redirect exclusion regular expression.</alt>
                                <link>images/webProjectSettings1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case build="7843">
                            <title nested="2">HTTP01-Challenge support</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>HTTP01-Challenge is used by some HTTPS certificate vendors as one of some different ways for proving domain/server ownership. This requires the site to have a well known place for the certificate vendor to get a token file. Enabling this support will create the necessary folder tree and security permissions for allowing access to the folder path.</p>
                                <p>Choose either LetsEncypt or Custom from the challenge vendor list. If Custom is selected, you then need to enter the well known path used by the certifcate vendor. The path is relative to the web site root.</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[.well-known\challenge]]></example>
                            <figure>
                                <title>HTTP01-Challenge configuration.</title>
                                <alt>HTTP01 challenge configuration</alt>
                                <link>images/webProjectSettings2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Aex files</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">File list</title>
                            <description>Property name: aexFiles.fileNames Specify the name of any .aex files that you want to load when this project is run. AEX Files specified here are loaded automatically when the application is run. It is not necessary to use the a5w_load_aex() function.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>File Download</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Allowed filenames</title>
                            <description>Enter a comma delimited list of allowed files that can be downloaded from the server. Enter filename patterns using wildcard characters (* and ?). To allow any type of file, enter *.* For example, if you enter: a5*.xls,a5*.pdf - Only .xls files and .pdf files that start with 'a5' can be downloaded. If you only want to specify a list of blocked filename patterns, leave this property blank, or enter *.*.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Disallowed filename</title>
                            <description>Enter a comma delimited list of files that can not be downloaded from the server. Enter filename patterns using wildcard characters (* and ?).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Allowed folders</title>
                            <description>Enter a comma delimited list of folder names from which files can be downloaded. You can use wildcard characters (* and ?) in the name. Example: *\images,*\pdf - would allow user to download from a folder called 'images' or 'pdf' on any drive. d:\images would only allow download from the 'images' folder on drive D on the server.</description>
                            <obsolete>
                                <p>&lt;UserSessionFolder&gt; is not supported in Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                            </obsolete>
                            <note>
                                <p>If you leave this blank (not recommended) then files can be downloaded from any folder.</p>
                            </note>
                            <note>
                                <p>You can use the &lt;ApplicationRoot&gt; placeholder in the folder name you specify. e.g. &lt;ApplicationRoot&gt;\DownloadFolder</p>
                            </note>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Javascript Libraries</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">jQuery Core</title>
                            <description>Load jQuery core Javascript Library. You can choose where the library is loaded from. Alpha Anywhere has a built-in version of this library, or you can load it from the Google Content Delivery Network, or the jQuery Content Delivery Network. When you load from Google, you must specify the version you want to load. When you load from the jQuery CDN, the latest stable release is automatically loaded.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">jQuery Core Version</title>
                            <description>Specify the version number you want to load</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">jQuery UI</title>
                            <description>Load jQuery UI Javascript Library. Requires jQuery Core. You can choose where the library is loaded from. Alpha Anywhere has a built-in version of this library, or you can load it from the Google Content Delivery Network.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">jQuery UI Version</title>
                            <description>Specify the version number you want to load</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Links</title>
                            <description>Specify a list of Javascript libraries to link</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Include Image Gallery</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Image Gallery Javascript libraries should be loaded. If you use the Image Gallery anywhere in your application you must check this option. NOTE: If this option is checked, then you must also check the options to load jQuery core.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Include Google JSAPI library</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Google Javascript API library should be loaded. This is needed if you use the Google visualization library in the UX component.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="7077">
                            <title nested="2">Include JitsiMeet library</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Jitsi Meet library should be loaded. The Jisti Meet library is required if any components in your project contain a [Jitsi Meet control].</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Cordova/PhoneGap libraries</title>
                            <description>If you are building a hybrid mobile application that requires a Cordova Javascript library, specify where the Javascript should be loaded from. Javascript can be loaded from one of the following locations:</description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name>BuiltIn</name>
                                    <description>Use the built-in version of either the iOS or Android library</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Local</name>
                                    <description>Use a version that is loaded from a file in the web root</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>If the file is loaded from a "Local" folder, it must be loaded from a folder that follows the required naming convention:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[Javascript\Cordova\IOS\currentVersion\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\IOS\2.8.0\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\Android\currentVersion\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\Android\2.8.0\cordova.js]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Include CKEdit HTML Editor Javascript library</title>
                            <description>If your component uses the CKEdit HTML editor you must check this box to load the necessary Javascript and CSS libraries.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Dates</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case build="5581">
                            <title nested="2">Switch year</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Switch year]* defines how to interpret two-digit years in a date. If the year is greater than the switch year, it will be interpreted as being in the 1900s. For example, "12/25/22" will be interpreted as December 25, 2022 while "03/17/59" is interpreted as March 17, 1959.</p>
                                <p>Leave this property blank to use the default switch year. The current default switch year is "30".</p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>It is recommended that you use four digit years rather than two digit years in your applications.</p>
                            </important>
                        </case>
                        <case build="7572">
                            <title nested="2">Server-side date/time format for UX and Grid components</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The date/time format to use on the server. The date/time is specified using Xbasic date/time formatting elements. For example, *[xb:yyyy-MM-dd 0h:0m:0s]*. Leave blank to use machine regional settings. See [Date and Time Format Elements] for more information.</p>
                                <p>This property is useful for applications deployed on Alpha Cloud because Alpha Cloud runs with regional setting set to MM-dd-yyyy format. If you are moving your application from a self-hosted server to Alpha Cloud, you can change the server-side date/time format here instead of editing every component to set the date/time format.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="7572">
                            <title nested="2">Server-side date format for UX and Grid components</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The date format to use on the server. The date is specified using Xbasic date formatting elements. For example, *[xb:yyyy-MM-dd]*. Leave blank to use machine regional settings. See [Date and Time Format Elements] for more information.</p>
                                <p>This property is useful for applications deployed on Alpha Cloud because Alpha Cloud runs with regional setting set to MM-dd-yyyy format. If you are moving your application from a self-hosted server to Alpha Cloud, you can change the server-side date format here instead of editing every component to set the date format.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>CSS Libraries</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">jQuery CSS</title>
                            <description>Specify which jQuery UI CSS library should be loaded. These libraries are loaded from the Google Content Delivery Network.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Links</title>
                            <description>Specify a list of CSS libraries to link in the application.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Resource Providers</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Named Providers</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>A Named Provider is used to connect to an external service that can be used for user authentication and access to other resources such as social media.  Resource providers such as Google and Facebook can be used for user authentication or access services available from the provider, such as calendars and documents.</p>
                                <p>A user can log onto a system using their credentials from the provider in place of the user name and password in the web security system.</p>
                                <p>Named Resources can be created for the following providers in Alpha Anywhere:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list bullet="true">
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Box (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Dropbox (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Facebook (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Google (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>LinkedIn (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Live Connect (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Salesforce (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Spotify (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Twitter (OAuth)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Googleservice (API)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>SalesforceService (API)</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Twillio (API)</name>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="3">Videos</title>
                            <videos>
                                <title>Creating a Named Resource for Salesforce</title>
                                <video>
                                    <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
                                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/9333abd7</link>
                                </video>
                                <video>
                                    <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
                                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/110062a4</link>
                                </video>
                            </videos>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <videos>
                                <title>Alternative Login - Creating a Named Provider</title>
                                <description>See [Alternative Logins] for more information.</description>
                                <video>
                                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/c09bbb08</link>
                                </video>
                            </videos>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Webkit (Chrome/Safari) Specific</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Allow static text selection</title>
                            <description>Defines whether or not static text can be selected in a mobile or web application. For mobile applications, this property should be set to *[xb:.f.]*. This will prevent static-text on a page from being selected. For desktop applications you might want to set this property to *[xb:.t.]* so that users can select static-text.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Stripe Checkout</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Settings for configuring Stripe. See the [Stripe Genie...] to learn how to integrate Stripe into your applications.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Define keys</title>
                            <description>If your application uses Stripe Checkout, you can specify your Stripe API key here.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>E-mail Settings</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">SMTP Server</title>
                            <description>The URL or IP Address for the SMTP server for sending email.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">SMTP server port</title>
                            <description>The port used by the SMTP server.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">SSL Option</title>
                            <description>Defines the SSL option to use when sending email. If SSL is not used, leave this property blank. Example settings: SSL, TLS.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">E-mail account user name</title>
                            <description>The user name for the email account used to send email.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">E-mail account password</title>
                            <description>The password for the email account used to send email.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">From address</title>
                            <description>The default from address for emails sent from the application. If using SparkPost or SendGrid, your verified sender address.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">From alias</title>
                            <description>The default friendly name for the from address for emails sent from the application.</description>
                        </case>
                        <!--
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Mandrill key</title>
                            <description>If you use the Mandrill web service to send email, you can set the key value here. If you set the value here you will not need to set the value each time you call the Mandrill web service (using the email_send_mandrill() Xbasic function).</description>
                        </case>
                        -->
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">SparkPost/SendGrid key</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If sending email using SparkPost or SendGrid, your SparkPost or SendGrid API Key. If using SendGrid, prefix the SendGrid API key with *[xb:sendgrid:]*. If set, Alpha Anywhere will use the API key specified in the *[ui:SparkPost key]* property when calling the [email_send_sparkpost()] Xbasic function if no key is specified in the function call.</p>
                                <p>When defining an Email action, either using [Action Javascript] or [Action Scripting], specifying a value of *[ui:&lt;Project&gt;]* or leaving the value blank for the SparkPost key property will use the API key specified in the Web Project Settings.</p>
                                <p>Emails sent using SparkPost or SendGrid are sent using the SparkPost or SendGrid API. Your API key is required to send emails using SparkPost or SendGrid.</p>
                                <p>You can optionally specify the *[ui:From address]* and *[ui:From alias]* above. The *[ui:From address]* should be your verified sender for your SparkPost or SendGrid service. Sending email using SendGrid requires your verified sender address for the account. If not supplied here, you will need to provide your verified sender address in the action or script that calls the service.</p>
                                <p>All other settings are ignored.</p>
                            </description>
                            <note>
                                <p>For more information about SparkPost API keys, see *[extlink:SparkPost API Keys@https://www.sparkpost.com/docs/getting-started/create-api-keys/]*.</p>
                                <p>For more information about SendGrid API keys, see *[extlink:SendGrid API Keys@https://docs.sendgrid.com/ui/account-and-settings/api-keys]*.</p>
                            </note>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default sending method</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The method to use when sending email. You can choose *[ui:Internal]* to use Alpha Anywhere's internal email functions or *[ui:SparkPost]* to use the SparkPost or SendGrid web service.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>E-mail Outbox</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:E-mail Outbox]* is a table used to store a copy of email messages sent from a web application.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/emailOutboxSettingsProperties.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Defines the table type. This can be DBF or SQL (recommended).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>If the *[ui:Table type]* is SQL, the *[ui:Connection string]* property must be defined. This property specifies what connection string should be used to connect to the database that contains the email outbox table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Table name]* defines what table in the data source is the email outbox table. You can use the *[ui:Create E-mail Outbox Table]* link in the *[ui:Define E-mail Outbox Table]* dialog to generate a table in the destination database if one doesn't exist.</p>
                                <p>Alternatively, you can create the table yourself. The email outbox table must have the following structure:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[Field name: ID, Type: Numeric(8), Primary key: True, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: True
Field name: wasSent, Type: Character(3), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: errorText, Type: Character(255), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: dateStamp, Type: DateTime, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: subject, Type: Character(255), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: Message, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: SentTo, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: CC, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: BCC, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: Attachments, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: Comments, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: sent_by, Type: Character(255), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: sent_by_alias, Type: Character(255), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
]]>                            </example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Sequence name</title>
                            <description>Specify the sequence name for the table. The Sequence name is only needed for databases such as Oracle and PostgreSQL that use sequences for auto-increment fields.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The field map defines how the fields in the table map to the required email outbox fields. Use the *[ui:Auto map fields]* link to automatically map the fields. Any fields that don't use the same name as the ones shown below need to be manually mapped:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Field Name</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Field Map Property</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>ID</name>
                                            <description>Primary key field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>wasSent</name>
                                            <description>WasSent field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>errorText</name>
                                            <description>Error Text field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>dateStamp</name>
                                            <description>DateStamp field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>subject</name>
                                            <description>Subject field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Message</name>
                                            <description>Message</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>SentTo</name>
                                            <description>Sent To</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>CC</name>
                                            <description>CC</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>BCC</name>
                                            <description>BCC</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Attachments</name>
                                            <description>Attachments</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Comments</name>
                                            <description>Comments</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sent_by</name>
                                            <description>Sent_By field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sent_by_alias</name>
                                            <description>Sent_By Alias field</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The *[ui:Define E-mail Outbox Table]* dialog is shown when the [...] smart field button is clicked for any of the *[ui:E-mail Outbox]* properties.</title>
                                <link>images/emailOutboxSettingsProperties2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="5022">
                    <title>Audit table (for SQL tables)</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Auditing can be enabled to keep track of edits made to SQL tables in an application. Information about each Insert, Update and Delete is kept in the Audit table. This table keeps track of the type of edit, the user id of the person making the edit, the name of table that was edited, and the old and new value of each field that was edited.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <videos>
                                <title>Video: Auditing Table Edits</title>
                                <description>
                                    <p> In many applications it is desirable to keep track of every edit made to a SQL table so you can know what fields were changed, who made the edit and when the edit was made. This is often achieved by added update, insert and delete triggers to the SQL database. But in cases where it is not possible to modify the database, you can use the built-in auditing feature in Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                                    <p>In the first video we show how the auditing feature is set up and used.</p>
                                    <p>In cases where updates to SQL tables are made in your own Xbasic code (as opposed to from UX and Grid components), it is necessary to manually update the audit log. In the second video we show how this is done.</p>
                                </description>
                                <date>2018-15-06</date>
                                <video>
                                    <name>Watch Video Part 1</name>
                                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/9f4b4693</link>
                                </video>
                                <video>
                                    <name>Watch Video Part 2</name>
                                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/5e9f39a9</link>
                                </video>
                            </videos>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>To turn on the Auditing feature, check the *[ui:Keep track of edits to tables made through Grid and UX components]* property.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/audit1.gif</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once you do this, you will be able to specify the connection string to the database where the Audit table is stored. You can either map an existing table, or create a new table.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/audit2.gif</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>By default, the User Id of the user who made the edit to a table is obtained from the Alpha Anywhere security framework (by evaluating the context.security.currentUser expression). However, if you are not using the Alpha Anywhere security framework, you can define a custom expression to get the user id of the person who made the edit.</p>
                        <p>In the case where you are making updates to SQL tables in your own Xbasic code, you will need to manually update the audit log table. There are two helper function in Xbasic to make this easy:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>[a5Helper_getAuditInfoFromSQLStatement()] - Called before the SQL is executed to capture the new and old values for each field being edited.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>[a5Helper_writeToAuditingLog()] - Writes to the Audit table after the SQL has been executed.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>For example, the following code updates a table and also updates the audit log:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[dim cn as sql::Connection
cn.open("::Name::AADemo-Northwind")
dim args as sql::arguments
args.add("primaryKey","ALFKI")
args.add("title","Manager")


dim sql as c
sql = "update Customers set ContactTitle = :title where CustomerID = :primaryKey"

'capture the BEFORE update values
dim dataJson as c
dataJson = a5Helper_getAuditInfoFromSQLStatement(cn,sql,args.xml)

flag = cn.Execute(sql,args)

'write to the auditing table
a5Helper_writeToAuditingLog(cn,"Update",dataJson,"CustomerID","ALFKI")]]></example>
                    <tip>The Audit table can grow to be very large in a large application used by many people. You might want to implement a strategy to purge old records from the audit table from time to time.</tip>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>A complete list of properties for configuring table auditing are listed below:</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Keep track of edits to tables made through Grid and UX Components</title>
                            <description>If checked, enables table auditing in Grid and UX Components.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>The *[ui:Connection string]* property defines the connection to the SQL database where the audit table is defined. If the audit table doesn't exist, you can create one using  the *[ui:Create Audit Table]* link at the bottom of the *[ui:Define Audit Table]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/auditTable1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Table name]* property defines the table in the database where the audits are written. If no table exists in your database, you can create the table from within Alpha Anywhere using the *[ui:]* link. Using this link will both create the table and populate the *[ui:Field map]*, as well.</p>
                                <p>If you manually create the audit table, the table must contain the following fields:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[Field name: id, Type: Numeric(10), Primary key: True, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: True
Field name: operation, Type: Character(20), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: UserId, Type: Character(100), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: dateStamp, Type: DateTime, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: data, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: databaseTableName, Type: Character(100), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: primaryKeyFields, Type: Character(200), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: primaryKeyValue, Type: Character(200), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: connectionStringToDatabases, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: comment, Type: Character(100), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: userfield1, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Field map]* defines a mapping between columns in the audit table and the data collected and written to the table by Alpha Anywhere. The *[ui:Auto map fields]* link can be used to automatically map fields in the table to the audit fields.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Expression for User Id</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Defines the user Id to log in the audit table. If you use the Alpha Anywhere Security Framework, *[xb:Context.Security.CurrentUser]* will be used to retrieve the user Id.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/auditTable2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>If you are not using the Alpha Anywhere Security Framework, you can define a custom expression for the user Id. In many cases, the user Id is stored in a session variable that is set when a user logs into the system. For example, *[xb:Context.session.userid]*. To set the *[ui:Expression for User Id]* to use this session variable, you would uncheck the *[ui:Use security framework to get User Id?]* and enter the following in the *[ui:Expression to evaluate to get User Id]* text box:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[Context.session.userid]]></example>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="5137">
                    <title nested="2">User Defined Fields</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can add a user defined field to the audit table to capture any additional information that you want at the time the audit table is updated. If you set the value in a special session variable called *[xb:session.__audit_userfield1]*, the value in this variable will be written to the user defined field when the audit table is updated. If you want to store a significant amount of information in this field, consider creating a string of JSON data. The JSON data can have a large number of properties.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Extended user security info</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Extended user security info]* settings are used to configure the Extended User Information table. Web security tables in the Alpha Anywhere Security Framework have a fixed schema and cannot be modified. If you need to store additional information about a user that the Web Security Framework doesn't include in the web security tables, you can use an Extended User Information table.</p>
                        <p>The Extended User Information table can contain any information you would like to collect and store about a logged in user. The table, at a minimum, must include a User ID field, which is used to link the Extended User Information table records to a user in the security framework.</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Connection string</name>
                                    <description>The *[ui:Connection string]* property defines the connection to the SQL database where the extended user information is stored.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Table name</name>
                                    <description>The name of the Extended User Information table.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Userid field name</name>
                                    <description>The field in the table that contains the user id.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>If you do not have a table already in your database for storing the Extended User Information, you can create one directly from Alpha Anywhere using the *[ui:Create Extended User-information Table]* link in the Extended User Information Table dialog. The *[ui:Default field list]* link in the window used to define the fields in the Extended User Information table can be used to generate a set of suggested fields to include in your table in addition to the User ID:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example caption="Default field list"><![CDATA[UserId|c|100||PrimaryKey
Firstname|c|100
Lastname|c|100
AvatarURL|c|250
Company|c|100
Department|c|100
SecurityGroups|c|250
OtherOptionsJSON|M]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>All fields and field names are optional, however you *[must]* include a field that stores the user ID.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Repository Settings</title>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/repositorySettingsProperties.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>A repository is a table (either .dbf or SQL) where a web application can read or write data. The data are typically items such as email templates, or saved queries, or other settings. For the most part, the repository is for internal use by components, but developers can also make use of it using the following functions:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>[a5w_SaveToWebAppRepository Function] - Saves some data to the repository. Returns .t. if the data was saved, or .f. if it was not saved.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>[a5w_GetFromWebAppRepository Function] - Retrieves a piece of data from the repository.</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>[a5w_enumerateWebAppRepository Function] - Enumerates the key values of the objects stores in the repository and returns them in a CR/LF-delimited list. You can optionally filter the objects by objectType, componentGuid, and/or userId.</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>For an example of how you can use these functions with the repository table, see the [UX_Ad_Hoc_SQL_QueryBuilder UX template].</p>
                        <p>The following properties are available for configuring the *[ui:Repository Settings]*:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The *[ui:Define Repository Table]* is shown when the [...] smart field button is clicked for any of the Repository Settings properties.</title>
                        <link>images/repositorySettingsProperties2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Defines the table type. This can be DBF or SQL (recommended).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>If the *[ui:Table type]* is SQL, the *[ui:Connection string]* property must be defined. This property specifies what connection string should be used to connect to the database that contains the repository table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Table name]* defines what table in the data source is the repository table. You can use the *[ui:Create Repository Table]* link in the *[ui:Define Repository Table]* dialog to generate a table in the destination database if one doesn't exist.</p>
                                <p>Alternatively, you can create the table yourself. The repository table must have the following structure:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[Field name: key, Type: Character(100), Primary key: True, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: objectType, Type: Character(40), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: dateStamp, Type: DateTime, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: componentGUID, Type: Character(40), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: userId, Type: Character(40), Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: data, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: securityGroups, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The field map defines how the fields in the table map to the required repository fields. Use the *[ui:Auto map fields]* link to automatically map the fields. Any fields that don't use the same name as the ones shown below need to be manually mapped:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Field Name</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Field Map Property</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>key</name>
                                            <description>Repository Key field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>objectType</name>
                                            <description>Object Type field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>dateStamp</name>
                                            <description>DateStamp field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>componentGUID</name>
                                            <description>ComponentGUID field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>userId</name>
                                            <description>UserId field</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>data</name>
                                            <description>Data</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>securityGroups</name>
                                            <description>Security Groups</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="7796">
                    <title>GlobalSettings Table</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Global Settings table can be used to store settings as name-value pairs in a SQL database. Settings can be accessed and managed server-side at runtime throughout the application using the [a5_globalSetting_add()], [a5_globalSetting_get()], and [a5_globalSetting_delete()] functions.</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="xb" caption="Using the a5_globalSetting* functions in the Interative Window."><![CDATA[dim settingName as c = "test"
dim settingValue as c = "This is my test value."

dim result as L
result = a5_globalsetting_add(settingName, settingValue)
? result
= .T.

dim existingValue as c
existingValue = a5_globalsetting_get(settingName)
? existingValue
= "This is my test value."

result = a5_globalsetting_delete(settingName)
? result
= .T.

existingValue = a5_globalsetting_get(settingName)
? existingValue
= ""]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>The *[ui:GlobalSettings Table]* settings are used to configure the Global Settings table.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Defines the table type. This can be DBF or SQL (recommended).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>If the *[ui:Table type]* is SQL, the *[ui:Connection string]* property must be defined. This property specifies what connection string should be used to connect to the database that contains the Global Settings table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Table name]* defines what table in the data source is the Global Settings table. You can use the *[ui:Create Global Settings Table]* link in the *[ui:Define Global Settings Table]* dialog to generate a table in the destination database if one doesn't exist.</p>
                                <p>Alternatively, you can create the table yourself. The Global Settings table must have the following structure:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example code=""><![CDATA[Field name: id, Type: Numeric(10), Primary key: True, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: True
Field name: settingName, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: True, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: settingValue, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field Map</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The field map defines how the fields in the table map to the required component security settings fields. Use the *[ui:Auto map fields]* link to automatically map the fields. Any fields that don't use the same name as the ones shown below need to be manually mapped:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Field Name</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Field Map Property</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>ID field</name>
                                    <description>The field that contains the primary key for the table.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Setting name</name>
                                    <description>The field that contains the setting name.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Setting value</name>
                                    <description>The field that contains the setting value.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="7796">
                    <title>SQL Log Table</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can now log all SQL CRUD statements executed by a List with a Detail View, a Grid, or a data bound UX component to a table. The SQL Log table contains the sql that got executed, the arguments that were defined, the result of the command, the error message if the SQL failed, the date and time of the command, and how long it took for the SQL to execute.</p>
                        <p>To enable SQL Logging, the properties must be configured in Project Properties.</p>
                        <p>You can dynamically turn SQL logging on or off by setting a value in the enabled field in the table specified in the Remote enable/disable logging table name property.</p>
                        <p>For example, assume that you have defined a SQL Log table, but have not specified the Remote enable/disable logging table name property. SQL logging is then enabled.</p>
                        <p>However, if you have specified a value for the Remote enable/disable logging table name property then Alpha Anywhere will query the value of the enabled field in this table. If the enabled field value in the first record in the table is true, logging will be enabled. If the value is false, logging is disabled.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Configure using GlobalSettings Properties</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Typically the SQLLog table is configured at design time by setting properties in the Web Project Properties dialog. You can configure the SQLLog table at run-time by setting Global Settings.</p>
                                <p>The following Global Settings can be used to configure the SQLLog table:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Setting</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sqlLog_table</name>
                                            <description>The name of the SQLLog table</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sqlLog_connectionString</name>
                                            <description>The name of the connection string where the SQLog table is stored</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sqlLog_fieldMap</name>
                                            <description>The field map -- can be blank</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>sqlLog_maxAge</name>
                                            <description>Defaults to 30. records that are more than maxAge days old are deleted from the log when the log is updated.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                                <p>If the table is specified, but does not exist, the table will be created.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="6960">
                    <title>Component Security</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Access to buttons in a TabbedUI's navigation menu can be restricted using security groups. These security settings can be stored in an external database, allowing you to give your users the ability at runtime to change access control in the TabbedUI.</p>
                        <p>*[ui:Component Security]* settings are used to configure the component security settings table where the security group information is stored for a TabbedUI using the [Store security groups in database] feature.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Defines the table type. This can be DBF or SQL (recommended).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>If the *[ui:Table type]* is SQL, the *[ui:Connection string]* property must be defined. This property specifies what connection string should be used to connect to the database that contains the component security settings table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The *[ui:Table name]* defines what table in the data source is the component security settings table. You can use the *[ui:Create Component Security Settings Table]* link in the *[ui:Define Component Security Settings Table]* dialog to generate a table in the destination database if one doesn't exist.</p>
                                <p>Alternatively, you can create the table yourself. The component security settings table must have the following structure:</p>
                            </description>
                            <example code=""><![CDATA[Field name: ComponentGuid, Type: Character(100), Primary key: True, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False
Field name: securitySettingsJSON, Type: Memo, Primary key: False, Allow Nulls: False, Is Auto-increment: False]]></example>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field Map</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The field map defines how the fields in the table map to the required component security settings fields. Use the *[ui:Auto map fields]* link to automatically map the fields. Any fields that don't use the same name as the ones shown below need to be manually mapped:</p>
                            </description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Field Name</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Field Map Property</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>ComponentGuid</name>
                                    <description>Component GUID field</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>securitySettingsJSON</name>
                                    <description>Security data</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Work Queue Table Settings</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Specify the table type for the Work Queue.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>Specify the connection string to the database for the Work Queue.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>Specify the name of the table for the Work Queue.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>Specify how the fields in the Work Queue table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Help Table Settings</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Help Table is a .DBF or SQL table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>Specify the connection string to the SQL database.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>Specify the table name.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>Specify how the fields in the Help Table table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Text Dictionary Table Settings</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Text Dictionary Table is a .DBF or SQL table.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>Specify the connection string to the SQL database.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>Specify the table name.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>Specify how the fields in the Text Dictionary Table table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Offline Data Synchronization Log Table Settings</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table type</title>
                            <description>ALWAYS SET TO SQL</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Connection string</title>
                            <description>Specify the connection string to the SQL database.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Table name</title>
                            <description>Specify the table name.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Field map</title>
                            <description>Specify how the fields in the Data Synchronization Log table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Application Global Variables</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Define application variables</title>
                            <description>Specify any application global variables. These variables can be seen by every page and component in this application.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Calendar Component</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">License number</title>
                            <description>Specify the license number for your Calendar component. The license number in the Calendar component itself should be set to: &lt;GetFromProjectSetings&gt;</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>PDF Printing Options</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <obsolete>
                                <p>This property is no longer available in Alpha Anywhere build 7661 and newer. All reports will be generated using PDFDirect. Reports can no longer be created using the Amyuni driver.</p>
                            </obsolete>
                            <title nested="2" build="6945">Use direct to PDF</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If you check this option, all reports that use the PDF option will use the PDFDirect option. This includes overwriting Action Scripting *[ui:Initial View]* and Action Javascript *[link:Initial view@https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/index?search=open%20a%20report,%20label%20or%20letter%20layout]*.</p>
                                <p>PDFDirect generates PDFs without using the Amyuni Printer Driver. Some PDF Options are not available when using PDFDirect.</p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>*[How to report PDF reporting issues to Alpha Software]*</p>
                                <p>If your report does not render correctly when printed as a PDF, right click on the report in the Web Project Control Panel and select the Create Bug Report menu option under the Datasources menu. Select a location to store the .zip file and be sure to check the Include Raw Pages option. Send the zip file to [bugs@alphasoftware.com].</p>
                            </important>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use Microsoft XPS printer to generate PDF files</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify if the Microsoft XPS printer should be used to generate PDF files. When you use this option, you can specify if the resulting XPS files should be converted to PDF files before being sent to the browser, or if they should be sent to the browser as XPS files.</p>
                                <p>This option is not shown if *[ui:Use direct to PDF]* is checked.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Convert XPS files to PDF before sending to client</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Defines whether or not XPS files should be converted to a PDF format before being sent to the client.</p>
                                <p>This option is only shown if *[ui:Use Microsoft XPS printer to generate PDF files]* is checked.</p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>If you choose to send the resulting XPS files to the browser without first converting them to PDF, only Microsoft Internet Explorer will be able to display the file directly in the browser. All other browsers will download the file and you will have to use the local XPS viewer application to see the file.</p>
                            </important>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Allow all international characters in free-form reports</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Applies to reports with a SQL data source.</p>
                                <p>If unchecked, Alpha Anywhere renders reports using a .DBF table for report data. This legacy reporting logic does not support UTF8.</p>
                                <p>This option is not shown if *[ui:Use direct to PDF]* is checked.</p>
                            </description>
                            <note>
                                <p>If reports use international characters, enable the option for *[ui:Multilingual support]* in the *[ui:PDF Options]*.</p>
                            </note>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">PDF Options</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Default settings for creating PDF reports. Settings can be set for individual reports created using Action Scripting, Action Javascript, or Xbasic. Options specified for individual reports override the project default.</p>
                            </description>
                            <important>
                                <p>Some *[ui:PDF Options]* are not supported when using Direct to PDF.</p>
                            </important>
                            <cases>
                                <case>
                                    <title nested="3">PDF Options</title>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Multilingual support</name>
                                            <description>Adds support for international character sets.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Embed fonts</name>
                                            <description>Include required fonts in the PDF instead of allowing them to be resolved externally. </description>
                                            <note>If the font is protected, it can't be embedded; this is often the case for bar code fonts, such as Code39.</note>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Linearize</name>
                                            <description>Uses a format that is better for web viewing. This format makes it possible to view the first page of a large PDF before all remaining pages are downloaded.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Black and white</name>
                                            <description>Converts all colors to black, white, and gray.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Convert hyperlinks</name>
                                            <description>Converts all hyperlinks started with "http://" into live links in the resulting PDF document.
                                            </description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>JPEG Image Quality</name>
                                            <description>Set the quality of JPEG images; this is a trade-off between image fidelity and size. Low quality uses the highest compression and produces the smallest images. No Compression produces the largest, highest-quality images.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </case>
                                <case>
                                    <title nested="3">Watermark Options</title>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Watermark</name>
                                            <description>If enabled, prints a watermark on every page in the report. The properties below are also exposed.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Watermark type</name>
                                            <description>Specifies how to create the watermark. The options are:</description>
                                            <list>
                                                <item>
                                                    <name>Text</name>
                                                    <description>Watermark is defined as text, including the font, color, orientation, and position.</description>
                                                </item>
                                                <item>
                                                    <name>PDF</name>
                                                    <description>Watermark is defined as a PDF. Use this option to display a logo or other image as a watermark.</description>
                                                </item>
                                            </list>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Text</name>
                                            <description>The text to use as a watermark. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Font name</name>
                                            <description>The font to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Font size</name>
                                            <description>The font size to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Orientation</name>
                                            <description>The rotation of the watermark text in 0.1 degree increments. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Font color</name>
                                            <description>The font color to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Horizontal position</name>
                                            <description>The horizontal position of the watermark text in 0.1 inch units. This positive value measured from the left edge of the page should take into account the minimum printer margin. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Vertical position</name>
                                            <description>The vertical position of the watermark text in 0.1 inch units. This negative value measured from the top of the page should take into account the minimum printer margin. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Watermark file name</name>
                                            <description>The name of a PDF file to use as the watermark. Optionally, click *[ui:Click to create PDF from Bitmap]* to display the Create PDF File from Bitmap dialog. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:PDF]*</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Foreground</name>
                                            <description>When enabled, places the watermark above the page text, partially obscuring page content. When disabled, places the watermark below the page text.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </case>
                                <case>
                                    <title nested="3">Encryption Options</title>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Encrypt PDF file</name>
                                            <description>Check this property if you want to require a password to open the PDF file or set file permissions for the PDF. If enabled, the properties below are also exposed.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Owner password</name>
                                            <description>Specifies the text to use as the owner password. Only the owner can change the User password and the document other settings.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>User password</name>
                                            <description>Specifies the text to use as the read password.
                                            </description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Can print</name>
                                            <description>Specifies whether the reader can print the document.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Can modify document</name>
                                            <description>Specifies whether the reader can edit the document.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Can copy</name>
                                            <description>Specifies whether the reader can select text in the document and copy it.
                                            </description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Can add notes</name>
                                            <description>Specifies whether the reader can add notes.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Use 128 bit key</name>
                                            <description>Selects between 40 bit and 128 bit encryption. Readers will need Adobe Acrobat version 5 or higher to read 128 bit encrypted files.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </case>
                                <case>
                                    <title nested="3">Other Options</title>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>PDF Title</name>
                                            <description>The title of the PDF. This title is shown in some browser PDF viewers.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </case>
                            </cases>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Print timeout (seconds)</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Large PDF reports may take a long time to build and you may want to cancel reports that take too long to create.</p>
                                <p>The print timeout cancels any reports that do not completed within the specified time (in seconds). Set the timeout to 0 to allow all reports to run to completion.</p>
                                <p>An error will be reported back to the user if a report is cancelled because it exceeded the allowed time.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Print timeout message (optional)</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The system will generate an error message if a PDF report times out. Any optional message entered here will replace the system error message if the report times out.</p>
                                <p>This option is only shown if *[ui:Print timeout (seconds)]* is not zero.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2" buid="7509">Maximum Pages</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Limits the number of pages a PDF report can contain. By default, this value is set to 1000. Set to 0 to allow an unlimited number of pages.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Report Server</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Disable</title>
                            <description>Specify if the Report Server (used for printing PDF Reports in Web Applications) should be disabled. By default (in V12 and above) a 4 core Report Server is automatically enabled. (To license a Report Server that uses more than 4 cores, contact Alpha Software).</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use For HTML Reports</title>
                            <description>Offload HTML reports to the report server. This option should be used under conditions where your HTML reports are very large or complex.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Web-socket Applications</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Enable web-socket application</title>
                            <description>Specify if web-socket applications are enabled.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Web-socket server port</title>
                            <description>Specify the port that the web-socket server runs on. This must be a different port than the Alpha Anywhere server</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Excel Files</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2" build="6010">Extension</title>
                            <description>The default file extension to use for generated Excel files. This option can be used to force all files to use the *[.xlsx]* extension. This property can be set to the following:</description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Extension</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>.xls</name>
                                    <description>Default extension used. File extension used for Excel files created using versions of Office prior to 2007.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>.xlsx</name>
                                    <description>File extension used for Excel files created using Office 2007 and newer.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Design-time Properties</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Automatic Backups</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Backup folder</title>
                            <description>When you edit your Components an automatic backup is created. If you leave this property blank, the backups are stored in a subfolder in your web project. You can specify a folder where you would like the backups to be stored.</description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="5581">
                            <title nested="2">Delete old backups</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If enabled, allows you to configure when backup files should be cleaned up.</p>
                                <p>When you edit a component (i.e. Grid, UX, etc.) a backup copy is automatically made. The folder where the backups are stored can become quite large over time. You can specify that backups more than a certain number of days old should be purged. When purging old backups you can also specify the maximum number of backups to retain and the minimum number of backups to retain.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="5581">
                            <title nested="2">Number of days</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The number of days to keep a backup. If the backup is older than the specified number of days, it will be automatically deleted unless the number of existing backups is less than the specified *[ui:Minimum number of backups]*. Leave this value blank to keep all backups.</p>
                                <p>This property is only available when *[ui:Delete old backups]* has been enabled.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="5581">
                            <title nested="2">Maximum number of backups</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The maximum number of backup files to keep. Leave blank to specify no limit.</p>
                                <p>This property is only available when *[ui:Delete old backups]* has been enabled.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case build="5581">
                            <title nested="2">Minimum number of backups</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The minimum number of backups to retain. When deleting old backup files, you can use this property to guarantee that a number of backups are retained. Leave blank to set the minimum to 1.</p>
                                <p>This property is only available when *[ui:Delete old backups]* has been enabled.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Create AEX for Live Preview</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Auto-create AEX for Live Preview</title>
                            <description>When doing a Live Preview from a component builder, should all functions and classes defined in the Code tab of the Control Panel be compiled into an AEX file and automatically be published to the LivePreview folder? If you components do not reference any global UDFs, then this property can be turned off.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Live Preview</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Prompt to start server for Live Preview</title>
                            <description>When you select Live Preview while working in a Component Builder, if the server is not started, Alpha Anywhere will prompt if you want to start the server. In some cases you might have a server started in another Alpha Anywhere instance, so it would not be necessary to start the server in the current Alpha Anywhere instance. If you check this property, the prompt to start the server will be suppressed.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>A5_Application.A5I File</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Encrypt connection strings</title>
                            <description>Specify if connection strings in the a5_application.a5i file should be encrypted. Encryption is recommended. Turn encryption off if you are trying to debug a connection problem and want to see what connection strings are getting published.</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section build="6232">
                    <title>Encrypt Published Components</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Encrypted published components</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Alpha Anywhere can encrypt select file types when they are published. This allows developers who deploy application at on-site client locations to protect their work.</p>
                                <p>If enabled, the following files will be encrypted when published. Note that component files must be saved using the [Formatted JSON file format]:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list bullet="true">
                                        <item>
                                            <name>UX Components</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Tabbed UI Components</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Page Builder Components</name>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Xbasic Function Library and Module files</name>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                                <p>File types that are *[not]* encrypted include Grid Components, CSS files, JavaScript files, images, .a5w pages, and other static resources.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link link="Using the Stripe API From Xbasic">Stripe Genie...</link>
        <link link="api a5helper writetoauditinglog function">a5Helper_writeToAuditingLog()</link>
        <link link="api a5helper getauditinfofromsqlstatement function">a5Helper_getAuditInfoFromSQLStatement()</link>
        <link link="alpha%20anywhere%20alternative%20login%20-%20authentication%20and%20authorization%20using%20social%20network%20credentials">Alternative Login</link>
        <link link="api%20a5w%20save%20to%20web%20app%20repository%20function">a5w_SaveToWebAppRepository Function</link>
        <link link="api%20a5w%20get%20frm%20web%20app%20repository%20function">a5w_GetFromWebAppRepository Function</link>
        <link link="api%20a5w%20enumerate%20web%20app%20repository%20function">a5w_enumerateWebAppRepository Function</link>
        <link link="uxadhocsqlquerybuilder template">UX_Ad_Hoc_SQL_QueryBuilder UX template</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="alpha%20anywhere%20alternative%20login%20-%20authentication%20and%20authorization%20using%20social%20network%20credentials">Alternative Logins</link>
        <link link="bulk%20operation%20change%20storage%20type">Formatted JSON file format</link>
        <link link="tabbedui%20storesecuritygroupsdb">Store security groups in database</link>
        <link link="ux controls other controls jitsi meet">Jitsi Meet control</link>
        <link href="mailto:bugs@alphasoftware.com">bugs@alphasoftware.com</link>
        <link link="api%20date%20and%20time%20format%20elements">Date and Time Format Elements</link>
        <link link="api%20email%20send%20sparkpost%20function">email_send_sparkpost()</link>
        <link link="send%20email">Action Javascript</link>
        <link link="ux%20server-side%20actions%20send%20an%20email%20message">Action Scripting</link>
        <link link="a5_globalsetting_add function">a5_globalSetting_add()</link>
        <link link="a5_globalsetting_delete function">a5_globalSetting_delete()</link>
        <link link="a5_globalsetting_get function">a5_globalSetting_get()</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="https://blog.chromium.org/2019/10/developers-get-ready-for-new.html">Developers: Get Ready for New SameSite=None; Secure Cookie Settings</ref>
        <ref link="reporting pdfreports pdfdirect">Generating Reports with "Direct to PDF"</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>box.com,email settings</terms>
</page>