<page>
	<topic>Go to Record Key</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Go to Record Key action displays the records matching a key value. The key value can be defined ahead of time, or by prompting the user at run-time.</description>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Go to record in which Form/Browse window? field. This field will be grayed out unless this action is based on a Form or Browse. The choices are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Current Form or Browse Window". </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Another Form or Browse Window". </description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Another Form or Browse Window", in the Window Name field select either:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Forms" </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Browses" </description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select one of the listed forms or browses.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection from the How will you specify the record number to go to? list. The options are:</description>
				
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Specify record key value now" </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Specify a variable that contains the key value" </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Specify an expression that evaluates to the key value" </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Prompt user at run time" </description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>If you selected "Specify record number now", enter the number in the Key value field.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>If you selected "Specify a variable that contains the record number", enter the variable name in the Variable Name field. Optionally, click the 'down' icon button to select an existing variable.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>If the variable is new, select is type from the Variable Type list.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>If you selected "Specify an expression that evaluates to the record number", enter the expression in the Expression field. Optionally, click the x-y button to open the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
					<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Go to Record Number</ref>
		<ref><![CDATA[<OBJECT>.FINDBY_DEFINEDKEY()]]></ref>
		
		
	</see>
	
</page>