<page>
    <shortlink>ux properties application cache</shortlink>
    <topic>Application Cache</topic>
    <description>Properties for configuring the UX Component to use the AppCache for building offline web applications.</description>
    <!--list:.-->
    <!--order:Create static HTML page
Static HTML page name
Javascript - cacheError
Javascript - cacheProgress
Javascript - updateReady-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Building Offline HTML5 Applications</title>
            <description>
                <p>Offline enabled HTML pages can be loaded into a browser even if no internet connection is available.</p>
                <p>To turn on this feature, click the smart field for the [Create a static HTML page with an application cache] property, as shown in the image below.</p>
                <p>When this property is checked, when you save the UX component, a special sub-directory in the Web Project folder is created. This directory is called *[ui:StaticHTMLFileset]* and it contains the static HTML page with the rendered UX component and all of the files referenced by this page (e.g. Javascript, CSS and image files). The directly also contains an application manifest file which lists all of the files reference by the static HTML page. The application manifest file is linked in the head of the static HTML page by specifying a value for the *[ui:manifest]* attribute in the *[ui:<![CDATA[<html>]]>]* tag. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[<html manifest="cache_myuxcomponent.appmanifest">]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Application Cache can be turned on in a UX Component by checking the Create a static HTML page with an application cache property</title>
                <link>images/appcache.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
            <p>When a static HTML page that includes a manifest is loaded, all of the files listed in the manifest are stored in the browser's ApplicationData storage area.</p>
            <p>When a static HTML page is loaded, the browser checks to see if a cached version of the page and all of the files it references exists in the browser's ApplicationData storage area. If so, the page is loaded from the ApplicationData storage area. To determine if the cached version is stale or not, but browser will attempt to contact the server (if an internet connection is available) to check if a newer version of the manifest is available.</p>
            <p>If a newer manifest is available, the browser will download and cache the new version of the static HTML page and its referenced files.</p>
            <p>While the browser is downloading files listed in the manifest, a series of events will fire. You can specify event handlers for these events in your UX component.</p>
            <p>When you click the smart field for the [Create a static HTML page with an application cache] property, you can automatically generate default code for the [error], [updateready] and [progress] Application Cache events.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="Create static HTML page.xml">Create a static HTML page with an application cache</link>
        <link href="cacheError.xml">error</link>
        <link href="cacheProgress.xml">progress</link>
        <link href="updateReady.xml">updateready</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=buildingdisconnectedapplications">Building Disconnected Applications</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>appcache,offline web app</terms>
</page>