<page>
	<topic>Format Menu Functions</topic>
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Font</title>
				<description>[a]. Available only when you select text on the WYSIWYG tab. Displays the Font dialog box and wraps the selected text with the following HTML codes:</description>
			<example><![CDATA[Font_Name size= Font_Size > Selected Text .]]></example>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Edit Style Sheets</title>
				<description>allows you to edit an existing CSS style sheet.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Link Style Sheet</title>
				<description>Displays the Link Style Sheet dialog, which allows you to link to a CSS style sheet located locally or at a URL address. Note: A local style sheet must first be added to the current project.
 </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Remove Formatting</title>
				<description>Available only when you select text on the WYSIWYG tab. Removes all HTML formatting codes.
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Properties</title>
				<description>[hand]</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Formatting Text</title>
		<description>To change the font, point size, style, or color of text:</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Display the WYSIWYG tab of your HTML Editor window.</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Select the text and click Format > Font.</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, select values from the Font, Style, and Size lists.</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>You may also enter a point size, such as 8.5, into the Size field. </description>
				<figure><link>images/UG_HTML_Editor_Font_Properties.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, select a color from the Color list.</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, click [abar] to display the Color dialog.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, select a color from either of the Basic colors or Custom colors palettes.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, click Define Custom Colors >> and select a color from the larger multi-colored window at right.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, enter Hue, Saturation, and Luminance values (0 to 255).
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, enter Red, Green, and Blue values (0 to 255).
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>If you create a new color definition, you may click A dd to Custom Colors to add it to the Custom colors palette.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>The dialog will generate HTML code for font and color similar to the following.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<example><![CDATA[<FONT color=#0000ff face=Verdana>....</FONT>]]></example>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>The dialog will generate .... for bold, .... for italic, and .... with a bar under it for underline.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Using a Cascading Style Sheet
</title>
		<description>There are two approaches to applying a cascading style sheet to your page. You can either link to the style sheet or embed its contents between tags.
To embed a style sheet into the page:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select Format > Edit Style Sheets(s)... to display the CSS Editor.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Import CSS to display the Import dialog.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select Append and OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Navigate to the .CSS file, select it, and click Open.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click OK to return to the HTML Editor. The Style list box will list the embedded styles.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>	
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>To link to a local style sheet:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>First, add the style sheet to your project.
</description>
		</step>
				<step>
			<description>Select Format > Link Style Sheet... to display the CSS Editor.
</description>
		</step>
				<step>
			<description>Click Local Style Sheet.
</description>
		</step>
				<step>
			<description>Select the style sheet from the list and click Link. The Style list box will list the linked styles.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>	
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>To link to a remote style sheet:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>First, add the style sheet to your project.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select Format > Link Style Sheet... to display the CSS Editor.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Absolute URL.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Enter the URL, directory location, and filename of the .CSS file in the URL Style Sheet control.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the style sheet from the list and click Link.
</description>
<note>The Style list box will not list styles from the remote style sheet. You will have to display the Source tab and enter appropriate HTML codes into the page .</note>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>	
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.</limitations>
	<links>
		<link href="images/Filter_Font_Styles.gif">a</link>
		<link href="images/Properties_button.gif">hand</link>
	</links>
	<see>
		<ref>Using the HTML Editor</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>