<page>
	<topic>SuperControls</topic>
	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Overview of New Supercontrol Types</title>
<description>There are several new controls that can be placed on Forms, and (for some of the supercontrols), on other layout types. These new controls are called 'supercontrols' because they go far beyond the simple controls (like textboxes, labels, etc.) that you can currently place on Forms. 
The following table summarizes the new controls that can be placed on Forms:
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Record Navigator Trackbar  </title>
		<description>Allows you to move through the records in a Form by dragging on a trackbar or scrollbar. When you drag on a trackbar, bubble help show you information from the record that you would be on if you were to stop dragging.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Embedded Xdialog</title>
		<description>Allows you to embed an Xdialog in a Form. The Xdialog definition can either be stored in the Form definition itself, or it can be a Global Script. You can bind fields and variables in your Form to the variables shown in the Xdialog. For example, if the table on which the Form is based has a field called 'firstname' and the Xdialog displays an input control for a variable called 'fn', you can bind the 'firstname' field to the 'fn' variable. This means that as you navigate from one record to the next, the value shown in the Xdialog automatically changes to show the value for the current record. Similarly, if you edit the value in the field on the Xdialog, the bound field in the Form's table is automatically updated.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Hyperlink</title>
		<description>The hyperlink super control is a very simple form of a button that looks like a hyperlink on an HTML page, rather than a standard button on a Form. When you click on the hyperlink any Xbasic code can be executed.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Report Preview</title>
		<description>Allows you to embed a window in a Form that will show Reports, Labels or Letters. The Report can be automatically filtered based on data in the current record. When you navigate from record to record, the report preview window is automatically updated.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Clock</title>
		<description>Allows you to embed a clock control on a Form. The clock can be bound to a time or shorttime field (or variable) in one of the tables that the Form is based on. When you navigate from record to record, the time displayed on the clock is automatically updated. If you change the time in the clock control, the field or variable to which the clock is bound is automatically changed.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Calendar</title>
		<description>Allows you to embed a calendar control on a Form. The calendar can be bound to a date field (or variable) in one of the tables that the Form is based on. When you navigate from record to record, the date displayed on the calendar is automatically updated. If you change the date in the calendar control, the field or variable to which the calendar is bound is automatically changed.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>HTML Forms</title>
		<description>HTML Forms are windows in your Form that contain HTML content. The HTML content will typically contain HTML form elements, such as input controls, text areas, buttons etc. You can bind fields and variable in your Form to the HTML input controls in the HTML form. As you navigate from record to record in the form, the values shown in the HTML form controls will automatically be updated. And similarly, if you edit the value in any of the bound HTML form controls, the corresponding field in the Form's table is automatically updated. </description>
	<note>The HTML Form supercontrol can also be used in the Xdialog Genie is Action Scripts.</note>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>PDF Viewer</title>
		<description>The PDF Viewer control allows you to place a window on your Form that will display a PDF document. You must have Adobe Acrobat reader installed for this feature to work.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Web Content</title>
		<description>Allows you to display a web page in a window on a Form. The URL for the web page can either be static, or dynamically computed from data in the current record. Pre-defined templates for Google Maps, Google Search, MSN Maps, and Yahoo Maps are provided. You can also create your own templates.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>HTML Content</title>
		<description>Puts static HTML content in a window on a Form. The static content is specified by an expression that evaluates to the HTML text that you want to display. </description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
<section>
	<title>Inserting a Supercontrol on a Form</title>
	<description>To place an Supercontrol on a form, select the SuperControl tool on the toolbar, draw the control on the form. As soon as you release the mouse button, the pop-up 'Insert Supercontrol' dialog appears, as shown below.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn10.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn7.jpg</link></figure>
</section>
<section>
	<description>Make your selection, and then press the Insert button.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Placing a Supercontrol on the Toolbox</title>
			<description>If you expect to use any of the Supercontrols frequently, then you can put that control directly on the toolbox. This will give you single click access to the control in the future.
To place a Supercontrol on the toolbox, right click on any Icon on the toolbox and select 'Add Supercontrol to Toolbox...'.
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Editing a Supercontrol</title>
<description>After you have placed a supercontrol on a Form layout you can edit its properties. To display the supercontrol's Properties Dialog, either right click on the supercontrol and select 'Supercontrol Designer...' from the right click menu, or click on the small button at the top right corner of the supercontrol. To edit a supercontrol, click on the button in the top right corner.
</description>	
<figure><link>images/WorkIn12.gif</link></figure>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>HTML Form Supercontrol</title>
	<description>The HTML Form supercontrol allows you to place a window on your Form that contains an HTML form. The controls in the HTML form can be bound to the fields in the table that the Form is based on. The HTML Form supercontrol is aimed at users who have a good understanding of HTML and CSS and want to extend their forms using effects more easily accomplished in HTML than using standard Alpha Anywhere form design features.

The screenshot below shows a Form with standard Alpha Anywhere controls in the top section, and an HTML form showing the save fields in the bottom section:
</description>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHTMLFormsBasicExample.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>When you place the HTML Form supercontrol on a Form, the following Designer screen is shown, HTML Form supercontrol  Designer:</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn29.jpg</link></figure>
<cases><case>
	
	<title>Tab Names:</title>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>HTML Body</title>
			<description>This page allows you to define the HTML layout of the HTML Form. </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Bindings</title>
			<description>This page allows you to define bindings between the controls on your HTML Form and the fields and variables in the underlying table that the form is based on. For example, if the Form is based on the 'Customer' table and you have an input control on the HTML Form with an id of 'fn', you can bind to 'firstname' field from the 'Customer' table to the 'fn' control on the HTML Form.

You can also define 'Property Bindings' which allow you to define expressions that automatically control property values on the HTML Form. For example, you might want to automatically show the border around an input control in red if some field value is above a certain amount.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>CSS</title>
			<description>This page allows you to define any CSS used in your HTML Form. You have access to Alpha Anywhere's full featured CSS editor from this tab pane.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Linked Files</title>
			<description>If your HTML Form references any CSS or Javascript that is stored in separate files, you can defined the links to these files on this page.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Initial Code</title>
			<description>This page allows you to specify any Xbasic code that you want to execute before the HTML Form is instantiated.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Events</title>
			<description>This page allows you to define Xbasic event handlers for any event on the HTML Form that  you want to handle using Xbasic. For example, you might have defined a hyperlink control on the HTML Form. If you want to respond to the onclick event of this hyperlink using an Xbasic event handler,  you would define the event handler on this tab. Note however, that if you want to use Javascript to handle events, the Javascript would be inserted into the HTML on the HTML Body tab.</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
</case>

<case>
	<title>Field Bindings</title>
	<description>The controls on the HTML Form supercontrol can be bound to fields and variables in the underlying table(s) that the container Form is based on. For example in the in the screenshot shown above, the HTML Supercontrol is placed on a Form that is based on the 'customer' table. The HTML form's controls are bound to the firstname, lastname, etc. fields in underlying table.
To define the field bindings, select the Bindings tab in the Designer. Bindings tab allows you to define bindings between controls on the HTML form and the underlying table that the container form is based on.

</description>
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>Property Bindings
</title>
	<description>Property Bindings are an extremely powerful feature of HTML Forms. Property Bindings allow you to bind a property value of an element on the HTML form to the result of an Xbasic expression. For example, you might want to put a red border around a field if a certain condition was met. To define a Property Binding, select the Bindings tab in the Designer. In the example shown below, we set the 'style.borderColor' property of the 'billCountry' input control to 'red' if the Bill_country field is blank. If it is not blank we set it to a null value, which means that the default value for the property is used (as defined by the CSS that was defined for the HTML Form). To edit a supercontrol, click on the button in the top right corner.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn31.jpg</link></figure>
</case>

<case>
	<description>In this next example, lets assume that we are displaying a built-in Alpha Anywhere icon in the HTML form which can be done by using the special 'a5:image' attribute on an  tag.
The following HTML shown an image called 'OverdueIcon'.
</description>
	<note>Built-in Alpha Anywhere icons also include any images that you add to the Code tab on the Control Panel.</note>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>Assume that we would like to display an image called 'currentIcon' if a customer's account was current, and the 'OverdueIcon' if the balance was overdue.
To do this we would define a property binding for the 'image1' element on the HTML Form, setting the 'a5:image' property to the result of this expression:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[iif(date() > dueDate,"OverdueIcon","currentIcon")
]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of property bindings.
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHTMLFormsPropertyBinding.swf</link>
			
		</video>
			
			
		
		
	</videos>
	
</case>
<case>
	
	<title>Xbasic Event Handlers</title>
	<description>The HTML form raises the standard HTML Form events. These are:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>onclick
</description>
		</case>
	<case>
			<description>onmousedown
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onmouseup
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onmouseover
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onmouseout
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onchange
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onblur
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onfocus
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onkeypress
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onkeydown
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>onkeyup
</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>You can write event handlers for these events using standard Xbasic scripts. If you prefer, you can also write event handlers for these events using Javascript. However, being able to write event handlers for HTML events using Xbasic provides a big benefit to users who already know Xbasic, but not Javascript.
To handle an event using Xbasic, the event is specified by prefixing the event name with 'a5:'. For example, the following shows the HTML for the 'bill_address2' input control. Notice that the event handler is specified as 'a5:onblur'. This indicates that the 'onblur' event will be handled using an Xbasic function called 'address2_onblur()'.
</description>
<note>The onblur event fires when the control looses focus.</note>
</case>
<case>
	<example><![CDATA[<input id="billAddress2" class="edit" style="width: 2.75in;" 
a5:on<x>blur="address2_on<x>blur()"/>]]></example>
</case>

<case>
	<description>The Xbasic function address2_onblur() is defined on the Events tab. For example, the following simple event could be defined that checks to see if the user use the abbreviation 'Apt.' in the field, and if so, change it to 'Apartment':
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[function address2_onblur as v ()
if word(self.Bill_address_2,1," ") = "Apt." then 
    self.Bill_address_2 = stritran(self.Bill_address_2,"Apt.","Apartment")
end if 
end function
]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	
	<description>Notice that in order to refer to any of the fields in the table (or tables) that the Form is based on you must use the 'self.' prefix. If you are referencing a field in a child table, or a form variable, you need to qualify the fieldname with its alias, but you must still use the self prefix. For example:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>self.customer->lastname
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>self.var->formVar1
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>Accessing the DOM in Your Event Handler Scripts
</title>
	<description>Your Xbasic event handler scripts have full access to the HTML DOM (Document Object Model) and can manipulate any aspect of the DOM.
To get a pointer to the DOM, you would insert this code into your event handler function:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[DIM DOM as p 
DOM = self.htmlform.object.ax.document
]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	<description>For example, the following Xbasic code snippet gets a pointer to the DOM, then gets a pointer to the input control with the id of 'billAddress1' and then sets its border color to red. Note that when working with the DOM, object ids and property names are all case sensitive.
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[DIM DOM as p 
DOM = self.htmlform.object.ax.document
id = DOM.getElementById("billAddress1")
id.style.borderColor = "red"
]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	<description>If we had wanted to handle the onblur event using Javascript, then we would have specified the control as  (leaving out the 'a5:' prefix on the event name):
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[<input id="billAddress2" class="edit" style="width: 2.75in;" 
on<x>blur="address2_on<x>blur()"/>]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>The address2_onblur() function would have been written in Javascript and would appear in tags in the HTML Body.
</description>
</case>


<case>
	<title>Alpha Anywhere HTML Controls</title>
	<description>When you define the HTML for your HTML Form, you can use the standard HTML tags. However, there are also a series of special tags that you can use to define the following controls in your HTML Form:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Accordion</title>
			<description>Allows you to create an accordion control with multiple panes. You can place any HTML content in each accordion pane. You can specify whether only one pane is open at a time, or whether multiple panes can be visible simultaneously. The image below shows an accordion with four panes, only one of which can be visible at a time: 

</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn32.jpg</link></figure>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Tab</title>
			<description>Allows you to create a tab control with multiple panes. The tab buttons can be placed on top, bottom, left or right of the client area. You can place any HTML content in each tab pane. The image below shows a tab control:</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn8.gif</link></figure>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Conditional Block</title>
			<description>Allows you to create a series of panes (just like a tab control). An Xbasic expression determines which pane is visible. This is similar to the 'Conditional Object' control that can be placed on all Layout objects (e.g. Forms, Reports, Labels, Letters). Any HTML content can be placed in each pane of the Conditional Block.</description>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Condition</title>
			<description>Defines some HTML content that is either displayed or not displayed depending on the result of an Xbasic expression. You can specify if the space taken by the control is preserved or not when the control's content is not displayed. For example, you might want to display some message on the form if the user enters an invalid value into a control.</description>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Dynamic Content Region</title>
			<description>Creates a region in the HTML layout whose content is dynamically updated by an XBasic expression. When the XBasic expression changes the HTML content is automatically updated. For example, you might have an Xbasic variable that contains a string of text that is an HTML table. When you want to change the rows or columns in the table, just set this variable to a new value that contains the new table layout and the Dynamic Content Region on the HTML Form will be updated. In the example below, the table is in a Dynamic Content Region. The HTML for the table is in a string variable. When this variable changes, the Dynamic Content Region is automatically updated.</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn35.jpg</link></figure>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Dynamic Select</title>
			<description>Allows you to dynamically set and change the choices in a dropdownbox (i.e. both a listbox and a combobox) by setting an Xbasic variable to a comma-delimited list of choices.</description>

		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Alpha Anywhere Image</title>
			<description>Normally, the HTML tag is used to display the image in a free-standing image file. This control allows you to use any of the hundreds of built-in Alpha Anywhere images directly.</description>

		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</case>
<case>
	<note>Examples of all of these special Alpha Anywhere HTML controls can be found in the sample 'Learning Xdialog' database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. See the 'HTML Forms' section in the 'What's new in Version 9' category.
To place an Alpha Anywhere HTML control in your HTML Form, click the 'A5 Controls' button on the toolbar when the 'HTML Body' tab is active.

</note>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>Placing an Alpha Anywhere HTML control in your HTML Form.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn33.jpg</link></figure>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>The following dialog allows you to select the appropriate Alpha Anywhere control, Selecting an Alpha Anywhere HTML Control:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn34.jpg</link></figure>
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Accordion Control
</title>
	<description>When you place an Accordion control in your HTML form, a genie is displayed that allows you to set the properties of the accordion. Accordion control Genie.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn36.jpg</link></figure>
	
</case>

<case>
	<description>In the top part of the Genie you can enter a list of pane titles to appear in the accordion. Enter a CR-LF delimited list.
Next, you can choose a style for the accordion from the list of available styles.
You can optionally specify the height and width of the accordion control. If you leave these prompts blank the accordion will automatically stretch to the size of its contents.
You can also specify if the currently open pane is closed when a new pane is opened.
When you click the OK button, the HTML for the control is inserted into the HTML Body of the HTML Form. For example:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[Pane 1  
                Content for Pane 1 pane here...
        Pane 2
                Content for Pane 2 pane here...]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<note>Notice that the accordion uses special A5 HTML tags: , and .
</note>
</case>
<case>
	
	<title>Editing an Accordion Control using the Genie
</title>
<description>After the Accordion control has been placed in the HTML form, you can either edit the HTML directly, or you can display a genie. 
To display the genie, click in the opening tag, and then right click.  Select 'Edit Accordion Control' from the right click menu. The Accordion Control Editor.
</description>	
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn37.jpg</link></figure>
</case>
<case>
	<description>The Genie allows you to:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Add and delete tab panes
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Reorder tab panes
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Change the style of the accordion
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Edit the CSS for the various classes that are used to define the appearance of the Accordion
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Specify the Accordion variable (see below for more on the Accordion variable).
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>The Accordion variable is a character variable that contains a CR-LF delimited string of numeric values showing the index values of the open tabs. For example, let's assume that you have defined an Accordion with four tabs. If you have set the 'Single Band' property to false (meaning that multiple tab bands can be open at the same time), and if you have opened tab pane 1 and 3 the Accordion variable will contain:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[1
3 ]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	<description>The value in the Accordion variable can be set. For example, if you set the Accordion variable to "4", pane number four will open, and all other panes will close.
</description>
</case>

<case>
	<title>Accordion Control Events
</title>
	<description>The Accordion control exposes two events:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>beforeChange</title>
			<description>Fires when the user attempts to change the active tab, but before the change is actually made. If the event handler returns .f. then the tab is not changed.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>afterChange</title>
			<description>Fires after the user has changed the active tab.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
	
	
</case>
<case>
	<note>Because the accordion is an Alpha Anywhere HTML control, not a native HTML control, the event handlers for the beforeChange and afterChange events can only be written in Xbasic.</note>
</case>


<case>
	<description>In the following example, accordion control is placed on a form and an event handler is defined for the beforeChange event:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[Pane 1
            
                Content for Pane 1 pane here...
            
    
    
        Pane 2
            
                Content for Pane 2 pane here...
             ]]></example>
	
</case>

<case>
	<description>Here is the event handler function (defined on the Events tab of the HTML Form builder):
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[function canchangetab as l ()
q = ui_msg_box("Notice","Allow me to change the active tab?",UI_YES_NO)
if q = ui_yes_selected then 
    canchangetab = .t.
else
    canchangetab = .f.
end if 
end function 
]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>Setting and Getting Open Panes using Xbasic 
</title>
	<description>It is often necessary to determine which panes are currently open and to set the open panes using Xbasic. It is also a requirement sometime to be able to set the initial open panes when the accordion is loaded.
The open panes are controlled by the variable that is set in the tag. For example, in the code fragment below, the accordion variable is set to 'accordion_var'. 
</description>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>'Accordion_var' is a character variable that has a CRLF delimited list of open panes (in the case where the accordion is configured to allow multiple open panes). For example if pane 1 and 3 were open, this variable would contain:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[1
3
]]></example>
</case>

<case>
	<description>If the accordion is configured to only allow a single open pane, then of course, the accordion variable will not be a CRLF delimited list, but will be a single value.
To set the initially open panes, in the 'Initial Code' tab, simply dim and set the value of the accordion variable ('accordion_var' in this example).
</description>
	<figure><link>images/NewInA66.jpg</link></figure>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>In the context of an Xdialog, the value of the accordion variable ('accordion_var' in this example) can be read and set directly. So, if you place an HTML Form that contains an accordion on an Xdialog, you can simply put code like this in the Xdialog event handler:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[if a_dlg_button = "closeAllPanes" then 
    a_dlg_button  = ""
    accordion_var = ""
end if 

if a_dlg_button = "openFirstPane" then 
    a_dlg_button = ""
    accordion_var = "1"
end if 
]]></example>
	
</case>

<case>
	<description>However, in the case of an accordion control embedded in an HTML Form Supercontrol on a Form layout, you cannot directly get at the accordion variable ('accordion_var' in this example). Instead you must use the .SetVariable() and .GetVariable() methods to set and get 'accordion_var'.
For exmaple (assume that when you placed the HTML Form Supercontrol on the Form layout, the object name you assigned to the control was 'htmlform1'):
</description>
	<example><![CDATA['set the accordion to open panes 1, 2 and 3
htmlform1.SetVariable("accordion_var",comma_to_crlf("1,2,3"))

'show which panes are currently open
dim openpanes as c 
openpanes =  htmlform1.GetVariable("accordion_var")
ui_msg_box("Open Panes",openpanes)
]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of the Accordion control in an HTML Form supercontrol (part 1)   
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHTMLFormsAccordion.swf</link>
		</video>
			<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of the Accordion control in an HTML Form supercontrol (part 2)
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHTMLFormsCSS.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Tab Control</title>
<description>When you place a Tab control in your HTML form, a genie is displayed that allows you to set the properties of the tab control.
The HTML Form Tab Control Genie.</description>	
<figure><link>images/NewInA65.jpg</link></figure>	
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>The top part of the window shows a CRLF delimited list of tab pane titles. The middle part of the windows shows a list of style templates that you can choose from to control the look of the tab object.
Pane width and pane height can be left blank, in which case the tab object will be sized automatically based on the size of the content in the tab panes.
The location of the tab buttons can be set in the Tab Location dropdown box. The tab location can be top, left, right, or bottom.
When you click OK, the HTML for the tab object is inserted into the HTML Form genie, as shown below:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[    Pane 1
        
            Content for Pane 1 pane here...
        
    
    
        Pane 2
        
            Content for Pane 2 pane here...
        
    
    
        Pane 3
        
            Content for Pane 3 pane here...]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	<description>Notice that the tab object uses special tags. The tab is . This contains a series of tags, and so on.
You can bring up the genie again, but putting the insertion point in the opening tag, and then right clicking.
</description>
	
</case>

<case>
	<title>Tab Control Events
</title>
<description>The Tab control exposes two events:
</description>	
<cases>
	<case><title>beforeChange</title>
<description>Fires when the user attempts to change the active tab, but before the change is actually made. If the event handler returns .f. then the tab is not changed.</description>	
	</case>
	<case><title>afterChange</title>
<description>Fires after the user has changed the active tab.</description>	
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</case>
<case>
	<note>Because the tab control is an Alpha Anywhere HTML control, not a native HTML control, the event handlers for the beforeChange and afterChange events can only be written in Xbasic.

</note>
</case>

<case>
	<title>Setting and Getting the Current Tab Pane using Xbasic 
</title>
<description>It is often necessary to determine which pane is selected and to set the current pane using Xbasic. It is also a requirement sometime to be able to set the initial open pane when the tab is loaded.
The open pane is controlled by the variable that is set in the tag. For example, in the code fragment below, the tab variable is set to 'tab_var'. 


'Tab_var' is a character variable that has a value of "1", "2", "3", etc., depending on whether the first, second, third, etc. tab pane is currently selected.
To set the initially open pane, in the 'Initial Code' tab, simply dim and set the value of the tab variable ('tab_var' in this example).
</description>	
<figure><link>images/NewInA67.jpg</link></figure>	
</case>
<case>
	<description>In the context of an Xdialog, the value of the tab variable ('tab_var' in this example) can be read and set directly. So, if you place an HTML Form that contains a tab control on an Xdialog, you can simply put code like this in the Xdialog event handler:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[if a_dlg_button = "selectPane2" then 
    a_dlg_button = ""
    tab_var = "2"
end if 
]]></example>
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>However, in the case of a tab control embedded in an HTML Form Supercontrol on a Form layout, you cannot directly get at the tab  variable ('tab_var' in this example). Instead you must use the .SetVariable() and .GetVariable() methods to set and get 'accordion_var'.
For example (assume that when you placed the HTML Form Supercontrol on the Form layout, the object name you assigned to the control was 'htmlform1'):
</description>
<example><![CDATA['set the tab to select pane 2 
htmlform1.SetVariable("tab_var","2")

'show which tab pane is currently selected
dim pane as c 
pane = htmlform1.GetVariable("tab_var")
ui_msg_box("Selected Pane",pane)
]]></example>
	
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Conditional Block Control</title>
	<description>When you place a Conditional Block control into an HTML Form supercontrol, the following HTML in inserted. Notice that this HTML uses the special and tags. There can be an unlimited number of tags within the conditional block.
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[Thank you for you payment by check number ]]></example>
	
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere evaluates the  pane expressions and displays the first pane for which the expression evaluates to .t.. 
Only one pane can be visible. If more than one pane expression evaluates to .t., the last pane that evaluates to .t. is displayed.
To create a default pane (i.e. a pane that is shown if none of other expressions is .t.), create a pane with an expression of '.t.' and make this the last pane in the  list.

In the following example, different content is displayed depending on whether the 'methodOfPayment' field is 'check' or 'creditcard':
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[    Thank you for you check. 
 We have charged  your credit card.]]></example>
	
	
</case>
<case>
	<description>Notice that the quoted strings in the expression are quoted using single quotes because the expression as a whole is quoted with double quotes. You cannot use escaped quotes (e.g. \" ) inside the expression as you normally can do within Alpha Anywhere expressions.
</description>
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Condition Control</title>
<description>When you place a Conditional control into an HTML Form supercontrol, the following HTML in inserted. Notice that this HTML uses the special tag. 


The expression, which is an Xbasic expression, determines whether the HTML contained between the opening and closing tags is displayed. The 'preserveLayoutSpace' attribute determines whether the space taken by control is preserved when the content is not shown. I.e. if the space is preserved, then it is as if the content is displayed in invisible ink. If the space is not preserved, the HTML is laid out as if the HTML in the Condition control was not there at all.
The Condition control and the Conditional Block command can be confusingly similar.
The Conditional Block is suited for situations where you want to display one of several different blocks of HTML depending on the what condition is true. For example, you might have defined 10 different blocks of HTML and you want to display one of these blocks depending on what value an expression evaluates to.
On the other hand, a Condition control is suited for situations where some particular block of HTML is either present or not present in your HTML form. For example, you might have defined a block of HTML that says 'This account is overdue' which you only want to show if the account is overdue.
</description>	
	
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Dynamic Content Region Control</title>
<description>When you place a Dynamic Content control into an HTML Form supercontrol, the following HTML is inserted. Notice that this HTML uses a special tag.
 

The expression is an Xbasic expression that evaluates to some HTML. When the value of the expression changes, the contents of the Dynamic Content Region is automatically refreshed. 
The displayMode attribute can be set to either 'inline' or 'block'. The default, if the attribute is omitted is 'block'. If the displayMode is set to 'inline', then the Dynamic Content control is rendered immediately adjacent to any preceding HTML content. If the displayMode attribute is set to 'block', then the Dynamic Content is rendered on a new line.
For example, assume that your HTML form had the following Dynamic Content Region control defined:
 

If the Notes field or variable contained this string: "Hello World" then the Dynamic Content Region would display:
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[Hello World]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	<title>The Dynamic Select Control
</title>
<description>The Dynamic Select Control is a standard HTML select control whose choices are dynamically set to the result of an Xbasic expression that returns a CR-LF delimited list of values.
When you insert the Dynamic Select control into an HTML Form supercontrol, the following HTML is inserted. 

Notice that this is the standard HTML select control, but with a special a5:listExpression attribute.
For example, the following will display a drop down box showing all of the built-in Alpha Anywhere color names:
</description>	
	
</case>
<case>
	
<description>To display one value, but return another value, each entry in the CR-LF delimited list can be for the form:/description>	
	<example><![CDATA[displayValue|storedValue
]]></example>
</case>
<case>
	
<description>For example:
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[red|r
    green|g
    blue|b]]></example>
</case>


<case>
	
<description>To create a listbox (rather than a drop down box), you just specify a size attribute on the dropdown</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[<select size="10" id="" 
a5:listExpression="a5.color_enum()"></select>]]></example>
</case>

<case>
	<title>The Alpha Anywhere Image Control
</title>
<description>Normally, when you display an image in an HTML document, the image must be a free-standing file. Alpha Anywhere comes with hundreds of built-in images (for example all of the images that appear on the toolbar buttons) which you might want to place on an HTML form. Having to export these images to free-standing files just so that they can be incorporated into an HTML Form would be inconvenient. The Alpha Anywhere Image control allows you to embed any of the built-in Alpha Anywhere images in your HTML Form control.
</description>	
	
</case>
<case>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Putting it all together - a video of an advanced HTML Form</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHTMLFormsExtendedExample.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
	
</case>

</cases>	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Hyperlink Supercontrol
</title>
	<description>The Hyperlink supercontrol allows you to put hyperlinks on a form. Hyperlinks are just like buttons - when you click then, some Xbasic code is executed - but they take up less space on your form. Another nice advantage of the hyperlink super control is the ease with which they can be enabled/disabled. You can specify an expression that if True, enables the hyperlink and if False, disables the hyperlink.
The image below shows a hyperlink control on a form. As you see, the hyperlink is much less obtrusive than the 'Print this Invoice' button.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn9.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<description>See the section above, 'Inserting a Supercontrol on a Form' for information on how to place a hyperlink control on a form.
When you place a hyperlink control on form, the Hyperlink Builder is displayed. This dialog allows you to define these properties:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Text</title>
			<description>The text that appears in the hyperlink.</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<title>Enabled</title>
			<description>An expression that returns .t. or .f. . If the expression returns a .f. value, the hyperlink is disabled. If you leave the expression blank, the hyperlink is always enabled.</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<title>Event</title>
			<description>The Xbasic code to execute when the hyperlink is clicked.</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</section>
<section>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn11.jpg</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsHyperlink.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Record Navigator Supercontrol
</title>
<description>The Record Navigator supercontrol allows you to put a record navigator on a Form. There are three types of record navigators that you can choose from:
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Trackbar
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Scrollbar
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>VCR Buttons
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>The trackbar and scrollbar options allow you to choose a vertical or horizontal orientation. The trackbar option also gives you control over the tickmarks on the trackbar.
A particularly nice feature of the trackbar is the ability to configure it to show bubble help as you are dragging on the slider. The bubble help will show the logical record number, and if the data is sorted in some order other than record number order, it will also show the key value of the current key. For example, in the image below the bubble help shows that if the trackbar slider were to be dropped in its current position, the current record would become logical record number 12 (which has a Lastname value of 'Copen').
See the section above, 'Inserting a Supercontrol on a Form' for information on how to place a Record Navigator supercontrol on a form.
Form showing a Record Navigator supercontrol configured as a horizontal trackbar. Notice the bubble help on the slider as it is being moved.'
</description>
<figure><link>images/WorkIn15.jpg</link></figure>	
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<description>Builder for the Record Navigator supercontrol.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn16.jpg</link></figure>
</section>

<section>
	<description>Form showing three Record Navigators in each of the available styles - trackbar, scrollbar and VCR buttons.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn17.jpg</link></figure>
</section>

<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsRecordNavigator.swf</link>
			
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Embedded Xdialog Supercontrol</title>
<description>Using the Embedded Xdialog supercontrol, it is now possible to put Xdialogs on Forms. You can define as many 'windows' as you want on your Form, and each of these windows can host an Xdialog.
The ability to include Xdialogs in Forms provides developers with an extremely powerful tool for creating highly customized Forms. This feature is aimed at  users who are comfortable creating Xdialogs and who want to achieve some effect in a Form that is more easily done using Xdialog than native Form controls.
Alpha Anywhere supports two kinds of embedded Xdialogs - unbound and bound.
In an unbound Xdialog the variables shown in the Xdialog are not bound to any of the fields or variables in the Form. However, in a bound Xdialog, the variables in the Xdialog can be bound to Form fields and variables. This means, for example, that if you have a variable on the Xdialog called (say) 'fn' and a field on the Form called (say) 'firstname', and you bind 'fn' to 'firstname' then if you edit the value in the 'fn' variable on the Xdialog, the value of the 'firstname' field is automatically changed, and vice versa.
See the section above, 'Inserting a Supercontrol on a Form' for information on how to place an Embedded Xdialog supercontrol on a Form.
The Xbasic code that renders the Xdialog can either be stored in the Form layout itself, or it can be a Global Script (i.e. visible on the Code tab of the Control  Panel).
</description>	
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Rules for Embedded Xdialogs
</title>
		<description>Xdialogs that are embedded in forms must obey these rules:
</description>	
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>The Xdialog must be modeless (i.e. it must use the ui_modeless_dlg() function)
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>It must use a specific title - a variable called 'dlgTitle'. Your Xbasic script must not initialize this variable. Its value will be automatically set by Alpha Anywhere when the script is run to populate the Xdialog window.
</description>
				</case>
				
				
			</cases>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>When you place an Embedded Xdialog supercontrol on a Form the following dialog is shown where you can define the Xdialog:
The builder for the Embedded Xdialog supercontrol. </description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn18.jpg</link></figure>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>The 'Storage' combobox allows you to select 'Local' or 'External'. If you select the 'Local' option, the Xbasic code that you define to display the Xdialog will be stored in the Form definition. If you select the 'External' option, then you can specify the name of a global script that displays the Xdialog. This global script must follow the rules shown above for embedded Xdialogs. If you select a global script that does not follow the rules, Alpha Anywhere will display a warning. 
The Embedded Xdialog supercontrol properties dialog - showing a warning because an invalid script has been selected.</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn19.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>The following example shows an Xdialog that displays some fields from the Form's underlying table:
Form with an embedded Xialog supercontrol.</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn2.jpg</link></figure>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Here is how the Xdialog is defined:
</description>
			<example><![CDATA[dim fn as c 
dim ln as c 
dim address1 as c 
dim address2 as c 
dim city as c 
dim state as c 
dim zip as c 

ui_modeless_dlg_box(dlgTitle,<
]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<videos>
				<video>
					<name>Click here to watch a video of this form in action.</name>
					<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsReportPreviewDemo.swf</link>
				</video>
				
				
			</videos>
			
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>When you place a Report Preview supercontrol on a Form, the following dialog is shown:
Report Preview supercontrol Propeties Dialog</description>
			<figure><link>images/WorkIn6.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<description>The dialog allows you to select the Report, Label or Letter that is shown in the Report Preview supercontrol and also allows you to specify how the report is linked to the the current record in the Form.
You can either enter a custom link expression, or you can use the genie to help you define the link between the data in the current record and the report.
The genie makes it very easy to define the link. You simply specify how fields from the table that the report is based on are matched to fields in the table that the Form is based on.
If you choose 'Custom filter expression' you can enter an arbitrary filter expression. Note that the filter expression is a string that contains an expression that will be evaluated at runtime. Click the 'See examples' hyperlink for examples of how to specify the filter expression.
If you choose the 'Custom filter expression' option, you can define a filter expression that include arguments. For example:
</description>
			<example><![CDATA["customer_id = :whatCustomerId"
]]></example>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>You can use the Arguments tab on the above dialog to define how the 'whatCustomerId' argument will get its value. Typically, you will define an expression whose result is used to define the value of the argument at runtime. For example, you might define the following expession for the 'whatCustomerId' argument:
</description>
			<example><![CDATA[customer_id
]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>At runtime, the argument value is set to the value in the 'customer_id' field for the current record.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Toolbar Buttons
</title>
			<description>If the report that is shown in the Report Preview supercontrol is a multi-page report, you will want to include toolbar buttons for navigation. The 'Toolbar' tab in the properties dialog allows you to specify which of the standard Preview window toolbar buttons should be shown in the control. 
</description>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<videos>
				<video>
					<name>Click here to see a video demonstration of this feature
</name>
					<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsReportPreviewHowToPlace.swf</link>
				</video>
				
			</videos>
			
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Clock Supercontrol</title>
<description>The clock supercontrol displays an image of an analog clock on on the Form. The control can be bound to a time or shorttime field or variable from the Form. The hands on the clock will show the time of the field or variable to which it is bound. You can change the time by dragging on the hands of the clock, or typing in to the textbox shown below the clock. Form with a two Clock supercontrols bound to the 'starttime' and 'endtime' fields
</description>	
<figure><link>images/WorkIn9.jpg</link></figure>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>When you place a Clock supercontrol on a Form the following Properties dialog is shown:
Clock supercontrol Properties Dialog:</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn10.jpg</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>The 'Bind To' prompt lets you specify what field or variable in the form the clock should be bound to. The 'Appearance' prompt allows you to several different visual styles. The 'Show Numeric Input' checkbox controls whether the clock also has a textbox where you can enter the time rather than having to drag on the clock handles.
The properties dialog also gives you a lot of control over the colors of the various aspects of the clock.
</description>
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Clock Events</title>
<description>You can define event handlers for the following events on the clock:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>onInitialize</title>
			<description>Fires when the clock is instantiated.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>onTimeSelect</title>
			<description>Fires when the user changes the value shown by the clock.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>onMeridianChange</title>
			<description>Fires when the user changes from AM to PM or vise versa.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>
<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Click here to see a video demonstration of this feature.
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsClock.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<title>Calendar Supercontrol
</title>
	<description>The Calendar supercontrol displays an image of a calendar on the Form. The control can be bound to a date or time field or variable from the form. You can change the date in the bound field or variable by clicking on a date value in the calendar.
Form showing Date controls bound to Calendar supercontrols.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn12.jpg</link></figure>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>When you place a Calendar supercontrol on a form the Properties dialog box shown below is opened. Calendar Supercontrol Properties Dialog Box.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn13.jpg</link></figure>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<description>The 'Use Dropdowns' prompt controls whether drop down lists are used to select the Month and Year, or an alternative user interface is used. This alternative user interface is illustrated in the sequence of screens shown below:
Screen 1. User clicks on the Title Bar (showing April, 2008) to 
change either the month or year.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn14.jpg</link></figure>
	
	
</section>


<section>
	<description>Screen 2. The Calendar supercontrol now shows a list of Months. 
If the user clicks on the title bar a second time, a list of months is shown.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn20.jpg</link></figure>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<description>Screen 2. The Calendar supercontrol now shows a list of Years. 
If the user clicks on the title bar a third time, a list of years is shown.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn21.jpg</link></figure>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Date Ranges</title>
	<description>You can specify a range of valid dates that can be selected on the calendar. To turn on this feature, check the 'Use Range' checkbox.
</description>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Disabled Dates
</title>
	<description>You can specify a list of disabled dates and days. The user will not be able to select these dates on the calendar. 
</description>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Flagged Dates
</title>
	<description>You can specify a list of dates that should be flagged on the calendar. If a date on the calendar is flagged, it is shown with a special box around it. In the image shown below, November 28, 2007 has been flagged. The list of dates that should be flagged can by dynamically controlled by code in the Calendar control's event handlers. Calendar showing a flagged date.
</description>
<figure><link>images/WorkIn22.jpg</link></figure>
</section>


<section>
	<title>Events</title>
	<description>The 'Events' tab on the Properties dialog allows you to define handlers for the following events:
</description>
<list>
	<item>
		<name>Event</name>
		<description>Description</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>onInitialize</name>
		<description>Fires when the calendar is initialized.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>onDateSelect</name>
		<description>Fires when the user selects a date.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>onRightClick</name>
		<description>Fires when the user right-clicks on the calendar.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>onYearNavigate</name>
		<description>Fires when the user changes the year.</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>onMonthNavigate</name>
		<description>Fires when the user changes the month.</description>
	</item>
	
	
</list>
</section>
<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsCalendar.swf</link>
		</video>
		
	</videos>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>PDF Viewer Supercontrol</title>
<description>The PDF Viewer supercontrol allows you to place a window on a Form that will display the contents of a PDF file. The name of the PDF file to display can either be explicitly supplied, or it can be the result of an expression. 
When you place the PDF Viewer supercontrol on a form, the Properties dialog is displayed. PDF Viewer supercontrol Properties Dialog
</description>	
<figure><link>images/WorkIn23.jpg</link></figure>	
	
	
</section>

<section>
	
	<description>To enter an explicit filename, click the 'Select PDF File' hyperlink. 
To enter an expression that evaluates to a filename, click the XY icon.
You can preview the result by clicking on the Preview button.
</description>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.
</name>
			<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsPDFViewer.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<title>Web Content Supercontrol</title>
<description>The Web Content supercontrol allows you to display a web page in a window on your Form. The URL for the web page you display can either be static (e.g. "www.yahoo.com"), or it can be dynamically computed from fields in the current record (e.g. "www.myintranet.com/customerSummary.asp?customerId=" + cust_id ).
The Web Content supercontrol comes preconfigured with the following templates:
</description>	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Google Image Search
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Google Maps
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Google Search
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>MSN Maps
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Yahoo Maps
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
	
<description>You can also select the generic 'User Defined URL Expression' to specify an arbitrary URL expression that can either be static or dynamically computed from data in the current record.
When you choose one of the pre-defined templates, the properties dialog prompts you for matches between fields in the current record and fields in the template.
For example, in the screen below, the 'Google Maps' template has been selected. This template needs values for the following fields:
</description>	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Address 1
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Address 2
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>City
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>State
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Zip
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Country
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<description>You must specify which fields in the current record map to these template fields. Web Content supercontrol Properties Dialog.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn25.jpg</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>In addition to the pre-defined templates, you can also create your own templates. To create a new template, click the 'User defined templates' hyperlink at the bottom left corner of the dialog. The 'New Template' dialog opened as shown below. If the template is dynamic, use fieldnames or expressions enclosed in curly parentheses for the dynamic portions of the URL. Defining a new template for the 'Web Content' supercontrol.
</description>
<figure><link>images/WorkIn24.jpg</link></figure>
</section>

<section>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch a video demonstration of this feature.
</name>
<link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/VideoNewV9/SuperControlsGoogleMaps.swf</link>	
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	
</section>

<section>
	
	<title>HTML Content Supercontrol</title>
<description>The HTML Content supercontrol allows you to put static HTML content in a window on a form. The static content is specified by an expression that evaluates to the HTML text that you want to display. 
When you place the HTML Content supercontrol on a form, the expression builder is displayed where you can enter any expression that evaluates to some HTML text.
</description>	
<figure><link>images/WorkIn26.jpg</link></figure>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>HTML Content supercontrol showing some HTML text on the form.</description>
	<figure><link>images/WorkIn27.jpg</link></figure>
</section>

<section>
	<description>Sample expressions that can be used for the HTML Content supercontrol:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Notes</title>
			<description>Assume that 'Notes' is a memo field that contains HTML text. This will display the the HTML in the 'Notes' field in the window. </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>file.to_string("c:\myHTMLfiles\file1.html")</title>
			<description>This will display the contents in the file 'c:\myHTMLfiles\file1.html' in the window.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>"Hello world"</title>
			<description>This will display the string 'Hello world' in the window.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>"Hello world
Have a good day
"
</title>
			<description>This will display a string with the first line in bold and the next line in a normal font.</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>

</sections>	
	
	
	
	
</page>