<page>
	<topic>Using Hidden Form Controls</topic>
	<description>Web publishing applications only. A hidden form on a field is a way to submit data from the current page to the form's target without displaying that data to the application user. 
For example, take the following form that could be for a user to request more information from your website. This form would be part of page1.a5w. 
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<example><![CDATA[<form target="page2.a5w"> 
First name: <input type="text" name="fname"><br /> 
Last name: <input type="text" name="lname"><br /> 
Email address: <input type="text" name="email"><br /> 
Your question: <textarea name="question" rows="5" cols="50"></textarea><br /> 
<input type="submit"> 
</form>
]]></example>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Hidden_variable_1.png</link></figure>
</section>	

<section>
	<description><![CDATA[This will collect the basic information from a site visitor and presumably page2.a5w will put it in a database where a customer service representative can respond to the question. But let us say you would like to know how these inquisitive visitors are finding your web site. You can simply ask them by adding the following HTML within the <form>...</form>.  ]]></description>
	<example><![CDATA[<form target="page2.a5w"> 
...
How did you find us: <input type="radio" name="howfind" value="Google">Google <input type="radio" name="howhear" value="Yahoo">Yahoo <input type="radio" name="howhear" value="other">other<br />
<input type="submit"> 
</form>
]]></example>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Hidden_variable_2.png</link></figure>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>Now the user is presented with check boxes to explain how they found you. But this could be made easier for the user by not asking them. Request.Referer (yes, it really is referer, not referrer). It is defined by the HTTP specification and has remained unchanged for historical compatibility) will contain the URL of the page from which the user came. So instead of a radio button asking the user where they came from, you can find out on our own. 

The problem is that page2.a5w which is doing the recording is preceded by page1.a5w and that's not what you want to record. So you need to look at Request.Referer on page1.a5w and pass it along to page2.a5w. 
One way to do this is with:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[ How did you find us: <input type="text" name="howfind" value=" <%a5 ? Request.Referer %> "><br />
]]></example>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>But now the user sees the question posed to them and has an opportunity to change the answer. What you really want to do is hide this data from the user since they do not need to be concerned with supplying it and we do not want to give them an opportunity to modify it. This can be accomplished by changing the above to be a hidden field: </description>
	<note>Don't try running this in the WYSIWYG mode, run it in the code editor.</note>
</section>



<section>
	
	<example><![CDATA[<html>
<head>
<meta name="generator" content="Alpha Five HTML Editor">
</head>
<body>
<form target="page2.a5w">
First name: <input name="fname" ><br >
Last name: <input name="lname" ><br >
Email address: <input name="email" ><br >
Your question: <textarea name=question rows=5 cols=50></textarea><br >
<input type="hidden" name="howfind" value=" <%a5
if eval_valid("Request.referer") then
? Request.Referer
end if %> ">
<input type="submit" value="Submit Query">
</form>
</body></html>
]]></example>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Hidden_variable_3.gif</link></figure>
</section>	
	<section>
		<description>One thing to keep in mind with this example is that Request.Referer will not always exist. If a user types in a URL directly or starts from their bookmarks, there is no previous page so there is no Request.Referer. Currently this means you need to do an eval_valid() on Request.Referer before you can use it.</description>
	</section>
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>A5W Page HTML FORM Syntax</ref>
</see>
	
</page>