<page>
    <shortlink>gridsearch properties save and load searches properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Save and Load Searches Properties</topic>
    <description>Add the ability to save and load search criteria in the Grid Component by enabling Saved Searches.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Search criteria can be saved and loaded using a repository stored in a SQL or DBF database. The repository settings are configured in the Web Project Properties. Settings specific to the Grid's Search Part are available in the *[ui:Save and Load Searches Properties]*.</p>
        <p>Available properties are listed below.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Allow user to save search criteria</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the user can save search criteria in the Search Part form. The search criteria are saved in the Repository. To configure the Repository, go to Project Properties on the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Allow user to load search criteria</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the user can load previously saved search criteria into the Search Part form. The search criteria are loaded from the Repository. To configure the Repository, go to Project Properties on the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Load search prompt</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the prompt to display on the dialog where the user is prompted for the name of the saved search to load.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Save search prompt</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the prompt to display on the dialog where the user is prompted for the name to give the search criteria when they are saved to the Repository.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Load search button bubble-help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify message shown when the user clicks or mouses-over the button bubble-help for the load search button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Execute search on load</title>
            <description>
                <p>When loading a saved search, should it be immediately executed?</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Save search button bubble-help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify message shown when the user clicks or mouses-over the button bubble-help for the save search button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Listbox heading</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the text to show above the listbox where the existing saved searches are shown.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Listbox height</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the height of the listbox that shows the existing saved searches. Use CSS syntax. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[1in]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[100px]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[3em]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Dialog width</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the approximate width of the dialog. Use CSS syntax. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[2in]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[300px]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Auto-load choices</title>
            <description>
                <p>When the user opens the dialog to load/save a search, should the list of existing saved searches be populated, or should this be deferred until the user explicitly requests that the list be populated.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Prompt to load text</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the text for the prompt to populate the listbox showing existing saved searches.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Load search button</title>
            <description>
                <p>Load search button property</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Save search button</title>
            <description>
                <p>Save search button property</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Cancel button</title>
            <description>
                <p>Cancel button property</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Warning message - blank name</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the warning message to show if the user tries to save search criteria without specifying the name to assign to the save criteria.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Warning message - duplicate name</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the error message to show if the user tries to save search criteria using a duplicate name.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>