<page>
    <shortlink>gridsearch properties search options properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Search Options Properties</topic>
    <description>Search Options Properties</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Show title</title>
            <description>
                <p>Show a title above the Search part?</p>
            </description>
            <note>To enable the 'Show/Hide of Search part' prompt, you MUST display the search title.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Title</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the title to be shown above the Search part.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Title when hidden</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the title to show when the Search part is hidden.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Enable show/hide of Search part</title>
            <description>
                <p>Can the user click on the Search part's title to hide/show the Search part?</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Show/hide button icon</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the icon for the show/hide button. This button appears in the title bar above the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Show/hide button bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the bubble help for the icon for the show/hide button. This button appears in the title bar above the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Animation</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the Search Part should be animated when it is shown or hidden. You can choose different effects.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Initial state</title>
            <description>
                <p>Initial state of the Search part when the page is displayed.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search button label</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the label for the 'Search' button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Use icon for search button</title>
            <description>
                <p>Should an icon be used for the search button? To customize the icon, go to Grid, Properties, Customization, Customize icons.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Orientation</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the Search fields are laid out vertically or horizontally.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Has 'Clear Search' link</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the Search part has a link to clear the search criteria and show all records.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>'Clear Search' label</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the text to show on the 'Clear Search' link.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>'Clear Search' bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the text to show on the 'Clear Search' link or button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Use icon for clear search link</title>
            <description>
                <p>Should an icon be used for the clear search link? To customize the icon, go to Grid, Properties, Customization, Customize icons.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search style</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Search style]* defines the default search behavior for the search fields. The search style can be overwritten for individual fields using the field's *[ui:Display Settings]* &gt; *[ui:Search style]* property.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Search Style</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>1</name>
                    <description>Performs an 'Exact Match' search. A field only matches if it exactly matches the search criteria. Exact Match may or may not perform a case insensitive search -- case-sensitive matching is database specific.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>2</name>
                    <description>Performs an 'Is Contained In' search. Search criteria matches if it is contained in the field.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>3</name>
                    <description>Performs a 'Starts with' search. Search criteria matches if the field starts with the search criteria.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>4</name>
                    <description>Performs a 'Wildcard' search. The user can enter wildcard characters in their search terms. Wildcard characters include '*', '%' or '?'. If QBE syntax is turned on you can enter multiple wildcard criteria, delimited with either a comma or &amp;&amp; - use &amp;&amp; to combine criteria with an AND clause.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>11</name>
                    <description>Performs a case-insensitive 'Exact Match'.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>12</name>
                    <description>Performs a case-insensitive 'Is Contained In' search.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>13</name>
                    <description>Performs a case-insensitive 'Starts with' search.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>14</name>
                    <description>Performs a case-insensitive 'Wildcard' search.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search rules</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify rules when Grid supports multiple types of searches (e.g. Quick search, Alphabet button, Search Part, and Query by Example searches).</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Show single 'Keyword' search field</title>
            <description>
                <p>Instead of showing individual search fields, show a single search field. If a match is found in any of the search fields, the record is returned.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Allow 'Query By Form' syntax</title>
            <description>
                <p>Support Alpha Anywhere's QBF syntax. For example, the following will search for "CA" and "MA":</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[CA,MA]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Range searches can be performed using QBF syntax. For example, to search for all values between 123 and 345:</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[123..345]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This same syntax can be used with dates. This example will search for dates &lt;=12/03/2014:
                </p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[..12/3/2014]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>QBF Operator Exceptions</title>
            <description>
                <p>The 'Query By Form' operators are: .. (two dots), , (comma), &gt;, &gt;=, &lt;, &lt;= and =. You can specify that you want to treat some of these operators as literal strings. Enter a pipe delimited list of exclusions. For example, if you enter</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[..|=]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>this indicates that the .. (two dots) operator and the = sign should be treated as literal strings, not search operators.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Combine search criteria using</title>
            <description>
                <p>If user enters search criteria into multiple fields, combine using 'AND', or 'OR'. Select 1 for 'AND', or 2 for 'OR'.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Keyword search field label</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the label for the keyword search field.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Disable browser auto-complete feature</title>
            <description>
                <p>In most browsers, when you type into a search field, the browser will try to auto-complete your entry. You can disable this behavior in the browser.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Toolbar position</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Search Toolbar contains the 'Search' and 'Clear Search' buttons. Specify if the toolbar should be shown above or below the search fields. The toolbar position can be set to one of the following:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Toolbar Position</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Above</name>
                    <description>Toolbar is shown above the search fields.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Below</name>
                    <description>Toolbar is shown below the search fields.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>None</name>
                    <description>The toolbar is not shown.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If you select 'None', the toolbar is not shown. The 'None' choice is only appropriate if you are using cascading DropdownBoxes and you have set the last DropdownBox to 'Auto-Submit' the search, or you have designed a free-form search with your own custom button to submit the search. Your custom button must have this Javascript in its 'onClick' event:</p>
            </description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[{grid.object}.submitSearchForm(); return false;]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Help window</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if an icon should be shown in the Toolbar to open a window that displays help for this component.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Help ID</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the ID of the help text to display in the window.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Help button icon</title>
            <description>
                <p>The icon shown for the Help button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Help button bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the bubble help for the help button icon.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search highlighting</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify whether, when the user does a Search, Quick Search, or QBE Search, if the search strings should be highlighted in fields in the Grid in which they were found.</p>
            </description>
            <note>Search highlighting only applies to Label controls.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Embed search in Grid part</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the search part should be embedded in the Grid part.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Position in Grid</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify where in the Grid the Search part should be embedded. The Search part can be embedded either Above or Below the Grid component titles.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Above titles</name>
                    <description>Search part is shown above titles.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Below titles</name>
                    <description>Search part is shown below titles.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Has free-form layout</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the embedded Search Part uses a free-form layout. If you check this you can define a single free-form region, or a free-form region above each column. If you do not check this, the standard Search Part that you have defined is embedded in the Grid (with these exceptions: the 'sort by' and 'records per page' listboxes that optionally appear in the Search Part are turned off.)</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Free-form search style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if there is a free-form region above each column in the Grid for search fields, or a single free-form region with a colspan that spans all of the Grid columns.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Free-form region for each column</name>
                    <description>A free-form region is defined for each column.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Single free-form region</name>
                    <description>A single free-form region spanning all Grid columns is defined.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Free-form search template</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the free-form search template.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Display search/clear icons in row selector</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if 'Search' and 'Clear Search' icons should be shown in the row selector column. If you do not include these buttons here then you will need to include them in at least one of the free-form search areas above each column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search button icon</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the icon for the search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search button bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify bubble help for the icon for the search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Clear search button icon</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the icon for the clear search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Clear search button bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the bubble help for the icon for the clear search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>