<page>
    <topic>Group name</topic>
    <description>When you define an editor inside an editor set, and you click on a given field in the Form View, 
        you then have the option of editing that individual field inside the editor. 
        If you wanted to click on a single field in the Form View, like an ADDRESS field, 
        and then edit multiple fields in one go, you would need a 'group' of editors. Click on a given field in the group and 
        you will be able to edit all of the fields in that group.
    </description>
<sections>
    <section>
        <figure><title>The Group name property</title><link>images/group.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <figure><title>Assigning a defined group</title><link>images/group3.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>For a video explanation on how to use groups watch these three videos: [Part 1], [Part 2], [Part 3].</description>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Defining Groups</title>
        <description>Clicking the [...] button next to the Group name property loads a list of defined 'groups' created from existing fields 
            inside the form view. In order to define a new group click the 'Create/manage/edit Groups' button at the bottom-center of the Form View Builder's 
            Fields pane.
        </description>
        <figure><title>The 'Create/manage/edit Groups' button</title><link>images/group2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description><![CDATA[This will open the Define Groups dialog along with a list of Group Properties. Here you can add a new group by clicking the 'Add Group' button.
            The 'Manage Fields in Group' button opens a dialog that lets you assign fields to a group from a list of available fields. Use the right > arrow 
            to add fields to a group and the left < arrow to remove them.]]>
        </description>
        <cases>
            <case>
                <figure><title>Adding a group</title><link>images/group4.png</link></figure>
                
            </case>
               <case>
                <figure><title>Defining the Fields in a group.</title><link>images/group5.png</link></figure>
                
            </case>
           
            
        </cases>
        <note>If you are defining a group editor it will probably be necessary to make a few changes to 
            the 'Set value in editor' property. This is found in the Editor's properties list, not in the form view. Watch the videos or follow 
            the guide below on Implementing groups for more details.</note>
    </section>
    
</sections>

<links>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_formview_groups_1.swf">Part 1</link>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_formview_groups_2.swf">Part 2</link>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_formview_groups_3.swf">Part 3</link>
    <link href="images/open.png">...</link>
</links>

</page>