<page>
	<topic>Freeform Edit Regions</topic>
	<description>Freeform Edit Regions give you the ability to place arbitrary HTML above, below, to the left, or to the right of your grid.
</description>
	<!--list:.-->
	<!--order:
Above Grid.xml
belowgrid.xml
leftofgrid.xml
rightofgrid.xml
-->
	<discussion>
		<p>Custom HTML can be inserted above, below, left, or right of the Grid component. To do this, click the button [...] for the region to open the Freeform Edit Region editor. The editor is an HTML editor that provides both WYSIWYG and code mode.</p>
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>The editor contains a number of features that help make it easy to add and edit HTML, including a set of common word processing tools. The editing toolbar includes buttons to change the font type, size, and color; creating underlined, bold, or italic text; add images, tables, and hyperlinks; right, center, and left justify text; spell-checking, copy and paste tools, and more.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<figure>
						<title>HTML Editor toolset</title>
						<link>images/1_freeform3.png</link>
					</figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<figure>
						<title>HTML in Freeform Edit Region dialog</title>
						<link>images/1_freeform.png</link>
					</figure>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/1_alphabet20.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Freeform Edit Regions</title>
			<discussion>
				<p>The Grid component has four freeform edit regions. The location of these regions and their corresponding Xbasic property, which can be referenced in override properties for a Grid component, are listed below.</p>
			</discussion>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title nested="2">Above grid</title>
					<description>Defines HTML that appears above the grid.</description>
					<example>
						<![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Top as C ]]>
					</example>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title nested="2">Below grid</title>
					<description>Defines HTML that appears below the grid.</description>
					<example>
						<![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Bottom as C ]]>
					</example>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title nested="2">Left of grid</title>
					<description>Defines HTML that appears to the left of the grid.</description>
					<example>
						<![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Left as C ]]>
					</example>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title nested="2">Right of grid</title>
					<description>Defines HTML that appears to the right of the grid.</description>
					<example>
						<![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Right as C ]]>
					</example>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<links>
		<link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
	</links>
	<see>
		<ref link="grid fieldrowprops freeformtemplalte">Freeform template Property</ref>
	</see>
</page>