<page>
 <topic>Push Notifications : Pushwoosh Component Template</topic>
	<description>
		This component template demonstrates the use of the PhoneGap Pushwoosh plugin which enables sending and receiving push notifications powered by Pushwoosh.
	</description>

	<discussion>
		The component requires the user to login using the Alpha Security Framework and upon successful login, a private push notification is sent to an administrative app user. A map is then displayed, allowing the user to login to a specific location. A typical use case might be a service technician checking in to a job site. When the user checks in, the device's lat/lon is reverse geocoded (using Google's geocoding API) and the location address is sent via a push notification to an administrative user.
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pn_app_screens.jpg</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Pushwoosh Account Sign-up</title>
			<description>
				<p>Visit the Pushwoosh website at *[extlink:http://www.pushwoosh.com]* to setup a trial account. The trial account is valid for 14 days and gives you full access to all of the services offered by Pushwoosh.</p>
			</description>
			<figure><link>images/pw_website.jpg</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Android Configuration</title>
			<description>
				<p>Your Android application must be configured to use the Google Cloud Messaging (GCM) service.</p>
				<p>You will use the Google Cloud Platform Console to setup a project and to enable the GCM service for your app.
				</p>
				<p>See *[extlink:http://docs.pushwoosh.com/docs/gcm-configuration]* </p>
			</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>
				*[Make sure to set the framework to PhoneGap Build.]*
			</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_config_android.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>iOS Configuration</title>
			<description>
				<p>Your iOS application must be configured to connect to the Apple Push Notification Service.</p>
				
				<p>You will need to generate an APNS certificate that ties the application id to the push notification certificate that is uploaded to the Pushwoosh server.
				</p>
				<p>See *[extlink:http://docs.pushwoosh.com/docs/apns-configuration]* </p>
			</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_config_ios.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Managing Pushwoosh Applications</title>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_applications.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>
				To add your application and enable push notifications for your apps, click on the Applications link in the Pushwoosh control panel.
			</description>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_config_platforms.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_geozones.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_define_tags.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_defining_filters.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_filters.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_push_using_filters.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/pw_api_access.png</link></figure>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
</page>