<page build="7704">
    <shortlink>critical changes alpha anywhere 4_6_3_0</shortlink>
    <topic>Deprecated and Obsolete Features introduced in Alpha Anywhere 4.6.3.0</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Alpha Anywhere 4.6.3.0 deprecated manipulating argument values on the client, as well as the Xbasic saveAs() method for Forms and Browses.</p>
    </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Argument Client-side Manipulation Removed</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[js:{dialog.object}.setArgumentValue()]* has been deprecated in Alpha Anywhere 4.6.3.0. This method previously allowed you to change the value in an argument using client-side code. With the release of Alpha Anywhere 4.6.3.0, an argument's value can only be changed with sever-side code (Xbasic).</p>
                <p>This change was made to close a security vulnerability. Argument values are still stored in the {dialog.object}.stateInfo object, but the values are encrypted.</p>
                <p>To change a value in an argument using server-side code, you must make an Ajax Callback. In the Xbasic function that handles the callback, you can add this code to set the argument value:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[e.arguments.set("argument_name","argument_value")]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>where *[em:argument_name]* is the name of the argument to update and *[em:argument_value]* is the value to store in the argument. For example:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[function setCustomerArgument as c (e as p)

    ' Set the "Customer" argument to the value in the customer
    ' control on the UX:
    dim currentCustomer as C = e.dataSubmitted.customer
    e.arguments.set("Customer", currentCustomer)

    return ""

end function]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>saveAs() Method Deprecated for Forms and Browses</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[xb:&lt;form&gt;.saveAs()]* and *[xb:&lt;browse&gt;.saveAs()]* methods are deprecated. If you want to print a browse or form layout, you must create a report and then import the form or browse as as new report. You can then use [report.saveAs()] method to print the report.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="api%20objects%20report%20object%20save%20as%20function">report.saveAs()</link>
    </links>
</page>