<page>
    <shortlink>UX Property Local CSS definitions</shortlink>
    <topic>Local CSS definitions</topic>
    <description>Define any local CSS classes. NOTE, you can include SASS syntax in your CSS 
        definition. For more information on SASS syntax see [http://sass-lang.com/]
    </description>
    
<sections>
    
    <section>
        <description>There are two types of CSS classes used extensively in Alpha Anywhere and with UX components. 
            These are abstract CSS classes and physical CSS classes. Abstract classes are essentially placeholders. 
            When you build a component, the different html elements that are used to display the component each receive 
            an abstract CSS definition. These abstract CSS classes are extremely raw looking and can be viewed by 
            setting the [Resolve abstract CSS class names] property to be unchecked. </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Abstract CSS classes are not seen in most components because their values, unless otherwise 
            specified, are assigned to a physical CSS classes. When you assign a style to a component,
             using the [Style name] property, Alpha Anywhere automatically maps the physical CSS classes 
             conforming to that style on to each of the available abstract classes. While the physical CSS classes 
             may look considerably better than the abstract CSS classes you easily make minor adjustments to them.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>The 'Local CSS definitions' property allows you to define new physical CSS classes for controls 
            in your component. Once a physical CSS class exists it can be assigned to an abstract class 
            using the [Class map] property. This will override the default physical CSS class definition that 
            Alpha Anywhere generates.</description>
    </section>
    
</sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux properties class map">Class map</ref>
        <ref link="UX Properties Resolve abstract CSS class names">Style name</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="http://sass-lang.com/">http://sass-lang.com/</link>
        <link link="ux properties class map">Class map</link>
        <link link="UX Properties Resolve abstract CSS class names">Resolve abstract CSS class names</link>
    </links>
</page>