<page>
    <shortlink>UX Property Local CSS definitions</shortlink>
    <topic>Local CSS definitions</topic>
    <description>Define any local CSS classes. NOTE, you can include SASS syntax in your CSS 
        definition. For more information on SASS syntax see [http://sass-lang.com/]
    </description>
    
<sections>
    
    <section>
        <description>There are two types of CSS classes used extensively in Alpha Anywhere and with UX components. 
            These are abstract CSS classes and physical CSS classes. Abstract classes are essentially placeholders. 
            When you build a component, the different html elements that are used to display the component each receive 
            an abstract CSS definition. These abstract CSS classes are extremely raw looking and can be viewed by 
            setting the [Resolve abstract CSS class names] property to be unchecked. </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Abstract CSS classes are not seen in most components because their values, unless otherwise 
            specified, are assigned to physical CSS classes. When you assign a style to a component,
             using the [Style name] property, Alpha Anywhere automatically maps the physical CSS classes 
             conforming to that style on to each of the available abstract classes. If you want 
             to change any of these physical CSS classes, it is easy to create a new class and then assign a 
             given abstract class to your newly defined physical CSS class, overriding the Alpha Anywhere default 
             altogether.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>The 'Local CSS definitions' property allows you to define new physical CSS classes for controls 
            in your component. These physical CSS classes can be assigned to an abstract class 
            using the [Class map] property. This will override the default physical CSS class definition that 
            Alpha Anywhere generates. Alternatively you can create the CSS class name first, in the [Class map] property, 
            and then add a CSS definition in the 'Local CSS definitions' property.</description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>The CSS Editor</title>
        <description>Clicking on the 'Local CSS definitions' property, on the UX Properties page in the CSS/SVG section,
             will open the CSS Editor. </description>
        
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>The Code Tab</title>
        <description>You can open the 'Code' tab at the bottom of the CSS Editor. The Code tab allows you to create new CSS class definitions. Once a new class is defined you can 
            modify the CSS directly in the Code tab or use a propsheet to add styling in the Design tab. CSS class 
            definitions start with a period '.' followed by the name of the CSS class and then a pair of curly braces 
            '{}' that contain the class definition. 
        </description>
        
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
        <title>The Design Tab</title>
        
        <description>Once you define a CSS class in the CSS Editor's 'Code' tab,
             you can then add styling information to the class definition. The 'Design' tab lets 
             you modify CSS classes using the same style editing property sheet that is used in other parts of the UX Builder 
            and in Alpha Anywhere. To edit a class simply highlight it in the CSS class list on the right side 
            of the tab and then make changes to that classes properties.
        </description>
        
        
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        
        
        
    </section>
    
    
    
</sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux properties class map">Class map</ref>
        <ref link="UX Properties Resolve abstract CSS class names">Style name</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="http://sass-lang.com/">http://sass-lang.com/</link>
        <link link="ux properties class map">Class map</link>
        <link link="UX Properties Resolve abstract CSS class names">Resolve abstract CSS class names</link>
    </links>
</page>