<page>
	<topic>Query Operations</topic>
	<description>This page provides an overview of query operations and looks at how to perform them.</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Overview of Query Operations
</title>
<description>The Query operation saves filter and order expressions for a table or set. The query that you create here can be seen on the Operations tab of the Control Panel and on the Saved Queries tab of the Primary Index or Query dialog box.</description>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Performing a Query Operation
</title>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Display the Operations tab of the Control Panel.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click New.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select "Query Records" from the Select operation list.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the target table or set from the Select Table/Set list.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>For those who know how to write Xbasic expressions, click Create to display the Query Builder dialog.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>For those who know how to write Xbasic expressions, click Create to display the Query Builder dialog.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>For those who would like to create the query interactively, click Create Using Genie to display the Query Genie.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>To run the finished query immediately click the 'lightning' icon to Run.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>To run the finished query against a specific layout based on the selected table or set, click  Run Special.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Select the Layout Type.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select the Layout Name and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>To save the operation click the save and enter the name of the operation into the Save Query dialog and click OK.
</description>
<note>The next step is a one-way operation from Query Genie to Query Builder.</note>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you created the query with the Query Genie, you may convert your inputs to filter and order expressions by clicking  Convert. The results will appear in the Query Builder.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Overview of Batch Operations</ref>
		<ref>Query Genie</ref>
		<ref>Query Builder</ref>
		<ref>Query by Form</ref>
		<ref>Query by Expression</ref>
		<ref>Quickly Sorting/Filtering Records</ref>
		<ref>Table Operation Methods</ref>
		<ref>Query Functions and Methods</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>