<page>
    <topic>Foreign character support </topic>
   <description>In July, I told you about one of the new features of Alpha Five Version 10, its foreign language support for labels and instructions in web apps built by Version 10. Well, we've one upped ourselves by adding international character support for the DATA (UTF8 is the technical term.)
</description> 

<sections>
    <section>
        <description>Web apps can be designed to support virtually any language, using that language's characters. Here's an example of an Alpha Five Version 10 app using Chinese characters.
       </description>
        <videos>
            <video>
                <description>Video | </description>
                <link>http://www.screencast.com/users/AlphaSoftware/folders/Jing/media/a7eac757-c824-4f8c-ac00-215b55b1dd8f</link>
            </video>
        </videos>
    </section>     
        <section>
        <description>What does it mean   It means that if you are building Codeless AJAX (TM) Web applications against SQL databases in Alpha Five v10 - you will be able to serve people worldwide with the data in their native tongue. Besides Chinese - what are examples of languages that are supported  
</description>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <cases>
            <case>
                <description>
   Tibetan:                                                     </description></case><case><description>
Chinese:                         </description></case><case><description>
Chinese (Traditional):                         </description></case><case><description>
Taiwanese: G a e-t ng chia  h po-l , ma be tio  h-siong.</description></case><case><description>
Japanese:                                                   </description></case><case><description>
Korean:                           .                     </description></case><case><description>
Vietnamese (qu  c ng  ): T i c  th   an th  y tinh m  kh ng h  i g .</description></case><case><description>
Vietnamese (n m) :   </description></case><case><description>
Khmer:                                                                      </description></case><case><description>
Turkish: Cam yiyebilirim, bana zarari dokunmaz.</description></case><case><description>
Turkish (Ottoman):                                                        </description></case><case><description>
Bangla / Bengali:                                  ,                                                    </description></case><case><description>
Marathi:                            ,                              .</description></case><case><description>
Hindi:                                                                                                  .</description></case><case><description>
Tamil:                                                 ,                                                         .</description></case><case><description>
Telugu:                                                                                                        </description></case><case><description>
Urdu:                                                                                       </description></case><case><description>
Pashto:                                                            </description></case><case><description>
Farsi / Persian: .                                                                     </description></case><case><description>
Arabic:                                                                       .</description></case><case><description>
Lao:                                                                                         .</description></case><case><description>
Thai:                                                                        </description></case><case><description>
Mongolian (Cyrillic):                                ,                               </description></case><case><description>
Mongolian (Classic) :                                                                              </description></case><case><description>

Classical Greek:   a         a  e     d    a a    t    t         e      pte  .</description></case><case><description>
Greek (monotonic):   p         a f     spas     a     a                    a p       t  p  ta.</description></case><case><description>
Greek (polytonic):   p            f     spas     a     a                       p       t  p  ta.</description></case><case><description>

Old French: Je puis mangier del voirre. Ne me nuit.</description></case><case><description>
French: Je peux manger du verre,  a ne me fait pas mal.</description></case><case><description>
Proven al / Occitan: P di manjar de veire, me nafrari  pas.</description></case><case><description>
Qu b cois: J'peux manger d'la vitre,  a m'fa pas mal.</description></case><case><description>
Walloon: Dji pou magn  do v re,  oula m' freut n n m .</description></case><case><description>
Picard: Ch'peux mingi du verre, cha m'fo  mie n'ma.</description></case><case><description>
Krey l Ayisyen: Mwen kap manje v , li pa blese'm.</description></case><case><description>
Basque: Kristala jan dezaket, ez dit minik ematen.</description></case><case><description>
Catalan / Catal : Puc menjar vidre, que no em fa mal.</description></case><case><description>
Spanish: Puedo comer vidrio, no me hace da o.</description></case><case><description>
Aragones: Puedo minchar beire, no me'n fa mal .</description></case><case><description>
Galician: Eu podo xantar cristais e non cortarme.</description></case><case><description>
European Portuguese: Posso comer vidro, n o me faz mal.</description></case><case><description>
Brazilian Portuguese : Posso comer vidro, n o me machuca.</description></case><case><description>
Caboverdiano/Kabuverdianu: M' pod  cum  vidru, ca ta magu -m'.</description></case><case><description>
Zeneise (Genovese): P sso mangi  o veddro e o no me f  m .</description></case><case><description>
Romansch (Grischun): Jau sai mangiar vaider, senza che quai fa donn a mai.</description></case><case><description>

Romanian: Pot sa man nc sticla   i ea nu ma rane  te.</description></case><case><description>
Esperanto: Mi povas mangi vitron, gi ne damagas min.</description></case><case><description>

Cornish: M  a yl dybry gw der hag  f ny wra ow ankenya.</description></case><case><description>
Welsh: Dw i'n gallu bwyta gwydr, 'dyw e ddim yn gwneud dolur i mi.</description></case><case><description>
Manx Gaelic: Foddym gee glonney agh cha jean eh gortaghey mee.</description></case><case><description>
Old Irish (Latin): Con iccim ithi nglano. N m g na.</description></case><case><description>
Irish: Is f idir liom gloinne a ithe. N  dh anann s  dochar ar bith dom.</description></case><case><description>
Scottish Gaelic: S urrainn dhomh gloinne ithe; cha ghoirtich i mi.</description></case><case><description>
Anglo-Saxon (Latin): Ic m g gl s eotan ond hit ne hearmia  me.</description></case><case><description>
Middle English: Ich canne glas eten and hit hirti  me nou  t.</description></case><case><description>
English (IPA): a   k n i  t gl    s  nd   t d  z n  t h    t mi   (Received Pronunciation)</description></case><case><description>
Jamaican: Mi kian niam glas han i neba hot mi.</description></case><case><description>
Lalland Scots / Doric: Ah can eat gless, it disnae hurt us.</description></case><case><description>

Old Norse (Latin): Ek get eti  gler  n  ess a  ver a s r</description></case><case><description>
Norsk / Norwegian (Nynorsk): Eg kan eta glas utan   skada meg.</description></case><case><description>
Norsk / Norwegian (Bokm l): Jeg kan spise glass uten   skade meg.</description></case><case><description>
F royskt / Faroese: Eg kann eta glas, ska aleysur.</description></case><case><description>
 slenska / Icelandic:  g get eti  gler  n  ess a  mei a mig.</description></case><case><description>
Svenska / Swedish: Jag kan  ta glas utan att skada mig.</description></case><case><description>
Dansk / Danish: Jeg kan spise glas, det g r ikke ondt p  mig.</description></case><case><description>
S nderjysk:   ka  e glass uhen at det go m  naue.</description></case><case><description>
Frysk / Frisian: Ik kin gl s ite, it docht me net sear.</description></case><case><description>
Nederlands / Dutch: Ik kan glas eten, het doet m   geen kwaad.</description></case><case><description>
Kirchr adsj/B chesserplat: Iech ken glaas   se, mer 't deet miech jing pieng</description></case><case><description>
Afrikaans: Ek kan glas eet, maar dit doen my nie skade nie.</description></case><case><description>
L tzebuergescht / Luxemburgish: Ech kan Glas iessen, daat deet mir n t wei.</description></case><case><description>
Deutsch / German: Ich kann Glas essen, ohne mir zu schaden.</description></case><case><description>
Ruhrdeutsch: Ich kann Glas verkasematuckeln, ohne dattet mich wat jucken tut.</description></case><case><description>
Langenfelder Platt: Isch kann Jlaas kimmeln, uuhne datt mich datt weh d  d.</description></case><case><description>
Lausitzer Mundart ("Lusatian"): Ich koann Gloos assn und doas dudd merr ni wii.</description></case><case><description>
Odenw lderisch: Iech konn glaasch voschbachteln ohne dass es mir ebbs daun doun dud.</description></case><case><description>
S chsisch / Saxon: 'sch kann Glos essn, ohne dass'sch mer wehtue.</description></case><case><description>
Pf lzisch: Isch konn Glass fresse ohne dasses mer ebbes ausmache dud.</description></case><case><description>
Schw bisch / Swabian: I k  Glas fr ssa, ond des macht mr nix!</description></case><case><description>
Bayrisch / Bavarian: I koh Glos esa, und es duard ma ned wei.</description></case><case><description>
Allemannisch: I kaun Gloos essen, es tuat ma ned weh</description></case><case><description>
Schwyzerd tsch (Z rich): Ich chan Glaas  sse, das schadt mir n d.</description></case><case><description>
Schwyzerd tsch (Luzern): Ech cha Gl s  sse, das schadt mer ned.</description></case><case><description>
Hungarian: Meg tudom enni az  veget, nem lesz tole bajom.</description></case><case><description>
Suomi / Finnish: Voin sy d  lasia, se ei vahingoita minua.</description></case><case><description>
Sami (Northern): S ht n borrat l sa, dat ii leat b vccas.</description></case><case><description>
Erzian:                                   ,                                         .</description></case><case><description>
Northern Karelian: Mie voin syvv  lasie ta minla ei ole kipie.</description></case><case><description>
Southern Karelian: Min  voin syvv  st'oklua dai minule ei ole kibie.</description></case><case><description>
Estonian: Ma v in klaasi s  a, see ei tee mulle midagi.</description></case><case><description>
Latvian: Es varu est stiklu, tas man nekaite.</description></case><case><description>
Lithuanian: A  galiu valgyti stikla ir jis manes ne eid ia</description></case><case><description>
Czech: Mohu j st sklo, neubl    mi.</description></case><case><description>
Slovak: M  em jest sklo. Nezran  ma.</description></case><case><description>
Polska / Polish: Moge jesc szklo i mi nie szkodzi.</description></case><case><description>
Slovenian: Lahko jem steklo, ne da bi mi  kodovalo.</description></case><case><description>
Croatian: Ja mogu jesti staklo i ne boli me.</description></case><case><description>
Serbian (Latin): Ja mogu da jedem staklo.</description></case><case><description>
Serbian (Cyrillic):                                           .</description></case><case><description>
Macedonian:                                                                .</description></case><case><description>
Russian:                                                                 .</description></case><case><description>
Belarusian (Cyrillic):                                                                 .</description></case><case><description>
Belarusian (Lacinka): Ja mahu jesci  klo, jano mne ne  kodzic.</description></case><case><description>
Ukrainian:                                                                        .</description></case><case><description>
Bulgarian:                                                         .</description></case><case><description>
Georgian:                                             .</description></case><case><description>
Armenian:                                                                           :</description></case><case><description>
Albanian: Un  mund t  ha qelq dhe nuk m  gjen gj .</description></case><case><description>
Maltese: Nista' niekol il-hgieg u ma jaghmilli xejn.</description></case><case><description>
Hebrew:                                                                  .</description></case><case><description>
Yiddish:                                                                        .</description></case><case><description>

Twi: Metumi awe tumpan,   ny   me hwee.</description></case><case><description>
Hausa (Latin): Ina iya taunar gilashi kuma in gama lafiya.</description></case><case><description>
Hausa (Ajami) :                                                                                          </description></case><case><description>
Yoruba: Mo l  je   d g , k  n  pa m  l ra.</description></case><case><description>
Lingala: Nakok  kol ya bit ni bya milungi, ekos la ng   mab  t   .</description></case><case><description>
(Ki)Swahili: Naweza kula bilauri na sikunyui.</description></case><case><description>
Malay: Saya boleh makan kaca dan ia tidak mencederakan saya.</description></case><case><description>
Tagalog: Kaya kong kumain nang bubog at hindi ako masaktan.</description></case><case><description>
Chamorro: Si a yo' chumocho krestat, ti ha na'lalamen yo'.</description></case><case><description>
Javanese: Aku isa mangan beling tanpa lara.</description></case><case><description>
Bislama: Mi save kakae glas, hemi no save katem mi.</description></case><case><description>
Hawaiian: Hiki ia  u ke   ai i ke aniani;   a  ole no la au e   eha.</description></case><case><description>
Marquesan: E ko  ana e kai i te karahi, mea   a,   a  e hauhau.</description></case><case><description>
Chinook Jargon: Naika m  km  k kaksh  t labutay, pi weyk ukuk munk-sik nay.</description></case><case><description>
Navajo: Ts so' yisha ago b  n shghah d   doo shil neezgai da.</description></case><case><description>
Cherokee (and Chinook, Cree, Ojibwa, Lakota, Inuktitut, N huatl, Quechua, and other American languages):</description></case><case><description>

Lojban: mi kakne le nu citka le blaci .iku'i le se go'i na xrani mi</description></case><case><description>
N rdicg: Lj r ye caudran cr ne    jor c  ran.</description></case>
     
        </cases>
        
        
    </section>
</sections>


    
</page>