<page>
	<topic>Layout Table Reports
</topic>
<description>Alpha Anywhere now has two styles of reports, the traditional free form banded report, and a new layout table banded report. For web use, most people will want to use the new layout table report with HTML output.
To create a Layout Table Report, first create a report with the Quick Report Genie, then convert the Quick Report to a Layout Table Report.
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Strengths of Layout Table Reports
</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Capable of generating high quality HTML output 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Capable of generating Excel output with excellent fidelity to the design 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Capable of creating rounded corners across sections of the report, effectively putting an attractive frame around all or part of the report 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Improved style sheet support, with different styles for the header, summaries, and details 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Easier to maintain columnar reports, since inserting a new column will automatically adjust the other columns. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Can be used as linked reports 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Does not use the Amyuni driver for HTML or Excel output 
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Strengths of Free Form Reports
</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Offer absolute positioning, for precise control over reports to be output onto pre-printed forms 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Allow for conditional report objects 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Capable of creating multi-column reports 
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Layout Table Report Topics
</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Converting a Quick Report to a Layout Table Report  
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Editing a Layout Table Report 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Using a Layout Table Report 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Layout Table Report Example: Customer List 
</description>
	</case>
</cases>	
</section>		
</sections>	
	
</page>