<page>
	<topic>Adding a Global Image to Your Workspace</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<description>You can store bitmap images in the workspace (e.g., in the ALB file). The bitmaps are shown on the Code tab in the Control Panel. The advantage of storing the bitmaps in the workspace is that the bitmap files will be copied when you copy the workspace.
You can insert icon bitmaps (ICO files) into your workspace from the Windows Explorer by dragging and dropping the ICO file into the Alpha Anywhere Control Panel.
</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Adding a Global image to your Workspace</title>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Display the Code tab of the Control Panel.</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click New > Bitmap to display the Create Global Bitmap dialog box.</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the image's name in the Bitmap Object Name field.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Import Bitmap from File.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>1. Navigate to and select the image file.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>2. Click Open.
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, if you have previously copied an image to the clipboard, click Paste Bitmap from Clipboard.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, if you want to store the image in a different workspace.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click the '...' button to navigate to and select a different workspace library (.ALB) file.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Click Open.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to add your new global image or Cancel to quit without action.</description>
	</step>

</steps>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>You will have to exit from your workspace and reload it before you can use a stored global bitmap. To use a stored global bitmap.
</description>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Display the Insert Image Dialog Box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select Current Workspace Images.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the image from the list that appears.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Insert.
</description>
	</step>
</steps>	
	
</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Manipulating Global Bitmaps</ref>
		
	</see>
	
</page>