<page>
	<topic>Zip Workspace</topic>
	<description>A Zip file is a standard file format that is used to store files in a compressed form. You can use products such as WinZip? to view the contents of a zip file. If you don't have WinZip, you can download a shareware version from www.shareware.com.
You may zip all or parts of a workspace into a compressed zip file.
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
<note>You cannot zip part of a password protected workspace.</note>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The Zip Workspace function is an excellent way to move a workspace to a new location.
To zip a workspace:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select Tools > Zip Workspace... .
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Enter the path and name of the new zip file or click the 'open folder' icon to specify the path and name of a zip file to replace.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Folder_button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Compact Workspace before zipping? to potentially reduce its size.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Include absolute path names in zip file? if you want the recipient to be able to replicate your directory structure.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Include Web Project files. (Alpha Five version 6 and above.)
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, to make the list easier to read:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click Sort by Extension to group like files together.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Click Sort by Name to alphabetize the list.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click Sort by Natural to sort the list by creation date.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Hide support files? to show only workspace, table, and set files.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place checkmarks to the left of the files that you wish to send in the Files to Zip list.
</description>
			<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Optionally, click Mark All to place checkmarks next to all files.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Optionally, click Unmark All to remove checkmarks from all files.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Optionally, click Mark Files... to display the Mark Files dialog box.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>4. Click OK to place checkmarks to the left of all files.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>5. Click Data Files Only and OK to place checkmarks to the left of data files only.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>6. Click Application Files Only and OK to place checkmarks to the left of application files only.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>7. Optionally, click Unmark Files... to display the Un-mark Files dialog box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>8. Click OK to remove checkmarks from the left of all files.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>9. Click Data Files Only and OK to remove checkmarks from the left of data files only.
</description>
	</case>
		<case>
		<description>10. Click Application Files Only and OK to remove checkmarks from the left of application files only.
</description>
<figure><link>images/dbtable4.png</link></figure>
	</case>
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Save Settings to display the Save Send Workspace Settings dialog box.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Optionally, enter a Name for the configuration and click OK to save it.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Optionally, select a previously saved configuration in the Choices list and click Delete to remove it.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Optionally, select a previously saved configuration in the Choices list, click Rename, enter a new name, and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>4. Optionally, select a previously saved configuration in the Choices list, click Copy To, select another workspace (.ALB file), and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Load Settings to display the Load Send Workspace Settings dialog box.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Select a previously saved configuration in the Choices list and click OK to load it.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Zip Files to create the zip file.
</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Zip Table</ref>
		<ref>Zip Set</ref>
		<ref>Send Workspace</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>