<page>
	<topic>Zip Tables, Sets, and Workspaces</topic>
	<description>You can zip tables, sets, and entire workspaces from within Alpha Anywhere.
</description>
<sections>
<section>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select Tools > Zip Workspace.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, change the name or folder location of the zip file to create.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Compact Workspace before zipping. This potentially reduces the size of the zip file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Include absolute path names in zip file. This causes the files to be upzipped to the same location they came from and may be a problem if unzipped on a different computer.
</description>
<note>By default Alpha Anywhere includes all related files (i.e., indexes, dictionaries, and Help files) in the zip file. For example, when you zip a set, Alpha Anywhere automatically includes all of the tables that comprise the set. However, you can select files to include and exclude.</note>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, sort the files in the list box by Extension, Name, or Natural (the order in which the files appear in the workspace).
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Hide support files. Alpha Anywhere will show the .dbf file, but hide the corresponding .fpt, .cdx, .ddd, .ddm and .ddx files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click the  Mark Files and Un-mark Files buttons mark or un-mark all files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Save Settings to save the operation with a name.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Load Settings to load a previously saved zip operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Zip Files to create the zip file. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Zip_Database.png</link></figure>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>ZIP_FILES()</ref>
	<ref>Run a Custom Backup Job</ref>
	
</see>	
	
</page>