<page>
	<topic>Browse Functions and Methods</topic>
	
	<sections>
<section>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere provides the following Browse methods based on the default BROWSE object.
</description>
	<cases>
		<case><title>
.ARCHIVE</title><description>
Prints Layout_Name to file in the .PDF format.</description></case><case><title>
.DELETE()</title><description>
Deletes the browse from disk.</description></case><case><title>
.DIALOG()</title><description>
Opens Form_Name as a dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
.LOAD()</title><description>
Loads Browse Name into memory and returns an object pointer.</description></case><case><title>
.PREVIEW()</title><description>
Displays the browse and the selected records in the Print Preview dialog.</description></case><case><title>
.PRINT()</title><description>
Obsolete, see PRINT_BROWSE().
.PRINT()previews the print formatted browse on the screen.</description></case><case><title>
.SAVEAS()</title><description>
Prints the browse to file in the specified format. If no format is specified, the .PDF format is used.</description></case><case><title>
.VIEW()</title><description>
Opens Browse Name and returns an object pointer.</description></case><case><title>
.VIEWQUERIED()</title><description>
Opens Browse Name and returns an object pointer.</description></case><case><title>
.WINDOW_POSITION()</title><description>
Positions a browse window on the screen.</description></case>
		
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
	
</section>		
		
<section>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere provides the following browse methods. The use of these methods requires the pointer returned by the BROWSE.LOAD() method.
</description>
	<cases>
		
	<case><title>
ACTIVATE()</title><description>
 
Sets focus to the browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ACTIVE() </title><description>      
 
Returns the name of the column with focus.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ACTIVE_DRILLDOWN()</title><description>
 
Returns the column that has deepest focus.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ACTIVE_PREV() </title><description>
 
Returns the name of the column which previously had focus.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ALLOW_CHANGE()</title><description>
 
Sets the Allow Changes flag for a form or browse. When the flag is .T., data can be edited.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ALLOWCHANGESTATUS()</title><description>
 
Returns .T. (TRUE) if the layout allows editing; otherwise, it returns .F. (FALSE).</description></case><case><title>
 

.ARCHIVE()</title><description>
 
Prints Layout_Name to file in the .PDF format.</description></case><case><title>
 

.BASEQUERYRUN()</title><description>
 
Sets the base filter and order expressions for a layout.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CANCEL()</title><description>
 
Cancels any changes made to the current record before the records is saved.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CHANGE_MODE()</title><description>
 
Put a browse layout into change mode, just as if the user had done so by beginning to type into any field.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CHILD()</title><description>
 
Returns a pointer to the specified child object.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CHILD_ENUM()</title><description>
 
Returns a CR-LF separated list of all the child objects on the browse, in tab order.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CHILDREN()</title><description>
 
Returns the number of objects that a browse object contains.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CLASS()</title><description>
 
Returns the class (i.e., type) of the object.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CLOSE()</title><description>
 
Closes the form or browse window.</description></case><case><title>
 

.COMMIT()</title><description>
 
Saves the current record.</description></case><case><title>
 

.COPY_PREV_FIELD()</title><description>
 
Copies the value from the corresponding field in the previous record into the current field.</description></case><case><title>
 

.COPY_PREV_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Copies values from the previous record into the current record.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CURRENT_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Returns the record number of the current browse row.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CURSOR_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the character position of the cursor.</description></case><case><title>
 

.CURSOR_SET()</title><description>
 
Places the cursor at the specified character Position.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DATA_ENTRY_STYLE()</title><description>
 
Returns the window mode of the layout.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DELETE_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Deletes the current record in a form or a browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DIAL_PHONE()</title><description>
 
Dials the phone number in the column and row that currently has focus.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DICTIONARY_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the name of the dictionary file that contains the browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DISABLE()</title><description>
 
Makes an object unable to receive focus. May also gray the object. Works with forms, browses, fields, buttons, check boxes, etc.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DOWN()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus down as if the user had pressed the Down key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.DUPLICATE_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Creates a new record that is a duplicate of the current record and then moves focus to the new record.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ENABLE()</title><description>
 
Makes an object able to receive focus. Works with forms, browses, fields, buttons, check boxes, etc.</description></case><case><title>
 

.END()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the end of the row as if the user had pressed the End key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.EVAL()</title><description>
 
Interprets a character string as an Xbasic expression.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FETCH_FIRST()</title><description>
 
Moves to the first record in the current query.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FETCH_LAST()</title><description>
 
Moves to the last record in the current query. Works with forms and browses.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FETCH_NEXT()</title><description>
 
Moves to the next record in the current query.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FETCH_PREV()</title><description>
 
Moves to the previous record in the current query. Works with forms and browses.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FILTER_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the current filter expression for the layout.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FIND()</title><description>
 
Does a Find by Key for value. If value is not specified, the built-in Find dialog is displayed.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FIND_AND_REPLACE()</title><description>
 
Displays the Find and Replace dialog box. If layout has the Change mode restricted, then only the Find tab is shown.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FINDBY_DEFINEDKEY()</title><description>
 
A high level approach to displaying the Find by Key dialog box that allows you to customize its appearance and preset its filter.</description></case><case><title>
 

.FORM_VIEW()</title><description>
 
Toggles a browse window into a form window.</description></case><case><title>
 

.GETACTIVEOBJPARENT()</title><description>
 
Returns a pointer to the container of the object that has focus.</description></case><case><title>
 

.HAS_METHOD()</title><description>
 
Returns .T. (TRUE) if the browse supports the named method.</description></case><case><title>
 

.HIDE()</title><description>
 
Hides an object.</description></case><case><title>
 

.HOME()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the beginning of the row as if the user had pressed the Home key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ICON_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the filename of the browse icon.</description></case><case><title>
 

.INDEX_NAME()</title><description>
 
Returns the name of the current primary index or query.</description></case><case><title>
 

.INDEX_POINTER()</title><description>
 
Returns a pointer to the current primary index or query.</description></case><case><title>
 

.INDEX_SET()</title><description>
 
Selects an index or query list as the primary index for a form or browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.INDEX_SETEXPLICIT()</title><description>
 
Sets the primary index for the browse.
 </description></case><case><title>

.IndexSetDialog()</title><description>
 
Displays the Primary Index or Query dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.IS_ON_LAST_OBJECT()</title><description>
 
Returns .T. (TRUE) if the object is the last object on the browse, as specified in the browse's tab order.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ISVISIBLE()</title><description>
 
Returns .T. (TRUE) if the browse is visible.</description></case><case><title>
 

.KINDOF()</title><description>
 
Returns the kind of object represented by a browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.LEFT()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the left as if the user had pressed the Left key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.LOCATE()</title><description>
 
Displays the Locate dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.LOCATE_NEXT()</title><description>
 
Finds the next record with a field value matching value. If field is not specified, all fields are searched. Otherwise, only the specified field is searched.</description></case><case><title>
 

.LOCATE_PREV()</title><description>
 
Finds the previous record with a field value matching value. If field is not specified, all fields are searched. Otherwise, only the specified field is searched.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MARK_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Marks the current record.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MAXIMIZE()</title><description>
 
Maximizes the browse window.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MENUITEMCHECK()</title><description>
 
Displays or removes a checkmark next to a menu entry.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MENUITEMENABLE()</title><description>
 
Enables or disables (grays) a menu entry.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MENUITEMRESET()</title><description>
 
Enables and removes any checkmarks from a menu entry.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MINIMIZE()</title><description>
 
Minimizes the browse window.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MODE_GET()</title><description>
 
returns the current mode of the layout. Possible modes are: VIEW, CHANGE, ENTER, QUERY and FIND.</description></case><case><title>
 

.MULTI_SELECT()</title><description>
 
Displays the Multi-Select Records dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.NAME()</title><description>
 
Returns the browse's name.</description></case><case><title>
 

.NAVIGATOR()</title><description>
 
Displays the Goto which field? dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.NEW_RECORD()</title><description>
 
Enters a new record into a browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.NEXT()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the next control in the tab order as if the user had pressed the Tab key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.ORDER_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the current order expression for the browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.OUPUT_FILE_OVERRIDE()</title><description>
 
Sets the name of the file to be printed. It returns the name, if any, of the file currently set to be printed.</description></case><case><title>
 

.PREV()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the previous control in the tab order as if the user had pressed the Shift-Tab key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.PRINTER_OVERRIDE()</title><description>
 
Sets the printer configuration, and optionally, saves the current configuration before overwriting it.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUERY_BY_EXPN()</title><description>
 
Displays the Query by Expression dialog.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUERY_BY_TABLE()</title><description>
 
Opens the Query by Table dialog.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUERY_GENIE()</title><description>
 
Displays the Query Genie dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUERYRUN()</title><description>
 
Applies a query to the current browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICK_EXPORT()</title><description>
 
Exports the currently selected records to Excel.</description></case><case><title>
 

. QUICK_SEARCH()</title><description>
 
Performs the same action as the Quick Filter command.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICK_SEARCHEXCL()</title><description>
 
Opposite of the .QUICK_SEARCH() methods. Finds all records that do NOT match the value in the current control.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICK_SORT()</title><description>
 
Performs the same action as the Quick Sort command. Works with forms and browses.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICKFILTER()</title><description>
 
Returns a count of the matching records, as if you had clicked the Quick Filter icon.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICK_SEARCH()</title><description>
 
Performs the same action as the Quick Filter command and finds all records that match the value in the current control.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICK_SEARCHEXCL()</title><description>
 
performs the opposite action as the Quick Filter command and finds all records that do NOT match the value in the current control.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICKSORTEXPLICIT()</title><description>
 
Sorts the table or set on the indicated field and then displays it in the current browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICKSORTMULTIFLD()</title><description>
 
Displays the Custom Sort dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICKSRCHEXPLICIT()</title><description>
 
Filters the records in a browse based on the value of a field.</description></case><case><title>
 

.QUICKSRCHMULTIFLD()</title><description>
 
Displays the multi-field Quick Filter dialog.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RECORDS_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the number of records displayed by the layout.</description></case><case><title>
 

.REFERENCE_EXPRESSION_GET()</title><description>
 
Returns the reference expression to reconstruct a reference to the object.</description></case><case><title>
 

.REFRESH()</title><description>
 
Forces the browse to re-fetch data from its data source, and then to repaint itself. Works with all controls. Note, this method does not re-query the table to see if the record content of the browse has changed.</description></case><case><title>
 

.REFRESH_BROWSE()</title><description>
 
Refreshes the browse, as if you had pressed Browse > Refresh Display.</description></case><case><title>
 

.REFRESH_FIELDS()</title><description>
 
Executes the .REFRESH() method on each cell on a browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.REFRESH_LAYOUT()</title><description>
 
Refreshes the browse, as if you had pressed Browse > Refresh Display.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RESTORE()</title><description>
 
Restores a minimized or maximized window to normal size.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RESYNCH()</title><description>
 
Requeries the table, re-fetches all data for the form, and repaints the form.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RIGHT()</title><description>
 
Moves the focus to the right as if the user had pressed the Right key.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RIGHTCLICK()</title><description>
 
Displays the Right Click menu.</description></case><case><title>
 

.RUN_SAVED_QUERY()</title><description>
 
Runs a saved query. If Query_Name is not specified, Alpha Anywhere prompts for a name.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SELECT_TEXT()</title><description>
 
Selects text in the current field from Start_Position for Length characters.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SELECTED_RECORDS()</title><description>
 
Returns a list of the currently selected record numbers.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SEND()</title><description>
 
Emails the browse.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SESSIONHANDLE()</title><description>
 
Returns the session handle associated with the object.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SET_DIRTY()</title><description>
 
Indicates that layout needs to be saved.</description></case><case><title>
 

.IndexSetDialog()</title><description>
 
Displays the Select</description></case><case><title>
 

.SHOW()</title><description>
 
Shows an object that may previously have been hidden using the .HIDE() method. Works with forms, browses, fields, buttons, check boxes,  text, lines and most other objects on forms.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SHOW_ALL()</title><description>
 
Turns off the current query and shows all records in the table (subject to any base filter that may have been specified in the form or browses Filter/Order properties).</description></case><case><title>
 

.SHOW_MEMO()</title><description>
 
Opens the memo editor for a memo field. Works with forms and browses.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SPECIALQUERIES()</title><description>
 
Displays the Select Filter dialog box.</description></case><case><title>
 

.SPELL_CHECK()</title><description>
 
Displays the object specified by  and the Spellchecker dialog box.</description></case>

<case>
<title>.TABLE_GET()</title>
<description>Returns the  object pointer to the table that contains the data on the browse.
</description>
</case>	
		

<case>
<title>.TOGGLE_FORMBROWSE()</title>
<description>
 
Switches the browse to a form display.
 </description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.TOOLBARCHANGE()</title>
<description>Loads and displays the selected toolbar.
</description>
</case>			

<case>
<title>.ToolbarControlEnable()</title>
<description>Enables or disables the specified item on the control bar.</description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.TYPE()</title>
<description>Returns the type of data bound to an browse.
</description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.UNMARK_RECORD()</title>
<description>Un-marks the current record.</description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.UP()</title>
<description>Moves the focus up as if the user had pressed the Up key.</description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.VARIABLES()</title>
<description>Returns a pointer to a dot variable that contains the values of the selected variables.
</description>
</case>	

<case>
<title>.WINDOW_POSITION()</title>
<description>Sets the location of the browse on the screen.</description>
</case>	


<case>
<title>.ZORDER()</title>
<description>Sets the stacking position of a browse.
</description>
</case>	
	</cases>
	
	
	
</section>			
<section>
	<description>The following functions and methods are useful for manipulating browses.</description>
<cases>
	<case>
<title>A5.BROWSE_ENUM()</title>
<description>Returns a list of browses.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>A5.BROWSE_LOCATION()</title>
<description>Returns the name of the file that contains the browse.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>A5_BROWSE_CREATE()</title>
<description>Displays the New Browse dialog, which allows you to select the fields that will appear in the new browse.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>A5_LAYOUT_DESIGN()</title>
<description>Opens the named layout in the appropriate editor.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_BROWSE()</title>
<description>Opens the default browse for the specified table.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>ADHOCVIEW()</title>
<description>Creates a temporary browse or form for the table or set defined by a provided table or set name. The resulting layout can be user modifiable or locked to prevent user modifications.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>ALLOW_EDITING()</title>
<description>Returns the current setting of the Form > Allow Edits, or Browse > Allow Edits menu command.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>BROWSE_OBJECTS_GET()</title>
<description>Returns a list of the columns on a browse.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>CLOSE_IF_EXISTS()</title>
<description>Closes a browse if it is open.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>CURRENT_HIGHLIGHTED_RECORDS()</title>
<description>Returns the rows currently highlighted in a browse.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>LAYOUT_DELETE()</title>
<description>Deletes the named Form, Browse, Label, Letter, or Report.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>LAYOUT_RENAME()</title>
<description>Renames or copies the named Form, Browse, Label, Letter, or Report.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>PREVIEW_BROWSE()</title>
<description>Previews the browse as it would appear if printed.
</description>
</case>		
<case>
<title>PRINT_BROWSE()</title>
<description>Creates the selected browse and then displays the Print dialog box.
</description>
</case>		
	
	
</cases>	
	
	
</section>			
	</sections>
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
</page>