<page>
    <topic>Building Master Detail Applications with Alpha Anywhere</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Alpha Anywhere's built-in data integration makes creating Master Detail applications built on relational data very easy. Depending on the type of application you plan to build - mobile or web - several approaches are available to you for creating a Master Detail application. Master Detail applications can be built using Grid Components, UX Components, or a combination of both.</p>
    </description>
    <groups>
        <group background="true">
            <title>Important Notice for Community Edition Users</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>These tutorials were built using the full Alpha Anywhere Development Environment. Portions of these tutorials may not apply due to features that are not available in Community Edition. Community Edition users may encounter screens that don't match their environment due to differences between the two development environments.</p>
                        <p>We strongly recommend starting with the tutorials in the *[extlink:Alpha Software Learning Center@https://learn.alphasoftware.com]* to start learning Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>In a Master Detail application, database information is displayed using a combination of a "master" list of records and one or more "detail" interfaces that show related data. An example of a Master Detail relationship is shown below:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/customerOrderDetail.svg</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
    <!--order:
Master Detail App with List and FormView
Master Detail App with Grid Components
Master Detail App with Repeating Sections
--> <!--list:.-->
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
</page>