<page>
    <shortlink>Building Master Detail Mobile Applications Using the List, FormView and ControlBar Controls</shortlink>
    <topic>Building Master Detail Mobile Applications Using the List, FormView and ControlBar Controls</topic>
    <description>Learn how to build a Master Detail using the List and FormView Controls in a UX Component. The List and FormView controls allow you to create a light-weight application that can be deployed in either the web or mobile environment. In this tutorial, we demonstrate creating a Master-Detail mobile application that takes advantage of several features, including Editors and the ControlBar, to create an easy-to-use responsive interface.</description>
    <groups>
        <group background="true">
            <title>Overview</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>                            
                        <p>In this video tutorial, we show how implement a Master-Detail application using the FormView control. The app allows users to edit data from the Customers and Orders table in the sample Northwind database. This is a classic Master-Detail form: Each customer has multiple orders. The UX component uses two Lists joined in a parent-child relationship. The parent List displays data from the Customer table and the child List display the related orders from the Orders table.</p>
                        <p>Each List has a Detail View, but in both cases, the Detail View is implemented using the FormView control.</p>
                        <p>Once we are done building the basic functionality, we 'mobilize' the app by wrapping sections of the component in PanelCards and add a ControlBar to provide the ability to navigate the application.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>To follow along with this tutorial, you will need a connection string to the Northwind database. Alpha Anywhere ships with a pre-defined connection string to the Northwind database called 'AADemo-Northwind'.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>If the 'AADemo-Northwind' connection string is not listed in the Connection Strings dialog, you can create one by clicking the *[ui:Create 'AADemo-Northwind' demo connection string]* link at the bottom of the connection string dialog:</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <note>This tutorial was built for Alpha Anywhere v4.3 or newer.</note>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Tutorial</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <videos>
                        <title>Building a Mobile Master-Detail Form using The List, FormView and ControlBar Controls</title>
                        <description>To learn how to build a Master-Detail mobile application using the List, FormView, and ControlBar controls, watch the video below.</description>
                        <video>
                            <name>Watch Video</name>
                            <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/96430372</link>
                        </video>
                        <date>2016-11-10</date>
                    </videos>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Download the Components Used in the Tutorial</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you'd prefer to follow along, you can [Download the Components] used in the videos. These components can be used to follow along with the tutorial or as a starting point for your own Master-Detail application.</p>
                        <p>When you run the components in Working or Live Preview, you may see the following error:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>The components in the download require two connection strings, one named "northwind" and the other named "mysql_northwind". The easiest way to create these connection strings is to copy the 'AADemo-Northwind' connection string. The 'AADemo-Northwind' connection is a connection string that connects to the Northwind MS Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere.</description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title>Creating the 'Northwind' and 'mysql_northwind' Connection Strings for the Downloaded Components</title>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog. This can be done from the Web Projects Control Panel. Under the *[ui:Edit]* menu, select *[ui:Manage connection strings]* &gt; *[ui:AlphaDAO Connection strings]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Select the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string. If the connection string is not listed, click the *[ui:Create 'AADemo-Northwind' demo connection string]*  to create it. With the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string selected, click the *[ui:Copy]* button.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Name the connection string *[Northwind]* and paste the copied 'AADemo-Northwind' connection string in the *[ui:Connection String]* text box. Click *[ui:OK]* to save the connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Repeat the previous 2 steps to create a connection string named *[mysql_northwind]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <link>images/mdForm_connStr7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/customerOrdersFormViewPanels.zip">Download the Components</link>
        <link link="creating alphadao connection strings">Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="building master detail web applications with grid components">Building Master Detail Web Applications with Grid Components</ref>
        <ref link="Building Master Detail Applications for Web Applications - UX Component">Building Master Detail Applications for Web Applications with UX Components</ref>
    </see>
</page>