<page>
    <topic>Arrays</topic>
    <description>This section discusses creating .Net Array objects from XBasic.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>While XBasic will automatically convert built-in XBasic array types into equivalent .Net, there are conditions where it is required that .Net arrays be explicitly created.  </p>
        <p>A good example of where explicitly created .Net array objects are needed is with the many 'value' types. In XBasic, numeric values are generally always floating point. 
        When we convert a numeric array to DotNot implicitly on invocation, the .Net type is always created as an array of Double values.</p>
        <p>If the .Net property you are setting, or method you are calling expects an array of 32 Bit integer values (Int32) then 
        passing an array of Double will result in a type error, and the call will fail.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Creating and Assigning an Array of Int32 types from XBasic</title>
            <description>            
                <p>When the type specified in an xbasic array dim statement is a .Net type, the array that is created will be a .Net array type.</p>
                <p>Note that unlike Xbasic arrays, .Net arrays are always a fixed size, so you need to know the number of elements up front.</p>
                <p>Note that unlike C#, the array operator in XBasic starts at '1' not '0'.</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim arr[2] as System::Int32
arr[1] = 100
arr[2] = 200
]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating and Multidimension Arrays</title>
            <description>
                <p>The following is an example of a complex array with multiple dimensions.</p>
                <p>Note that Xbasic always adds one to the index, so the index column and row '2,3' from Xbasic is '1,2' in .Net.</p>                
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim arr[3,4] as system::Int32
? arr.GetLength(0)
= 3
? arr.GetLength(1)
= 4

arr[1,1] = 101
arr[1,2] = 102
arr[1,3] = 103
arr[1,4] = 104
arr[2,1] = 201
arr[2,2] = 202
arr[2,3] = 203
arr[2,4] = 204
arr[3,1] = 301
arr[3,2] = 302
arr[3,3] = 303
arr[3,4] = 304

? arr[2,3]
= 203

? arr.Get(1,2)
= 203

]]></example>
    </section>

        <section>
            <title>Creating and Arrays with different Bounds</title>
            <description>
                <p>Bounds can be specified in the xbasic DIM statement, but like the default '0' lower bound, all the bounds are adjusted by one for xbasic.</p>                
                <p>Note that lower bounds returned for first and second dimension are 1 and 100, even though we specified 2 and 101.
                  The array entry '2,102' is actually '1,101' in .Net.</p>                
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim arr[2..4,101..102] as system::Int32
? arr.GetLength(0)
= 3

? arr.GetLength(1)
= 2
? arr.GetLowerBound(0)
= 1
? arr.GetLowerBound(1)
= 100

arr[2,101] = 1
arr[3,101] = 2
arr[4,101] = 3
arr[2,102] = 4
arr[3,102] = 5
arr[4,102] = 6

? arr[2,102]
= 4

? arr.Get(1,101)
= 4
]]></example>
    </section>    

    </sections>
</page>