<page>
    <shortlink>viewbox sample list of orders for a customer json</shortlink>
    <topic>List of orders for a customer (uses static JSON data)</topic>
    <description>Example showing a list of orders for a customer based on static JSON data. No SQL database is required.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>This example shows how rich HTML output can be created by merging data in a JavaScript object with a [Client Side Template]. This example can be thought of as a client-side report writer. It would be easy to make various parts of the report 'hot' (i.e. fire events) by adding event handlers into the HTML template defined in the ViewBox.</p>
        <p>This sample is the same as the List of orders for a customer (from the Northwind sample database) sample. The difference between the two samples is that this sample uses statically defined data in a JSON object.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/listOfOrdersJSON1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The JavaScript object for the data displayed in this ViewBox is an array of customers with nested arrays of orders for each customer. Each order contains a nested array of order details. The object is merged with a [Client Side Template] to generate the final result.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The List of orders for a customer (uses static JSON data) template example is loaded by clicking the Load Sample ViewBox link on the Home tab of the ViewBox Builder.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/loadListOfOrdersJSON.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=client%20side%20templates">Client Side Template</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=client%20side%20templates">Client Side Template Syntax</ref>
    </see>
</page>