<page>
    <shortlink>viewbox sample list of orders for a customer northwind</shortlink>
    <topic>List of orders for a customer (from the Northwind sample database)</topic>
     <description>Example showing a list of orders for a customer based on data in the Northwind sample database. Requires a named SQL connection string called 'northwind'.</description>
     <discussion>
        <p>This example the shows how rich HTML output can be created by merging data in a JavaScript object with a [Client Side Template]. This example can be thought of as a client-side report writer. It would be easy to make various parts of the report 'hot' (i.e. fire events) by adding event handlers into the HTML template defined in the ViewBox.</p>
        <p>This sample is the same as the List of orders for a customer (uses static JSON data) sample. The difference between the two samples is that this sample demonstrates loading data dynamically from a SQL database. The SQL Database used is the Northwind database, which ships with Alpha Anywhere. In order to use this example, you must first create a connection string to the Northwind database named "Northwind".</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/listOfOrdersNorthwind.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The List of orders for a customer (from the Northwind sample database) template example is loaded by clicking the Load Sample ViewBox link on the Home tab of the ViewBox Builder.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/loadListOfOrdersNorthwind.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you do not have a connection string called "Northwind" that connects to the Northwind database, you can create one as follows:</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Open the ViewBox Builder for the ViewBox control loaded with the List of orders for a customer (from the Northwind sample database) sample.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the Data Source tab, click the [...] button to open the Nested SQL Query editor.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the *[ui:Select...]* button to open the Connection String dialog.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the Connection String dialog, click the *[ui:Edit Saved Connections]* link to open the Connection string editor.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string. If the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string is not listed, click the *[ui:Create 'AADemo-Northwind' demo connection string]* link to create one. This link will only be available if the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string does not exist.</p>
                        <p>With the *[AADemo-Northwind]* connection string selected, click the *[ui:Copy]* button.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Next, click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Paste the copied connection string in the *[ui:Connection String]* text box. Name the connection string "Northwind".</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Test the connection string to verify that it worked. If the connection string fails to work, please follow the instructions in the [Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings] tutorial to create a connection string to the Northwind database.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/northwind6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new connection string.</p>
                        <p>In the *[ui:Connection String]* dialog, click *[ui:Cancel]* to close the dialog without changing anything. Your connection string not be deleted.</p>
                        <p>Continue to close all dialogs by clicking the *[ui:Cancel]* button. Once you have returned to the UX Builder, run your component in Working Preview to verify your new connection string is working.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="creating alphadao connection strings">Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings</link>
        <link link="client side templates">Client Side Template</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="client side templates">Client Side Template Syntax</ref>
    </see>
</page>