<page>
	<topic>Stylesheets Dialog</topic>
	<description>Opening the stylesheets dialog, using the stylesheets dialog, applying a stylesheet to a layout, 
		creating a new stylesheet, updating a stylesheet, and deleting a stylesheet.
	</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Opening the Stylesheets Dialog
</title>
<description>You can apply a Stylesheet to a layout in Design Mode using the Stylesheets dialog. To open the Stylesheets dialog:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In layout design mode, select Stylesheets > Apply or Create a Stylesheet. Stylesheet Gallery:
</description>
		<figure><link>images/Style_Sheet_Gallery.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Using the Stylesheets Dialog</title>
<description>The left column of the Stylesheets dialog lists the available Style Sheets. Clicking on a stylesheet name displays a preview of the style sheet in the Preview pane. The right column lists the commands available.
</description>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Applying a Stylesheet to a Layout
</title>
<description>To apply a selected Stylesheet to a layout:
</description>	

	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the Style Sheet from the list and click the Apply button.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>The layout is updated to reflect the Stylesheet formatting.
</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
</section>


<section>
	<title>Creating a New Stylesheet
</title>
<description>There are two ways to create a new Stylesheet. You can create a Style Sheet based on an open layout, or copy an existing Stylesheet. Copying Stylesheets lets you create variations without losing the original, and lets you modify the built-in Alpha Five Stylesheets.
To create a new Stylesheet based on the current layout:
</description>	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Click the Create New button.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the Create New Stylesheet dialog box, enter a Style Name for your new Stylesheet. Entering a Style Name:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/Create_New_Stylesheet_1.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
</section>
<section>
	
	<description>To copy an existing style:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the Stylesheets dialog, select the style you want to copy.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click the Duplicate button.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Enter a Style Name for the new style and click Duplicate. Enter a Style Name for the Duplicate:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/Create_New_Stylesheet_2.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
	</steps>
</section>
<section>
	<description>The new style appears in the Stylesheets dialog.
</description>
</section>


<section>
	<title>Updating a Stylesheet
</title>
<description>You can update an existing Stylesheet to reflect the formatting of a layout. Note : Updating a Stylesheet overwrites existing properties in the Stylesheet. You cannot update system Style Sheets.
To update an existing Stylesheet:
</description>	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the Stylesheets dialog, select the style you want to update.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click the Update button.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Alpha prompts you to make sure you want to overwrite the Stylesheet.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
</section>


<section>
	<title>Deleting a Stylesheet
</title>
<description>You can delete user-created Stylesheets, but not the system Stylesheets.
To delete a Stylesheet:
</description>	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the Stylesheets dialog, select the style you want to delete.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click the Delete button.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Alpha prompts you to makes sure you want to delete the Stylesheet.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Importing and Exporting Stylesheets">Importing and Exporting Stylesheets</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Managing Style Properties">Managing Style Properties</ref>
		
	</see>
	
	
</page>