<page>
    <shortlink>svg</shortlink>
    <topic>SVG</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere now comes with a set of pre-defined SVG icons that can be used with any style. These SVG icons are the same icons that the new Alpha stylesheet uses.</description>
    <!--list:.-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When you are using a stylesheet other than the Alpha stylesheet, when you open the SVG Icon picker you will see that the system SVG icons are shown in a category called System SVG Icons.  In addition, the Class dropdown will have three special auto-generated classes that can be applied to the SVG icons. These are:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>icon</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>iconSizeable</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>iconDisabled</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The definition of these classes are shown below.</p>
                <p>If you do not select any class, some of the images will not render properly because the stroke color of the SVG icon is not defined.</p>
                <p>You must select either icon or iconSizeable for the icons to render correctly.</p>
                <p>You will notice that the icon class defines a explicit size for the icon (26 x 26 px). Therefore changing the size using the slider on the dialog will have no effect.</p>
                <p>If you would like to be able to size the icon, you should select the iconSizeable class.</p>
                <p>You can also define your own classes in the component's Local CSS, or Linked CSS to apply to the SVG icon.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/systemsvgicons.jpg</link>
            </figure>
            <example><![CDATA[.icon {
    vertical-align: middle;
    width: 26px;
    height: 26px;
    fill: #333;
    stroke: #333;
}
.iconSizeable {
    vertical-align: middle;
    width: auto;
    height: auto;
    fill: #333;
    stroke: #333;
}
.iconDisabled {
    opacity: .25;
}]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>