<page source="Xbasicaddins/webcomponentbuilder.a5lib/scripts/a5w_publish2.a5udf" generated="true" >
  <shortlink>api a5w publish2 function source</shortlink>
   <topic>a5w_publish2 Function</topic>
   <description>A wrapper around the a5w_publish() function to make it easier for create command line programs that automate publishing. Call a5w_publish2("help") to get help on the options.</description>


   <prototype>L a5w_publish2(* opsIn )</prototype>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>opsIn</name>
         <description>
You can either pass in a dot variable or a JSON string to the function.
The dot variable (or the JSON string) can define the following properties:
         </description>
         <list>
         <item><name>projName</name><description>the name of the Web Project you want to publish. If you leave this blank the last selected project is used.</description></item>
         <item><name>profile</name><description>name of the publishing profile to use. If you leave this blank "Local Webroot" is used.</description></item>
         <item><name>publish_type</name><description>1 = all files in project, 2 = selected files (specified by the 'files' property). Note: if you set to 1, the 'flagPublishSupportFiles' property is set to .t.</description></item>
         <item><name>files</name><description>CR-LF delimited list of files to publish. Must set publish_type to 2. File names are relative. e.g. 'MyUXComponent.a5wcmp'.</description></item>
         <item><name>flagOptimizePublishing</name><description>default to .t. - specifies if the publishing history should be checked to see if the file has been previously published. If .t., then only files that have not been published since they were last changed are published.</description></item>
         <item><name>flagPublishDatabaseALB</name><description>default to .f. 'Workspace' SQL reports are stored in the Workspace files (.alb, .alm, .alx). If you are using Workspace SQL reports (as opposed to Project reports), you can specify if the Workspace SQL reports should be published.</description></item>
         <item><name>flagPublishSecurityTables</name><description>default to .f. - Specify if security tables (containing user and group settings) should be published.</description></item>
         <item><name>flagPublishSupportFiles</name><description>default .t. - only applies if publish_type is 2. Support files include CSS and Javascript files.</description></item>
         <item><name>flagCreateAex</name><description>default .f. - if you have global functions definedas L = default .f.</description></item>
         </list>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
<terms>publishing,a5w,function,help</terms>


</page> 