<page>
    <topic>How to Export Tables from a Database</topic>
    <description>When sharing components or sending in a bug report, you need to include a backup of the table(s) referenced by the component. Otherwise, the component cannot be run. This article describes how to export data from tables in MySQL or SQL Server.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Exporting Tables Using Navicat</title>
            <description>Navicat is a popular tool used by many Alpha Anywhere developers to work with SQL databases. Navicat's Export Wizard can be used to export multiple tables from a database to SQL files.</description>
            <note>These instructions show creating a SQL dump from a SQL Server Express database using Navicat for SQL Server. However, the process is the same if you use Navicat for MySQL.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In Navicat, expand the database that contains the tables you want to export. Click on "Tables" listed under the database in the database explorer to display all of the tables. Click on the *[ui:Export Wizard]* toolbar button.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/navicat_export1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the first page in the export wizard, select *[ui:SQL sript file (*.sql)]*. Click *[ui:Next>]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/navicat_export2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the tables you wish to export. Click *[ui:Next>]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/navicat_export3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>The columns to export page lists what columns from each table will be exported. By default, all columns from each table will be exported. Click *[ui:Next>]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/navicat_export4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the additional options page, cick *[ui:Next>]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/navicat_export5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the final page, click *[ui:Start]* to export the data. When the export finishes, click *[ui:Close]*. The generated SQL files will contain the create and insert statments necessary to import the tables to another database.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Click Start to begin the export.</title>
                        <link>images/navicat_export6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Export is complete.</title>
                        <link>images/navicat_export7.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Exporting Tables Using MySQL Workbench</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In MySQL Workbench, click *[ui:Data Export]* under the Management options to opent he Data Export tool. </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/mysql_export1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click on the database you wish to export.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the tables you want to export.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Make sure *[Dump Structure and Data]* is selected for the Tables to Export dropdown box.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Choose *[ui:Export to Self-Contained File]*.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:Start]* to begin the export. Close the Data Export tool when the export is complete.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/mysql_export2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        
    </sections>
</page>