<page>
    <topic>How to Display a QR Code in a Report</topic>
    <description>You can generate and display QR codes in reports using a variety of methods.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Creating QR Codes using Calculated Fields</title>
            <description>
                <p>Calculated fields can be used to generate and display QR Codes in a Freeform report.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Under the *[ui:Report]* menu, select *[ui:Calculated fields...]*</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Create a new calculated field using the [qrcode_bitmap] function. The qrcode_bitmap function generates a QR Code for a specified character value. For example, the code below generates a QR Code for the "Contactname" field that is 300 x 300 pixels in size and stores it in a calculated field called "qrcode":</description>
                    <example><![CDATA[qrcode = qrcode_bitmap(Contactname,'M',300,300)]]></example>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Insert your calculated field into your report. Make sure to size the field large enough to fit the generated QR Code.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For an alternative method for displaying QR Codes in Freeform reports, watch this video:</description>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Displaying QR Codes in Freeform Reports using the printQRCode Function</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/reports_printingQRCodes.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Layout Table Reports</title>
            <description>
                <p>In Layout Table Reports, you can easily display a QR Code by checking the *[ui:Display QRCode for text cell]* option in the Cell Contents dialog for a cell in the report. Alpha Anywhere will generate a QR Code based on the cell's contents.</p>
                <p>Watch the video below for full step-by-step instructions on how to display a QR Code in a Layout Table Report.</p>
            </description>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Displaying QR Codes in Layout Table Reports</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/qrcodes_displaying_inreports.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=qrcode_bitmap Function">qrcode_bitmap</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=QRCode Namespace">QRCode Namespace</ref>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=qrcode_bitmap Function">qrcode_bitmap Function</ref>
    </see>
</page>