<page>
    <shortlink>bulk operation change storage type</shortlink>
    <topic>Change Component storage type</topic>
    <description>Change the storage type for Grid and UX Components. The storage type can be either JSON or Binary.</description>
    <discussion>UX Components and Grid Components can be saved as formatted JSON or binary. The *[ui:Change Component storage type]* bulk operation allows you to quickly change the storage type for multiple UX or Grid components to *[ui:Formatted JSON]* or *[ui:Binary]*.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>How to Perform a Change Component storage type Bulk Operation</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>To perform a *[ui:Change Component storage type]* bulk operation, open the Web Projects Control Panel and select *[ui:Bulk Operations]* &gt; *[ui:Change Component storage type...]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu:</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/bulkChangeStorageType.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the type of components you would like to update. You can choose *[ui:Grid Components]* or *[ui:UX Components]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/bulkChangeStorageType1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the Components by checking the checkbox next to the filename. You can use the *[ui:Select All]*, *[ui:Un-Select All]* or *[ui:Wildcard Select]* links to select files.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/bulkChangeStorageType2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Choose the storage type to use in the *[ui:Save component as:]* dropdown. The component can be stored as one of the following types:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Storage Type</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Formatted JSON</name>
                            <description>Component properties will be saved in clear text. This is useful if you are using a source or version control system that supports displaying differences between file versions.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Binary</name>
                            <description>Component is stored as binary. Binary files are smaller than Formatted JSON.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to perform the bulk operation. A notice with a summary of the operation will be shown when the bulk operation completes.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/bulkChangeStorageType3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>