<page>
	<topic>Connecting to SQL Server</topic>
<description>Alpha Anywhere AlphaDAO provides an extension driver for SQL Server to simplify building connections using any of the SQL Server ODBC drivers provided by Microsoft.  
			You must first install the appropriate driver for the version of your SQL Server database.
			In the connection string dialog, select the version of the database you are connecting to.
			Alpha Anywhere will select the installed driver that is the best fit for the target version.
			</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Using the SQL Server Connection String Dialog</title>
			<description>When you select SQL Server as your connection type in the connection string dialog, the dialog below will be displayed.  
				Select the version of your database, enter the server name and provide any authentication information required to connect to your database. 
				The values you select will be generated into the connection string at the top of the dialog for you as you make changes.
					</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
            <note>
              	<p>Before you begin, make sure you have installed and configured your SQL Server server and installed the appropriate client side driver.
		For more information on installing and configuring SQL Server, see
              *[extlink:https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/sql-server/sql-server-downloads]*.
		</p>
		<p>
              	If you do not install the version of the ODBC driver Microsoft recommends for your database, you may be able to connect, but you could get
		errors or unexpected results when executing SQL.
		</p>
		<p>
		<strong>Important: </strong> Alpha Anyhere is a 32-bit executable.  You must install the 32-bit ODBC client driver for your database.  
						To view those drivers, you will need to run the 32-bit ODBC Data Source Administator found at c:\windows\syswow64\odbcad32.exe.
		</p>
	</note>
	<note>
		<p>The table below lists the database version and the recommended driver for that database.
		The version that you see in the Microsoft ODBC administrator dialog is for the client driver of that name specifically.  It is independent of the database server version. <br/>
		You may need to update your client driver from time to time as updates are made available from Microsoft.
		</p>
		<p>
		Again, the client driver name is the one that you want to match the database version.<br/><br/>
		</p>
	</note>
	<note>
		<p>
		As of this writing the following client drivers are available for the various versions of the SQL Server database.<br/>
		</p>
		<p>
		<table>
		<tr><th>SQL Server Version</th><th>Client Driver Name</th></tr>
		<tr><td>2017,2019</td><td>ODBC Driver 17 for SQL Server</td></tr>
		<tr><td>2016</td><td>ODBC Driver 13 for SQL Server</td></tr>
		<tr><td>2014</td><td>ODBC Driver 11 for SQL Server</td></tr>
		<tr><td>2012</td><td>SQL Server Native Client 11.0</td></tr>
		<tr><td>2008</td><td>SQL Server Native Client 10.0</td></tr>
		<tr><td>2005</td><td>SQL Native Client</td></tr>
		<tr><td>Older Versions</td><td>SQL Server</td></tr>
		</table>
		<br/><br/>
		</p>
		<p>
		Consult the documentation for Microsoft SQL Server for more information about downloading and installing client drivers.
		</p>
		<br/>
		<br/>
		
            </note>

				</case>
				<case>
				<description><p>The SQL Server connection string dialog has tab pages for general properties, timeouts, SSH tunneling, and advanced properties. 
						 Each of the properties are described below.</p>
				</description>
				<note>Click the Refresh button to see a list of databases, or leave the entry blank and click Test Connection.  
					Once you have made an initial connection, you can click the Create Database button to create a new database on the server.
				</note>
				<figure><link>images/SQLServerConnectionStringDialogGeneral.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
				<description>The Timeouts tab page lets you override default timeouts for login, the lifetime of the connection and for each query.
						</description>
				<figure><link>images/SQLServerConnectionStringDialogTimeouts.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
				<description>The SSH tab is used to enable a connection to a database using an SSH2 tunnel.
                    These connections are made from a local tunnel that is connected to a remote server and then finally to the actual database, 
			typically behind a firewall.
                    Alpha Anywhere will create and manage the tunnel for you based on the values you provide on this page.
						</description>
				<figure><link>images/SQLServerConnectionStringDialogSSH.png</link></figure>
				</case>

				<case>
				<description><p>The Advanced tab is used to set up a secure connection, enable column encryption, enter additional parameters
						and provide an initial command to be executed at connect time.</p>
				<p>To set SQL server parameters that are not directly supported by the SQL Server connection string dialog, enter them as comma separated
					key=value entries.  They will be passed directly to the connection string provided to SQL Server.</p>
				<p>To execute one or more commands immediately after connecting to the database, enter native SQL Server commands separated
					by a semi-colon.</p>
				</description>
				<figure><link>images/SQLServerConnectionStringDialogAdvanced.png</link></figure>
				</case>

			</cases>
		</section>
	
		<section>
			<title>SQL Server Connection String Properties</title>
			<list>
				<item>
					<name-title>Connection Property</name-title>
					<description-title>Description</description-title>
				</item>

				<item>
					<name>A5API</name>
					<description>Setting the connection property A5API to 'SQLServer' will load the SQL Server driver when you open a connection.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5DBVersion</name>
					<description>The version number of SQL Server your server is running. 
						This will assure that your client connects using the driver best matched to your SQL Server server.
						</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Server</name>
					<description>Enter the DNS name or IP address of your server.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Port</name>
					<description>SQL Server defaults to an IP address of 1433.
            					It is a good practice to set the server port to a different value so that it is not as obvious what port SQL Server 
						is running on.
						This is not a substitute for using secure connections.
						</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>UserName</name>
					<description>Set this value to the user name you wish to connect to the database with.  
					This is only needed if trusted_connection is not set to 'yes'</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Password</name>
					<description>Set this value to the password value you wish to connect to the database with.  
                This is only needed if trusted_connection is not set to 'yes'
                <note>Using the connection string dialog will obscure the password within the connection string.
                Publish functions encrypt the connection string.</note>
              </description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Database</name>
					<description>Enter or select the name of the database you are targeting.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5TraceSQL</name>
					<description>Set this value to Y to trace SQL statements.
            Within Alpha Anywhere messages are written to the trace pane.
            For Application Servers the output is written to a file.  The actual location varies by server.
						</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5LoginTimeout</name>
					<description>Set this value to control the timeout for new connections in seconds.
              Omit this setting to use the SQL Server ODBC driver default value.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5ConnectionTimeOut</name>
					<description>Set this value to control the timeout for the lifetime of a connection in seconds.
              Omit this setting to use the SQL Server ODBC driver default value.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5QueryTimeOut</name>
					<description>Set this value to control the timeout for a single query in seconds.
              Omit this setting to use the SQL Server ODBC driver default value.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5SSHTunnel</name>
					<description>Setting this value to Y requests that a tunnel be created to connect to the target database.
					<p>The conection string properties for SSH connections are discussed separately in
						*[link:Connecting Securely with SSH@Connecting Securely with SSH.html]*.
 						</p>
					</description>
				</item>

				<item>
					<name>A5SSL</name>
					<description>Set this value to 'Y' to encrypt connections to the server.
						The default value of this parameter is 'N'.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5TrustServerCertificate</name>
					<description>Set this value to 'Y' if you are using a self-signed certificate and do not want to check the server identity against a certificate authority.
						This value should never be set to 'Y' on a production server, but can be useful in testing out secure connections on a development server.
						The default value of this parameter is 'N'.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5EnableColumnEncryption</name>
					<description>Set this value to 'Y' to enable column encryption for the Always Encrypted feature of SQL Server.
						This will add the string "ColumnEncryption=Enabled" to the SQL Server connection string.
						For more information on this feature see *[extlink:https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/sql/relational-databases/security/encryption/always-encrypted-database-engine]*.
						The default value of this parameter is 'N'.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5ForceStringsToUTF</name>
					<description>Set this value to 'Y' to disable functions that send data to the database as wide characters (16-bit Unicode).
						Data will instead be bound and passed as multi-byte characters.
						The default value of this parameter is 'N'.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>A5ANSINullPadWarn</name>
					<description>This property is obsolete.
					</description>
				</item>
				<item>   
					<name>A5InitialCommand</name>
					<description>Set this value to the semi-colon delimited list of commands you want to execute after a connection is opened.</description>
				</item>

			</list>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Using Portable SQL with SQL Server</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
				<description>A SQL Server connection automatically selects SQL Server as it's syntax.  
						The SQL Server syntax handler reads table information, and generates DDL (Data Definition Language) such as CREATE TABLE, DROP TABLE and DML (Data Manipulation Language) such as SELECT, INSERT, UPDATE, DELETE.
						It is also responsible for translating AlphaDAO Portable SQL functions into native implementations.   
					</description>
				</case>
				<case>
				<note>The SQL Server syntax handler may be used with the ODBC and ADO.Net drivers as well.
						</note>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
</sections>
	
</page>


