<page build="3922">
    <topic>SQL Server LocalDB</topic>
    <description>LocalDB is a SQL database that is distributed with Alpha Anywhere</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>LocalDB is installed as part of the Alpha Anywhere installer. This means that as soon as Alpha Anywhere has been installed, developers will be able to start building applications that use a SQL database, even if they don't access to a SQL database of their own.</p> 
        <p>When Alpha Anywhere is started, a named instance for LocalDB is automatically created called *[AlphaAnywhere]*.</p>
        <p>To build a connection string to the LocalDB database, use the SQL Server driver and specify the Version as *[xb:2016]* and the Server Name as *[(localDB)\AlphaAnywhere]*.</p>
        <p>When you select a connection string in the various genies and builders, a hyperlink appears at the bottom of the dialog that allows you to automatically create a LocalDB version of the sample *[ui:Northwind]* database that is uses in many of the Alpha Anywhere tutorials and videos. When you click the hyperlink a named connection string called *[xb:AADemo-Northwind]* is created.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/aademo_hyperlink.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Building a SQLLocalDB Connection String</title>
            <description>A custom connection string can be created to LocalDB, either as a named connection using the Create SQL Connection String dialog or defining the connection string dynamically using Xbasic. The settings for building the connection string are shown below:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Setting</name-title>
                    <description-title>Value</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Connection Type</name>
                    <description>SQLServer</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Version</name>
                    <description>2016</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Server</name>
                    <description>(localdb)\AlphaAnywhere</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Login Timeout (in seconds)</name>
                    <description>30</description>
                </item>
            </list>
            <figure>
                <link>images/localdb_config.png</link>
            </figure>
            <note>If LocalDB is not running when a connection is opened, the LocalDB instance must be started. The delay waiting for the instance to start can exceed the default length of time Alpha Anywhere waits for login to complete, resulting in an error message. To avoid the timeout error, set the Login Timeout to at least 30 seconds.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Formatting Server Names for LocalDB</title>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere ships with LocalDB v13.0. You can also connect to other versions of LocalDB. LocalDB ships with a default server name. This server name is separate from the server created by Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                <p>The default server names for specific versions of LocalDB are listed below:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Version</name-title>
                    <description-title>Default Server Name</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SQLLocalDB v11.0</name>
                    <description>(localdb)\v11.0</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SQLLocalDB v12.0</name>
                    <description>(localdb)\MSSQLLocalDB</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SQLLocalDB v13.0</name>
                    <description>(localdb)\MSSQLLocalDB</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <terms>sqllocaldb,sql server,example database,getting started</terms>
    <see>
        <ref link="sql::localdb namespace">SQL::LocalDB Namespace</ref>
    </see>
</page>