<page deprecated="true" api="js">
    <shortlink>corejs dollar n</shortlink>
    <topic>$n Function</topic>
    <description>Get a pointer to elements in the DOM by name.</description>
    <syntax>$n(eleName as string [..., eleName-N as string])</syntax>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>eleName</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>The name of the element(s) to find.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>eleName-n</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>(optional) One or more additional names of the element(s) to find. Separate each name with a comma.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <description>
        <p>The *[js:$n()]* function gets elements in the HTML. It takes an arbitrary number of arguments, each a string with the *[js:eleName]* of the element you wish to get a pointer to.</p>
        <p>Getting elements by name returns an array because the name attribute is used to describe groups of controls - such as radio and checkbox groups. Therefore, even if there is only a single element with the given *[js:eleName]*, it will be returned inside a Javascript array.</p>
        <p>If you pass a single *[js:eleName]*, the function will return a Javascript array of pointers to the elements that match the *[js:eleName]* passed in.</p>
        <p>If you pass it multiple *[js:eleName]*s, the function will return a Javascript array of arrays of the HTML elements.</p>
        <p>If an element with the *[js:eleName]* specified does not exist, the function will automatically look for an element that has a ID of the passed in string, and return it.</p>
    </description>
    <example code="js"><![CDATA[/*Assume that you have two radio buttons with choices 'Male' and 'Female'. Each radio button has a unique ID, but they both have the same NAME, 'gender' */
var genderInputs = $n('gender');

/*Select the first radio button in the group*/
genderInputs[0].checked = true;]]></example>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=ux component getpointer method">{dialog.object}.getPointer Method</ref>
     </see>
</page>