<page>
    <shortlink>howto configure site use https iis</shortlink>
    <topic>How to configure a site to use HTTPS under IIS</topic>
    <description>Multiple version of the Application Server for IIS can be installed on one system for a single license. This allows you to test new releases or deploy multiple applications running on different versions of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Request and Install a Certificate from a Certificate Authority</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>IIS Manager can be used to create a certificate request and then install the certificate with complete a certificate request. These
						option are located under the &quot;Server Certificates&quot; feature in IIS Manager</p>
                    </description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the server node in the &quot;Connections&quot; pane</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Double click on the &quot;Server Certificates&quot; feature in the center pane in the &quot;IIS&quot; section.</description>
							<figure>
                                <link>images/iisManagerServerNode.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The &quot;Server Certificates&quot; feature will show the available certificates as well as the available action in the &quot;Actions&quot; pane on the right hand side.</description>
							<figure>
                                <link>images/iisManagerServerCertificates.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The certificate authority that you use may have its own way to create a certificate request. If it does, make sure that a &quot;Subject Alternative Name (SAN)&quot; is included in 
							the request. A certificate is required to have the host name in it to define what site the certificate is for. For 
							example &quot;www.alphasoftware.com&quot;. This host name also needs to be included as a Subject Alternative Name in the certificate otherwise 
							browsers may not validate the certificate. The &quot;Create certificate request...&quot; action in IIS Manager does not create a certificate request that 
							includes a Subject Alternative Name. Use the following steps to create a certificate request with a Subject Alternative Name.</description>
							<figure>
                                <link>images/iisManagerServerCertificates.png</link>
                            </figure>
							<steps>
								<step>
									<description>
										Open the machine management console (run MMC.exe).
									</description>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Choose &quot;Add/Remove snap-in...&quot; from the File menu.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestAddSnapin.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Select the &quot;Certificates&quot; snap-in from the left list, click the &quot;Add&quot; button in the middle of the dialog and then choose the &quot;Computer account&quot;. Click through the rest of th wizard to finish.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestAddSnapin.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Open the &quot;Certificates (Local Computer)&quot; node and right click on the &quot;Personal&quot; node, choose &quot;All Tasks&quot;, &quot;Advanced Operations&quot;, &quot;Create Custom Request...&quot;.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestCustomRequest.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Click &quot;Next&quot; then select &quot;Proceed without enrollment policy&quot;. Click &quot;Next&quot;.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestNoEnrollmentPolicy.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Click &quot;Next&quot; with the default on this page.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestCNGkey.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
								<step>
									<description>
										Click the little down arrow next to the word &quot;Details&quot;. Click on the &quot;Properties&quot; button.
									</description>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestCNGkey.png</link>
									</figure>
									<figure>
										<link>images/createCertRequestProperties.png</link>
									</figure>
								</step>
							</steps>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Once you have a certificate, </description>
							<figure>
                                <link>images/iisManagerServerCertificates.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Configure Certificate Used by a Site</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description></description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Select the site in IIS Manager.</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    <links>
        <link link="create a publish profile">Create a Publish Profile</link>
        <link href="https://download.alphasoftware.com/Installer/InstallAlphaAnywhere.exe">Universal Installer</link>
    </links>
</page>