<page>
    <shortlink>howto install multiple versions of iss</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Install Multiple Versions of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS</topic>
    <description>Multiple version of the Application Server for IIS can be installed on one system for a single license. This allows you to test new releases or deploy multiple applications running on different versions of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Install the Application Server to Another Directory</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>To run multiple versions of the Application Server for IIS, each version must be installed in a separate directory. When installing the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS, you can specify a different directory than the default directory as follows:</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Download and run the Full installer for the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the *[ui:Destination Location]* page, click the *[ui:Browse]* button to change the install location.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/iisInstall1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When prompted to choose the installation directory, change the installation directory and click *[ui:OK]*. You must manually type the folder name into the textbox. In the example below, the Application Server for IIS will be installed in "C:\Program Files(x86)\aa_iis_v4_5_5":</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/iisInstall2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <tip>When specifying the folder, using the build number (for pre-release builds) or Alpha Anywhere version (for release builds) in the folder name is helpful to distinguish different versions of Alpha Anywhere. You can locate the Build Number or Alpha Anywhere Version on the download page.</tip>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Finish the installation.</description>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Configure the IIS Publishing Profile</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>If more than one version of Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS is installed, the last one that was installed will set the registry key used by the "Default" location type. To ensure the correct version of Alpha Anywhere is used by a published application, the IIS Publishing Profile must specify the installation location of the version of the Application Server to use on the server.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Create a new IIS Publishing Profile</title>
                    <description>When creating a new IIS Publishing Profile, the version of Alpha Anywhere to use can be specified when configuring the *[ui:Alpha Anywhere Application Server Location]*:</description>
                    <note>Alternatively, you can copy an existing IIS profile. If you copy an existing IIS profile, see "Modify Existing Publishing Profiles" below for instructions on configuring the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS to use.</note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Create a new IIS Publishing Profile. Enter the publish information for your server as you would for a single version of Application Server installed on the server. Be sure to configure the profile with a unique Application Name so each application is published to a different location on the server.</description>
                            <note>For complete instructions on how to create a Publishing Profile for IIS, see [Create a Publish Profile].</note>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the *[ui:Alpha Anywhere Application Server Location]* page, change the Location type to *[ui:Custom]* and specify the path on the server to the installation directory of the version of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS to use.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/iisProfileNew.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Modify Existing Publishing Profiles</title>
                    <description>If you have previously published Alpha Anywhere Applications to the server running the Application Server for IIS, you must update the version of Alpha Anywhere to use. When using the "Default" version, the version of the Application Server for IIS that was installed last will be used. In the case where you add a pre-release build or setup an older version of the Application Server for IIS for testing, existing applications on the server will use the new version added to the server.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Open the existing IIS Publishing Profile for the server that will be running multiple versions of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Change the *[ui:Location of Alpha Anywhere Application Server]* from "Default" to "Custom" and specify the path on the server to the installation directory of the version of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS to use in the *[ui:Path to Alpha Anywhere Application Server]* property.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/iisProfileExisting.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Save the changes to the publishing profile and republish your applications. Repeat as needed for each existing IIS publishing profile.</description>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link link="create a publish profile">Create a Publish Profile</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="howto iis publishing production and test versions">How to Production and Development Versions of Your Web Application to Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS</ref>
    </see>
</page>