<page>
    <shortlink>ux component methods</shortlink>
    <topic>UX Component Methods</topic>
    <description>Properties and methods that can be used on the client-side to interact with UX components.</description>
    <properties>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.ComponentName}</name><description>	Gets replaced with the alias of the UX Component. For example, if the UX alias is 'DLG1', then is replaced with 'DLG1'.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.ControlIdEscaped}</name><description>The control Id of the control. Special characters in the id are Javascript escaped. You must use this placeholder (and not {dialog.ControlId}) if you want to use this placeholder in a selector (such as JQuery - jQuery('#{dialog.controlIDEscaped}') )</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.ControlId}</name><description>The control Id of the control. Note: See comment on {dialog.ControlIDEscaped}.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.EmbeddedCustomComponent_[Alias]}</name><description>Used to get the Object name of an embedded Custom Component. Replace [Alias] with the alias you specified for the embedded Custom Component object.
You can use this placeholder to execute methods on the embedded Custom Component.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.EmbeddedDialog_[UXAlias]}</name><description>Used to get the Object name of an embedded UX Component. Replace [UXAlias] with the alias you specified for the embedded UX object.
You can use this placeholder to execute methods on the embedded UX.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.EmbeddedGrid_[GridAlias]}</name><description>Used to get the Object name of an embedded Grid Component. Replace [GridAlias] with the alias you specified for the embedded Grid object.
You can use this placeholder to execute methods on the embedded Grid.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.listId}</name><description>For use with the List control. Gets replaced with the ID of the current List control.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.object}</name><description>Gets replaced with the name of the Javascript UX Component Object. For example, if the UX alias is 'DLG1', then is replaced with 'DLG1_DlgObj'. Use this placeholder when you want to call a method of the UX Object. e.g. {Dialog.Object}.submit(), to submit the UX to the server.</description></property>
        <property pseudo="true"><name>{dialog.Style}</name><description>Gets replaced with the style name of the UX. For example, if the style is 'GlassOlive', then gets replaced with 'GlassOlive'.</description></property>
    </properties>
    <!--list:.-->
</page>