<page>
   <topic>{dialog.object}.ajaxCallback Method</topic>
   <description>Does an Ajax callback to a server. </description>
  <syntax>{dialog.object}.ajaxCallback(part,rowNum,xbasicFunction [,callbackURL [,additionalData]]);</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
        <name>part</name>
        <description>In a grid component, part indicates the Grid part (Search, Grid, or Detail View) from which data should be submitted. In a UX Component, this parameter is not used and should be an empty string.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
        <name>row</name>
        <description>In a grid component, row indicates the Grid row from which data should be submitted. In a UX Component, this parameter is not used and should be an empty string.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>xBasicFunction</name>
         <description>The name of the Xbasic function you want to call on the server.</description>
     </argument>
    <argument>
      <name>callbackURL</name>
      <description>This parameter is almost always set to a blank string. It can be used to specify the URL you want to call to handle the callback. For example, you could call a .php, or .asp page to handle the callback. If this value is not blank then the setting for xbasicFunction is ignored.</description>
    </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>additionalData</name>
         <description><![CDATA[(optional) - any additional data you want to submit. The data in the controls on the UX Component is automatically submitted. This can be used to submit additional data. Specify a string of name/value pairs. e.g. 'data1=value1&data2=value2']]></description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
 <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.ajaxCallback('','','myAjaxCallback1','','data1=value1&data2=value2');]]></example>

  <sections>
    <section>
     <description>Data from the UX Component is submitted to the server. It is recommended that you use Action Javascript to write the code for you. This can be done by creating an *[ui:Ajax Callback Action]* either as a Javascript Action or as Action Javascript for a control's event.</description> 
      <note>The method has several blank arguments in order to keep the method prototype the same as for the Grid component.</note>
    </section>    
  </sections>
  
  
   <see>
      <ref link="/documentation/index?search={grid.object}.ajaxcallback method">{grid.object}.ajaxCallback Method</ref>
   </see>


<terms>ux component,ajax,ajax callback,function,xbasic</terms>

</page> 
