    <page>
    <topic>{dialog.object}.deleteRecord Method</topic>

    <description>Deletes the current record in the 'primary' table. Applies only to a component that has been bound to one or more tables.</description>
    
    <syntax>{dialog.object}.deleteRecord([options]);</syntax>
    
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>options</name>
            <description>Optional. A JSON object with one or more of the following properties:</description>
            <list>  
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>nextRecordToShow</name>
                    <description>if blank, then the next record in the keylist is shown. if 'newrecord', the new record is shown</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>confirmation</name>
                    <description>true/false - controls if the confirmation dialog is shown</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>serverSideCanDeleteFunction</name>
                    <description>name of the Xbasic function to call before the delete is executed</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>serverSideAfterDeleteFunction</name>
                    <description>name of the Xbasic function to call after the delete is executed</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    
    <discussion>
        <p>Applies only to a component that has been bound to one or more tables. Deletes the current record in the 'primary' table. (If the component is bound to a single table, the 'primary' table is the table to which the component is bound. However, if the component is bound to multiple (linked) tables, the 'primary' table is the top-most parent table of the linked tables.)</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
        <note>*[IMPORTANT]* This action can only be used if you have loaded primary keys for the primary table. You can load primary keys using the 'Get Primary Keys for Parent Table' server-side action in the onDialogInitialize event, or in an Ajax callback, using the 'Get Primary Key values for Records in a Query' action in Action Javascript. </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>After the record is deleted, focus will move to the next record in the primary key list that has been loaded.</p>
                <p>A confirmation dialog will be displayed before the callback is made.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Examples</title>
            <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord();]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To give focus to a new record (not the next record in the key list) after the delete:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord({nextRecordToShow :'newrecord'});]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To delete without displaying the confirmation dialog:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord({confirmation: false});]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    
    
    <see>
        <ref link="Dialog Component">{dialog.object}</ref>
    </see>

    <terms>ux component,ajax,components,confirmation,control,delete,function,list,load primary keys,move,new record,object,primary key,record,xbasic</terms>


    </page> 
