<page api="js" build="5303">
    <shortlink>ux component actionsheet method</shortlink>
    <topic>{dialog.object}.actionSheet Method</topic>
    <description>Displays an Action Sheet.</description>
    <prototypes>
        <prototype>{dialog.object}.actionSheet(menu [, width]);</prototype>
    </prototypes>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>menu</name>
            <type>array of arrays</type>
            <description>A Javascript array of arrays that defines the menu and the actions associated with each menu item. Each array within the outer array defines a menu group. Each item within the nested arrays is an object that defines either a menu item, or a comment. The objects have an *[js:html]* property and an optional *[js:action]* property. If an item does not have an *[js:action]* property is is a label. The action property is a Javascript function to call when the menu item is tapped. See example below.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument optional="true">
            <name>width</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>Defines the width of the action sheet. Expressed in absolute CSS units (e.g. '300px'). If omitted, the Action Sheet is the full width of the device.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <discussion>
        <p>A common user interface design in iOS mobile applications is the Action Sheet. An action sheet is a series of menu options that animates into display from the bottom of the screen. The menu can be divided into logical sections, as shown in the image below.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/actionsheet.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[js:{dialog.object}.actionSheet]* method can be used to display an Action Sheet.</p>
                <p>The following Javascript produces the Action Sheet shown in the image above</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var menu = [
    [
        {html: 'This is the help text above the Action Sheet. It does not have an action'},
        {html: 'Save', action: function(){alert('save');}},
        {html: 'Save As...', action: function(){alert('saveas');} }
    ],
    [
        {html: 'New', action: function(){alert('new')}},
        {html: 'Open...', action: function(){alert('open');}}
    ],
    [
        {html: 'Cancel', action: function(){alert('cancel');}}
    ]
];

{dialog.object}.actionSheet(menu);]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="">Action Javascript: ActionSheet</ref>
    </see>
</page>