<page api="js" build="5221">
    <shortlink>ux component phonegapunzipfiles method</shortlink>
    <topic parent="{dialog.object}" parentType="object" elementName="phoneGapUnzipFiles Method">{dialog.object}.phoneGapUnzipFiles Method</topic>
    <description>Unzip files on a mobile device built with PhoneGap.</description>
    <prototypes>
        <prototype>{dialog.object}.phoneGapUnzipFiles(explicitFilenameURI, filesystemSource, folderSource, zipFileName, fileSystemTarget, dirStructureTarget, onSuccess, onError, flagListUnzippedFiles)</prototype>
    </prototypes>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>explicitFilenameURI</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the fully qualified URI for the source zip file. This is an alternative to specifying the filesystemSource, folderSource and zipFileName . If you specify the filesystemSource, folderSource and zipFileName then you can set the explicitFilenameURI to a blank value.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>filesystemSource</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the file system part (e.g. 'temp', 'saved' etc) where the zip file is located</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>folderSource</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the folder where the zip file is located</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>zipFileName</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the zip filename (e.g. zipfile1.zip)</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>fileSystemTarget</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the file system part where the files should be unzipped (e.g. 'temp', 'saved' etc.)</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>dirStructureTarget</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>the directory structure in the target file system part where the files should be unzipped. If the directory structure does not exist, it will be created.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>onSuccess</name>
            <type>function</type>
            <description>callback function if files are successfully unzipped. If *[js:flagListUnzippedFiles]* is true, the callback function can reference *[js:filesArray]* - an array of all of the files that where unzipped</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>onError</name>
            <type>function</type>
            <description>callback function if the unzip action fails</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>flagListUnzippedFiles</name>
            <type>boolean</type>
            <description>true or false. If true, the *[js:onSuccess]* function is called with an array of files that were unzipped. If false, the onSuccess function is not called with any arguments.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[js:.phoneGapUnzipFiles()]* method can be used to unzip files in a PhoneGap application. The method includes arguments to specify the file system part and folder where the source zip file located, the file system part where you want the unzipped files to be placed and optionally can call the onSuccess callback function with an array that contains the files that were unzipped.</p>
    </discussion>
</page>