<page build="4223">
    <shortlink>ux properties publish data to client side property</shortlink>
    <topic>Publish data to client-side</topic>
    <description>Specify that all data series data should be published client-side, making it available in offline applications and client-side JavaScript.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p></p>
        <p>You define Date Series either by clicking on the [...] smart field for the Data Series property (on the UX Builder Properties pane), or by click on the Menu button.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Use the Menu button to define a Data Series.</title>
                <link>images/dataseries1.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The [Data series] UX Component property is used to create data series definitions.</title>
                <link>images/dataseries2.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Your Javascript code can reference the data in a Data Series using the following syntax:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.SeriesName.SubSeriesName]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If the Data Series has no sub-series, then syntax for referencing the Data Series is:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.SeriesName]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Understanding Data Series</title>
            <description>
                <p>A Data Series is a series of values. Say you have a SQL query that returns the data shown in the table below.</p>
                <p>Each column in the table is a series of data. For example, the data series in the first Firstname column is</p>
            </description>
            <example>Fred, Jane, Susan</example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <table>
                    <tr><th>Firstname</th><th>Lastname</th><th>Age</th></tr>
                    <tr><td>Fred</td><td>Smith</td><td>23</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Jane</td><td>Jones</td><td>35</td></tr>
                    <tr><td>Susan</td><td>Ganon</td><td>29</td></tr>
                </table>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The name of the Data Series represented by the first column in the above table is:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[Names.Firstname]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>(where '*[js:Names]*' is the arbitrary name given to the data table)</p>
                <p>A common use case for Data Series is in charting applications. Both the Chart and Javascript Chart control in the UX component consume data series for the data shown in the charts.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux properties data series property">Data series</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
</page>