<page>
    <shortlink>transform faq</shortlink>
    <topic>Frequently Asked Questions</topic>
    <description>TransForm FAQ</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>How do I invite users to my account?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Log in to TransForm Central. Then click the Home tab at the top. From the list of choices, choose Invite Users To Join a TransForm Account. On screen instructions will show you what to do.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>I Forgot My Password. What Should I Do?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Go to transform.alphasoftware.com. (Click the logout button if you are already logged in.) Click the Forgot Your Password link to reset your password. The new password is used both by TransForm Central and the TransForm mobile application.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where Do I Find the Mobile Application?</title>
            <description>
                <p>The TransForm Mobile Application is available for both iOS and Android. Do a search for "Alpha TransForm" in either the Apple App Store or Google Play. Once Alpha TransForm is installed, simply launch the app and login with your user name and password.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>What Account Privileges Can I Give to Other Users?</title>
            <description>
                <p>As the owner of your account, you can decide who gets to design forms, who gets to fill in forms, which forms a particular user has access to, and who gets to view the data. You can also assign someone else to be the Account Administrator. These privileges are called "roles," and you can assign them by logging in to TransForm Central. Click the Home tab, then click Manage User Roles.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where do I Enter My License Number?</title>
            <description>
                <p>The license number(s) you buy from the Alpha Software store are entered in TransForm Central. Click the Home tab, then click Account License Keys.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where do I Buy a License Number?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha TransForm licenses are available in the *[extlink:Alpha Software Store@https://www.alphasoftware.com/transform-quick-start-trial]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Design and Deploy a New Form?</title>
            <description>
                <p>To create and deploy new forms, log in to TransForm Central and click the Designer Tab at the Top of the page. Then click the + button to add a new Form Type. Choose either Copy Shared to start with a predefined template or click Add Blank to create a new form design from scratch. Follow the on screen prompts.</p>
                <p>When you are done, click the link labeled "Click To Save Changes" to save the form to the server. To use the new form on a mobile device, you will need to download it. See [How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How do I Create a New Form Using a Template?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Forms in TranForm Cental can be created by coping built-in templates on the Design tab:</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>In TransForm Central, open the Designer tab.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the + add button to add a new form. Then, click "Select Template".</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>A list of templates will be shown. Select the template you would like to use to create a new form. Then click "Copy Selected".</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Finally, click "Click to save changes" to save your new form.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Open the TransForm Mobile App and Log In. Click the Add Form tab, then click Refresh Definitions.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How Do I Review the Data Submitted in TransForm?</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can view the data collected in the TransForm app by logging into TransForm Central. Once you have logged in, click the Management Console tab.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>I added a new form type but I don't see it on the Management Console. How do I refresh the Form Types list on the Management Console?</title>
            <description>
                <p>To refresh the Types of Forms list on the Management Console, click the "refresh" link located at the bottom of the list.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>/images/mcRefreshFormTypesList.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>What is TPL?</title>
            <description>
                <p>TPL (TransForm Programming Language) is a traditional programming language tuned to the needs of TransForm forms.</p>
                <p>TPL code is used in TransForm in two main ways: Standalone expressions to calculate values for display or condition testing and multi-line functions to respond to events such as field value changes or to be called in expressions or other functions. </p>
                <p>To learn more, visit the [TransForm Programming Language Overview].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How do I open the TPL Code Editor for a Form Type?</title>
            <description>
                <p>In order to add TPL to events for fields or buttons, you must enable custom code for the form type. To do this, go to the Designer tab, select the form design to wish to customize, click *[ui:Advanced Features]* to display the advanced options for the form type. Locate the *[ui:Enable custom code for this form type]* property and select "Yes". Finally, click the *[ui:Edit Custom Code]* link to open the TPL Code Editor.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How do I add custom code to a button in my Form Type?</title>
            <description>
                <p>Custom code can be called when the user taps an Action Button in the form.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App?">How Do I Download New Form Types in the Mobile App</link>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Heading%20Template">Heading Template</link>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Heading%20Template">Heading Templates</link>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Listing%20Template">Listing Template</link>
        <link link="transform%20designer%20formtypeproperties#section1_Listing%20Template">Listing Templates</link>
        <link link="transform%20getfieldsinform%20method">GetFieldsInForm method</link>
        <link link="transform designer formtypeproperties#section1_Initialization Commands">Initialization Commands</link>
        <link link="transform designer commandtypes#section2_Initialization">Initialization</link>
        <link link="tpl overview">TransForm Programming Language Overview</link>
    </links>
</page>