<page>
	<topic>Configure Desktop Web Users Form Dialog
</topic>
	<description>Obsolete. The Configure Desktop Web Users Form dialog allows you to design the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog that is used to maintain the list of users of your web applications.
To open this dialog:</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<warning>OBSOLETE.</warning>
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Display the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Right click on the right window (which lists pages and components) and select Security > Security Settings.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Web Properties button in the Security Tables > User Table Configure Desktop Access property. 
</description>
				</step>
			</steps>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Record List Browse Properties</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Field List</title>
					<description>This property defines the fields to display in the user list. Click the web properties button to display the Select User Table. If your user table has additional field (above the minimum), this dialog allows you to display them.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Filter</title>
					<description>This property defines which user records will be displayed. By default, the filter is NULL (equivalent to ".T."), which displays all user records. Optionally, click web properties button to display the Expression Builder to help you define an expression that returns a logical value.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Order</title>
					<description>This property defines the order in which user records will be displayed. Optionally, click the web properties button to display the Order Builder to help you define an expression that returns a character value that refers to one or more table fields.</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Configure Main Form</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Form Title</title>
					<description>This property defines the title of the Configure Desktop Web Users form.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Title for User List Section</title>
					<description>This property defines the title to use for the frame around the list of users.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Title for User Edit Section</title>
					<description>This property defines the title to use for the frame around the controls that allow editing of user information.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Save Error Message</title>
					<description>This property defines message displayed in the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog to tell the user to save or cancel changes to a user security record.</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Button Text</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Save Button</title>
					<description>This property defines the label of the save button on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>New Button</title>
					<description>This property defines the label of the new button on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Cancel Button</title>
					<description>This property defines the label of the cancel button on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Close Button</title>
					<description>This property defines the label of the close button on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Field Titles</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>User ID Field</title>
					<description>This property defines the title of the User ID control on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Password Field</title>
					<description>This property defines the title of the Password control on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.</description>
				</case>
					<case>
					<title>Permissions</title>
					<description>This property defines the label of the Permissions button on the Enter/Edit Web Users? dialog.
</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.
</limitations>
	
	
</page>