<page>
	<topic>Defining Page Security</topic>
<description>OBSOLETE. The third step when implementing the web security framework is to define which of your pages will fall into these three categories:
</description>	
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>pages that web users can never open (Always Denied)
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>pages that web users can open without login (Always Allowed)
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>pages that web users can open after successful login (Login Required)
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<warning>OBSOLETE</warning>
	</section>
	<section>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Display the Web Projects Control Panel.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Click Web Security to display the Web Security dialog.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Select Page Security and click OK to display the Page Security Assignment dialog. This dialog initially lists all your pages except any pages listed as redirect pages in the left-most Always Denied column. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Page_Security_1.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Procedures</title>
		<description>Initially, all pages are listed under Always Denied. To make one or more pages available without login:
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select the pages in the Always Denied list and click Move Next button to move them to the Always Allowed list.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>You may also select the pages in the Login Required list and click Move previous to move them to the Always Allowed list.
</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		<note>If you disable the security framework, all pages will be available without login.</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>To make one or more pages unavailable:
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select the pages in the Login Required and click Move Previous button to move them to the Always Denied list.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Select the pages in the Always Allowed and click Move Previous button to move them to the Always Denied list.
</description>
			</step>
				
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>To define access privileges for one or more pages that requires login.
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, select one or more pages in the Login Required list.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, select a single page and click Select All Pages with the Same Permissions as the Current Page.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Optionally, select a single page and click Select All Pages with Differerent Permissions than the Current Page.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Click Set Permissions for Selected Pages to display the Permissions dialog.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>All pages listed in Login Required must have one or more groups assigned. 
</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>To control access to certain file types:
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Click Files Allowed by Type. to display the Files by Type List dialog.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Clear the check mark from any file type that you wish to prevent users from accessing.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Click OK to continue.
</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Setting Permission for a Single Page 
</title>
		<description>You can set the permission for a single page from the right click menu on the Web Projects Control Panel:
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select the name of a page in the list on the Web Projects Control Panel.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>Right click to open the right click menu. 
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>If the name selected is a a5w, htm, or html page, the menu will show an option for Page Security.
</description>
<figure><link>images/WP_Page_Right_Click_Security.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
			
			<step>
				<description>Select Page Security and the permission level desired.
</description>
			</step>
				<step>
				<description>If Requires Login is selected, the Permissions dialog will display.
</description>
			</step>
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.
</limitations>
<see>
	<ref>Web Application Security Framework</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>