<page>
	<topic>Webform Button Template Builder</topic>
<description>The Cascading Style Sheets of the Web Component Builder include buttons. In addition, there are multiple button templates that you can use in the Webform Button Genie. The buttons in the style sheets are specific implementations of the button templates. If none of these buttons or templates satisfies your requirements, you may create your own button templates.</description>	
	<sections>
<section>
	<warning>Obsolete</warning>
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Creating a New Template
</title>
<description>Good practice is to make all buttons the same height and width.
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the Webform Button Genie click Make Template to display the Webform Button Template Builder.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Initially, none of the 7 buttons at the top of the screen are defined. Your new template will presumably use all seven buttons, but this is not required.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select theFirst tab.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the design mode button to the left of the Foreground window. This displays the XPM Painter. Design the foreground of your graphic and return to the Webform Button Template Builder.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the design mode button to the left of the Background window. Fill the background of your graphic with the background design and return to the Webform Button Template Builder.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Switch to theLast tab.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the Paste button to the left of the Foreground window and select the First icon.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the Align Width button to flip the image horizontally.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the Paste button to the left of the Background window and select the First icon.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Use variations of these techniques to create your set of buttons.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>

	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Saving a Template
</title>
<description>Click the save button to save a work in progress.
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>To make a completed template available in the Webform Button Genie.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Display theOther tab.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Enter a name for the template in the Name field.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Click the save record button to Add Template to Library.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
</steps>

	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Repositioning a Foreground Image
</title>
<description>This short tutorial shows some of the features of the Webform Button Template Builder and XPM Painter.
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>While in theWebform Button Template Builder click the folder button Load Template.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select "capsol.a5_wf_nb_temp" and click Open.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select theNext tab. You will notice that the button has an image in the Background window, but no image in the Foreground window.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the design mode button to the left of the Foreground window. The background image size is 20 x 14 pixels. Enter these dimensions and click OK to display the XPM Painter. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WP_Button_template_builder_1.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the XPM paint icon and the arrow color. Create an arrow pointing to the right. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WP_Button_template_builder_2.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If your picture was placed too far to the left, you could reposition it by decreasing the left offset from 13 to 10. 
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to return to the Webform Button Template Builder. You can now see your new arrow design in the Foreground window. </description>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Button_template_builder_4.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>The following are pictures of the background and composite images. </description>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Button_template_builder_6.gif</link></figure>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Button_template_builder_5.gif</link></figure>
	
	
	</step>
	
</steps>

	
</section>		
				
	</sections>
	
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.
</limitations>
<see>
	<ref>Web Component Builder
</ref>
</see>	
	
	
</page>