<page>
    <shortlink>ux list detail view after synchronize record server side</shortlink>
    <topic>After synchronize record</topic>
    <description>An Xbasic function that is called after the data for each composite record is synchronized.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <important>Only applies to the top-most (parent) List control in a hierarchy of linked Lists with pre-fetched data.</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/afterSynchRecord.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Called after a composite record has been synchronized. A 'composite' record is the parent record and all of the linked child records.</p>
                <p>This event must be defined for the top-most parent List for a List hierarchy. For example, if your UX has a List showing Customers and a child List showing Orders (and if the child List is set to pre-fetch data), this event must be defined for the Customer List. Defining this event for the Orders List is meaningless.</p>
                <p>This event only fires if there were no synchronization errors (i.e. server-side validation, write conflict, or database errors.)</p>
                <p>This event is not called if a user defined synchronization is performed using the [On synchronize] event.</p> 
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <pages>
                <page>
                    <arguments>
                        <argument>
                            <name>e</name>
                            <type>P</type>
                            <description></description>
                            <properties>
                                <property>
                                    <name>data</name>
                                    <type>C</type>
                                    <description>The composite record data (which includes additional properties added during the processing of the data)</description>
                                </property>
                                <property optional="true">
                                    <name>javascript</name>
                                    <type>C</type>
                                    <description>Your code can optionally send back Javascript by setting the e.javascript property.</description>
                                </property>
                            </properties>
                        </argument>
                    </arguments>
                </page>
            </pages>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux list detail view on synchronize server side">On synchronize</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="BuildingDisconnectedApplications">List Control Overview : Building Disconnected Applications</ref>
    </see>
</page>