<page api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 listbox setgroupcollapse method</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.ListBox" parentType="class" elementName="setGroupCollapse Method" >A5.ListBox.setGroupCollapse Method</topic>
	<prototype>A5.ListBox.setGroupCollapse(group[,state[,animate]])</prototype>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name>group</name>
			<types><type>string</type><type>object</type></types>
			<description>The name of the group or an object containing details on multiple groups to collapse or expand. If auto grouping is being used and more then on level of grouping is defined, then an the group name will be a concatinated string that includes all parent group names joined by a period. For example "USA.D" for sub-group "D" in group "USA".</description>
		<properties>
			<property>
				<name>groups</name>
				<type>string</type>
				<description>Which groups to collapse or expand if multiple groups are being effected. Values can be "all", "level" or "match". If "all" is selected then all groups will be expanded or collapsed. If "level" is selected then only groups at the given level will be collapsed. If "match" is selected then each groups will be passed to a function to choose whether or not it matches the criterea.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>level</name>
				<type>number</type>
				<description>If "groups" is equal to "level" then the level of groups to collapse or expand.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>match</name>
				<type>function(name,data)</type>
				<description>If "groups" is equal to "match" then the function to choose which groups to collapse or expand.</description>
				<arguments>
					<argument>
						<name>name</name>
						<type>string</type>
						<description>The name of the group.</description>
					</argument>
					<argument>
						<name>data</name>
						<type>object</type>
						<description>The item data for the group.</description>
					</argument>
				</arguments>
			</property>
		</properties>
		</argument>
		<argument optional="true" >
			<name>state</name>
			<types><type>boolean</type><type>null</type></types>
			<description>If true is passed in then the group will be collapsed, otherwise the group will be expanded. If no value (or null) is passed in then the group state will be toggled.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument optional="true" >
			<name>animate</name>
			<type>boolean</type>
			<description>If true is passed in then the collapsing or expanding of the group will be done with animation.</description>
		</argument>
	</arguments>
	<description> Set the collapse state of a group.</description>
	<example code="js">
// To get a pointer to the A5.ListBox class see {dialog.object}.getControl
// assume lObj is a pointer to an instance of the A5.ListBox class, and the list has multiple levels of auto grouping
lObj.setGroupCollapse(['B',1],true); // set the group with the name "B" in the second level of grouping to be false</example>
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/ListBox_class/A5.ListBox.setGroupCollapse Method.xml</annotations>
</page>
