<page api="js">
    <shortlink>list object addTableRow method</shortlink>
    <topic>listObj.addTableRow Method</topic>
    <syntax>listObj.addTableRow(data [,options]);</syntax>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>data</name>
            <type>JSON Object</type>
            <description>An object with the values in the List that you want to set.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument optional="true">
            <name>options</name>
            <type>JSON Object</type>
            <description>An object with optional settings. The options object can contain these properties:</description>
            <properties>
                <property optional="true">
                    <name>setFocusToTargetRow</name>
                    <type>boolean</type>
                    <description>true/false - If true, then focus will be given to the target row. The default for this property is false.</description>
                </property>
                <property optional="true">
                    <name>insertRow</name>
                    <type>boolean</type>
                    <description>true/false -- Default false. Set to true if you want to insert at a specified position in the List rather than at the end. (Requires build 4444 or above)</description>
                </property>
                <property optional="true">
                    <name>insertPosition</name>
                    <type>number|string</type>
                    <description>If options.insertRow is true, specify where in the List the new row should be inserted. options.insertPosition can either be a number or a string. If it is a number, it represents a zero based row number in the List where the new record will be inserted. If it is a string it represents the List value where the new row will be inserted.</description>
                </property>
            </properties>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <description>Adds a row of data to a List with a Detail View.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Adds a new row of data to a List that has a Detail View. By default, the new row is added at the end of the List, but you can add the new row (i.e. insert the row) at any position by setting options.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example><![CDATA[//create a data object with values for the columns in the List you want to edit
var data = {};
data.FIRSTNAME = 'Cecelia';
data.LASTNAME = 'Longwood';

//define optional settings
var ops = {};
ops.setFocusToTargetRow = true;

//get a pointer to the List control and then call the .addTableRow() method
var listObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('CUSTOMERLIST')
listObj.addTableRow(data,ops);

//insert the new row at position 3 (zero based)
var ops = {};
ops.setFocusToTargetRow = true;
ops.insertRow = true;
ops.insertPosition = 3;
listObj.addTableRow(data,ops);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Contrast the *[js:.addTableRow()]* method with the List object's *[js:.appendRows()]* method.</p>
                <p>The *[js:.addTableRow()]* method is the programmatic equivalent of the user entering some values into the List Detail view controls and then clicking on the Save button to save their changes back to the List. When the user does this, the List becomes dirty and the edits that have been made to the list can be synchronized with the server.</p>
                <p>The *[js:.appendRows()]* method is a low level method that adds the data to the List, but this method does not add the necessary information to the List to cause the List row that was added to become dirty. The new row *[cannot]* be synchronized with the server.</p>
            </description>
            <note>To programmatically update a table row see the *[js:.updateTableRow()]* method.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>List Control with Detail View Part</limitations>
    <see>
        <ref link="list object updateTableRow method">listObj.updateTableRow()</ref>
        <ref link="buildingdisconnectedapplications">List Control Overview</ref>
    </see>
</page>