<page>
	<topic>User-Defined Functions</topic>

	
<description>It is also possible to define and use functions of your own.</description>	

<sections>
<section>
	<title>Discussion</title>
	<description>While Xbasic offers many powerful functions, it is also possible to define and use functions of your own. Alpha Anywhere lets you create two different kinds of user-defined functions. A local user defined function can be called from anywhere within the script in which it is declared. A global (or public) user defined function can be used anywhere in Alpha Anywhere, including in expressions for calculated fields on forms, and indexes.
For more information on local user-defined functions, see the FUNCTION statement description.

Note : Function names should begin with a letter (A-Z, a-z) and may contain numbers and underscore (_) characters. Although the use of the period (.) character is not prohibited, it may not be supported in future releases of Alpha Anywhere. See Also Parameters that Can be Passed to Global Functions, Global Scripts, Passing Variables by Reference, Defining a Function with Optional Pointer Variables
</description>
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	
	<title>Global User Defined Functions</title>
<description>Alpha Anywhere allows you to create global functions (also called User Defined Functions (UDFs) in some languages). Alpha Anywhere comes with many built in functions, such as TRIM(), SUBSTR()etc. These functions can be used in any Alpha Anywhere expression. For example, a calculated field might be defined with this expression. Trim(firstname) + " " + lastname.

Global Functions allow you to define your own functions, which can be used in Alpha Anywhere expressions just like the built in Alpha Anywhere functions. Global Functions are written in Xbasic. Here is an example of a simple Global Function:
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[function fullname as C (first as C, last as C)
    fullname = trim(first) + " " + last
end function ]]></example>	
</section>

<section>
<description>To use this Global Function in an expression (assuming that the first name field was called FN and that the last name field was called LN ), you would type:
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[fullname(fn, ln)]]></example>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>How to Define a Global Function
</title>
<description>To define a global function, select the Code tab on the Control Panel and click the New button. Check Function on the New Object dialog box. In the next dialog box, specify the function name, the data type that the function returns, and the operands that the function accepts. You can also define functions with optional operands. For each operand, you must specify the type. When you press the OK button, Alpha Anywhere displays the script editor with a code skeleton filled in describing the function.
For example, assume you defined a function called shipping_charge as a numeric function, with the following operands:
</description>	
	<list>
		<item>
			<name-title>Variable</name-title>
			<description-title>Type</description-title>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>state</name>
			<description>character</description>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>weight</name>
			<description>numeric</description>
		</item>
		
		
	</list>
</section>
<section>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere will create the following Xbasic skeleton for you in the Scripts tab of the Code Editor :
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[function shipping_charge as N (state as C, weight as N)
    'type your code here
end function
 ]]></example>
</section>

<section>
	<description>You will then need to enter the Xbasic code that defines this Global Function where the comment "type your code here" appears. To have the function return a value, assign the value to the function name in the Xbasic code. For example:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[order_total = order_amount + shipping_charge("NY", 3.5)
function shipping_charge as N (state as C, weight as N)
    'type your code here
    if (state = "MA") Then
        shipping_charge = 0
    else
        shipping_charge = weight * 2.5
    end if
end function ]]></example>
</section>
<section>
	<description>See the description of the FUNCTION command statement for more information on creating Global Functions, including information on how to define functions with optional operands.
</description>
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Optional Parameters</title>
	<description>If you want to make a parameter optional, provide a default value in the function definition. For example the following function sets the default value of state to "MA":
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[function shipping_charge as N ( order_total as N, state = "MA", weight as N)
    'type your code here
    if (state = "MA") Then
        shipping_charge = 0
    else
        shipping_charge = weight * 2.5
    end if
end function ]]></example>
<note>If you want to assign a NULL value to an optional parameter, you may use the NULL_VALUE() function.</note>
</section>

<section>
	<description>For example:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[FUNCTION ImALittleFunction as L ( EquipmentNum as C, tablePointer = NULL_VALUE()) ]]></example>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<description>If a function receives an optional pointer parameter, you can test whether you have received a value by using the TYPEOF() function. It will return "Z" for a NULL value.
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[function myfunc as l (optional_pointer = null_value() as p)
if typeof(optional_pointer) = "Z" then 
    'no optional_pointer was passed into this function call 
end if 

end function ]]></example>
	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>How to Share Global Functions
</title>
<description>You can use the global functions that you define in one database in another database. For example, while using a database called Invoice, you might have created the following global functions: FULLNAME(), INVOICE_TOTAL(), and SHIPPING_CHARGE(). Assume that you are now working in another database, called Inventory, for example, and you want to have access to the Global Functions that were defined for the Invoice database. To access these global functions, you can attach the library from the Invoice database to the Inventory database.
To attach an external library:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Give focus to the Control Panel.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select File > Database properties.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the Libraries tab.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Add the new library.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Restriction on the Use of Global Functions
</title>
<description>Global functions can be used anywhere in Alpha Anywhere where expressions are allowed. However, there are restrictions on the Xbasic code that the global function executes. For example, you might have defined a global function named OpenForm() that opens a form. You could use this global function in a push event for a button on a form, but you could not use this global functions in an index expression.
</description>	
	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Multiple Functions in a Single Script
</title>
<description>You may have multiple functions in a single script. However, only the function that shares the script name will be externally available. Consider the following script named global_function. Scripts through-out the application may call global_function, but only global_function may call local_function1() and local_function2(). 
</description>	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Global
</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<example><![CDATA[Function global_function as v (argument as c) ]]></example>
				</case>
				<case>
					
			<description>...code</description>

		</case>
				<case>
					<example><![CDATA[end function ]]></example>
				</case>
			</cases>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Available only to global_function()</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<example><![CDATA[function local_function1 as N ()
 ]]></example>
				</case>
					<case>
						<description>...code
</description>
					<example><![CDATA[end function
 ]]></example>
				</case>
					<case>
						<description>function local_function2 as c (args as P)
</description>
					<example><![CDATA[...code
 ]]></example>
				</case>
				<case>
					<example><![CDATA[end function ]]></example>
				</case>
			</cases>
			
			
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>






</sections>




<see>
	
	<ref>Xbasic Language Reference</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>