<page>
	<topic>Editing Properties</topic>
<description></description>	
	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Field validation setting</title>
	<description>The  video demonstrates Alpha Five Version 10's awesome agile development process in action. 
Late last week, Alpha customer Bob Moore made the request for a field validation feature in Alpha Five Version 10, and within an hour, our developers had it up and running. 
It doesn't get much better than that. 
Have a look at what Bob put together using this new field validation feature, and let us know what you think. 
What features do you want to see in Alpha Five?</description>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>New Records Edit Style</title>
	<description>The New records edit style property has two options. The first, AlwaysShown, always shows a row for entering a new record in an updateable grid. The second, ShowOnDemand, creates a link that replaces the edit row. Clicking the link will reveal or hide the new record row on demand. 
</description>
<figure><title>AlwaysShown setting
</title><link>images/01_Alwaysshow.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><title>ShowOnDemand creates a New Records link
</title><link>images/01_Alwaysshow2.png</link></figure>	
</section>


<section>
	<title>Row Edit Style</title>
	<description>The Row edit style  property comes with two options, AllRows  and RowOnDemand . Selecting the 'AllRows' option will cause an updateable grid to open with all rows in edit mode. Selecting the 'RowOnDemand' option will open the grid in view mode. A row can then be placed into edit mode either by clicking the 'Edit row' icon, or by double clicking on a field. If you double click on a field, initial focus will be on the field.  
</description>
<figure><title>AllRows in Edit Mode
</title><link>images/01_aupdate.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><title>RowOnDemand in View Mode
</title><link>images/01_aupdate2.png</link></figure>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>One edit row at a time
</title>
	<description>The One edit row at a time  property appears when the Row Edit Style  property is set to RowOnDemand . If this is checked, it will allow only one row at a time to be in edit mode. Multiple rows can be placed in edit mode if this is not selected. 
</description>
<figure><title>RowOnDemand. Only one row can be edited at a time.
</title><link>images/01_aupdate3.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	

	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>