<page>
	<topic>Editing Properties</topic>
<description></description>	
	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Field validation setting</title>
	<description>The  video demonstrates Alpha Five Version 10's awesome agile development process in action. 
Late last week, Alpha customer Bob Moore made the request for a field validation feature in Alpha Five Version 10, and within an hour, our developers had it up and running. 
It doesn't get much better than that. 
Have a look at what Bob put together using this new field validation feature, and let us know what you think. 
What features do you want to see in Alpha Five?</description>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>New Records Edit Style</title>
	<description>The New records edit style property has two options. The first, AlwaysShown, always shows a row for entering a new record in an updateable grid. The second, ShowOnDemand, creates a link that replaces the edit row. Clicking the link will reveal or hide the new record row on demand. 
</description>
<figure><title>AlwaysShown setting
</title><link>images/01_Alwaysshow.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><title>ShowOnDemand creates a New Records link
</title><link>images/01_Alwaysshow2.png</link></figure>	
</section>


<section>
	<title>Row Edit Style</title>
	<description>The Row edit style  property comes with two options, AllRows  and RowOnDemand . Selecting the 'AllRows' option will cause an updateable grid to open with all rows in edit mode. Selecting the 'RowOnDemand' option will open the grid in view mode. A row can then be placed into edit mode either by clicking the 'Edit row' icon, or by double clicking on a field. If you double click on a field, initial focus will be on the field.  
</description>
<figure><title>AllRows in Edit Mode
</title><link>images/01_aupdate.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><title>RowOnDemand in View Mode
</title><link>images/01_aupdate2.png</link></figure>	
</section>

<section>
	<description>With the 'Edit On Demand' option, the Grid is shown as using labels for each control. You can then double click on a field, or click the Edit icon, to turn that row into edit mode. You can specify if more than one row at a time can be in edit mode. If only one row is allowed in edit mode at a time, then when you put another row into edit mode, the row that is currently in edit mode is turned back into view mode.
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<figure><title>All rows are editable (V9 and older style)</title><link>images/allrowseditable.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<figure><title>Grid rows are editable on demand</title><link>images/EditonDemand.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<figure><title>Row 1 of the Grid has been put into edit mode</title><link>images/OneRowInEditMode.jpg</link></figure>
			
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</section>




<section>
	<title>One edit row at a time
</title>
	<description>The One edit row at a time  property appears when the Row Edit Style  property is set to RowOnDemand . If this is checked, it will allow only one row at a time to be in edit mode. Multiple rows can be placed in edit mode if this is not selected. 
</description>
<figure><title>RowOnDemand. Only one row can be edited at a time.
</title><link>images/01_aupdate3.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Show Row Errors in a Pop-up Window</title>
	<description>By default, when you submit a Grid and the server determines that there are errors in the data, the errors are either shown next to the field(s) that have errors, or in the case of 'row-level' errors, the errors are shown by turning on an error icon in the row selector, which the user can then hover over with the mouse to see the actual error text. This works well if the Grid has a tabular display. But in the case where the Grid is formatted as a Form, if the form has a large number of fields, the error icon can be too subtle and is easily overlooked. A new option allows you to display 'row-level' errors in a pop-up window.</description>
	
	<videos>
		<video>
			<description>Watch Video  |</description>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V10Videos/RowLevelErrorsInPopupWindow.swf</link>
		</video>
		
	</videos>
	
	
</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>