<page>
    <topic>Form properties</topic>
    <description>Opens the Form View Builder.</description>
    <!--list:.-->

<sections>
    <section>
        <description>A FormView control provides a very efficient way to create editable forms, bot large and small.
            Visually, these forms can be almost anything that can be expressed in HTML. The displayed fields in the 
            form can be made hot so that, when tapped, they bring up the appropriate editor editing the field value, or 
            to do 'editing in place' (such as when acting like a switch). The editors that the forms use are shared - many 
            fields on the form can use the same editor.
        </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>The editors used in a FormView control are contained in editor-sets. An editor-set can 
            contain multiple editors. When the user taps on a field, the associated editor for that field is invoked,
            and the editor-set that contains the selected editor is brought into view. For example, in a mobile phone 
            application (where the screen size is quite small), the editor-set might be in its own Panel Card that 
            animates into view, allowing the field value to be edited. When the edit is completed, the editor-set is closed 
            and the Panel Card that contains the editor-set is animated out of view.
        </description>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>The data source for a FormView control can be a List control, or arbitrary JSON data. In fact, a typical use case for a FormView 
            control, is to construct the DetailView for a List control.
        </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Some advantages of a FormView over creating an equivalent display using individual controls, such as buttons, labels, and textboxes, include:</description>
       <cases>
           <case>
               <description>The FormView HTML and usage of the DOM are usually much lighter weight than standard controls, 
                   resulting in faster performance and less run-time memory usage.</description>
           </case>
           <case>
               <description>The FormView Builder can configure much of the form automatically, or with simple operations that apply to multiple fields at once.</description>
           </case>
           <case>
               <description>It automatically provides lists of fields deduced from the data definitions to help guide you through construction.</description>
           </case>
           <case>
               <description>The use of shared editors can simplify and improve the User Interface and its construction.</description>
           </case>
           <case>
               <description>User Interface features, such as Next/Previous field navigation, are easily implemented.</description>
           </case>
           <case>
               <description>HTML Templating simplifies using HTML code provided by visual designers for both the entire form, or on a field-by-field basis.</description>
           </case>
           
           
       </cases> 
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>The FormView Builder provides flexible functionality for configuring the control with little or no coding. 
            It has separate tabs with dialog boxes for:
        </description>
        <cases>
            <case>
                <description>Specifying the most commonly needed properties of fields including specifying which editor-set and editor 
                    each field should use.
                </description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <description>Creating custom actions when a field is tapped, swiped, etc.</description>
            </case>
            <case>
                <description>Specifying the HTML template to display the form and its fields, with many built-in options for 
                    grouping, handing multiple values, and formatting.
                </description>
            </case>
            
        </cases>
        
    </section>
</sections>
</page>