<page build="4699">
    <shortlink>web security utilities</shortlink>
    <topic>Utilities for the Web Security System</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Used to verify if the defined security tables can be found.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Utilities]* tool is used to verify that the database where web security data is stored can be reached using the defined connection.</p>
        <p>The tool is found in the *[ui:Web Security]* window. It can be opened from the Web Projects Control Panel via the *[ui:[key] Web Security]* toolbar button.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Security Utilities Tool is opened by clicking 'Utilities' in the Web Security dialog.</title>
                <link>images/openUtilities.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If the security system connects to the SQL tables with Active Link tables, the utility has an option to *[ui:Validate Field Maps]*. The action will verify if the field map saved in the Active Link tables map to the correct field names in the SQL table.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/utilities.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The option will only check a single table if one is selected. If a table is selected, the option *[ui:Clear Selected]* will remove the selection and allow checking all tables.</p>
                <p>The option *[ui:Show Connection String]* will show the actual connection string used by a table if the table is selected. The normal configuration would have the same connection for all tables.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/utilities_conn.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Errors cannot be corrected if using Active Link tables, but the utility will show a message on close if any errors were found</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Changes can be made and saved if the security system is using a [DataLink file] in place of Active Link tables. The option to *[ui:Show Connection String]* is still shown, but the option to *[ui:Validate Field Maps]* will open a genie to remap the fields if any errors were found in the existing map. The genie will only allow selecting fields that are of the correct data type and length.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/utilities_tableNotFound.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Change Connection String]* option can be used to change the connection string. When clicked, a list of available connections is shown. Connections for all tables can be changed. The utility will check if the current tables exist in the new connection and will run the validation option if tables with the same names are found.</p>
                <p>The *[ui:Select New Table]* can be used to change the SQL Table used for storing web security values. Clicking the option will display a list of tables available in the target database. When a table is selected, the field map validation will run to allow remapping the fields as needed. *[ui:Select New Table]* can also be used create a new, empty table in the target database.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/utilities_selectTable.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Changes can be saved by the *[ui:Save Changes]* button, which is enabled when any changes are made.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="web application security guide#section1_Use DataLink File">DataLink file</link>
        <link href="/images/$$generic.key.png">key</link>
    </links>
</page>