<page api="xb" build="5271">
    <shortlink>api a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData function</shortlink>
    <topic>a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData Function</topic>
    <description>Generates the JSON to populate an Expanding Menu control from a 'friendly' menu definition.</description>
    <prototypes>
        <prototype>C json =  a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData(C menu )</prototype>
    </prototypes>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>menu</name>
            <type>c</type>
            <description>The friendly menu definition (see description below)</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
	<returns>
		<return>
			<name>json</name>
			<types>
				<type>c</type>
			</types>
			<description>Returns the 'friendly' menu formatted as JSON that can be used to populate an Expanding Menu control.</description>
		</return>
	</returns>
    <discussion>
        <p>The a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData() function can be used to generate the JSON needed to populate an Expanding Menu control from a menu definition that uses a CRLF list of menu entries, with tab indentation to indicate menu hierarchy.</p>
        <p>The menu definition allows you to assign a optional server-side show/hide expression and/or a set of security groups to any menu branch or leaf item. The JSON that is generated will honor the server-side show/hide expressions and security groups. For example, if a menu branch should only be available to someone who is a member of the Administrators group, the generated JSON will not include that branch if the currently logged in user is not in the Administrators group.</p>
        <p>The example below shows a "friendly" menu definition:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="xb" caption="A 'friendly' menu definition"><![CDATA[Alpha
	Alpha1
	Alpha2
		Alpha21
		Alpha22
Beta
	Beta1
Gamma
	Gamma1]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Each item in the menu can be followed by an optional JSON definition. This JSON definition can have these properties (all of which are optional)</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>icon</name>
                            <description>The icon to show to the left of menu item in the Expanding Menu.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>onclick</name>
                            <description>The Javascript code to execute when the menu item is clicked.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>serverSideShowHideExpn</name>
                            <description>The server-side expression. If this expression is false, the menu item is not shown.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>securityGroups</name>
                            <description>A comma delimited list of security groups. If the user is not in one of the security groups, the menu item is not shown.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>The above "friendly" menu definition, using the optional JSON settings string for some of the menu items:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[Alpha{serverSideShowHideExpn: 'session.var1 = "alpha"'}
	Alpha1
	Alpha2
		Alpha21{securityGroups: 'Administrator,Sales'}
		Alpha22
Beta
	Beta1
Gamma{icon: 'svgIcon=#alpha-icon-bandAidCrossed:icon,24'}
	Gamma1]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>