<page>
    <shortlink>ux components data binding</shortlink>
    <topic>Data Binding</topic>
    <description>Create new tables with fields that match the controls on your UX Component, or bind the controls in your UX Component to fields in existing tables. The Data Binding page lets you bind an entire UX component to new or existing SQL or DBF tables in a database and then assign controls to fields in those table accordingly. </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dataBinding.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:.-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You also do data binding when you create a Detail View from an SQL database inside a List Control. When you define the Detail view you specify that certain data controls should be bound to selected fields in the SQL table that the list is linked to. For example, in order to form the Detail View you might bind textbox control on your component named 'City' to a field in an SQL database name 'City'. This is 'data binding'. Once you do this, the data bound list control will appear on the Data Binding page's 'Summary' section, as demonstrated by the image below. </description>
            <figure>
                <title>A summary showing a List Detail-View with data binding</title>
                <link>images/datalist.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>One advantage of using the detail view of a list for data binding is that you are can do CRUD (create, read, update, delete) operations against two independent and unlinked tables from inside the same UX component. This as opposed to having one table or group of tables linked directly to the component itself. The difference between these two models of data binding is explained in [this video]. If you do, in fact, want to link your entire UX component to a given SQL or DBF database, you can do this using the options available on the data binding page. </description>
            <figure>
                <title>A summary showing a component with data binding</title>
                <link>images/datacomp.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <!--order:
Create Tables to Match Controls
Bind Controls to Existing Tables
Specify Primary Keys and Sequences
Permissions and Security
Refresh Table Information
Remove all Data Binding Settings
-->
    <links>
        <link href="https://share.vidyard.com/watch/uajuFTmVd7m8WRop99T9aJ">this video</link>
    </links>
</page>