<page>
    <shortlink>pre render at design time option warning message</shortlink>
    <topic>Pre-render at Design-Time Option - Warning Message</topic>
    <description>When you save a UX component that does not have the Pre-render Component at Design-time option turned on, a warning message now comes up telling you that it is recommended to turn this option on because of the significant speed improvement this options will give at run-time.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Pre-Render Optimization Warning Dialog</title>
                <link>images/preRenderOptimizationDialog.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If you choose not to turn the Pre-render option on, you can specify that the message should not be shown again for this component, or for all components.</p>
                <p>If you choose to turn the option on you can specify that the option should automatically be set to 'on' for all future UX components that you create.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <tip>If you choose the option to turn on pre-render for all UX components, you can un-set the option by going to View, Settings, Preferences, UX Component.</tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Understanding the Difference Between Applying Security and Server-Side Show/Hide Expressions Server-Side and Client-Side</title>
            <description>It is important to understand the difference between applying security and server-side show/hide expressions sever-side and client-side. When applied sever-side, the controls that should not be displayed to the user are physically removed from the HTML sent to the client. If applied client-side, the controls that should be hidden are *[still physically in the HTML]* but are hidden when the component is rendered. Therefore, the client-side option is *[less secure]* because a user may view the source on the page and see controls that may have been hidden.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>