<page>
    <topic>Inherit from</topic>
    <description>There are many built in functionalities inside Alpha Anywhere, such that it is not necessary to create custom data binding 
        for each item that you define. The 'Inherit from' property helps you define what functionalities pertain to what 
        items.
    </description>
    
  <sections>
      <section>
          <figure><link>images/inherit.png</link></figure>
      </section>
      <section>
          <description>The different options available in the Inherit from drop down let you specify what you want to happen 
              when an item is used. The actual event that triggers the item into action is defined in the 'Event to edit item'
              property that is displayed just below 'Inherit from'. The options available are as follows:
          </description>
          <cases>
              <case>
                  <title>*edit</title>
                  <description>This option will bring up an editor when an event happens. The editor is defined in the component 
                      using an Editor Set and an Editor container. The fields that the editor can edit are specified in the fields pane 
                      of the Form View builder using the 'Editor set' and 'Editor' properties. Define a field you want to edit, 
                      select an event that opens the field's editor from an item, and users will be able to edit that field when the event fires.</description>
              </case>
                <case>
                  <title>*group</title>
                  <description>*group is similar to *edit, except that rather than editing a single field after an event happens on an item,
                      you have the option of editing several fields at once with a single editor.</description>
              </case>
                <case>
                  <title>*toggle</title>
                  <description>*toggle means there is a boolean value for the item and that the Item is 
                      going to toggle between true and false every time a specified event happens to it. </description>
              </case>
                <case>
                  <title>*select</title>
                  <description>Say there are 5 buttons, and each is bound to a single item, called v1, and 
                      each button has a different value. 
                      When an event happens, *select will set the field to whatever value v1 is.</description>
              </case>
                <case>
                  <title>*multiple</title>
                  <description>*multiple is a lot like select but it allows you to remove values and do multiple selection. 
                      For example, if you have a app that lets users select their favorite colors, *multiple would allow for more than 
                      one field to be selected. All selections would be in the field.
</description>
              </case>
              
              
          </cases>
      </section>
      
      
  </sections>

item that is called pass fail 
changes item type from default to databound.

when you tap on this thing it will bring up an editor.


define onswipe - what value does that translate to. events set the data. inside he event get the name of the column 
that the thing happened on.

form a,b,c 

if you swipe a it sets the value a

data bound prop = 
inherit from - built in functionalities
the item will inherit this on what event?
onselect it will bring up editor

</page>