<page>
    <shortlink>report printing techniques embed fonts</shortlink>
    <topic>Embedding Fonts in Reports</topic>
    <description>If a PDF Report is opened on a device that does not have the font used to generate the PDF Report, the Report will not render as expected. To fix this, 'Embed fonts' must be enabled in the PDF options.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>In certain cases, generated PDF reports will not render correctly on iOS devices. The PDFs do not render on the iOS devices because they use fonts they are not native to the iOS device. This can happen if the 'Embed fonts' option is disabled when the PDF is generated. The solution is to turn the 'Embed fonts' option on in Project Properties.</p>
        <p>The Embed fonts option is turned on by default in Alpha Anywhere. Since this will result in slightly larger PDF files, some developers might want to not embed fonts in generated PDF files. This can be done by setting the property in the Project Properties.</p>
    </discussion>
    <note>'Embed fonts' was turned on by default in Alpha Anywhere build 4004.</note>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>How to Enable or Disable Embedded Fonts in PDF Reports</title>
            <description>By default, Alpha Anywhere automatically embeds fonts in PDF reports. You can disable (or enable) this behavior in Web Project Properties.</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>On the [Web Projects Control Panel], click on *[ui:Project Properties]* to open the Web Project Properties.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/enableDisableEmbedFont1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the *[ui:Run-time Properties]* tab, expand the *[ui:PDF Printing Options]* and click the [...] button for *[ui:PDF Options]* to open the PDF Options dialog.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/enableDisableEmbedFont2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Locate the *[ui:Embed fonts]* property. To embed fonts, check the *[ui:Embed fonts]* property. To disable font embedding, uncheck the *[ui:Embed fonts]* property.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/enableDisableEmbedFont3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Save your changes.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="Web Projects Control Panel">Web Projects Control Panel</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
</page>