<page>
    <topic>Tracking Down Request Failures</topic>
    <description>Tracking down request failures in IIS for HTTP status codes of 400 and above.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Requests can fail for reasons outside of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS. IIS has a component call Failed Request Tracing that can be used to track down why a request is failing.</p>
                <p>The Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS participates in failed request tracing, meaning that it will write messages to the failed request log. If the error occurs on an .a5w page, the details will be in the Xbasic error and/or trace logs.</p>
                <p>The Tracing feature when configuring IIS is required to use Failed Request Tracing. If Tracing is not installed on your system, you will need to add it.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Enabling Failed Request Tracing</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Select your web site in IIS Manager. It will be listed under "Sites" on the left-hand side.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the right hand "Actions" pane, click on "Failed Request Tracing..." and then enable it. Change the log path if needed.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Enabling Failed Request Tracking.</title>
                        <link>images/failedRequestTracking1.jpg</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>The *[web.config]* is set to trace HTTP response codes of 400 and above by default for a web application published from Alpha Anywhere Developer Edition. To verify this setting, select the web application and then the Failed Request Tracing item in the IIS group.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Verify settings are configured to trace HTTP response codes.</title>
                        <link>images/failedRequestTracking2.jpg</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>With Failed Request Tracing enabled, make a request from the browser to load the page. Once you’ve gotten the error go to the failed request logs folder to and double click on the frxxxxx.xml file and to view it.</description>
                    <note>If you want to clean up the request logs, only delete the .xml files. *[Do not delete the freb.xsl]*. The freb.xsl file is difficult to recreate.</note>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>