<page>
	<shortlink>grid properties linked content section</shortlink>
	<topic>Linked Grids and Content</topic>
	<description>When you are designing a grid, you can embed a 'Linked Grid' object or objects inside the grid part just as you would any other object (such as Tabs, Images, Frames, etc..).</description>
	<!--list:.-->
	<!--order:
Has linked Grids or other content.xml
Linked Content Definition.xml
locklinkedcontentwindow.xml
lockwindowtext.xml
lockwindowclassname.xml
-->
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>If you specify more than one Grid, the linked grids will display in a tab or accordion control. Linked grids can be linked to one or more fields in the current row. While they might sound mundane, linked grids have some powerful applications. If you are building a business application, for example, it is possible to link one customer on a grid containing customer names to a second grid containing information about everything that a customer has ever ordered from a given company. One could even create a third linked grid to display all of the other customers in the customer grid who happen to live in the same country.   </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Videos</title>
			<videos>
				<title>Linked content section</title>
				<description>You can create very powerful "master-detail" Grids by placing "Linked Content Sections" on the Grid. If a Linked Content Section contains more than one Grid, the content is displayed in a Tab or Accordion object. For example, you might have a Customer Grid that displays the Orders for the customer record that has focus. The Orders Grid, in turn, might display the Order Details for the order that has focus. There is no limit to the level of nesting of linked content. This video shows how easy it is to create a Linked Content Section. </description>
				<video>
					<name>Watch Video</name>
					<link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/ZPtHw7kWTE2YaX52uvDeYV</link>
				</video>
			</videos>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>