<page>
	  <topic>Above Grid</topic>
<description>To add HTML above your grid simply click the button [dot_img] next to the Above grid property. The Freeform Edit Region dialog will open.  Insert the desired HTML into the work area of the dialog. If you are not sure how you want the HTML to look, click the HTML Editor button at the bottom of the dialog to open the HTML editor.</description>
  
<sections>
	<section>
		
		<description>The editor contains a number of features, including a WYSIWYG (What you see is what you get) page, that help make editing HTML much easier. Here you will find most of the standard tools used in word processing. This includes means of setting the font type, size, and color; creating underlined, bold, or italic text; tools for adding images, tables, and hyperlinks; right, center, and left justification; spell-checking, copy and paste tools, and more. Once you have created some HTML click the Save [save_img]  button and it will be added to the Freeform Edit Region dialog.  
</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				
				<figure><title>HTML Editor toolset</title><link>images/1_freeform3.png</link></figure>
			</case>
			<case>
				
				<figure><title>HTML in Freeform Edit Region dialog</title><link>images/1_freeform.png</link></figure>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</section>	
	
	
	<section>
		
		
		<figure><link>images/1_alphabet20.png</link></figure>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>You can insert placeholders for the controls in your grid (e.g. {lastname}) or for the data that is in the control (e.g. {data.lastname}). 
If you have used a freeform edit region in a Grid created in V9 or earlier, you might need to change some of your placeholders to use the 'data.' prefix. After V10, labels are automatically wrapped in a span tag. In V9 and earlier, a label control was not wrapped in a span, and so the {lastname} placeholder, for example, would have been replaced with 'Smith'. But in V10, this placeholder will be replaced with 'Smith 
If your component was not expecting the to be in the replacement value, it might break your component. Changing the placeholder to use the 'data.' prefix will get you back to the V9 behavior. 
In the example shown below, if the {lastname} placeholder had been used, the image name would not have resolved correctly.</description>
		<figure><link>images/GridCo3.jpg</link></figure>
	</section>	
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Above grid</title>
			<description>Defines HTML that appears above the grid.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Top as C 
]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Below grid</title>
			<description>Defines HTML that appears below the grid.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Bottom as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Left of grid</title>
			<description>Defines HTML that appears to the left of the grid.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Left as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Right of grid</title>
			<description>Defines HTML that appears to the right of the grid.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[tmpl.EditRegion.Grid.Right as C ]]></example>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
</section>	
	
	
	
	
	</sections>
	
	<links>
		<link href="images/open.png">dot_img</link>
		
	</links>
	
</page>