<page>
	<shortlink>desktop a5startup.log</shortlink>
	<topic>Startup Log</topic>
	<description>When Alpha Anywhere starts up, a log can be created used to troubleshoot startup and workspace loading issues. If technical support is required from Alpha Software, the technician may request this file.</description>
	<discussion>
		<p>The default name for the log file is *[alpha5.log]* and located in the AppData folder (AppData\Roaming\Alpha Software\Alpha Anywhere Version 12). If workspace logging is enabled, timing information is appended to the log when a workspace is opened. The log is overwritten every time Alpha Anywhere is launched.</p>
		<p>The startup log records how long processes take to execute while Alpha Anywhere is starting or when Alpha Anywhere opens a workspace. For example:</p>
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<example>
				<![CDATA[Startup Log for Alpha Anywhere version 8.0 Build 1037 - Thu Jul 27 10:35:55 2006
[406 Ms. since start] Starting Alpha Anywhere [Task - 0 Ms.]
[408 Ms. since start] Setting Process Affinity to Primary Processor [Task - 0 Ms.]
[437 Ms. since start] Loaded Error Messages [Task - 31 Ms.]
[438 Ms. since start] Loaded Themes [Task - 0 Ms.]
[441 Ms. since start] Started Memory Manager [Task - 0 Ms.]
[443 Ms. since start] Processed Command Line Arguments [Task - 0 Ms.]
[446 Ms. since start] Checked Environment [Task - 15 Ms.]
[450 Ms. since start] Loaded Registry Information [Task - 0 Ms.]
... ]]>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Enabling the Startup Log</title>
			<description>The startup log can be enabled or disabled in the Alpha Anywhere Developer Edition settings. To enable the startup log:</description>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Open the settings dialog under *[ui:View]* &gt; *[ui:Settings]*</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Locate the startup log settings under *[ui:System]* &gt; *[ui:Technical Support]*</description>
					<figure>
						<link>images/a5startup_log.png</link>
					</figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enable the startup log. Alpha Anywhere can be configured to log information for the following events: when Alpha Anywhere is launched and/or every time a workspace is opened. Both events can be configured to log *[ui:Minimal]* or *[ui:Full]* details.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save your changes and restart Alpha Anywhere.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>