<page>
   <topic>UI_INFO Function</topic>
   <syntax>Numeric Result = UI_INFO(N option)</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>option</name>
         <description>Determines what information to return. Code has the following values:</description>
 <list>
 <item>
 <name>Code</name>
 <description>Parameters</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>0</name>
 <description>Returns the width of the screen in pixels</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>1</name>
 <description>Returns the height of the screen in pixels</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>2</name>
 <description>Returns the width of the Alpha Anywhere desktop in pixels</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>3</name>
 <description>Returns the height of the Alpha Anywhere desktop in pixels</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>4</name>
 <description>Returns the screen DPI x dimension (dots per inch x).</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>5</name>
 <description>Returns the screen DPI in the y dimension (dot per inch y)</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>6</name>
 <description>Returns the number of dialog units in the x dimension. (Primarily for internal use)</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>7</name>
 <description>Returns the number of dialog units in the y dimension. (Primarily for internal use)</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>8</name>
 <description>Returns the width of the client area (not including any vertically docked toolbars)</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>9</name>
 <description>Returns the height of the client area (not including any horizontally docked toolbars and menus).</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>10</name>
 <description>Returns the left edge of the client area, relative to the left edge of the screen</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>11</name>
 <description>Returns the top of the client area, relative to the top of the screen.</description>
 </item>
  
 <item>
 <name>12</name>
 <description>Returns the position of the left edge of the Windows work area (accounting for any space taken up the Task Bar, if it is docked on the left). 
</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>13</name>
 <description>Returns the position of the top edge of the Windows work area (accounting for any space taken up the Task Bar, if it is docked on the top). 
</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>14</name>
 <description>Returns the width of the Windows work area (screen size minus space taken up by the Task Bar, if it is docked on the left or right).
</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>15</name>
 <description>Returns the height of the Windows work area (screen size minus space taken up the by Task Bar, if it docked on the top or bottom). 
</description>
 </item>
 
 </list>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Get information about the user interface.</description>
   <discussion>
UI_INFO() returns information about the size in pixels of the Alpha Anywhere main window and the screen resolution of the user's computer.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.
   </discussion>
 
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>This following global function takes a window name as a parameter and it centers the window within the Alpha Anywhere desktop.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
function center as L(window as C)
    p = obj(window)
    a5_height = UI_info(3)
    a5_width = UI_info(0)
    width = p.width
    height = p.height
    newtop = (a5_height - height)/2
    newleft = (a5_width - width)/2
    p.top = newtop
    p.left = newleft
    p.activate()
end function

]]></example>
       </section>
       <section>
<description>To change the size of the Alpha Anywhere window set the values of A5.HEIGHT and A5.WIDTH.</description>
       
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>System Functions</ref>
   </see>
  
</page>