<page>
    <shortlink>transform quicklink</shortlink>
    <topic>TransForm QuickLink</topic>
    <description>
        Create URLs that point users directly to a specific form. 
    </description>

    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Overview</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Many types of workflow involve sending a message to an individual to have them click on a link and automatically view a single form, often answering questions such as giving approval, and then submitting that form for further action. The TransForm QuickLink functionality provides this capability.</p>
                    <p>Other parts of TransForm, like the Filler and Management Console, require the user to run them and then locate or create an appropriate form instance and work with it along with a list of other form instances and types of forms. This general purpose operation does not easily fit into those link-driven types of workflows and is cumbersome in those cases.</p>
                    <p>QuickLink also makes it easy to send a link to a user that includes custom data to pre-populate parts of a form before editing. For example, an email created from a template can include template data fields in the URL which are in turn passed to the form.</p>
                    <p>Another example of using QuickLink is an intranet web page that uses simple Javascript to create a URL that any authorized user can click on, log in with their credentials (if they are not already logged in), and have a new form instance created using custom initialization data (such as a work order number). The user can then fill in the rest of the form and then submit it – all in just a few clicks.</p>
                </description>           
         </section>
               
        <section>
            <title>Properties of QuickLink</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Using QuickLink to view and edit a form instance is similar to using the TransForm Filler once a particular form instance is chosen. Only the Form Details screens and Editors are shown. Unlike the Web Filler, there is no Forms List with QuickLink nor an Add a Blank Form list.</p>
                    <p>Unlike the Mobile Filler but similar to the Web Filler, QuickLink runs in a browser connected to the Internet. It is launched by going to a custom URL, usually from an email, text message, QR code, or web page. Once launched, it supports the viewing, editing, and saving of a single form instance. The link includes special information to identify the desired form instance. Optionally, the link can specify initial automatic positioning of the view of the form to a specific field or section.</p>
                    <p>QuickLink, once invoked, requires login with user name, password, and account credentials which persist in the browser during subsequent sessions. Multiple tabs in a browser may be open at once, all running different QuickLink URLs to edit different form instances.</p>
                    <p>Once a form instance has been displayed for viewing and/or edit, the user may quit the tab without saving. Once edits have been made, a “Save” button will be enabled in the upper left above the form. Pressing that button, or pressing a form button that executes a “save” operation, will upload the form instance data and switch to a final screen.</p>
                </description>           
         </section>

        <section>
            <title>Four Modes of Operation Available</title>
                 <description>
                    <p>TransForm QuickLink works in one of four modes of operation specified in the URL: Edit a single explicit existing form instance, Edit a duplicate of an explicit existing form instance, Create and edit a new form instance of a specified form type, and Choose a form instance by viewing one or more TransForm Queues for the account and selecting one of the available form instances in the queue.</p>
                    <p>The URL that is used to invoke QuickLink must include parameters (often called a Query component of the URL) after the domain and path, separated by a “?” character. The structure of the query follows a common Internet syntax. For example, the URL could be:</p>
                    <p>http://transform.alphasoftware.com/QuickLink?m=d&amp;f=lflza6l9_br9pnc11</p>
                    <p>In this case, the "http://transform.alphasoftware.com/QuickLink" is the part that indicates the address on a particular server. We will call that the "QuickLink Web Address". The part after the "?", "m=d&amp;f=lflza6l9_br9pnc11", is the query. Multiple parameters in the query are separated by the “&” character. An initial "&" after the "?" is optional. (The construction of URLs with query strings this way is a normal, well-documented, web-development technology.)</p>
                    <p>The four QuickLink modes are specified by using the parameters in the query. The "m" parameter is used to explicitly specify the mode. Allowed values are: i, d, n, and q (representing Instance, Duplicate, New, and Queue). If the m parameter is missing, “i” is assumed.</p>
                    <p>The other parameters are used to provide the details. The "f" parameter specifies a form instance ID. This is one of the metadata fields for a form instance and uniquely identifies the form instance within the TransForm system. The “a” parameter specifies the Account ID for the account that the user must be logged into. The “q” parameter specifies a specific Queue ID within the account. The “d” parameter specifies the Form Definition ID of a form type for the account. The “v” parameter specifies a URI-encoded string to be passed to the form instance being edited as the TPL $environment.editformvalue System Data value. The “t” parameter specifies a location other than the default top of the form being displayed to initially position to be visible on the screen.</p>
                    <p>The four modes and the other parameters are explained in more detail below.</p>
                </description>           
         </section>

        
        
        
        
        
        
    </sections>
</page>
