<page>
    <shortlink>howwto configure s3 bucket</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Configure an Amazon S3 Bucket</topic>
    <description>Amazon S3 Buckets can be used to store files, such as images or documents. S3 Buckets can also be used with AlphaLaunch to host application installation files.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Setting the CORS Policy</title>
            <description>
                <p>Before you can upload files to Amazon S3, you must configure your Amazon bucket to allow CORS support. CORS (Cross-Origin Resource Sharing) allows you to make callbacks to a different server than the server from which the page was originally loaded (your Alpha server). To configure your bucket you will need to open the *[extlink:AWS console@https://console.aws.amazon.com/console/home]*.</p>
                <p>To configure the CORS policy on an Amazon S3 Bucket, open the *[extlink:Amazon Web Services Management Console@https://console.aws.amazon.com/console/home]*, select the bucket, then click the *[ui:Properties]* button. From the Properties screen, open the *[ui:Permissions]* section. Then, click the *[ui:Edit CORS Configuration]* button.</p>
                <p>Below is a sample configuration that can be pasted into the configuration dialog:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[<CORSConfiguration>
    <CORSRule>
        <AllowedOrigin>*</AllowedOrigin>
        <AllowedMethod>PUT</AllowedMethod>
        <MaxAgeSeconds>3000</MaxAgeSeconds>
        <AllowedHeader>Content-Type</AllowedHeader>
        <AllowedHeader>x-amz-acl</AllowedHeader>
        <AllowedHeader>origin</AllowedHeader>
    </CORSRule>
</CORSConfiguration>
]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Setting a Bucket Policy</title>
            <description>
                <p>The S3 buckets used with Alpha Anywhere must have a CORS policy set. They also need a bucket policy to allow public read for objects in the Bucket - especially if you are using the Bucket to publish applications to AlphaLaunch. The Bucket policy can be set in the *[extlink:Amazon AWS management console@https://console.aws.amazon.com/console/home]* and it will look something like this:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[{
    "Id": "Policy1513279106848",
    "Version": "2012-10-17",
    "Statement": [
        {
            "Sid": "Stmt1513279094040",
            "Action": [
                "s3:GetObject"
            ],
            "Effect": "Allow",
            "Resource": "arn:aws:s3:::your-bucket-name/*",
            "Principal": "*"
        }
    ]
}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Additional Resources</title>
            <description>For more information on how to create and configure Amazon S3 Buckets, refer to *[extlink:Amazon's documentation@https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/UsingBucket.html]*.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref href="https://docs.aws.amazon.com/AmazonS3/latest/gsg/CreatingABucket.html">Amazon S3 - Create a Bucket (external link)</ref>
        <ref href="https://www.cloudberrylab.com/explorer.aspx">CloudBerry - A 3rd party client for managing Amazon S3 Buckets (external link)</ref>
    </see>
</page>