<page>
    <shortlink>how to copy code libraries from older versions of Alpha Anywhere</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Copy Code Libraries from Older Versions of Alpha Anywhere</topic>
    <description>Code Libraries from older versions of Alpha Anywhere can be copied into the current version of Alpha Anywhere. This is done by copying the Code Libraries from the older version of Alpha Anywhere to the directory where Code Libraries are stored in the current version of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Determine the source folder. Open the older version of Alpha Anywhere. Go to the Interactive Window and execute the following command to find out where the old Code Libraries are stored:</description>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[? A5_getCodeLibraryFolder()
= "C:\Users\Sarah\AppData\Roaming\Alpha Software\Alpha Anywhere Version 12\code_libraries"]]></example>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Find the destination folder. Open the current version of Alpha Anywhere. Go to the Interactive window and execute the same command as above to find out where to copy the old Code Libraries.</description>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[? a5_getcodelibraryfolder()
= "C:\Users\Sarah\AppData\Roaming\Alpha Software\Alpha Anywhere Version 12\code_libraries"]]></example>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Open both directories. Copy the Code Libraries from the source folder to the destination folder.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Once the old Code Libraries have been copied, refresh the Code Library by closing and re-opening the Code Editor in the current version of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="A5_getCodeLibraryFolder function">A5_getCodeLibraryFolder()</ref>
    </see>
</page>