<page build="">
    <shortlink>howot import and add svg to button</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Import an SVG Icon and Add it to a Button Control</topic>
    <description>SVG Icons from third-party sources or even those you've designed yourself can be added to and used in a component.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Custom SVG Icons can be added to your project by including them in your component's definition. The *[ui:Local SVG definitions]* property (Grid, UX, and Tabbed UI) is where you can add custom SVG Icon defintions for use in your component. The </p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In the UX Builder on the UX Controls open the 'Other Controls' menu. Click 
                    on the [Button] option to add a button control to the component.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Open the UX Properties page and scroll down to the CSS/SVG section. Click the 
                    [...] button next to the 'Local SVG definitions' property
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the 'Import SVG definition' button.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the 'Insert sample' button and enter a name like 'myIcon' into the 'Icon name' textbox. Click OK.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the 'Preview SVG Icons' to see the SVG icon.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>If you change the fill or stroke color on the preview page it will change the color of the icon on the preview page 
                     but will have no effect on the fill color or stroke color of the SVG icon when it is actually loaded into the control. 
                     These aspects of the SVG icon can either be added to the svg inline or defined on the UX Controls page when the SVG icon 
                     is assigned to a particular control and instance of that control.
                    </note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click OK and OK again to return to the UX Properties page.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Open the UX Controls page again and highlight the button control you defined.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg7.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the properties list on the right click the drop-down next to the 'Advanced button control type' 
                    property, in the Button Properties section, and select 'Image'. 
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the Image Appearance section click the [...] button next to the 
                    'Image name' property.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg10.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Choose the 'SVG' radio button and then click 'Select'.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg11.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the 'SVG Icon' dialog scroll to the bottom of the icons list. 
                    Highlight the icon you defined in the 'Local SVG Icons' section and click OK. 
                    Click OK again to return to the UX controls page.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg12.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] button next to the 'Hover image name' property.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg13.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Again select the 'SVG Icon' option and click Select.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg11.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the 'Local SVG Icons' section select the icon you defined. </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg14.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the arrow next to the 'Fill color' control in the top right corner of the SVG Icon dialog. 
                    Select a new fill color.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg15.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>When you set the fill color and stroke color in this case you will see all of the icons on the page turn to the color that 
                    was selected. This will not affect the final result when you run the actual application because you are defining only 
                    a instance for the SVG icon and only on this particular button control. 
                    </note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the arrow next to the 'Stroke color' control and select a new stroke color for the icon. 
                    Then click OK and OK again to return to the UX Controls page.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg16.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] button next to the 'Pressed image name' property.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg17.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the SVG option and click 'Select'.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg11.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Highlight the same icon and change the 'Fill color' and 'Stroke color' to something new. Click OK and OK again.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg18.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Run the component in Live Preview. You should see the SVG Icon that you imported (sampled) appear 
                    on a button.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg19.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Hover over the button and the color should change to match the color instance you defined.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg21.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click on the button and you should see the color change again.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/svg22.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
</page>