<page>
    <shortlink>Readonly Checkbox</shortlink>
    <topic>How to make a Checkbox Readonly</topic>
    <description>Learn how client-side enable expressions can be used to disable a checkbox, making it readonly.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>A checkbox HTML element doesn't have a "readonly" property. Consequently, the only way to make a checkbox appear to be "readonly" is to disable the control. A checkbox control can be disabled in Alpha Anywhere using Client-side Enable Expressions.</p>
                <p>Client-side enable expressions can be used to disable controls, creating a "readonly" effect. This method can be applied to a checkbox control in a component. The client-side enable expression can be a constant value or based on values in other fields in  your component.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/checkboxReadonly_enableExpression.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Static Client-side Enable Expression</title>
            <description>If the checkbox control should always be readonly, define the checkbox control's *[ui:Enable expression]* as "1=0". The expression, "1=0", will always be false. When a *[ui:Enable expression]* evaluates to false, the control will be disabled.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[1=0]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Dynamic Client-side Enable Expression</title>
            <description>If the checkbox control should be readonly only when data in another field in the component is a specific value, you can specify a dynamic *[ui:Enable expression]* that references the field. Click the [...] button for the checkbox control's *[ui:Enable expression]* property to open the client-side expression builder. Use the *[ui:Insert Field]* to insert a control into the expression. For example, the following expression will disable the checkbox control unless the value in the *[xb:State]* field is 'MA':</description>
            <example><![CDATA[State = 'MA']]></example>
            <figure>
                <link>images/checkboxReadonly_dynamic.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="images/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=Client Side Expressions, Validation, and Calculated Fields">Client Side Expressions, Validation, and Calculated Fields</ref>
    </see>
</page>