<page>
    <shortlink>api namespace Active Directory Domain ActiveDirectory Domain</shortlink>
    <topic>WindowsServices::ActiveDirectory::Domain Object</topic>
    <description>The WindowsServices::ActiveDirectory::Domain object contains properties and methods available for working with an Active Directory domain.</description>
    <properties>
	    <property readonly="true">
            <name>CallResult</name>
            <type>CallResult</type>
			<description>Domain.CallResult is used to check the success or failure of a method call or property get in the Domain object. Read Only.</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>UseSecureConnection</name>
            <type>L</type>
            <description>Connect to Active Directory domain using SSL over port 636. Read Write.</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Host</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>Host is the fully qualified domain name of the Active Directory host server. Read Write.</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Name</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>Name is the name of the Active Directory domain. Read Write.</description>
        </property>
        <property> 
            <name>NetBiosName</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>NetBiosName is the NetBios name of the Active Directory domain. Read Write.</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>UserId</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>
				<p>UserId is the user id/name used to access Active Directory. This can be left blank if credentials are not needed to access Active Directory. Read Write.</p>
				<p>This is akin to a connection string's credentials user name in that it is a user for accessing Active Directory and not a user in the application.</p> 
			</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>Password</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>Password is the password used with the UserId to access Active Directory. This can be left blank if credentials are not needed to access Active Directory. Read Write.</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>LoginOu</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>
				<p>LoginOu is the organizational unit used when validating application users' credentials. Read Write.</p>
				<p>This can be left blank and the entire Active Directory will be searched for a user. Set this to a specific organizational unit to restrict user that can log into the application.</p>
			</description>
        </property>
        <property readonly="true">
            <name>CurrentDomainServerName</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>CurrentDomainServerName is the fully qualified domain name of the Active Directory server if the machine is joined to an Active Directory domain. Read Only</description>
        </property>
        <property>
            <name>AdditionalUserAttributeNames</name>
            <type>C</type>
            <description>
				<p>AdditionalUserAttributeNames is a *[link:crlf@CRLF Function]* delimited list of attribute names to include when getting a user. 
				These attributes are in addition to the default set of user attributes. Read Write.</p>
				<p>User lookup under Active Directory can take a long time so attributes are only fetched at the time a user is authenticated. Default 
					user attributes are named properties on the *[link:User@./User/index.xml]* object. Any other attributes need to be included in this list and
					then can be retrieved using the User.GetAttribute() method.</p>
			</description>
        </property>
        <property readonly="true">
            <name>ConfigType</name>
            <type>Domain::ConfigurationType</type>
            <description>
				<p>ConfigType is the type of the way in which the Domain object was created. Read Only.</p>
				<p>
					Possible values are:
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>WindowsServices::AcitveDirectory::Domain::ConfigurationType::DEFAULT</name>
							<description>
								<p>Value 0</p>
								<p>The Domain object was configured by setting object properites.</p>
							</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>WindowsServices::AcitveDirectory::Domain::ConfigurationType::SECURITY_CONFIGURATION</name>
							<description>
								<p>Value 1</p>
								<p>The Domain object was configured by using the security configuration from the pubish profile.
								This option is only for use at runtime in the Application Server or Application Server for IIS.</p>
							</description>
                        </item>
					</list>
				</p>
				<p>
				</p>
			</description>
        </property>
    </properties>
    <!--list:.-->
</page>