<page>
	<shortlink>grid display settings control type property</shortlink>
	<topic parent="Display Settings Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Control type">Control type</topic>
	<description>You can pick what type of control you want to represent a given field using the Control Type property.</description>
	<discussion>
		<p>If your grid is 'Read only', then the fields that you put on the grid will be displayed by default using Label  controls. If the grid is Updatable , then the fields initially will be displayed using textbox controls. Label controls  display the value of the field but do not have a width setting. In contrast, textbox controls always have a specified character width, even if the field is Read only. For some data types, such as  Images  and dates, you will have to manually select the control type. You can select other control type by using the Control Type dropdown under Display Settings in the Field Properties list.</p>
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.text.png">Label</title>
			<description>A Label is read-only control suitable for character, numeric, and date/time data. See also [Label Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.edit.png">Textbox</title>
			<description>A Textbox is an editable control suitable for character, numeric, and date/time data. See also [Textbox Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.textarea.png">TextArea</title>
			<description>A TextArea is similar to a text box, but with multiple lines. See also [TextArea Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$generic.link.png">Link</title>
			<description>A Link is used to add a link that may open another page or select a record to display. See also [Link Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$generic.image.png">Image</title>
			<description>An Image can be used to display either embedded or linked images. See also [Image Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.editCombo.png">DropDownBox</title>
			<description>A DropDownBox is a list box that appears as either a list or combo box. Dropdown boxes present a selection from an existing list of values; that is hard coded or retrieved from a table. See also [DropDownBox Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.radio.png">RadioButton</title>
			<description>A RadioButton is a control that allows users to select one option from a list of values. See also [RadioButton Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$control.checkbox.png">Checkbox</title>
			<description>A Checkbox is a control that allows a selection of one or more options from a list of values. See also [Checkbox Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$code.aScript.png">Custom</title>
			<description>A Custom control type allows you to create the complete definition for the control using Xbasic and HTML to display the value for the field. See also [Custom Properties].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title icon="/images/$$format.border.style.dot.png">Hidden</title>
			<description>The Hidden control hides controls without hiding the column that contains them. See also [Hidden Properties].</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<links>
		<link link="gridfieldprops label properties">Label Properties</link>
		<link link="gridfieldprops textbox properties">Textbox Properties</link>
		<link link="gridfieldprops textarea properties">TextArea Properties</link>
		<link link="gridfieldprops link properties">Link Properties</link>
		<link link="grid dropdown box properties">DropDownBox Properties</link>
		<link link="gridfieldprops radiobutton properties">RadioButton Properties</link>
		<link link="grid checkbox properties">Checkbox Properties</link>
		<link link="grid custom control properties">Custom Properties</link>
		<link link="gridfieldprops hidden properties">Hidden Properties</link>
		<link link="fieldprops image properties properties">Image Properties</link>
	</links>
</page>