<page>
	<shortlink>grid field display format</shortlink>
	<topic>Display Format</topic>
	<description>If the control type is Label, Link, TextBox, or TextArea, the Display Format property allows you to automatically change the presentation of your data.</description>
	<discussion>
		<p>The *[ui:Display format]* is used to transform the value in the field before it is shown to the user. The transformation occurs on the server before data is sent to the client.</p>
		<p>The *[ui:Display format]* is often used to format data such as dates, currency values, convert a character value to uppercase, etc. If the field is an RTF Memo, contains HTML markup, or image data, *[ui:Special Formats]* can be used to format the value so it displays properly.</p>
		<p>The format can reference the current value in the field using the &lt;value&gt; placeholder. For example, the expression below will convert the first character in the field to upper case and leave the rest of the string unformatted:</p>
	</discussion>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<example code="ui">
				<![CDATA[f_upper(<value>)]]>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Pre-defined Formats</title>
			<description>Several pre-defined formats are available for the most common formats. A pre-defined format can be selected using one of the two buttons in the *[ui:Display Format]* dialog -- *[ui:Select Pre-Defined Format]* and *[ui:Special Formats]*. Depending on the data type of the field, the pre-defined formats available will vary.</description>
			<note>There are no predefined display formats for short time (Y) fields. However, you can write your own.</note>
			<figure>
				<title>Pre-defined formats for Character fields</title>
				<link>images/predefinedFormatsC.png</link>
			</figure>
			<figure>
				<title>Pre-defined formats for Date fields</title>
				<link>images/predefinedFormatsD.png</link>
			</figure>
			<figure>
				<title>Special Formats are built-in for Memo field and images</title>
				<link>images/specialformats1.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<note>If the control type is "TextBox" and the field type is "Date", then a Date Picker will appear. You must set the date picker format to use the same style.</note>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>International Currency Format</title>
			<description>
				<p>The *[ui:International Currency Format]* button opens a dialog that can be used to build a format for currency for countries throughout the world. The currency code is pre-defined for a variety of countries. Select the desired country from the dropdown list, use the text boxes to specify the decimal places, thousands separator, etc and click OK to insert the format into the Display Format dialog.</p>
			</description>
			<figure>
				<link>images/internationalCurrency1.png</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
        <section build="5862">
            <title>Default Time Display Format</title>
            <description>
                <p>	When you add a Date/time field (Time field), the default server side Display Format is set to the following:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[time("{grid.clientSideDateFormat} 0h:0m 0s am",<value>)]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>In Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4.8 and prior, the time format was set to *[xb:time("{grid.clientSideDateFormat}",&lt;value&gt;)]*. This resulted in the time portion being stripped from the date/time value.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
	</sections>
</page>