<page>
    <shortlink>fieldprops display settings initial value property</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Display Settings Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Initial value">Initial value</topic>
    <description>
        <p>The initial value of the field. The initial value defines the default value for new records.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Specify the default value for this field in new records. The default value can be literal value or an expression. Expressions can include functions and reference session and page variables. If the initial value is an expression, it must be preceded with an equal (=) sign. For example:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="xb">
                <![CDATA[=a5ws_getCurrentUser()]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Initializing to Today's Date/Time</title>
            <description>
                <p>For example, the following will set the default to today's date:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb">
                <![CDATA[=date()]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To set the default to the current time or current datetime, the *[xb:now()]* function can be used:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb">
                <![CDATA[=now()]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can also use session variables as default values. For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb">
                <![CDATA[=session.companyName]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can specify NULL to force the default new value to be blank.</p>
                <p>You can use Page Variables (i.e. the variables defined in the URL) by prefixing the variable name with 'PageVariable.' For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb">
                <![CDATA[=PageVariable.lastname]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Default Values for Numeric Controls</title>
            <description>For numeric fields, numbers must be entered with a period for the decimal separator, regardless of the regional settings on the machine where the server is running.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <description>To learn more about specifying the *[ui:Initial value]*, watch the videos below.</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Setting the Default Values In New Records In Grid Part</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The Grid allows you to enter new records directly in the Grid part or in the Detail View part. The Grid builder allows you to specify default values for fields in new records. This can be done by either specifying the field's "Initial Value" property, or by specifying code in the "onInitialValueCalculate" event.</p>
                    <p>In the case where data entry is done in the Grid Part (as opposed to the Detail View), the issue with the "onInitialValueCalculate" event (which is a server-side event) is that it is only called once: when the Grid is initially rendered. So, if you enter a new record and then save that record, the event is not called before the next new record is displayed.</p>
                    <p>This video shows how you can save the value of a field that was just entered inside the Grid's "stateInfo" object, and then use the "afterRowPopulate" event to retrieve that value and use it as a default in the next new record</p>
                </description>
                <note>The .setValue() method is not used to set the value of the field in the new record row because this would cause the new record row to go 'dirty'. Instead we get a pointer to the element and then simply set its value property.</note>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/VwcWKtXfpLkaXcbcauxyE5</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
