<page>
    <shortlink>fieldprops display settings validation xbasic property</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Display Settings Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Validation Xbasic">Validation Xbasic</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Xbasic can be added to this property to add custom validation rules for a field.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Specify Xbasic code to test if the data in this field is valid. By default, only dirty fields are validated. You can specify that all fields should be validated in [Update Settings &gt; Editing Properties].</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
			<videos>
				<title>Data Validation</title>
				<description>
					<p>The Grid component has exceptionally strong data validation features. This video demonstrates the validation features available, including Data validation rules, Data validation using custom Xbasic at the field level, Data validation events, and automatically honoring Field Rules for DBF tables.</p>
				</description>
				<video>
					<name>Watch Video</name>
					<link>https://www.viddler.com/v/c7406ad1</link>
				</video>
			</videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Validating Data</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The UX Component has an extremely rich set of features for validating data in the component. Validation rules can be defined declaratively, or by using code (either Javascript for client-side or Xbasic for server-side). Validation rules are evaluated on the client where possible (thus eliminating the need for an Ajax callback). Validation rules can be set to fire when the dialog is submitted, or immediately when the user tabs out of a field.</p>
                    <p>These video discuss the various validation options in the UX Component.</p>
                    <p>The videos below discuss the validation features of Alpha Anywhere. While these videos were recorded for the UX Component, the discussions about Validation rules, Validation Xbasic, and Immediate Validation apply to the Grid Component.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 1</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/3fc55726</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 2</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/3312f659</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 3</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/48114c8e</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 4</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/94436d7a</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 5</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/6849769c</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video Part 6</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/deba4308</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="editing properties#section1_Field validation setting">Update Settings &gt; Editing Properties</link>
    </links>
</page>
