<page>
    <shortlink>ux controls containers using customized radio buttons in an absolute layout container</shortlink>
    <topic>Using Customized Radio Buttons in an Absolute Layout Container</topic>
    <description>Radio-buttons can be used when there is a need to limit the users of an application 
        to selecting one choice from a number of options. When using radio-buttons inside an absolute 
        layout container, the button choices displayed inside to radio-button control can be customized 
        to appear as individual checkboxes. 
    </description>

<sections>
    <section>
        <description>The standard radio button control has a series of circles placed next to a number of choices, usually 
            displayed either horizontally or vertically. When the user selects one of the items in the radio-button control, 
            the other items are de-selected. This can be useful in situations where only one option can apply, 
            such as marital status on a 1040 form or the shipping options on a customer order. 
        </description>
        
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>One of the main advantages of the 'AbsoluteLayout' container is that it allows you to place controls 
            that are inside the container anywhere that you want to in the container's layout. With radio-button controls, 
            however, we want the ability not to just position the whole control inside the layout, but to also position 
            and style each of the choices that the radio-button control contains. The guide below demonstrates how to do this, as 
            does [this video]. 
        </description>
        
        
    </section>
<section>
    <title>Create a Control and an Absolute Layout Container</title>
    <steps>
        
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        
    </steps>

</section>
<section>
    <title>Add the Radio-Button Choices to the Layout</title>
    <steps>
        
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
         <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        
    </steps>

</section>
<section>
    
    <steps>
        
        <step>
            <description></description>
            <figure><link>images/ucrb.png</link></figure>
        </step>
        
    </steps>

</section>

    
</sections>    
    
    <links>
        <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_absoluteLayout_4.swf">this video</link>
        
    </links>
    <terms>container</terms>
</page>