<page>
    <shortlink>ux server-side actions Populate a Dialog with data from one or more tables</shortlink>
    <topic>Populate a Dialog with data from one or more tables</topic>
    <description>Populate the controls with data from one or more tables.</description>
    <sections>
     
        <section>
   <description>Use of this action is described in the "[Populating a Repeating Section from a Table]" guide 
       in the [RepeatingSection] part of the UX documentation.
   </description>
        </section>    
        
          <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Action Properties</title>
            
            <list>
                <item>
                <name-title>Populate Dialog Settings</name-title>
                <description>&#160;</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Primary key source</name>
                    <description>To populate the Dialog you must specify the primary key of the record you wish to load. You can 
                        either specify an explicit primary key value, or you can specify the name of a variable 
                        that contains the primary key. If the primary key contains multiple columns, you must enter 
                        the primary key value as a ||| (three pipes) delimited list of column values. 
                        For example, if the primary key is Firstname and Lastname, you could specify 
                        'Fred|||Smith' as the primary key value.
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Primary key value</name>
                    <description>Specify the primary key of the record you want to load. If the primary key 
                        has multiple columns, use ||| (three pipes) to delimit the values. For example, 
                        if the primary key is Firstname and Lastname, you could specify 'Fred|||Smith' as the 
                        primary key value.
                    </description>
                </item>
                 <item>
                    <name>Variable that contains the primary key</name>
                    <description>Specify tha name of the variable that contains the primary key of the record you wish 
                        to load. You can specify a local variable, defined in this event handler, or a session variable. 
                        This setting appears once the 'Primary key source' is set to 'ReadFromVariable'.</description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Record not found message</name>
                    <description>Specify the message to show if the record was not found. You can use [language tags] in the message. 
                        <![CDATA[(e.g. <a5:r>message</a5:r>)]]>
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Maximum number of child records to retrieve</name>
                    <description>If the Dialog has [Repeating Sections], specify the maximum number of records to retrieve for each 
                        Repeating Section in the Dialog.
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Show debugging information</name>
                    <description>Show the commands used to query the table(s) to retrieve the data to be shown 
                        in the Dialog and the Javascript response sent to the Dialog.
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Capture raw data</name>
                    <description>Specify if the data that is retrieved from the table should be made available 
                        to your script. If you select this option, then the data from the table(s) will be 
                        available in a dot variable whose name you can specify. For example, say you specify a dot variable 
                        called '_data'. The _data object will include variables like _data.FIRSTNAME, _data.QUANTITY_A5INSTANCE1 
                        (for data in a Repeating Section).
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Dot variable name for captured data</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the dot variable to use for the captured data.</description>
                </item>
                  
                
                
            </list>
            
        </section>
            
    </sections>
    
    
    
    <links>
        <link link="Populating a Repeating Section from a Table"></link>
        <link link="repeatingsection">RepeatingSection</link>
        <link link="ux properties active language">language tags</link>
        <link link="repeatingsection">Repeating Sections</link>
    </links>
</page>