<page>
    <shortlink>ux Server-side actions Save Submitted Data to Tables</shortlink>
    <topic>Save Submitted Data to Table(s)</topic>
    <description>Save the submitted data to one or more tables.</description>
    <sections>
     
        <section>
   <description>In order to define a 'Save Submitted Data to Table(s)' action it is necessary to 
       first add Data Binding to the component, meaning that the component must be tied to a either 
       a SQL or DBF table defined on the server. The process of adding this action to a server-side event 
       on a data-bound component is described on the "[Bind the controls on your UX to fields in one or more existing 
       tables]" page in the [Data Binding] section of the documentation.
   </description>
        </section>        
        
        
        
        
        
           <section>
                 <title>Save Submitted Data to Table(s) Action Properties</title>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
        <section>
             
            <list>
                 <item>
                    <name-title>Save Data</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After submit action</name>
                    <description>Specify the action to take after the submitted data has been saved.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Target page</name>
                    <description>Specify the target page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Use transactions</name>
                    <description>Should all of the SQL statements be wrapped inside a transaction? 
                        For example, if your Dialog has a Repeating Section so that some of the data 
                        is inserted into a 'header' table, and the data from the 'Repeating Section' is 
                        inserted into a 'detail' table, the record inserted into the 'header' table will be 
                        automatically deleted if an error occurs while entering data into the 'detail' table. 
                        Transactions are not supported for .dbf tables. Not all SQL databases support 
                        transactions.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Display debugging info</name>
                    <description>Specify if the SQL statements (for SQL tables), or Xbasic code (for .dbf 
                        tables) should be shown. Note: If the 'After submit action' is set to redirect, 
                        then you will not see the debugging information (unless there is an error), 
                        because control will be redirected to the target page. </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Debugging information placeholder</name>
                    <description>Specify where debugging information should be shown. If you are working in an application 
                        that uses Panels, you will typically put a placeholder in the Panel to show debugging information 
                        in the appropriate panel. Set to <![CDATA[<Default>]]> for the default placement of debugging information.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
                
                <item>
                    <name>Global errors placeholder</name>
                    <description>Specify where global errors (if a commit error that is not specific 
                        to a particular field) should be displayed. If you are working in 
                        an application that uses Panels, you will typically put a placeholder in the 
                        Panel to show Global errors in the appropriate panel. Set to <![CDATA[<Default>]]> 
                        for the default placement of global errors.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
        
        <section>
         
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>After Save Confirmation</name-title>
                     <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>Show a fade out message after record save</name>
                    <description>Specify if a confirmation message should be shown after a record is saved. 
                        Note that the message will not be shown if the action redirects to another page.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Message text</name>
                    <description>Specify the text of the confirmation message.
                         This setting appears once the 'Show a fade out message after record save' property is checked.</description>
                </item>
                 <item>
                    <name>Placeholder id where message is to be shown</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the placeholder where the confirmation message should be shown. 
                        To add a placeholder to the component select the [Placeholder] control in the 'Other Controls' section 
                        of the toolbox.  
                        This setting appears once the 'Show a fade out message after record save' property is checked.</description>
                </item>
                 <item>
                    <name>Message duration</name>
                    <description>Specify the duration of the message in milliseconds. For example, 2000 is 2 seconds. 
                        This setting appears once the 'Show a fade out message after record save' property is checked.</description>
                </item>
                 <item>
                    <name>Message style</name>
                    <description>Specify the style for the message. 'Default' will style the message based on the current 
                        component style. 'None' will not apply any style. You can add your own styling to the message text itself. 
                        This setting appears once the 'Show a fade out message after record save' property is checked.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Client-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of a Javascript function to call after the server-side 
                        event that saves the data has completed. The function gets passed as an 'e' object 
                        that contains certain properties, including 'recordWasSaved' which is true or false. 
                        Note: Event will not fire if the action redirects to another page.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data to pass to client side event</name>
                    <description>You can populate the 'e' object that is passed to the client-side 'After save' 
                        event with information that is available on the server.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save succeeded Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to execute if the save succeeded. 
                        You can use this property as an alternative to specifying the 'After save' 
                        Javascript function.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save failed Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to execute if the save failed. You can 
                        use this property as an alternative to specifying the 'After save' Javascript function.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
        
           <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Server-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name>BeforeRecordInsert Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>AfterRecordInsert Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>BeforeRecordUpdate Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>AfterRecordUpdate Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>BeforeRecordDelete Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>AfterRecordDelete Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>AfterSectionRowRefresh Function</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>onSQLError Function</name>
                    <description>Fires when a SQL error occurs after attempting a CRUD operation. 
                        Allows you to intercept the error message returned by the database and 
                        return a friendlier message.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
         <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Geography Fields</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name>Geocode record</name>
                    <description>When record is saved should the record be geo-coded? i.e. should a 
                        latitude/longitude value be computed for the address?
                    </description>
                </item>
                 <item>
                    <name>Location fields ('Geography' or 'Geometry type fields)</name>
                    <description>When record is saved should a 'location' field (i.e. a 
                        'Geography' or 'Geometry' field) be updated if a longitude or latitude field was edited. </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
            <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Refresh List Controls</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name>Refresh List Controls</name>
                    <description>After data is edited, specify if there are any List controls on the 
                        component that you want to refresh so that the data in the List controls reflect 
                        the edits that were saved.
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>List controls to refresh</name>
                    <description>Specify the ids of the List controls you want to refresh.</description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>&#160;</description>
        </section>
        
          <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Store Current Location Information</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>Store location information when record is saved</name>
                    <description>You can optionally store the location (latitude/longitude) in fields 
                        in the record you are editing. The location information is submitted when the 
                        Ajax callback is made. To submit location information when the 'Submit' button is 
                        pressed, the .Submit() method takes a special flag.
                         For example: submit(",",{getLocationData:true})
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Latitude field</name>
                    <description>Specify the field where the latitude value should be stored.</description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Longitude field</name>
                    <description>Specify the field where the longitude value should be stored</description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Update location field</name>
                    <description>Specify if the table has a Geography/Geometry field that should be updated.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Location field name</name>
                    <description>Brings up a dialog that lets you select the location field to be updated. If the 
                        field dialog does not show all of the fields in the table, go to the 'Data Binding' 
                        pane and click the 'Refresh Table Information' button.
                    </description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Store data for which operation types</name>
                    <description>Specify if the current location information should be stored only when inserting 
                        a new record, or when Inserting and Updating a record.
                    </description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        
        
    </sections>
    
    <links>
        <link link="data binding existing tables">Bind the controls on your UX to fields in one or more existing 
       tables</link>
        <link link="ux components data binding">Data Binding</link>
    </links>
    
    
</page>