<page>
    <shortlink>ux Server-side actions Save Submitted Data to Tables</shortlink>
    <topic>Save Submitted Data to Table(s)</topic>
    <description>Save the submitted data to one or more tables.</description>
    <sections>
     
        <section>
   <description>In order to define a 'Save Submitted Data to Table(s)' action it is necessary to 
       first add Data Binding to the component, meaning that the component must be tied to a either 
       a SQL or DBF table defined on the server.
   </description>
        </section>        
        <section>
            <list>
                 <item>
                    <name-title>Save Data</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After submit action</name>
                    <description>Specify the action to take after the submitted data has been saved.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Target page</name>
                    <description>Specify the target page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Use transactions</name>
                    <description>Should all of the SQL statements be wrapped inside a transaction? 
                        For example, if your Dialog has a Repeating Section so that some of the data 
                        is inserted into a 'header' table, and the data from the 'Repeating Section' is 
                        inserted into a 'detail' table, the record inserted into the 'header' table will be 
                        automatically deleted if an error occurs while entering data into the 'detail' table. 
                        Transactions are not supported for .dbf tables. Not all SQL databases support 
                        transactions.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Display debugging info</name>
                    <description>Specify if the SQL statements (for SQL tables), or Xbasic code (for .dbf 
                        tables) should be shown. Note: If the 'After submit action' is set to redirect, 
                        then you will not see the debugging information (unless there is an error), 
                        because control will be redirected to the target page. </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Global errors placeholder</name>
                    <description>Specify where global errors (if a commit error that is not specific 
                        to a particular field) should be displayed. If you are working in 
                        an application that uses Panels, you will typically put a placeholder in the 
                        Panel to show Global errors in the appropriate panel. Set to <![CDATA[<Default>]]> 
                        for the default placement of global errors.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>After Save Confirmation</name-title>
                     <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                    <item>
                    <name>Show a fade out message after record save</name>
                    <description>Specify if a confirmation message should be shown after a record is saved. 
                        Note that the message will not be shown if the action redirects to another page.
                    </description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Client-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of a Javascript function to call after the server-side 
                        event that saves the data has completed. The function gets passed as an 'e' object 
                        that contains certain properties, including 'recordWasSaved' which is true or false. 
                        Note: Event will not fire if the action redirects to another page.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data to pass to client side event</name>
                    <description>You can populate the 'e' object that is passed to the client-side 'After save' 
                        event with information that is available on the server.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save succeeded Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to execute if the save succeeded. 
                        You can use this property as an alternative to specifying the 'After save' 
                        Javascript function.
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After save failed Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to execute if the save failed. You can 
                        use this property as an alternative to specifying the 'After save' Javascript function.
                    </description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Server-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name-title></name-title>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
         <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Server-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name-title></name-title>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
            <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Server-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name-title></name-title>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
          <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Server-side Events</name-title>
                    <description-title>&#160;</description-title>
                </item>
                   <item>
                    <name-title></name-title>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                
            </list>
        </section>
        
        
    </sections>
</page>