<page>
	<topic>Application Development Tools, Functions</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>A5_ASCII_TABLE()
</title>
			<description>This function displays an ASCII character chart in a popup window.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>A5_CHECKINDEXESDIALOG()
</title>
			<description>The A5_CHECKINDEXESDIALOG() function displays the Check Indexes dialog box. When you run an index check from this dialog Alpha Five checks its index's validity and tells you if index keys are missing.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Action Scripting
</title>
			<description>Action Scripting is used to create and edit sequences of operations or function calls without actually touching the hidden Xbasic code. Action Scripting greatly speeds the development process by removing the developer from the complexities of coding and lets him or her concentrate on what the application is supposed to achieve. However, Action Scripting is also a tool for the Xbasic programmer. You can script a series of actions, then copy the underlying Xbasic code. It is an excellent way to discover recommended programming techniques, Xbasic functions, and speed up the programming process.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>ADO Record Set Genie
</title>
			<description>Selecting Code > More Genies > ADO Record Set while the Code Editor is open displays the ADO Record Set Genie. The ADO Record Set Genie allows you to create an Xdialog form that is bound to an ADO data source. The Xdialog form will allow you to view, edit, delete, and enter records. The genie is available. The genie leads you through the process of:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
	
			<description>selecting the OLE DB Provider</description>
		</case>
		<case>
	
			<description>selecting the Database</description>
		</case>
		<case>
		
			<description>entering user name and password (if necessary)</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			
			<description>building the connection string</description>
		</case>
				
			</cases>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Button Genie
</title>
			<description>The Button Genie generates all the Xdialog code for a button. It is one of several tools that make the creation of Xdialogs much easier. When working on a Xbasic script in the Code Editor, right click and select Genies ... > Xdialog > Button Genie ....
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Calculated Fields
</title>
			<description>Clicking the  icon when designing a form opens the Calculated Fields dialog box, which provides a list of form's calculated fields. Calculated fields are Xbasic expressions that calculate and display values. Here you can add, edit, and delete calculated fields.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Code Editor
</title>
			<description>The Code Editor is used to create and edit Xbasic scripts and functions and Action Script scripts. The Code Editor adds a new tab for each additional project that is currently in progress. There are three types of tabs for:</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Xbasic script and function editing</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Action Script editing</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Interactive testing of Xbasic code</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>You can freely switch back and forth between the windows and copy code between Xbasic scripts. There is a single Interactive window that allows you to operate in an interpretative mode and immediately see how Xbasic expressions evaluate.
You can easily select and open any item shown on the Code tab of the Control Panel. Clicking the sundial icon opens a list of your most recent files.
If you are working with a form or browse, clicking Select Object ... allows you to select any control on the form, and clicking Select Event ... allows you to attach a script to any of the control's events.
</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Code Explorer
</title>
			<description>Clicking View > Code Explorer... from Control Panel when designing a form displays the Code Explorer window. This utility allows to you see and edit all the scripts attached to a form.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Code Library
</title>
			<description>Clicking the book icon when using the Code Editor opens the Code Library. This utility allows you to create multiple named libraries, each of which may contain a large number of code snippets. Clicking on an entry in the code library inserts its code at the cursor location in your script. The user can add, delete, and edit entries in a selected library. Of particular interest is the ability to prompt the user to run a script or prompt the user to input variables before inserting code into the script.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Color Equation Genie
</title>
			<description>When designing a browse or a form with an embedded browse, the Other tab of the browse's Column Properties dialog provides an entry to the Color Equation Genie. This utility helps you design expressions that select row colors.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Debugger
</title>
			<description>The Debugger is an essential companion to the Code Editor. The Debugger allows you to step through an Xbasic script or function and watch as Alpha Five executes each line. You can selectively debug only portions of your code. You can set breakpoints and examine the value of variables, field values, complex expressions - nearly anything available to the script.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Expression Builder
</title>
			<description>Whenever you have to enter an expression and you click on the  icon you will display the Expression Builder. The Expression Builder provides access to all the inputs required to build any type of expression:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Form Fields</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Field Values in any Table's Record</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Functions</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Calculated Fields</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Program Variables</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>System Variables</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Code Snippets in your Code Library</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Objects</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
			
		</case>
		<case>
			
			<description>The Expression Builder automatically evaluates every expression and tells you what the result will be. You can "step through" the records in a table to observe how the evaluation changes. This prevents you from trying to use an invalid expression.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Expression Library
</title>
			<description>Clicking F9 when in the Expression Builder displays the Expression Library. The Expression Library stores expressions that can be inserted into your script with only a couple of keystrokes.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Field Rule Field Events
</title>
			<description>Right clicking on a table and selecting Edit Field Rules... opens the Field Rule Editor. This utility is one of the most powerful tools in the Alpha Five toolkit. Field rules allow you to specify many automatic controls over the behavior of a field. Of particular interest are the Field Rule Field Events, which allow you to attach Xbasic or Action Script code to the instants before and after the cursor enters and exits from a field.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Field Rule Record Events
</title>
			<description>Right clicking on a table and selecting Edit Field Rules... opens the Field Rule Editor. This utility allows you to specify many automatic controls over the behavior of a record. Field Rule Record Events allow you to attach Xbasic or Action Script code to the instants before and after you mark, unmark, delete, or move a record.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Filter Builder
</title>
			<description>Clicking [funnel_img] displays the Filter Builder, which lets you create powerful search operations (and associated Xbasic code) by navigating through easy-to-understand dialog boxes.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Font Equation Genie</title>
			<description>When designing a browse or a form with an embedded browse, the Other tab of the browse's Column Properties dialog provides an entry to the Font Equation Genie. This utility helps you design expressions that select fonts.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Form Variables</title>
			<description>Clicking [v_img] when designing a form opens the Specify Variables dialog box, which provides a list of the form's variable's names, types, and scopes. Here you can add, edit, and delete variables. You can optionally specify their initial values at startup.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Global Variables</title>
			<description>Clicking [v_img] when using the Code Editor opens the Global Variables dialog box, which provides a centralized, easily accessible list of variable names, their types, and their current values. Here you can add, edit, and delete variables. You can optionally specify their initial values at startup.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>HTML Editor</title>
			<description>Clicking View > HTML Editor displays the HTML Editor window. This is a full-featured HTML editor with a WYSIWYG preview mode. You can prepare HTML code here, then copy and paste it into Xdialog forms.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Index and Query List</title>
			<description>Clicking Control I when a form or browse is open displays this list of index and query names, order expressions, and filter expressions.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Index Builder</title>
			<description>Right clicking on a table or set and selecting Define Indexes ... displays the Index Builder. This essential utility builds the indexes for the tables of your database. It allows you to add, delete, or change indexes at any time.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Insert Key Codes</title>
			<description>Clicking Code > More Genies > Insert Key Code when in the Code Editor displays the Insert Key Codes dialog box. This utility generates the code sequences needed to represent control keystrokes on the keyboard.
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Manage Favorites</title>
			<description>Clicking Scripts > Manage Favorites List... when viewing a form or browse displays the Manage Favorites dialog box. This utility lets you create a toolbar and/or a menu that contains a list of scripts that you want you user to be able to run with a button click.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Menu Maker</title>
			<description>Clicking New > Menu from the Code tab of the Control Panel displays the Menu Maker. Here you can create a custom menu that runs internal functions, scripts, or user defined functions. You can specify the menus to appear in very specific circumstances when the user clicks the View menu selection or right clicks on an object. Objects can be forms, browses, form controls, form fields, and browse cells.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Object Explorer</title>
			<description>Clicking View > Object Explorer from the Control Panel displays the Object Explorer window. This utility allows to you identify the components of a form and examine all of their properties. It is particularly useful when debugging form behavior.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>OLE Automation Browser</title>
			<description>Clicking View > OLE Automation Browser when using the Code Editor opens the OLE Automation Object Browser dialog box. This is a new development tool for the programmer who wants to integrate ActiveX controls into his Alpha Five application. The OLE Automation Object Browser allows you to investigate the properties, methods, events, and constants of ActiveX controls on your computer.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Operations Genies</title>
			<description>Clicking Operations > New displays the Create New Operation dialog box. From here you can create and save a large number of repetitive maintenance operations for tables, records, and fields. Then, you can view, copy, and paste the resulting Xbasic code into a script or function.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Order Builder</title>
			<description>The Order Builder lets you create powerful sort operations (and associated Xbasic code) by navigating through an easy-to-understand dialog box.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Query Genie</title>
			<description>Clicking Query > Query Genie ... open the Query Genie. This utility lets you create powerful search and sort operations (and associated Xbasic code) by navigating through easy-to-understand dialog boxes.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Pop-Up Event Editor</title>
			<description>Clicking Object > Popup Event Editor when editing a layout opens the Pop-up Event Editor. This modeless editor allows you to create Xbasic and Action Script routines to respond to object events.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Primary Index or Query Dialog Box</title>
			<description>Clicking Query > Select Index/Query when viewing a layout displays the Primary Index or Query Dialog. This utility allows you to apply or delete indexes, query lists, or saved queries. It also provides a convenient reference for the fields of the currently open table or set.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Script Recorder</title>
			<description>Clicking View > Script Recorder Window opens the Script Recorder. This utility records your actions as you use Alpha Five as Xbasic code. Not every action that you perform interactively with Alpha Five is recorded, but most actions are recorded. It is an excellent way to learn Xbasic.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Static Text Genie</title>
			<description>The Static Text Genie generates properly formatted Xdialog code for static text. It is one of several tools that make the creation of Xdialogs much easier. When working on a Xbasic script in the Code Editor, right click and select Genies ... > Xdialog > Static Text Genie ....</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Table and Set Information</title>
			<description>Clicking View > Structure Information when you are displaying a form or browse opens the Table Information or Set Information dialog box.   These dialog boxes provide a quick summary of table relationships (in a set), field and index characteristics, and database statistics.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Toolbar Editor</title>
			<description>Clicking New > Toolbar from the Code tab of the Control Panel displays the Toolbar Editor. Here you can create a custom toolbar that runs internal functions, scripts, or user defined functions.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Trace Window</title>
			<description>Clicking View > Trace Window from Control Panel displays the Trace window. The Trace window is an essential debugging tool when you are developing scripts. You will notice that Alpha Five sends all types of messages and output to this window as it runs. For example, the Trace window is where you find detailed warning and error messages which would otherwise be too long or numerous for display in a dialog box.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Transform Code Utility</title>
			<description>Clicking Code > Transform when using the Code Editor opens the Transform Code dialog box, which provides a way to apply an Xbasic expression to currently selected lines of code. This utility can be used to remove blank lines from a script or sort entries in a list. It is particularly useful when manipulating lists in a script window.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Un-Dimmed Variables</title>
			<description>Clicking Code > Find Un-DIMmed Variables displays the Undimmed Variables dialog box. This useful utility will search for variables that have not been dimensioned and allow you to DIM them with a couple of mouse clicks.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Xbasic Script Genie</title>
			<description>Selecting Genies... > Xbasic Script Genie... while in the Code Editor displays the Xbasic Script Genie. The Xbasic Script Genie is used to automatically create Xbasic code for common operations.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Xbasic Explorer</title>
			<description>The Xbasic Explorer is an extremely useful tool when you are writing code in the Code Editor, or experimenting with code in the Interactive window. It is a complete reference of all of the commands, functions, methods, properties and constants in the Xbasic language. It also shows you all of the current objects that exist, all global variables that you have created, and all Global Functions that you have defined.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Xdialog Genie</title>
			<description>The Xdialog Genie is single component of the much larger Action Script Genie. However, it is notable as tool that produces fully functional Xdialog boxes with embedded controls and table lookups. The Xdialog Genie produces reusable Xdialog code and is an excellent way to start any Xdialog project.</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	
	
	
	
</section>	
	
	
	
</sections>	
	
<links>
	<link href="images/Filter_button.gif">funnel_img</link>
	<link href="images/Variables_button.gif">v_img</link>
	
</links>	
	
</page>