<page>
    <topic>Importing the Northwind Access Database into MySQL</topic>
    <description>A step-by-step tutorial for importing the Northwind Access Database into MySQL.</description>
    <discussion>The Northwind database is a Microsoft Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. In order to perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the Northwind Access database, the database must be copied to a directory where you have read/write access or converted to another database format. The Northwind Access database can be found inside the *[MDBFiles]* directory in your Alpha Anyhwere installation. Your Alpha Anyhwere install is typically located at *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\a5v12]*. In this tutorial, you will learn how to convert the Northwind Access database to a MySQL database.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <note>This tutorial demonstrates importing the Northwind database into MySQL Server using MySQL Workbench 6.3 CE.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Download the [northwindmysql.zip] file and extract its contents somewhere on your computer. The .zip contains the Northwind Access database in a self-contained SQL file named "northwindmysql.sql".</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Open MySQL Workbench. Under *[ui:Management]*, open the *[ui:Data Import/Restore]* tool.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>On the *[ui:Import from Disk]* tab, select *[ui:Import from Self-Contained File]*. Use the browse button to select the *[northwindmysql.sql]* file you extracted from the download in the first step.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the *[ui:Default Target Schema:]*. The *[northwindmysql.sql]* file does not have a target schema. Name the target schema "northwind".</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [start import] Start Import button to import the Northwind database into the selected target schema. The *[ui:Import Progress]* tab will display the progress of the import.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>You should now see a list of tables in the *[northwind]* schema. The Northwind database is now imported into MySQL.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title></title>
                        <link>images/northwindMySQL6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v12Download/northwindmysql.zip">northwindmysql.zip</link>
        <link href="./images/northwindMySQLImportButton.png">start import</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref>Getting Started With Alpha Anywhere - Build Your First Mobile App</ref>
        <ref>Importing the Northwind Access Database into SQL Server</ref>
        <ref>Configuring the Northwind Access Database</ref>
    </see>
</page>