<page>
	<topic>Create a New Table from Sample Data</topic>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere allows you to create a table by entering sample data.</description>
<sections>
	
<section>
	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Display the Tables/Sets tab of the Control Panel.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click New > New Table (Text mode ...) to display the Create Table - Text Mode dialog box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter the format of the fields, one line per row. The data should be structured as follows:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Field_Name</title>
		<description>Character. Can be up to 32 characters. The field name must start with a letter, and can contain the characters A-Z, 0-9, and the underscore character (_).</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Field_Type</title>
		<description>Character. Can be C (character), N (numeric), D (date), L (logical), M (memo), R (RTF memo), B (bitmap image), J (JPEG image), I (image reference), O (OLE).</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Character_Width</title>
		<description>Numeric. The total number of characters that the field will require.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Decimal_Width</title>
		<description>Numeric. Only required for numeric fields. The portion of the total field width used for the decimal value. The decimal point takes a character position.</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Table > Import Table Structure or Import Table Structure on the toolbar and select one or more field structures from any combination of other tables. Picture
</description>
<figure><link>images/XB_Import_Table_Field.png</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Create Table. The field specification syntax is the same as used in the Create Table dialog box in Design Mode. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/XB_a5_create_table_textmode().png</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>After creating a new table you will be asked to give it a name. Once you name the table and click 'Ok', the new table should appear under the Tables/Sets listed in your workspace. Double click on the new table in your Tables/Sets list and a dialog will load showing the structure of your new table.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Table_Structure.png</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>You can edit this structure by right clicking on the new table under Tables/Sets and selecting Edit Structure
</description>
		<figure><link>images/XB_TBL_POPULATE_FROM_STRING().png</link></figure>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Table_and_Field_Names</ref>
		<ref>Create a New Table</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Create a New Table by Example">Create a New Table by Example</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>