<page>
	<topic>ASWPRODUCTS.A5W</topic>
	<description>The application administrator uses the ASWPRODUCTS.A5W to input, edit, and delete product records.
</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Discussion</title>
		<description>This ASWPRODUCTS.A5W page includes an override of the static contents of the Ship Avail drop down list. The expression that generates the list also establishes the sort order for the list's values.
The page shows a technique to replace or add HTML for a freeform region. In this case, the technique specifies a cascading style sheet to use.
ASWPRODUCTS.A5W contains the NAV_INT navigation and GRD_INTPROD grid components.
</description>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Links</title>
		<description>The Products entry of the NAV_INT navigation component displays the ASWPRODUCTS.A5W page.
</description>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Edits to the Page Source
</title>
		<description>When you look at ASWPRODUCTS.A5W with the Source tab of the HTML Editor, you will see a large amount of HTML and Xbasic code. The HTML Editor placed almost all of it there automatically, as we used the WYSIWYG tab to place the tables, text, graphics, and components on the page. There are a few interesting exceptions, where we changed the page code through the Source tab.
This code is in the override section of the navigation component. The location = "Products" statement highlights the Products entry in the menu. 
</description>
		<example><![CDATA[with tmpl_NAV_INT
    location = "Products"
    componentName = "NAV_INT"
end with
]]></example>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<description>The TABLE.EXTERNAL_RECORD_CONTENT_GET() method returns a list of product availability time windows into the dropavail variable.
</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dropavail = table.external_record_content_get("PathAlias.ADB_Path\lk_avail", "alltrim(Ship_Avail)", "Ship_ord")
]]></example>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<description>This code populates the Ship Avail drop down list with the values stored in the dropavail variable. The code also adds the current page URL from the request.request_uri system variable to a link in the component that is used to reload the page to show updated images.
</description>
		<example><![CDATA[with tmpl_GRD_INTPROD
    style_name = pgstyle
    DetailField_Info17.DropdownBox.Choices = dropavail
    DetailField_Info21.link.ComputedAddress = request.request_uri
    componentName = "GRD_INTPROD"
end with]]></example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>The A5W_INCLUDE() statement is in the top row of the table. It loads TOPPAGE.A5W and displays a standard page header.
</description>
		<example><![CDATA[<%a5 a5w_include("toppage.a5w") 
 %> ]]></example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Page Security Information</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Login Required</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Groups Allowed > Accounting, Administrators, Clerical, Marketing </description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Web Pages</ref>
	</see>
	
	
</page>