<page>
	<topic>CHECKOUTREGISTER.A5W</topic>
<description>The CHECKOUTREGISTER.A5W page is a fourth optional step in the checkout process. It allows a customer to enter security information to complete the registratin process.
</description>	
<sections>
	
<section>
	<title>Discussion</title>
<description>The CHECKOUTREGISTER.A5W page contains the NAV_MAIN navigation and DLG_REGCART dialog component. The dialog's AfterValidate code saves the dialog values to protected session variables. It also saves any edits made to an existing customer record.
A pg parameter is added to the page URL to show what page should be opened after this page is completed. For example: checkoutregister.a5w?pg=processing.htm. The variable pg is saved in a hidden field so it will be available when the page is submitted.
</description>	
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Links</title>
<description>The CHECKOUTCOMP.A5WCHECKOUTCART.A5W and CheckOutCompPayPal.A5W pages may display the CHECKOUTREGISTER.A5W page if the current customer is not found in the customer table. Errors can cause the CHECKOUTREGISTER.A5W page to redirect back to the CHECKOUTCART.A5W page.
</description>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Page Source
</title>
<description>The first part of the page script runs before any HTML on the page. It checks the value of session.protectedchkout. If FALSE (.F.), the user is redirected to CHECKOUTCART.A5W. If the value of session.protectedchkout.firstname is NULL, the user has not finished the second checkout page, and is redirected to CHECKOUTCART.A5W. If the variable pg is not found or is NULL, the user is redirected to CHECKOUTCART.A5W 
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[if eval_valid("session.protectedchkout") = .F. no values passed from page 3
    response.redirect("checkoutcart.a5w")
    end
elseif session.protectedchkout.firstname = "" no values passed from page 3 (first_name was required)
    response.redirect("checkoutcart.a5w")
    end
end if 
if eval_valid("pg") = .F.  check if return page value passed
    response.redirect("checkoutcart.a5w")
    end
elseif pg = ""
    response.redirect("checkoutcart.a5w")
    end
end if ]]></example>
	
</section>			

<section>
	
<description>The variable session.protectedchkout.customer_id will have a value if the user is logged in and found in the customer table. If the user record already exists, they are redirected to the page saved in pg. 
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[if session.protectedchkout.customer_id <> ""  User logged in, values passed from page 3, ok to complete sale
    response.redirect(pg)  redirect selected page
    end
end if ]]></example>
	
</section>	


<section>
	
<description>The A5W_INCLUDE() statement is in the top row of the table. It loads TOPPAGE.A5W and displays a standard page header.</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[<%a5 a5w_include("toppage.a5w")%>]]></example>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>Here is code that displays the following information. 
Check Out
Step 4
New User Registration
Registration is required to complete the sale. 
The Email address entered will become your User ID.  The information on the previous page will be saved in your account. 
A user account will make your next shopping experience easier. Just log in and your information can be added to any new sale.
You can also use the registration to log in and view your sales history. </description>
	<example><![CDATA[<%a5 ?pg %>]]></example>
</section>
<section>
	<title>Page Security Information</title>
	<description>Always Allowed</description>
	
	
</section>

</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Web Pages</ref>
</see>	
</page>