<page>
	<topic>PRODUCTINFO.A5W</topic>
<description>The PRODUCTINFO.A5W is a public page that displays a single product record, allowing a customer to see a larger product picture and a longer product description.
</description>	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Discussion</title>
<description>The page calling the PRODUCTINFO.A5W page provides a filter expression in the URL that filters the GRD_PRODONE grid component so that it displays only one record.
PRODUCTINFO.A5W includes a custom JavaScript file named shopcart.js to show a popup for the shopping cart. The popup window appears when the customer clicks the shopping cart image.
PRODUCTINFO.A5W also contains the NAV_MAIN navigation component and GRD_PRODNAV grid component.
</description>	
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Links</title>
<description>The following links display the PRODUCTINFO.A5W page.
</description>	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>the link in the desc control in the GRD_SPEC grid component
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>the link in the description control in the GRD_PRODS grid component
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>the link in the desc control in the GRD_CART grid component
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>the link in the desc control in the GRD_CARTOUT grid component
</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Edits to the Page Source</title>
<description>When you look at PRODUCTINFO.A5W with the Source tab of the HTML Editor, you will see a large amount of HTML and Xbasic code. The HTML Editor placed almost all of it there automatically, as we used the WYSIWYG tab to place the tables, text, graphics, and components on the page. There are a few interesting exceptions, where we changed the page code through the Source tab.
The a5w_include("loggedinvalues.a5w") statement runs the code on the LOGGEDINVALUES.A5W page. This page creates and sets the values of session.protectedpUser.userid, session.protectedpUser.type, and session.protectedpUser.name.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[a5w_include("loggedinvalues.a5w")]]></example>	
	
</section>	
<section>
<description>Next, the code defines the welcome message for the current user. If no name was found for the current user, welcome is set to NULL. If a user name was found, the welcome message includes the session.protectedpUser.name.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[if session.protectedpUser.name = ""
    welcome = "" ' welcome message for current user shown below product navigation list
else
    welcome = "Welcome "+session.protectedpUser.name+"!"
end if]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>The location = "" statement clears any highlighted entries in the menu.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[with tmpl_NAV_MAIN
    location = ""
    componentName = "NAV_MAIN"
end with]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>The code gets the style from the grid component. It will be needed to format the welcome and header messages.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[pgstyle = tmpl_GRD_PRODNAV.style_name
]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>This code overrides the grid's filter to show only the record where Product_Id matches pid.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[with tmpl_GRD_PRODONE
    DBF.filter = "alltrim(Product_Id)=\"" + alltrim(pid) + "\""
    componentName = "GRD_PRODONE"
end with
]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>The page script then adds the search form. See Creating the Abstracted Search Code.
Later the pgstyle variable styles the heading of the page.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[Since 1982, Your Preferred Sporting Goods Supplier! Now with Many New Products
]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>This code places the customized search control on the page.
</description>	
<example><![CDATA[<%a5 ?search_html %>]]></example>	
</section>	

<section>
<description>If the welcome message is not NULL, the pgstyle variable styles the welcome message.</description>	

</section>	

<section>
	<title>Page Security Information
</title>
<description>Always Allowed</description>	

</section>	

	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Web Pages</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>