<page>
	<topic>Overview of the Development Environment</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Hardware and Software Requirements</title>
<description>Alpha Anywhere includes all the tools that you need to develop and test database applications for the Internet. You can build and test your database, web components, and web pages for functionality on a single computer. With an additional Application Server license, you can even host your web site on the same computer. For security reasons most developers will use a second computer as the web server.
</description>	
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>The Application Server</title>
<description>The Application Server is a fully functional HTTP server that will read, interpret, and deliver .A5W pages to remote Internet users. An .A5W page is a normal HTML page with additional embedded Xbasic code. The Application Server can support varying numbers of sessions, depending on the type of license you have purchased, the power of the computer hosting it, and the speed of your Internet connection.
Alpha Anywhere allows you to run the Application Server in local mode, to develop and test applications and pages on your computer, but does not support remote users. For this, you must purchase the appropriate Application Server license.
</description>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>The Web Component Builder</title>
<description>The Web Component Builder is a powerful utility that makes it easy to make local databases available to remote Internet users. With the Web Component Builder you create "components", which have the built-in capability of reading and writing to Alpha Anywhere, Microsoft Access, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, and other databases that support ADO or ODBC interfaces.
Grid components allow you to display and, scroll through multiple records coming from a single table, multiple joined tables, or a SQL SELECT statement. Grid components support the addition of new records, editing of existing records, and the deletion of records. When combined, grid components support interaction with multiple tables organized in one-to-many relationships.
Dialog components (forms) are able to display controls, set and read variables, and operate independently of any table.
You can style web components using the full range of HTML text and table formatting capabilities. Web components support cascading style sheets (CSS). Alpha Anywhere and above provide a large library of CSS style sheets and sophisticated tools to modify them to your requirements.
Once you create components, you place them on ordinary HTML pages using the HTML Editor. This full featured editor supports the editing of pages in both WYSIWYG and source code display modes. You may add any amount of additional HTML formatting around web components.
You may also place additional custom Xbasic coding inside of A5W pages. The Application Server reads A5W pages, interprets them into standard HTML pages, and delivers them to your Internet users.
</description>	
	
	
</section>		
	
</sections>	
	
	
	
</page>