<page>
    <topic>Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere Data Access Objects (AlphaDAO) let your web or mobile application communicate with a SQL Database. Learn how to create an AlphaDAO connection string to an Access, MySQL, or SQL Server database using the Northwind database that ships with Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Build a Database Connection String</title>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere can communicate with databases using an AlphaDAO connection string. AlphaDAO stands for "Alpha Anywhere Data Access Object". AlphaDAO is an interface through which you can access data stored in SQL, noSQL, DBaaS, SaaS, and other data sources, including static JSON and OData (Open Data Protocol) APIs. (See *[extlink:AlphaDAO Overview@http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index/AlphaDAO Overview]* and *[extlink:AlphaDAO Objects@http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index/AlphaDAO Objects]* for information on using AlphaDAO with xbasic.)</p>
                <p>In this step-by-step tutorial, uou will create an AlphaDAO connection string to communicate with the Northwind database. The Northwind database is a Microsoft Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. If desired, the Northwind database can be imported into SQL Server or MySQL. Choose the type of database connection string you wish to create from the list below, and click the link to get started.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>[Build an Access Connection String]</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>[Build a SQL Server Connection String]</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>[Build a MySQL Connection String]</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Build an Access Connection String</title>
                    <description>This section guides you through the process of setting up an Access AlphaDAO connection string to the Northwind database. In order to perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the Access Northwind database that ships with Alpha Anywhere, it must be copied from the installation directory to a directory in which you have read/write access.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Locate the *[Northwind.mdb]* Access database. It can be found in the installation directory for Alpha Anywhere inside the MDBFiles directory. EG, *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\a5v12\MDBFiles\]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The MDBFiles folder in the Alpha Anyhwere installation directory is where you can find the Northwind Access database</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring0.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[Northwind.mdb]* file and copy it to your Users directory. Your Users directory is typically located in *[bold:C:\Users\Your_Windows_UserName]*.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, build a connection string to the Northwind database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel in Alpha Anywhere, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" in the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind Access database.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>The Connection Type for your new connection string is "Access". The *[ui:Connection Type]* should be set to "Access" when the Create SQL Connection String dialog opens. If it is not, click the [...] button and select Access from the list of options.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Click the browse button for the *[ui:File Name]* option and navigate to where you copied the Northwind database. Select the Northwind.mdb file in your Users directory and click *[ui:Open]*.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select the Northwind database you copied to the Users directory.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind database is correct by clicking the "Test Connection" button. If everything is configured properly, it will display the "Succeeded" message.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Success! The connection string works.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>On some systems where Office 365 is installed, you may receive a *[Can't Load ODBCJI32.dll Error]* message. To fix this error, you will need to install the Microsoft Access Database Engine. You can download the Microsoft Access Database Engine Installer *[extlink:here@https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=13255]*. If the Microsoft Access Database Engine is already installed, running a 'Repair' on the engine should fix the issue. If this does not solve the issue, follow the instructions for [Build a SQL Server Connection String] or [Build a MySQL Connection String] to create a SQL Server or MySQL version of the Northwind database and connection string.</note>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the Access connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The connection string dialog listing the Northwind connection</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the Northwind connection string and return to the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The connection string generated using the Create SQL Connection String dialog</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog. You can now build a mobile or web application that communicates with the Northwind Access database. [Click here] for a list of tutorials that use the Northwind database.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for Access.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Build a SQL Server Connection String</title>
                    <description>This section guides you through the process of creating a SQL Server version of the Northwind database and setting up a SQL Server Alpha DAO connection string to communicate with the SQL Server Northwind database.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Follow the tutorial, *[extlink:Importing the Northwind Access Database into SQL Server@http://www.alphasoftware.com/documentation/pages/GettingStarted/GettingStartedTutorials/Setting Up A Workspace/Northwind/northwindSQLServer.xml]*, to create a Northwind SQL Server database. When you are finished, return to this guide and proceed to the next step.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind SQL Server database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connecton string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind SQL Server database.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[SQLServer]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Set the Connection Type to SQLServer.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Enter the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]* name, *[ui:Port]*, and *[ui:Credentials]* information for your SQL Server instance.</p>
                                <p>Server names should be in the form *[server\instanceName]*. If you omit the instance name, the default instance is assumed.</p>
                                <p>You can click the *[ui:How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?]* link to open the help popup (shown below) to find more information on the server name.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Configuration options for SQL Server.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Help popup for "How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?"</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Test the connection by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. You should see a success message. If you receive an error message, verify the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]*, *[ui:Port]* and *[ui:Credentials]* are correct.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Success! The SQL Server connection works.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Refresh]* button to populate the *[ui:Database]* dropdown box. Select the Northwind SQL Server database you created from the list of options. Click *[ui:OK]* to create the SQL Server connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Configuring SQL Server connection string. This is image shows a configuration for connecting to a SQL Server Express instance. The Northwind database in this SQL Server instance is named "northwindSQLServer".</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog. You can now build a mobile or web application that communicates with the Northwind SQL Server database. [Click here] for a list of tutorials that use the Northwind database.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for SQL Server.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Build a MySQL Connection String</title>
                    <description>This section guides you through creating a MySQL version of the Northwind database and setting up a MySQL AlphaDAO connection string to communicate with the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Download *[extlink:northwindmysql.zip@http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v12Download/northwindmysql.zip]* and unzip the file. This zip file contains a self-contained file of the MySQL Northwind database called "northwindmysql.sql".</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Contents of the northwindmysql.zip archive.</title>
                                <link>images/northwindMySQL.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Import the self-contained Northwind database into MySQL. You can find instructions *[extlink:here@https://dev.mysql.com/doc/workbench/en/wb-admin-export-import-management.html#wb-mysql-connections-navigator-management-data-import-restore]* for using MySQL Workbench to Import the database. Use the "Import from Self-Contained File" option for the Data Import.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Doing a Data Import using MySQL Workbench</title>
                                <link>images/mySQLDataRestore.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>*[Backup any existing MySQL databases]* before importing the Northwind database.</note>
                            <warning>*[There is no schema specified in the northwindmysql.sql file.]* You must specify the *[ui:Default Target Schema]*, otherwise the tables will be imported into the active schema. *[This may result in data being overwritten]* if the active schema contains table names matching tables in the Northwind database!</warning>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind MySQL database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connecton string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind MySQL database.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[MySQL]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Set the Connection Type to MySQL.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog Options for a "MySQL" Connection Type.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Configure the MySQL *[ui:Options]* for the connection. Enter "localhost" in *[ui:Hostname]*.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Enter the MySQL *[ui:Port]* number. If you used the default port number for your MySQL install, the port should be "3306".</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Enter the *[ui:User]* for accesing the MySQL database. On your development machine, this can be "root" or a user account you created.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Enter the password for the *[ui:User]* account specified.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind datbase is correct by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. You should see a success message. If you receive an error message, verify the *[ui:Hostname]*, *[ui:Port]*, *[ui:User]*, and *[ui:Password]* are correct.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Success! The connection string to the MySQL database works.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the MySQL Northwind database you created from the *[ui:Database]* list. If *[ui:Database]* does not have any options, click the *[ui:Refresh]* button. If it still does not list any databases, verify the User you have chosen has access to the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Configuring the MySQL connection string. The Northwind database in this MySQL instance is named "northwind".</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the MySQL connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Click OK to save the MySQL Connection string.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog. You can now build a mobile or web application that communicates with the Northwind MySQL database. [Click here] for a list of tutorials that use the Northwind database.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for MySQL</title>
                                <link>images/connectionstringMySQL6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Getting Started Tutorials</title>
            <description>The tutorials listed below are part of our Getting Started Tutorials. Follow these step-by-step tutorials to build a mobile or web application that communicates with the Northwind database.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[[Build Your First Mobile App]]*</p>
                        <p>Build a Mobile Application that interacts with the Northwind database, an Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. You will learn how to build connection strings to interact with SQL databases and the basic building blocks of mobile applications in Alpha Anywhere. When you complete this tutorial, you will have a mobile application that is ready to deploy using PhoneGap Build.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[[Building Your First Web Application]]*</p>
                        <p>Get a flying start to building your first web application with Alpha Anywhere's Flying Start Genie. In this tutorial, you'll build a web application with a Tabbed UI interface that can be used to manage data in the Northwind database, an Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. You will learn how the Flying Start Genie can be used to quickly get started building a web application. You will also learn how to add action javascript for opening grid components and how to create a UX component as an alternative interface for editing records in a Grid.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="images/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link href="/images/$$generic.link.png">ManageConnStr</link>
        <link href="#section1_Build an Access Connection String">Build an Access Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section1_Build a SQL Server Connection String">Build a SQL Server Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section1_Build a MySQL Connection String">Build a MySQL Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section1_Getting Started Tutorials">Click here</link>
        <link href="../Build a Mobile App/index.xml">Build Your First Mobile App</link>
        <link href="../Build A Web App/index.xml">Building Your First Web Application</link>
    </links>
</page>