<page>
    <shortlink>mobile and web components</shortlink>
    <topic>Mobile and Web Components</topic>
    <description>Components are the building blocks of Alpha Anywhere applications. A workspace can contain one or more components. Some types of components are better suited for mobile applications or web applications.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Building Mobile Applications</title>
            <description>The UX Component is used exclusively to create Mobile Applications.</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Name</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[UX Component]</name>
                    <description>The UX Component is the core component for building mobile apps.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Building Web Applications</title>
            <description>All components in Alpha Anywhere can be used to build web applications. A variety of highly-customized components are available to provide specific functionality, such as calendars, image galleries, or video players. Note that everything that you can build using other types of components can also be built using the UX Component.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Name</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[UX Component]</name>
                    <description>The UX component is an ideal choice for any web and mobile application due to its versatility, including the wide range of controls for displaying and editing your data as well as it's ability to integrate with multiple data sources.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Grid Component]</name>
                    <description>A Grid Component is used to provide an interface for viewing and modifying data in database in web applications. For a lighter-weight alternative, consider the [List Control] in a UX Component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Tabbed UI Component]</name>
                    <description>The Tabbed UI Component can be used to create a tabbed interface for a web application.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Login Component]</name>
                    <description>The Login Component is used with the Alpha Anywhere Web Security System. It provides an interface for users to enter their credentials (i.e. user name and password) as well as optional options for password reset.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[AppLauncher Component]</name>
                    <description>The AppLauncher component can be used to determine the type of device a user is running on and dynamically load a component that was designed for the device. This same behavior can be accomplished by building a response [UX Component].</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Page Layout Component]</name>
                    <description>The Page Layout Component is used to create a complex page layout for a web application. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Navigation System Component]</name>
                    <description>The Navigation System component can be used to add horizontal or vertical toolbars with submenus, allowing you to add navigation to a web application. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Maintenance Component</name>
                    <description>The Maintenance Component can be used to perform maintenance on DBF tables used in any application built with Alpha Anywhere. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Google Map Component]</name>
                    <description>The Google Map Component can be used to display a Map that uses the Google Maps API. A Google Maps API key (set in the [Project Properties]) is required to use this component. See also [Alternative Views] (Grids) and the UX Component [Map Control]. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Video Player Component]</name>
                    <description>The Video Component lets you display and play an HTML5 video, Flash video, or an embedded hybrid of HTML5/Flash video and player from YouTube. See also the [VideoPlayer], [VideoPlayer (mobile-optimized)], and [VideoRecorderPlayer] controls in the [UX Component]. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Calendar Component]</name>
                    <description>The Calendar Component is a third party component that allows you to display and edit appointments, events, etc. It requires a Web2Cal license, which must be purchased separately. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Image Gallery Component]</name>
                    <description>The Image Gallery Component can be used to create an image gallery that displays images stored in a folder on a server. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Custom Component]</name>
                    <description>Custom Components allow you to create a complete custom component where you define the Xbasic code that generates the HTML and JavaScript the component will emit. This component type is intended for advanced developers. This component is not available in Community Edition.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Legacy Components</title>
            <description>Several legacy components are also included in Alpha Anywhere These components are for compatibility purposes only for applications built using older versions of Alpha Anywhere. Legacy components are not available in Community Edition.</description>
            <obsolete>These components are obsolete and should not be used in applications built using Alpha Anywhere.</obsolete>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Name</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Dialog (Classic)</name>
                    <description>The Dialog allows you to create forms to prompt the user for information. The Dialog (Classic) does not support Ajax callbacks nor does it work with Alpha Anywhere's security system. Use the [UX Component] instead.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Grid Linker</name>
                    <description>The Grid Linker component allows you to link two or more Grid components in a one-to-many relationship. The same thing can be accomplished using [Linked Grids] or [Row Expanders] in a Grid Component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Tabbed Grid Linker</name>
                    <description>the Tabbed Grid Linker component displays a parent Grid component with a series of tab buttons that allows you to select which component to display. The same thing can be accomplished with [Linked Grids] or [Row Expanders] in a Grid Component.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a Component</title>
            <description>
                <p>New Components can be added using the *[ui:[new]New]* button on the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar. The *[ui:[new]New]* button will open the New File dialog.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/new_web_component1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Select *[ui:Web Components]* and click *[ui:Next]*. Choose the component to create from the choices shown.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/new_web_component2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The New File dialog displays your installed user-defined components in addition to all the provided system components. Legacy components are shown below all other components and are hidden by default (*[recommended]*).</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/$$file.new.png">new</link>
        <link link="grid properties row expander">Row Expanders</link>
        <link link="grid properties linked content section">Linked Grids</link>
        <link link="ux component">UX Component</link>
        <link link="guides custom and userdefined custom components">Custom Component</link>
        <link link="AppLauncher Component">AppLauncher Component</link>
        <link link="server component Image Gallery Component">Image Gallery Component</link>
        <link link="web components calendar component">Calendar Component</link>
        <link link="server component Video Player Component">Video Player Component</link>
        <link link="server component Google Map Component">Google Map Component</link>
        <link link="guides login component">Login Component</link>
        <link link="guides navigation system component">Navigation System Component</link>
        <link link="page layout component">Page Layout Component</link>
        <link link="tabbed ui builder">Tabbed UI Component</link>
        <link link="grid components">Grid Component</link>
        <link link="ux template SecurityFramework LoginComponent">SecurityFramework-LoginComponent</link>
        <link link="ux template SecurityFramework LoginComponentMobileApp">SecurityFramework-LoginComponentMobileApp</link>
        <link link="ux data controls list control">List Control</link>
        <link link="ux data controls map control">Map Control</link>
        <link link="grid alternative views properties">Alternative Views</link>
        <link link="Web Project Profile Properties">Project Properties</link>
        <link link="ux controls other controls videoplayer">VideoPlayer</link>
        <link link="ux data controls more controls videoplayer controls">VideoPlayer (mobile-optimized)</link>
        <link link="ux data controls more controls video recorder player controls">VideoRecorderPlayer</link>
        
    </links>
</page>