<page build="0">
    <shortlink>security seedusersgroups</shortlink>
    <topic>Seed Users and Groups</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Seed users and groups are managed using the Security Framework tools in the development environment.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Seed users and groups are used during the development process to aid with configuring security permissions for page and component access as well as provide the initial set of users and groups for an application when it's first published. The seed users and groups in an app are managed using the Users and Groups tools found in the Web Security settings on the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Web Security Tools</title>
                <alt>Web Security Tools</alt>
                <link>images/usersGroups.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Users and Groups]* tool provides an interface for working with seed users and groups in the development environment. The dialog has two tabs: *[ui:Users]* and *[ui:Groups]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editing Seed Users</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Users]* tab displays a list of users on the left and their assigned groups on the right. Users can be added or removed from groups using the checkboxes located to the left of the group names. The *[ui:Add User]*, *[ui:Edit User]*, and *[ui:Delete User]* buttons along the bottom can be used to add new users, edit user ids and passwords, or remove users from the seed users.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Web Users and Groups - Users</title>
                <alt>Web Users and Groups - Users</alt>
                <link>images/users.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Edit User]* dialog includes a button to edit the Extended User Information for the seed user. If the Extended User Information Table has not been configured for the project, you will be prompted to create one. See [Storing Additional User Information] and [Extended User Information Table] to learn more.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Edit User dialog</title>
                <alt>Edit User dialog</alt>
                <link>images/editUser.png</link>
            </figure>
            <important>
                <p>Information entered into the Extended User Information is not published with seed users and groups for an application and may not be available in your published application if you have separate development and production databases (which is recommended). See [Managing Users and Groups in an Application] and [Storing Additional User Information] for more information about working with Extended User Information in a published application.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Editing Seed Groups</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Groups]* tab displays a list of groups on the left and the users who are members of the group on the right. Users can be added or removed from groups using the checkbox to the left of the user id. The *[ui:Add Group]*, *[ui:Edit Group]*, and *[ui:Delete Group]* buttons can be used to add new groups, rename a group, or remove a group from the seed groups.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Web Users and Groups - Groups</title>
                <alt>Web Users and Groups - Groups</alt>
                <link>images/groups.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Viewing Page/Component Authorization</title>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to managing groups, you can also view summary group information for Pages and Components using the *[ui:]* link. The *[ui:Security Summary for Group]* displays two lists: a list of all files that access is always allowed and a list of files that can only be accessed if the user is a member of the selected group. The selected group is displayed in the dialog's title.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Security Summary for Group: ADMINISTRATOR</title>
                <alt>Security Summary for Group: ADMINISTRATOR</alt>
                <link>images/groupSummary.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:Security Summary for Group]* is informational only. To change access permissions for files and folders, see [Configuring Page and Folder Security] and [Configuring Component and Report Security].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Importing/Exporting Seed Users and Groups</title>
            <description>
                <p>Import/Export options are available on both the *[ui:Users]* and *[ui:Groups]* tabs for seed users and groups. These options can be used to export your seed users and groups from one project and import them into another.</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Import/Export Tool</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[ui:Import Users from Excel file]*</name>
                            <description>Available on both the *[ui:Users]* and *[ui:Groups]* tabs. Imports users from an Excel file. The Excel file must define the User id, Password, and Groups to assign the user. Use the *[ui:Create sample Excel file]* link in the *[ui:Import Users/Groups from Excel]* dialog to get a template Excel file. You must specify a fully qualified file path and name with an .xlsx extension to generate the template. Any users and groups specified in the template will be created if the user or group does not exist in the seed users and groups.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[ui:Export/Import Users JSON]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>Available on the *[ui:Users]* tab. Used to export or import Users as JSON. When exporting, the JSON containing the seed users is shown, which you can copy and paste into the import Users as JSON window in another project or save to a file and shared with another developer.</p>
                                <p>When importing, you will be prompted to enter the JSON containing the users to import. The JSON is typically created by exporting users as JSON from another project.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[ui:Import / Export Users to/from .dbf Table]*</name>
                            <description>Available on the *[ui:Users]* tab. This option can be used to import or export seed Users from a .dbf Table from another project.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[ui:Export/Import groups]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>Available on the*[ui:Groups]* tab.  Used to export or import seed groups as JSON. When exporting, the JSON containing the seed groups is shown, which you can copy and paste into the import Groups window in another project or save to a file and shared with another developer.</p>
                                <p>When importing, you will be prompted to enter the JSON containing the groups to import. The JSON is typically created by using this tool to export groups from another project.</p></description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[ui:Export/Import group membership]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>Available on the*[ui:Groups]* tab.  Used to export or import seed users' group membership as JSON. When exporting, the JSON containing the seed group membership is shown, which you can copy and paste into the import group membership window in another project or save to a file and shared with another developer.</p>
                                <p>When importing, you will be prompted to enter the JSON containing the group membership to import. The JSON is typically created by using this tool to export group membership from another project.</p></description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Publishing Seed Users and Groups</title>
            <description>
                <p>The first time an application is published to the Alpha Anywhere Application Server, the seed users and groups are copied to the server. The way seed users and groups are published depends on the hosting solution you're using. Links to introductory details about publishing your application for Alpha Cloud, the Application Server for IIS, and the Classic Application Server are listed below.</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>[Publishing Your First Application to the Alpha Cloud] - includes a basic overview of publishing users and groups (referred to as "roles" in Alpha Cloud)</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>[Create an IIS Publish Profile] - this article links to [Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Provider Configuration], which contains more detailed information on setting up a security provider for storing users and groups (referred to as "roles" in IIS) in a published application.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>[Publish an Application to the Classic Server Using HTTP Publish] - Includes information on how to ensure seed users and groups are published to the Classic Server.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>Seed users usually not re-published with an application after their initial deployment unless explicitly published. Management of users is done using interfaces included in the published application. These interfaces must be added to your project. You can use the [Security Quick Setup Genie] to quickly add interfaces for login and user management.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
<!--    <next> See [Managing Users and Groups in an Application] to learn how to create and use components to manage users and groups in a published app.
        <link link="security manageusersgroupsapp">Managing Users and Groups in an Application</link>
    </next> -->
    <links>
       <!-- <link link="security manageusersgroupsapp">Managing Users and Groups in an Application</link> -->
        <link link="security framework extended user information table">Storing Additional User Information</link>
        <link link="security%20framework%20extended%20user%20information%20table">Extended User Information Table</link>
        <link link="web application security guide#group_Page%20Security">Configuring Page and Folder Security</link>
        <link link="web application security guide#group_Component%20Security">Configuring Component and Report Security</link>
        <link link="alpha%20cloud%20alpha%20anywhere%20developers%20guide%20publishing%20your%20application">Publishing Your First Application to the Alpha Cloud</link>
        <link link="create%20a%20publish%20profile">Create an IIS Publish Profile</link>
        <link link="alpha%20anywhere%20application%20server%20for%20iis%20provider%20configuration">Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS Provider Configuration</link>
        <link link="publishing%20to%20a%20remote%20server%20using%20http">Publish an Application to the Classic Server Using HTTP Publish</link>
        <link link="security quicksetup">Security Quick Setup Genie</link>
    </links>
</page>