<page>
	<topic>User Interface / User Experience</topic>
	
<description>Alpha Anywhere allows you to build applications for the desktop/web, and for mobile devices - such as smartphones and tablets. You can also build single applications that have interfaces that can adapt to each type of device. A typical example, might be an application tailored for data collection on a tablet, but also includes an administrative interface that is accessed from a web browser on a desktop computer. </description>	
	
	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Components</title>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere applications are created using Alpha Anywhere Components. Think of these as building blocks of your application. 
Some components are designed specifically for mobile devices, while others are best used for desktop/web applications because they are more memory or processor intensive. 
</description>
	
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Desktop vs Web</title>
	<description>When Alpha Five, the predecessor of Alpha Anywhere, was first created, it was designed to build only Windows desktop applications. The tools for doing this are still available in the Control Panel of the Alpha Anywhere interface, which allows you to modify legacy applications that were created in Alpha Five. 

</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>While you can use these older tools for building new desktop applications, we strongly suggest that you not use these tools, and instead use Web components. This allows you to bring your application to the web in the future if you desire. It also allows you to use non-Windows machines to access your application, such as Mac computers and less expensive machines like Netbooks. 
</description>
</section>
<section>
	<title>Mobile Considerations</title>
	<description>Mobile devices differences from Desktop, Laptop, and Notebook computers in several important ways - besides simply screen size and processing power. These differences include: </description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Varying Screen Size and Orientation </title>
			<description>Because phones and tablets can be held in two different orientations (portrait and landscape), and because different devices use different screen resolutions, your application needs to take this into consideration. There are two approaches to this: [Adaptive Design and Responsive Design]. Adaptive design detects the size and/or orientation of the screen and launches a different versions of the interface. While a Responsive Design has just one version of the interface that can automatically change it's size and shape. </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Hardware Access</title>
			<description>Mobile devices have special hardware, like cameras, GPS, accelerometers, battery sensors, and more. Some features, like GPS, can be accessed by HTML5 and Javascript, but other require native code written for the device on which it is run. Alpha Anywhere includes this code for you through [PhoneGap]. 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Mobile Deployment</title>
			<description>Mobile applications can be deployed in several ways. You can simply access an HTML5 application by using the phone or tablet's browser. Or, you can wrap your HTML5 application in the [PhoneGap] shell and distribute it on an adhoc basis, in a public store (like the Apple App Store), or in a private store accessible only to members of your company or organization. See [Deployment] for more information. </description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
	<links>
		<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/testdoc/pages/Obsolete/from%20tlc/UX/Adaptive%20and%20Responsive%20Design.xml">Adaptive Design and Responsive Design</link>
	<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/testdoc/pages/Guides/PhoneGap/index.xml">PhoneGap</link>
	<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/testdoc/pages/Obsolete/from%20tlc/Deployment/index.xml">Deployment</link>
	</links>
	
</page>