<page>
   <topic>A5WS_User_File_Field_List Function</topic>
   <syntax>Field_List as C = a5ws_User_File_Field_List([C format [,* request ]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     
     <argument>
         <name>Field_List</name>
         <description>A CR-LF list of user table fields used in the current web project.</description>
     </argument>
     
     <argument>
         <name>format</name>
         <description>Optional. A display  format information to use to output field information. Options are:
 </description>
 <list><item><name>
 "n" =  fieldname
</name></item><item><name>
 "t" =  simple field type
</name></item><item><name>
 "w" =  field width 
 </name></item><item><name>
 Default is fieldname only. If format is specified, the output will use the "|" delimiter between values. 
</name></item></list>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>request</name>
         <description>Optional. The Request system variable. This variable explicitly passes all request variables  to the function. Required if run from a web page.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Retrieve a list of active fields in CR-LF list for web user table in the current project. Format - n - fieldnames, t - simple field type, w - field width.  </description>
   <discussion>
Retrieve a list of active fields in CR-LF list for web user table in the current project. The field list will be determined by the current security settings and will show only fields currently used. The Request system variable is only needed if the function is used on a web page or in a web component. 
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>The following code run in the interactive window will return a list of user table fields for the current selected web project profile. </description>
            <example><![CDATA[
?a5ws_User_File_Field_List()
= Email
Guid
PassEnt
PassExp
Password
RedirPage
RememberMe
Ulink
Userid
]]></example>
       </section>
       
        <section>
            <description>The following code run in the interactive window will return a list of user table fields and information about the fields. The width information is helpful when building a web component. </description>
            <example><![CDATA[
?a5ws_User_File_Field_List("ntw")
= Email|C|40
Guid|C|36
PassEnt|T|17
PassExp|T|17
Password|C|40
RedirPage|C|60
RememberMe|L|1
Ulink|C|40
Userid|C|60
]]></example>
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   <limitations>Web applications only.</limitations>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Web/Web Application/Application Functions/Web Application Functions.html">Web Application Functions</ref>
      <ref>Retrieve a list of the active fields for the web user table in the current project</ref>
   </see>

<terms>web application,security,a5w,display,field,function,list,security settings,system,variable,window</terms>

</page>