<page api="js">
    <shortlink>corejs dollar gvs function</shortlink>
    <topic>$gvs Function</topic>
    <prototype>$gvs(element)</prototype>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>element</name>
            <types>
                <type>element object</type>
                <type>string</type>
                <type>array</type>
            </types>
            <description>A string with the ID or NAME of the element, a pointer to an HTML element, or an array of either of the previous.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <returns>
        <return>
            <name>Value</name>
            <type>array</type>
            <description>Returns the value of the specified element(s).</description>
        </return>
    </returns>
    <description>The $gvs() function gets the value from a single 'conceptual' element.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A 'conceptual' control in the HTML can be represented by multiple physical elements. For example, a radio button with the choices 'Green', 'Red' and 'Blue' can be thought of as a single 'conceptual' control, but the HTML will contain three physical elements, one for each of the options.</p>
        <p>If the control passed in has multiple values, as with a SELECT set to allow multiple selections, or a checkbox group, the function will return an array of values. Otherwise it will return a string of the value.</p>
        <p>You can also use $gvs() against elements that are not form controls - the function will return the innerHTML property of the element.</p>
    </discussion>
    <example code="js"><![CDATA[/*Assume that the HTML contains this markup for a radio button group
<input type="radio" name="FavoriteColor" value="Red"  id="radio1"  /><label for="radio1">Red</label>
<input type="radio" name="FavoriteColor" value="Blue"  id="radio2"  /><label for="radio2">Blue</label>
<input type="radio" name="FavoriteColor" value="Green"  id="radio3"  /><label for="radio3">Green</label>
*/
 
/*Get the selected value in the 'FavoriteColor' radio button control*/
alert($gvs('FavoriteColor'));
 
 
/*Assume that the HTML contains a SELECT control that allows multiple selections.
Red and Green are currently selected
<select id="FavoriteColorSelect" size="5"  multiple="multiple">
    <option selected="selected">Red</option>
    <option>Blue</option>
    <option selected="selected">Green</option>
</select>
*/
 
/*Get the current selections in the SELECT control into an array*/
arr = $gvs('FavoriteColorSelect');
 
/*Assume that the HTML contains a SPAN with an ID of 'span1'
Display the innerHTML property of the span.*/
?alert($gvs('span1'));]]></example>
            <important>Use *[link:{dialog.object}.getPointer()@ux component getpointer method]* to get the DOM element for a control.</important>
    <see>
        <ref link="Using Core Libraries in Components">Using Core Library Functions in Components</ref>
    </see>
</page>