<page build="0">
    <shortlink>gridprops alternate column shading</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Shading and Dividers Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Alternate Column Shading">Alternate Column Shading</topic>
    <description>Checking this box creates columns with alternating colors in the Grid layout. Checking the Alternate Column Shading property reveals two more properties, Even column band size and Odd column band size.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>The 'even' and 'odd' are supposed to refer to the color of a given band. Due to a legacy bug, however, the Even and Odd colors on the Alternate Column Shading property are actually reversed, i.e the even band is actually an odd number. The number after these two properties, 1 by default, indicates how many grid columns that color band encompasses.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Alternate Column Shading properties</title>
                <alt>Alternate Column Shading properties</alt>
                <link>images/1_shading5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Even column band size 1, Odd column band size 1</title>
                <alt>Even column band size 1, Odd column band size 1</alt>
                <link>images/1_shading2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Specifying Colors</title>
            <description>
                <p>The colors used when alternating column colors are defined in the Web Theme assigned to the Grid component. The *[ui:Data alt class name]* property in the Grid's web theme configuration defines the class name(s) applied to the alternate columns. Even columns in the Grid use the default background color. Odd columns use the *[ui:Data alt class name]*.</p>
                <p>See [Alternate Row Shading] for more information on how to customize the alternate colors used in the Grid.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>Both the alternate rows and alternate columns use the same class name in the web theme, *[ui:Data alt class name]*.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Component Xbasic Implementation</title>
            <description>The Xbasic that defines these settings in the Grid's definition are:</description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA['Alternate column shading
tmpl.alternate_column_bands as L
'Even column band size
tmpl.even_column_band_size as N
'Odd column band size
tmpl.odd_column_band_size as N]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="gridprops alternate row shading">Alternate Row Shading</link>
    </links>
</page>