<page build="0">
    <shortlink>grid shading and dividers conditional style server_side</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Shading and Dividers Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Conditional Style (Server-Side)">Conditional style (server-side)</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Applies custom CSS styling to rows in the Grid that match a Condition. The Condition is computed on the server.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>You can use the Conditional style property to set conditional styles for rows in the Grid. This property can be used to call out data in the Grid that requires special attention. For example, this property could be used to highlight overdue invoices or client jobs that are not assigned to an employee.</p>
        <p>If the conditional expression evaluates to true, the styling is applied to the Grid row. If multiple expressions evaluate to true for a row, the first expression is applied.</p>
        <p>The conditional expressions can refer to values in the Grid row as well as summary values. Field names can be inserted using the *[ui:Insert Fieldname]* link. *[ui:Insert Function]* can be used to insert a function from a list of functions available for use in the server-side computation.</p>
        <p>The *[ui:Conditional style (server-side)]* is evaluated on the server before the data for the Grid is downloaded. If you are displaying a large number of records, conditional server-side styling can have a negative performance impact. If you experience poor performance using the *[ui:Conditional style (server-side)]*, consider using the [Conditional style (client-side)] instead to apply dynamic styling.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Conditional Style (server-side) dialog</title>
                <alt>Conditional Style (server-side) dialog</alt>
                <link>images/serversideConditional.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Rules for Expressions</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Conditional style (server-side)]* expressions are written using Xbasic syntax (examples below):</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Logical operators are *[xb:.and.]*, *[xb:.or.]*, and *[xb:.not.]*.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>String literals are defined using double quotes.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <example caption="Example Expressions"><![CDATA[quantity > 100 .and. quantity < 200
state = "MA"]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Using Summary Values</title>
            <description>
                <p>If a field has a summary value calculation, the summary value can be referenced in the expression using the syntax:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[summary.fieldname.summary_type]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>where *[em:fieldname]* is the field's name and *[em:summary_type]* is the type of summary calculation. For example, if you have enabled *[ui:Average]* for a field called *[quantity]*, the summary value is referenced as:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[summary.quantity.average]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>If the field name contains a space (e.g. "quantity ordered"), the space is replaced with an underscore:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[summary.quantity_ordered.average]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>See [Summary Values] to learn how to enable summary values for a field.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="gridprops conditional style clientside">Conditional style (client-side)</link>
        <link link="summary%20values">Summary Values</link>
    </links>
</page>