<page>
	<topic>Print Current Record</topic>
<description>You can print records from within form or browse View. The toolbar includes a drop-down button, which you can set to either the Print Current Record button, or the Print/Send Selected Records button.</description>	
<sections>
	
<section>
	
	<figure><link>images/Dropdown_Print_Menu.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The Print Current Record button displays a dialog that lets you Print, Preview, Email, or Save to File the current record using any of the available layouts. For example, while viewing a particular record, you could use this command to print the current record using a Label layout that you previously defined.
</description>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select File > Print Current Record....
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select your print option by clicking either Print, Preview, Email, or Save to File.

</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, select a different layout type.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the layout to print from the list box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to see the Xbasic code that you are generating.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click Copy to copy this Xbasic code to the clipboard.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Click OK to continue.</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [save_img] to save the current settings of the dialog box for the next time you use it.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected Print in step 2, click Print to continue or Cancel to quit.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected Preview in step 2, click Preview to continue or Cancel to quit.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected Email in step 2,
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Optionally, click Send Options to display the Options dialog box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Select the Send As mode. The choices are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Adobe Acrobat PDF File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Dynamic HTML File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Rich Text Format File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Plain Text" 
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Make a choice in Send Using. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Default Email Client" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Alpha Anywhere Email Client" 
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>4. Click OK to save your choices or Cancel to discard them.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Send to continue or Cancel to quit.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected Save to File in step 2,
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Select the Save As mode. The choices are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Adobe Acrobat PDF File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Dynamic HTML File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Rich Text Format File" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Plain Text" 
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Check the Open file check box if you want to see the file you are saving.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click OK to save your choices or Cancel to discard them.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Save to continue or Cancel to quit.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Saving Settings
</title>
<description>If, when you select Print Current Record, you want Alpha Anywhere to default to a particular layout (for example, a Letter layout called ThanksForOrder ):
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Select the Layout Type in the drop-down list box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select the Letter layout you want to use.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Click the Save button (image of blue floppy disk in the lower left corner) to remember your selection the next time you use this command.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Creating a Button or a Script that Prints</title>
<description>If you want to create a script or a button to automate printing the current record, then you can click the [binoculars_img] View Xbasic button to show the Xbasic code associated with the command to print the current record. If you want a button to produce this particular print action.
</description>	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Sketch the button on your form.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Copy this code.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Right click the button and select Events > OnPush.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Paste this code.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
<section>
	<title>Print/Send Selected Records
</title>
<description>The Print/Send Selected Records button displays the Print Layout Genie that lets you print, preview, email, or save to a file the records in the current table or set, using any of the layouts that have been defined for that table or set.
</description>	
	
</section>

	
</sections>	
	<links>
		<link href="images/Preview_Button.gif">binoculars_img</link>
		
		<link href="images/Save_button.gif">save_img</link>
	</links>
	
<see>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Print Layout Genie">Print Layout Genie</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>