<page build="0">
    <shortlink>data binding properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Data Binding</topic>
    <description>
        <p>You can use data binding to create new tables with fields that can then be used within the UX component. This is done on the '[Data Binding]' page of the UX Builder. Once the data from a new or existing table has been bound to the component you can use the properties in this section to bind a control to one of the fields in that data-bound table. It is also possible to [match controls to a data bound table] on the Data Binding page itself.</p>
    </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Updateable</title>
            <description>
                <p>Whether or not the value in this control should be saved to a field in a table. If this box is unchecked, the control is still editable, and the value in the control will still be submitted when the Dialog is submitted.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Table alias</title>
            <description>
                <p>The table alias to which this control is bound. If not bound, leave blank or specify: *[code:*unbound]*</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Field name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The field in the data bound table where this control should be saved.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>NULL if blank</title>
            <description>
                <p>Applies only to SQL Tables. If checked, a *[sql:NULL]* value is inserted into the table if the field is blank.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section build="6999">
            <title>Encrypt field</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Encrypt field]* property specifies whether or not data in a field is encrypted. If checked, data is encrypted by Alpha Anywhere when written to the field and decrypted when read from the field.</p>
                <p>When Alpha Anywhere encrypts the data, it prepends the field data with the prefix *[sql:ENCRYPTED:]*.</p>
                <p>*[Field encryption is only supported for character fields.]*</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section build="6999">
            <title>Encryption key</title>
            <description>
                <p>Enabling *[ui:Encrypt field]* exposes the *[ui:Encryption key]* field. The *[ui:Encryption key]* is used to encrypt and decrypt the values in the field. This key can be the same for all fields or unique for each field.</p>
                <p>The *[ui:Encryption key]* can be defined at design-time, either in this property or in the Project Properties, or at runtime using a session variable. For example:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[session.myKey]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>If you define the key in Project Properties, set *[ui:Encryption key]* to *[xb:&lt;Default&gt;]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux components data binding">Data Binding</link>
        <link link="data binding existing tables">match controls to a data bound table</link>

    </links>

</page>