<page build="0">
    <shortlink>tf onsubmit email</shortlink>
    <topic parent="TransForm onSubmit Event Builder" parentType="guide" elementName="Send Email">TransForm onSubmit Event: Send Email</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Sends an email with the data from the Form that was submitted.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Send Email]* TransForm onSubmit action send an email to a specific email address with the data in the Form that was submitted. The email address is defined at the time the action is created. The Form data can be sent in one of the following formats:</p>
        <p>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>*[JSON]* - the Form data will be shown in raw JSON format in the body of the e-mail message</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>*[HTML]* - the Form data will be shown as formatted HTML in the body of the e-mail message</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>*[EXCEL]* - the Form data will be exported to an Excel file and sent as an attachment to the e-mail message</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>By default, the action is defined for *[all]* Form Types in the TransForm account. You can restrict the action to specific Form Types with a filter. The filter is defined as a comma-delimited list of Form Types. The wildcard character "*" can be used when defining the Form Types filter. For example:</p>
        <p>
            <example caption="Using a wild card to define a Form Types filter"><![CDATA[inspection*,expenses]]></example>
        </p>
        <p>The filter above will execute the Send Email action if the submitted Form's type starts with *[inspection]* or is the *[expenses]* Form Type.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <tip>
                <p>If you want to send a formatted report showing some or all of the data in the Form that was submitted to an email address that is specified in the Form data (for example, you want to send a summary of work done to the email address specified in the Form's *[ui:email]* field), use the [Report] action.</p>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring the Send Email Action</title>
            <figure>
                <title>The Send Email Action Editor</title>
                <alt>The Send Email Action Editor</alt>
                <link>images/sendEmail1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The following properties are used to configure the *[ui:Send Email]* action.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Send to</name>
                    <description>A comma delimited list of email addresses.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Subject</name>
                    <description>The subject for the email message.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Format</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The type of data format used to send the submitted Form data. Data can be formatted as:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>JSON - data is shown in JSON format in the body of the email message</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>HTML - data is shown as formatted HTML in the body of the message</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>EXCEL - data is in an Excel file that is attached to the email message</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Form Ids</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>The forms the Send Email action applies to. Form Types are specified as a comma delimited list of Form Type Ids. You can use wildcard characters in the Form Type Ids.</p>
                        <p>To specify that the action applies to all form types, leave blank or enter: *</p>
                        <p>The [...] smart field button for the property opens the *[ui:Select Forms]* dialog, which can be used to select Form Types from the TransForm Account that should send an email when submitted.</p>
                    </description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="tf onsubmit report">Report</link>
    </links>
</page>