<page>
    <topic>Image capture settings</topic>
    <description>Clicking on the Image capture settings property will open the Image Capture Properties Genie.
        This Genie allows you to capture an image. On a device that has a camera, the image is captured using the camera.
        For devices that do not support a camera, you can choose an image from the filesystem. Camera access is either 
        done using PhoneGap or HTML5. Once the image has been captured a Javascript event is fired.
    </description>




<sections>
    <section>
        <title>Image Capture Properties</title>
           <description></description>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Javascript to execute when image has been captured</title>
        <description>Specify the Javascript to call once the image has been captured. Your Javascript can reference e.data.
            In the case where PhoneGap is used, you can also reference e.fileSystemURL, the file system URL of the image.
        </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        
        <figure><title>The Image Capture Properties genie</title><link>images/capturegenie.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
      <section>
        <title>Image capture method</title>
        <description>Specify the method for obtaining the image. If the component is running in a PhoneGap shell, then you can use PhoneGap to access the camera 
            (if you are not in a PhoneGap shell, the user will get an error if they try to capture an image). If you select 'PhoneGapPreferred' then the PhoneGap 
            method will be used if the component is running in a PhoneGap shell, otherwise the HTML5 method will be used.
        </description>
    </section>
    
    
 
 

    <section>
        <title>HTML5 Options</title>
        <description></description>
    </section>
    
      <section>
        <title>Resize image</title>
        <description>Specify the policy for resizing the image. 'Always' means that the image will always be resized, regardless of its raw size.
            'Only if Image Exceeds Max Size' will only resize the raw image if the maximum size is exceeded. </description>
    </section>
    
       
      <section>
        <title>Image compression</title>
        <description>Specify the image compression factor to use when capturing an image using HTML5.
             1 equals no compression and 0 is maximum compression. Using maximum compression may result in artifacts depending on the size of the image and also the 
             Max image height and width.
        </description>
    </section>
    
      <section>
        <title>Max image height</title>
        <description>Specify the Maximum height in pixels</description>
    </section>
    
    
    
   <section>
        <title>Max image width</title>
        <description>Specify the Maximum width in pixels.</description>
    </section>
  

    <section>
       <title>Client-side events</title>
        <description></description>
    </section>
    
    <section>
       <title>Before image capture</title>
        <description>Specify the Javascript to run before the image is captured. If your code contains 'return false;' then the image 
            capture is cancelled.
        </description>
    </section>
    
    </sections>
    
 

</page>