<page build="7739">
    <shortlink>security quicksetup</shortlink>
    <topic>Enabling the Security Framework with the Quick Setup Genie</topic>
    <description>
        <p>The Security Framework Quick Setup Genie can be used to quickly create users, groups, and the components necessary to add authentication to your application.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Quick Setup Genie allows you to configure the Security Framework for a Web Project more quickly that it could be done by selecting the Security Configuration menu command when you click the Web Security button at the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Security Framework Menu</title>
                <alt>Security Framework Menu</alt>
                <link>images/quickSetupMenu.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>Security Framework Dialog</title>
                <alt>Security Framework Dialog</alt>
                <link>images/quickSetupDialog.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When you select the Quick Setup Genie, the following dialog is displayed:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Security Quick Setup Genie</title>
                <alt>Security Quick Setup Genie</alt>
                <link>images/quickSetupGenie1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can specify:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>*[The number of sample users to create.]* You can modify users later.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[The number of sample groups to create.]* You can modify groups later.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[Create sample components.]* If you check this option, the genie will add sample components to your project that you can use as-is, delete, or modify.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[Optionally create an extended user information table for the project.]* The extended user information table is used to store additional information about each user. For example, it can be used to indicate that a particular user has turned on two-factor authentication. If you choose not to create the extended user information table in the Genie you can always add it later on by going to the Project Properties dialog.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>The sample components that the genie adds to your project include the following components:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Component</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>login</name>
                            <description>A UX component that serves as the Login component.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>masterTabbedUI</name>
                            <description>A TabbedUI component. This component is typically the main menu of your web application. The components that you build in a web application can be launched from a TabbedUI component. The TabbedUI component is displayed when the login component is configured to RedirectToTargetPage in the After login behavior property.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>reset_password</name>
                            <description>A UX component that is launched from the masterTabbedUI component that allows a logged in user to change their password.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>two_factor_authentication_preferences</name>
                            <description>A UX component that is launched from the masterTabbedUI component that allows a logged in user to set their preferences for two-factor authentication. The extended user information table must be enabled to use this component.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>extended_user_information</name>
                            <description>A UX component that is launched from the masterTabbedUI component that allows a logged in user to edit their data in the extended user information table. The extended user information table must be enabled to use this component.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>When you click the *[ui:Yes]* button, the Genie enables the Security Framework (if not already enabled) and then displays a summary of the sample users and groups that were created.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>A list of sample users and groups generated by the genie</title>
                <alt>A list of sample users and groups generated by the genie</alt>
                <link>images/securitygenie2.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Next, the Genie prompts for the type of style to use for the login component.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Login Component Style Prompt</title>
                <alt>Login Component Style Prompt</alt>
                <link>images/securitygenie3.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can choose from one of two styles for the login UX: an image displayed to the left of the login controls or an image behind the login controls, as shown in the images below:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Login Component Layout with Image on Left</title>
                <alt>Login Component Layout with Image on Left</alt>
                <link>images/imageleft.jpg</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>Login Component Layout with Image in the Background</title>
                <alt>Login Component Layout with Image in the Background</alt>
                <link>images/imageright.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If you specified that you want to create the Extended User Information Table, the Genie will prompt you to create the table next. You can specify the connection string to the SQL database where the table will be created. The table where the extended user information is stored can be an existing table or a new table which can be created from within Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Extended User Information Table dialog</title>
                <alt>Extended User Information Table dialog</alt>
                <link>images/securitygenie4.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using the Quick Setup Genie</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you create a new project, it is quite common to turn on the Security Framework to enable login to your application. There are quite a few steps to set up the Security Framework and it can be quite tedious. The Quick Setup Genie configures the Security Framework and creates sample users and groups to get you started very quickly.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how the Quick Setup Genie works.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_quicksetupgenie.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using a UX Component as your Login</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you enable the Security Framework for your project you will need a login dialog where users will log into your application. A UX component can be used as the Login component and can be configured to allow password reset and new account creation.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to use a UX component as your Login dialog.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Configuring a UX as a Login Component</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_uxlogincomponent.mp4</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Using a UX as a Login Component</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_uxlogincomponentinaction.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Reset Password</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in any Security Framework is the ability for the user to reset their password if they have forgotten it. The typical pattern for this is to send an email to the user. The email has a link that the user can click to bring up a dialog where they can change their password.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how this is done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_forgotpassword.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Create new account</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in any Security Framework is the ability for a user to create a new account.</p>
                    <p>In addition, if the Web Project has defined an Extended User information table, then at the same time that the user creates their new account, they can choose to enable two-factor authentication.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how this is done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_createaccount.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>After Login Behavior	</title>
                <description>
                    <p>After the user has logged into your application using a UX component, configured as a Login dialog, the after login behavior can either redirect the user to another page in your application, or to another Panel in the UX component.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how the after login behavior is configured.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_afterlogin.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Persistent Login</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement when building an application with the Security Framework is to enable persistent login. With persistent login, a user will not need to log into the app again after they have successfully logged in once.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how persistent login is enabled.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-06-22</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/security_persistentLogin.mp4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Webinar: Intro to The New Alpha Anywhere Security Genie</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Dion McCormick presents an introduction to Alpha Anywhere's new Security Genie.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-10-20</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cXoB9Jy8Fqs</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="security framework users and groups">Managing Users and Groups</ref>
    </see>
</page>