<page>
	<topic>Adapting to a Different Server Date Format</topic>
	<description>The application developer created a grid with a search component with a date field. The Application Server was located on a machine where the regional settings were set for US dates (i.e. MM/DD/YYYY ). The users, however, wanted to search using DD/MM/YYYY date formats. The solution was to edit the .A5W page that displays the component. </description>
	<sections>
<section>
	<note> The FixDateString() function makes it possible to adapt a web application used by persons who expect a YMD date format to a Application Server that uses a MDY date format.</note>
	
	
</section>		
		<section>
	<description>Assume that your component name is grid1 and that the date field is called date1. Note that component name is actually set in this code block with the command.</description>		
			<example><![CDATA[with tmpl 
 componentname = "grid1" 
 end with
 ]]></example>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Create the grid component with the search form. The search form has a date field named date1.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Place the grid component on an A5W page.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Display the Source tab of the HTML Editor.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Add the following code after the  tag. Note that the variable names have the form: componentName_s_fieldname.</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		<section>
	
			<example><![CDATA[<%a5

if eval_valid("grid1_s_date1") then 
 if grid1_s_date1 <> "" then 
 grid1_s_date1 = "" + date_value( val( word(grid1_s_date1, 3, "-") ), val( word(grid1_s_date1, 2, "-") ), val( word(grid1_s_date1, 1, "-") ) ) 
 end if 
 end if 
 %>
 ]]></example>
			
		</section>
		<section>
				<description>When the user clicks the search button, the variables are submitted with the page. The date1 search field have a value that looks like 31/12/2015. The above code intercepts this value and changes it to 12/31/2015 before the grid component sees it.</description>	
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</page>