<page>
	<topic>Editing a Tabbed GridLinker Template
</topic><description>Web publishing applications only. The Tabbed GridLinker template defines how any parent and child grid will be displayed. You may modify:
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>The content and relative positions of the grid components
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>The formatting of the tables that contain parent and child grids
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Other constant HTML content that you want to appear above, below, between, and to the sides of the grids
</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>To edit the template used by a tabbed GridLinker:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>In the Tabbed GridLinker Builder, select any grid that has a child grid.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Check the Grid Properties > Customize page layout field.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click the '...' button in the Grid Properties > Page layout template field to display the Tabbed Grid Layout dialog.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>You may edit the template in either the HTML Editor or in this dialog box.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. To edit the template in the HTML Editor, click Edit in HTML Editor.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. The resulting WYSIWYG and Source tabs allows you to modify and insert and format other HTML content. For example, the default formatting places a single black line one pixel wide around each child grid. Here is an example that changes the thickness and color of the line around the child table.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Repeat steps 1 through 4 for each parent grid that has a child grid.
</description>
<example><![CDATA['original formatting
<td style="BORDER-RIGHT: black 1px solid;
BORDER-TOP: black 1px solid;
BORDER-LEFT: black 1px solid;
BORDER-BOTTOM: black 1px solid" >
'modified formatting
<td style="BORDER-RIGHT: #800000 3px solid;
BORDER-TOP: #800000 3px solid;
BORDER-LEFT: #800000 3px solid;
BORDER-BOTTOM: #800000 3px solid" >
 ]]></example>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The picture below shows before (on the left) and after (on the right). 
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WP_Modify_Child_Table_Cell.gif</link></figure>
</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Creating Tabbed GridLinker Components
</ref>
	</see>
</page>