<page>
	
	<topic>Grid Query</topic>

	<groups>
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Define a Table Query</title>
		<description>When building components in the Grid Builder it is often necessary to pull specific data and records from a given table, be it .dbf or SQL. To do this it is necessary to create a Table Query.    
</description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>		
		
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Select Grid > Query (DBF).
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select the data source table from the Table Name list.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Creating Table Aliases </title>
				<description>A table alias can make your grid portable, by separating it from direct reference to a table name. as long as a table has the same structure and the same alias, it can use a grid originally built for another table.
Optionally, enter an alias for the table. If you do not enter an alias, it will default to the name of the table.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Creating Calculated Fields</title>
				<description>A calculated value may be displayed, but not edited. Typically, you compute a calculated value based on the values of several other fields in each record. To create a calculated value to place on the grid Optionally, click Calculated fieldsto display the Define Calculated Fields dialog box.
</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<note>Alpha Anywhere documentation and software has traditionally referred the values that you calculate and place on a layout as "calculated fields". However, these values are not fields, because they are not stored in a table record. They are temporary variables that are created and calculated on demand.</note>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>1. Enter calculated value expressions, one per line, in the format = . For example:
</description>
<example><![CDATA[=]]></example>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>2. Optionally, click Expression Builderto use the Expression Builder to help you define the calculated value.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>3. Optionally, click F2 - Fieldsto display a list of table fields to insert into the expression.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>4. Optionally, click F4 - Functionsto display a list of functions to insert into the expression.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>5. Optionally, use the [azup_img] and [zadown_img] buttons to sort the list of calculated values.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>6. Optionally, use the [upbar_img],[up_img],[down_img] and [downbar_img] buttons to reorganize the sequence of calculated values.
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>7. Click OKto continue or Cancelto discard your inputs.
</description>
					</case>
					
					
				</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Define Arguments </title>
				<description>Optionally, if you want to provide a value for use in the grid's filter expression, click Define Argumentsto display the Define Arguments dialog box.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Enter a Filter Expression </title>
				<description>Optionally, enter a logical expression that selects records from the table into the Filter field. You may click [xy_img] to use the Expression Builder to help you define the expression. A blank filter expression retrieves all records in the table.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, check Unique records onlyto eliminate records with duplicate values.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Enter an Order Expression </title>
				<description>Optionally, enter a character expression that orders selected records into the Order field. You may click [updown_img] to use the Order Builder to help you define the expression. A blank order expression retrieves records in record number order.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Optionally, click Ascendingor Descendingto change the sequence of records.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<title>Enable Editing of Records 
</title>
				<description>Optionally, check Read only to indicate that you do not need to define a primary key.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click Define Primary Key(s)to define the field or character expression that will uniquely identify records.
</description>
			</step>
			
			
			
		</steps>
	</section>	
	<section>
		<note>Since record locking is not possible in a web environment, it is highly desirable to have a way to uniquely identify each record. The default identification for a record is its number, which in some circumstances can change.</note>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>See Also Selecting the Fields to Display 
</description>
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>			
		
		
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>		
		
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>			
		
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>		
		
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>			
						
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>		
		
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>			
		
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>		
		
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title></title>
		<description></description>
	</section>	
</sections>	
</group>			
						
	
	</groups>
	
<links>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Sort_Ascending_button.gif">azup_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Sort_Descending_button.gif">zadown_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Move_First_button.gif">upbar_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Move_Up_Button.gif">up_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Move_Down_Button.gif">down_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Move_Last_button.gif">downbar_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Espression_Button_black.gif">xy_img</link>
	<link href="../../Data/FieldRules/images/Order_button.gif">updown_img</link>
	
	
</links>
	

	
	
	
</page>