<page>
	<topic>Introducing the Grid Builder</topic>

<groups>

<group background="true">
	
<sections>
<section>

	<description>In addition to UX components, grid components are an important part of Alpha Anywhere Web Publishing. They retrieve and display data from a variety of types of databases. They allow the user to search for, edit, insert, and delete records. You create grid components with the Grid Builder.  
</description>
</section>	
	
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
	
</group>
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Finding the Grid Builder
</title>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>If you have set up Web Security already, Go to the Web Projects Control Panel and click  in the Create dropdown list to open the Select Grid Component Dialog.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>1. Alternatively, click New on the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>2. In the New File Dialog select Web Component and click Next > .</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>3. When asked what type file you want to create, click Grid and Next > .</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
				
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>The Select Grid Component Dialog will load. Choose whether you want to work from a template or start with blank Grid Component  and click OK . The Grid Builder will appear.</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>	
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
</group>

<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Grid Templates </title>
			<description>Whenever you create a new grid component in Alpha Anywhere, the Grid Templates Genie pops up, which lets you select one of several pre-defined templates or a template from your own library of templates.Templates can be a great time saver because you can pre-set a multitude of properties whenever you create a new component. This video    demonstrates how you can use existing templates, and how you can define your own templates.  
</description>		
		</section>	
	</sections>
</group>
	
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Toolbar Functions
</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Toolbar.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<title>Save  </title>
							<description>Saves the currently open grid.  </description>
							<figure><link>images/Save_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Save As</title>
							<description>Saves the currently open grid after asking for the path and filename.</description>
							<figure><link>images/Save_As_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Save Page</title>
							<description>Creates a temporary file that contains the grid, optionally opening the page in the HTML Editor.  
</description>
							<figure><link>images/Insert_Code_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Open</title>
							<description>Allows you to select and open an existing grid from any of your projects.  
</description>
							<figure><link>images/Load_button_2.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>New</title>
							<description>Allows you to create a new grid.</description>
							<figure><link>images/New_Query_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Browser</title>
							<description>Displays the grid component in a temporary page in your browser of choice.</description>
							<figure><link>images/Preview_Button_2.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Remote Test</title>
							<description>Test on a remote device (such as a phone or tablet)</description>
							<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_BlueLightning.png</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Publish</title>
							<description>Publishes the grid to the destination associated with the selected profile.</description>
							<figure><link>images/Publish_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Web Projects</title>
							<description>Displays the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
							<figure><link>images/Control_Panel_button.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>SQL</title>
							<description>Loads the SQL Tools menu.</description>
							<figure><link>images/A_SQL.png</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Web Style Builder</title>
							<description>Opens the Web Style Builder</description>
							<figure><link>images/A_Abutton.png</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Server</title>
							<description>Turn the server on and off, when on the server icon appears green.</description>
							<figure><link>images/A_Server.png</link></figure>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Close</title>
							<description>Closes the Grid Builder.  </description>
							<figure><link>images/Close_button_2.gif</link></figure>
						</case>
						
						
						
					</cases>
					
					
				</case>
				
			</cases>
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
</group>	
<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Page Menu</title>
			<description>The page menu allows you to select different sets of menus. Different menus will appear or disappear, depending on the options that you select. Most of these Dependencies are determined under the Component Type page. If you click Grid is: Updateable under component type, for example, the ' Update Settings ' Page will appear under the Grid tree. However, setting your grid to this will prevent you from checking off the ' Grid contains a 'Detail View' part ' check box; that is also located on the Component Type page. Without this box checked the Detail View options, show below, will not appear under the Component Type tree menu.  
</description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
</group>
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Page_menu.png</link></figure>
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Menu Options</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Component Type</title>
					<description>Defines the style of the grid and whether it will have search and/or detail parts.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Data Source</title>
					<description>Defines the type of database connection that you require.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Query (DBF)  
Grid > Query (AlphaDAO)
</title>
					<description>Specifies the database, table, filter expression, and order expression.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the grid and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Properties</title>
					<description>Sets properties for the grid, including style.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid > Update Settings</title>
					<description>Appears if the grid is updateable. Sets add, edit, and insert properties.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Search > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the search part and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Search > Properties  </title>
					<description>Sets properties for the search part.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Detail View > Fields  </title>
					<description>Selects the fields that appear in the detail view part and sets their properties.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Detail View > Properties</title>
					<description>Sets properties for the detail view part.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Events  </title>
					<description>Allows you to create scripts to respond to grid events.  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Information  </title>
					<description>Allows you to record information about the grid.  </description>
				</case>
				
				
			</cases>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>
<group background="true">
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Component Type Page
</title>
		<description>The Component Type page defines the major characteristics of a grid. You can easily access this page by clicking the Component Type icon at the top of the Component Type tree menu on the left. Contained within the Component Type page is the Grid Layout Menu. This menu lets you choose how data will be displayed on your grid. The preview window in the right hand side of the Component Type window will give you a general idea of how these options will affect the final grid display. Clicking the Tabular option will display multiple records in a tabular layout. Clicking the Form (Columnar) option will display data in a Form layout. Form layouts are typically used to present one record at a time. However, you can use Form layouts to display multiple records at once (i.e. 'repeating' forms). The 'repeating' forms can be displayed either in a vertical list (i.e. a single 'column' of forms), or in multiple columns (i.e. 'snaking' columns). Clicking the Stacked Columnar option displays data in a vertical list.  
</description>	
			
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>There are a number of dependencies within in the Component Type Page. What you choose here will determine what options you have going forward in designing you web component.  
</description>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Clicking Grid is: Read only will cause the grid's fields to be displayed in label controls that users will be able to read but not change. Clicking this will also open the 'Grid contains a Detail View part?' option on the Control Type page. If checked, this option will create a form that displays information about one of the records in the grid. It will also allow the Detail View options to appear in the Component Type Tree, which will let you design the detail view and how you would like the fields within it to be presented.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_DetailView.png</link></figure>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Clicking Grid is: Updateable will enable features that display text box controls and let users update information in the grid. Clicking this option will make Grid > Update Settings appear in the Component Type tree. This will let you let you make a number of choices about how information on your grid is updated and who is allowed to update information.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_Update Settings.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Checking the Grid contains a 'Search' part? check box will create a search box that will let users search your grid for specific records. Clicking this will also enable the Search > Fields and Search > Properties options in the Component Type menu. Among other things, these options will let you design the search box to your liking and choose what fields you want to allow it to access. </description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
	
</group>	
	
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Component_Type_menu.png</link></figure>
	
		</section>
<section>
	<title>Component Type Options</title>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Grid Layout</title>
			<description>Defines the style of the grid and whether it will have search and/or detail parts.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Grid is: Read only  </title>
			<description>Causes the search fields to be displayed in label controls.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Grid is: Updateable  </title>
			<description>Causes the search fields to be displayed in text box controls.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Grid contains a 'Search' part?  </title>
			<description>Displays the Search > Fieldsand Search > Propertiesmenus.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Grid contains a 'Detail View' part?  </title>
			<description>Displays the Detail view > Fields and Detail view > Properties menus.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DetailView is: Read only  </title>
			<description>Causes the detail view fields to be displayed in label controls.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DetailView is: Updateable  </title>
			<description>Causes the detail view fields to be displayed in text box controls.  </description>
		</case>
		
		
		
	</cases>
	
</section>		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>
	
<group background="true">
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Preview Pane</title>
			<description>The Preview Paneappears in the Component Type page and shows a small sample of the grid's appearance using the currently selected style sheet. Clicking the Click here to zoom preview window text at the bottom of the preview pane puts the preview inside of its own Component Layout dialog. If you change the properties of your grid and click the Refresh Preview button, these changes will be reflected in the Preview Pane (as shown below). Alpha Anywhere also contains Live Preview and Working Preview windows that let you see your component on the server and debug it.  
</description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<figure><link>images/A_Component Layout.png</link></figure>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
</group>
	
<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Grid Data Source Menu</title>
			<description>The Grid > Data Source Menuprovides two options that select the type of database connection that will be used: .dbf Tables or an SQL database accessed via AlphaDAO (Alpha Data Access Objects). Selecting one or the other will open either the Grid > Query(DBF) menu or the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) menu.  </description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
</group>	
	
<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Grid Query (DBF) Menu</title>
			<description>This menu defines the grid's data source. Depending on what you select from the ' Display data from' option this source data will be derived from either an Alpha Anywhere table or a view. Choosing Table will specify that the grid will come from a single table name and table alias fields. The table to be used is entered in the ' Table name ' textbox. Simply click on the dropdown to the right of the textbox and select one of the existing Alpha Anywhere tables saved in your workspace.  The 'Table alias', or the name used by Alpha Anywhere to refer to the table internally, is filled in automatically when you select a table name. The ' Calculated fields ' option lets you input new fields into your grid based on existing data in your grid. This is only really possible in the Grid Builder for work with read-only files. If you click on 'Calculated fields', the Calculated Values Dialog will open. To create new fields from existing ones simply type in the name of the new field and specify which existing fields will supply data to the new one. The Calculated Values dialog has drop down lists of functions and existing fields to make this task simple. It also contains a number of additional tools as well as connections to the Expression builder dialog, Fields dialog, and the Function Finder.  
</description>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>A new fullnamefield being generated from first and last names.  
</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_Calculated Values.png</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>The Calculate Values Dialog has additional tools  
</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_Calculated Values2.png</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<description>The Define Arguments button in the Table query loads the Define Arguments dialog which lets you specify arguments to be used in filter and order expressions. The Filter option lets you filter  
 existing records for records containing certain characteristics. To create a filter click the to the right of the 'Filter' textbox. 
</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_expression builder.png</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>This will load the Expression Builder . If you want help creating a filter in the Expression Builder just click on the Filter Genie button to load the Filter Builder dialog. This will make it easy to choose which fields you want to filter and how you want to filter them.  
Creating a filter for all first names containing 's':</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_Filterbuilder.png</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>The Order option in the Table query lets you choose which field you will use to order you records by.  If you want, you can actually order your grid using multiple fields, first sorting by one field, then another, and another. To do this, click the  button to the right of the Order option. This will open an Order Builder dialog that has dropdowns for all of your fields and an A...Z or Z...A sort option. Below the Order option, Sort Direction lets you decide whether the records are sorted in an ascending or descending direction. The Define Primary Key(s) button at the bottom of the table query lets you define whether to use record number or an expression for the tables primary key. Using an expression here is recommended, as a record's record number can change after a table is packed.  


</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>See also Define a Table Query</description>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</group>	


<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			
			<description>Alpha Anywhere Table Query</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_QueryChoice.png</link></figure>
			
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Table Query Options</title>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Display data from: Table</title>
					<description>Specifies that the grid will come from a single table. Displays the Table name and Table alias fields.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Display data from: View</title>
					<description>Specifies that the grid will contain fields from 2 or more tables. Displays the Tables in Viewand Fields in Viewbuttons.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Table name</title>
					<description>Displays a list of tables in the current database.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Refresh</title>
					<description>Refreshes the contents of the Table namelist.</description>
					<figure><link>images/Refresh_Field_List_Button.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Table alias  </title>
					<description>This is the name that is used internally to refer to the table.  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Tables in View</title>
					<description></description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Fields in View</title>
					<description>Displays the Select Fields in Viewdialog, where you select the fields to display and define calculated fields.  
</description>
				</case>
				
				
				
			</cases>
			
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group background="true">
	
<sections>
	<section>
		<description>If you choose Display data from: View rather than table, you will specify that the grid will come from a view that contains fields from 2 or more tables. It will also change the options on the Grid Query (DBF) Menu by displaying the Tables in View and Fields in View buttons. The other options that you saw in the 'Display data from: Table' explanation above will remain the same. Clicking the Tables in View: button will load the Add Table dialog which will ask you to select a table to use from a list. Unless you specify otherwise the Add Table dialog will also add an alias to the selected table. Click OK and the Define Join dialog will load. Add another table or simply click OK again and the table will be added to 'Tables in View'. If click the Tables in View button after adding a table you will be taken directly to the Define Join dialog. If you add a second table to Define Join you will be asked to define the link properties between the new and existing tables.  
</description>
		<figure><link>images/A_Linkproperties.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description><![CDATA[Clicking the Fields in View button will load the Select Fields in View Dialog. Here you can create a list of fields and calculated field definitions. The fields that you see in Fields in View will be the fields contained in the tables you selected using Tables in View. The Select Fields in View dialog allows you to select the fields from a table that you want to work with in your View. To add an individual field, simply highlight it using the list of the left and then click the single arrow button > to bring it into the view. To move all the fields in your tables into the view select a field in the list and click the double arrows >> to bring them into the view. Similarly, select a field in the view list on the right and click the single < or double << arrows pointing the opposite direction to remove one or all of the fields from the view. Once a field is in the view, you can place an = sign after the field to gain access to the Expression Builder. The Expression Builder button will appear at the bottom of the dialog as soon as you do this.  
]]></description>
		<figure><link>images/A_Expressionbuilderaccess.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<description>See also  
Define a View Query.  
Expression Builder.   </description>
		
	</section>
</sections>			
</group>

<group>
<sections>
	
	<section>
		
		<description>Alpha Anywhere View Query
</description>
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Alpha_View_query.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>View Query Options</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Arguments</title>
				<description>Displays the Define Arguments dialog, where you specify arguments to be used in filter and order expressions.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Filter</title>
				<description>Specifies the expression that selects the records that will be included in the grid.  
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Order  </title>
				<description>Specifies the expression that orders selected records.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Sort Direction  </title>
				<description>Specifies whether the order of records will be ascending or descending.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Unique records only</title>
				<description>Specifies that the grid will display unique records only.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Read only</title>
				<description>Specifies that the grid's fields will be displayed in label controls.  </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Define Primary Key(s)</title>
				<description>Specifies the field(s) that uniquely identify each record.  </description>
			</case>
			
			
			
		</cases>
		
		
		
	</section>
	
	
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
	
</group>


<group background="true">
	<sections>
<section>
	
	<description>The Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) menu defines the grid's data source, which is a SQL SELECT statement directed to a SQL back-end database. SQL or Structured Query Language is used to manage data within many databases. To access and manipulate this data you will need to first establish a connection string. Fortunately, Alpha Anywhere makes this as easy as selecting the file to connect to. When you first open the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) menu it will ask you for a Connection Type: at the top of the screen. If you don't want to give your connection a name select Specify Connection String from the Connection Type dropdown and click the Build button. This will load the Create SQL Connection String Dialog . At the top of the Create SQL Connection String Dialog you will notice another Connection Type dropdown. Here you can choose the database software that contains the data which you want to access and where you will ultimately store your data. Most of these Connection Types will prompt you to select the File Name: you wish to connect to under the Options menu. Click OK and the connection string should appear on the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) page.  
The Create SQL Connection String Dialog  
</description>
	<figure><link>images/A_ConnectionString.png</link></figure>
	
</section>		
<section>
	
	<description>If you are creating a lot of connection strings and storing data in different databases you might want to give your connection strings a name for ease of use.  On the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) page go to the Connection Type: option and select Use Named Connection String . Next click Add/Edit Saved Connections to add a new named string. This will load the AlphaDAO Connections dialog box. Click New , this will load the New AlphaDAO Connection dialog. Enter the Connection Name: of your new connection in the textbox at the top of the dialog. Then place the connection string path in textbox entitled ' Connection String: '. If you do not know the path you can click Build, which will bring you back to the Create SQL Connection String Dialog and help you create a new path.  
Creating a New Connection Name  </description>
	<figure><link>images/A_AlphaDAOpath.png</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<description>Once a connection string name is defined you can connect to it by going to the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) page and clicking the Select... button next to the Connection Name textbox. This will open the AlphaDAO Connection Strings dialog and will show you a list of all your named connections. Select the connection you want to use and click OK . Your connection will now appear on the Grid > Query(AlphaDAO) page. Click Connect to connect to it.  
</description>
	
</section>		
	<section>
		<description>Also see  
Create SQL Connection String Dialog.   
</description>
		
		
	</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</group>

<group>
	
<sections>
	
<section>
	<description>Connecting with a SQL Database Using a Named Connection String
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_AlphaDAO_connection.png</link></figure>
</section>	
	<section>
	<description>Connecting with a SQL Database By Building a Connection String
</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_SQL1.png</link></figure>
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Building a Connection String Options</title>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Connection type</title>
			<description>Specifies the type of connection to the database.  </description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Use Named Connection String" - allows you to select from the Connection Namelist  
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Specify Connection String" - click the Zoomor Buildbuttons to define a connection string.  
</description>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Build</title>
			<description>Displays the Create SQL Connection String dialog, where you can create a connection string.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Zoom  </title>
			<description>Displays the Edit Connection Stringdialog, where you can enter a connection string.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Connection Name</title>
			<description>Specifies the saved connection that you will use to connect to the database.  </description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Add/Edit Saved Connections  </title>
			<description>Displays the Connectionsdialog, where you can select, create, or edit a connection string.  </description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
	
</section>
<section>
	
	<description>AlphaDAO Table Query
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_AlphaDAO_Table_query.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	
	<description>AlphaDAO SQL Query
</description>
	<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_AlphaDAO_SQL_query.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	
	<description>Stored Procedure Query
</description>
	<figure><link>images/A_Stored Procedure.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Key Functions</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Base on: Table or View</title>
		<description>Displays the Table/View name, Table/View alias, Filter, and Order byfields.  </description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Base on: SQL Select Statement</title>
		<description>Displays the Edit SQLbutton, SQL Select Statementwindow, and Select Primary Key(s)button.  </description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Table/View name</title>
		<description>Displays a list of tables in the current database.  </description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Refresh</title>
		<description>Refreshes the contents of the Table/View namelist.  </description>
		<figure><link>images/Refresh_Field_List_Button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Table/View alias</title>
		<description>This is the name that is used internally to refer to the table.  </description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Arguments</title>
		<description>Displays the Define Arguments dialog, where you specifies arguments to be used in filter and order expressions.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Filter  </title>
		<description>Specifies the expression that selects the records that will be included in the grid.  </description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Order by</title>
		<description>Specifies the expression that orders selected records.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Read only</title>
		<description>Specifies that the grid's fields will be displayed in label controls.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Edit SQL</title>
		<description>Displays the SQL Builderdialog, where you can define a SQL SELECT statement.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Select</title>
		<description>Specifies the field(s) that uniquely identify each record. </description>
	</case>
	
	
	
</cases>	
</section>
</sections>	
</group>

<group background="true">
	
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Grid Fields Menu</title>
		<description>The Grid > Fields menu shows the fields that have been returned by your table or view selection or SQL query. You move these fields from the Available Fields list to the Selected Fields list to display them on the grid. See also  Selecting the Fields to Display  .  
</description>
		
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Available and Selected Fields Lists
</description>
			<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Fields_menu.png</link></figure>
			
			
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<title>Grid is Editable?</title>
					<description>Allows you to change a read-only grid to an editable grid.</description>
					<figure><link></link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Available Fields:  
</title>
					<description>Shows the fields that have been returned by your table or view selection or SQL query.  
</description>
					<figure><link></link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Selected  :  
</title>
					<description>Shows the fields that will appear on the grid, and the order in which the will appear. The top to bottom list order is the same as the left to right display order.  
</description>
					<figure><link></link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Add Field</title>
					<description>Add selected fields to the Selected Fieldslist.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/Move_Right_Button.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Add All Fields</title>
					<description>Adds all fields to the Selected Fieldslist.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/Move_Last_Button_2.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Remove Field</title>
					<description>Removes selected fields from the Selected Fieldslist.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/Move_Left_Button.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Remove All Fields</title>
					<description>Removes all fields from the Selected Fieldslist.  
</description>
					<figure><link>images/Move_First_Button_3.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Field to Top</title>
					<description>Move the selected field to the top of the Selected Fields list.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_UpArrow.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Move Field Up</title>
					<description>Move the selected field up in the Selected Fieldslist.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_UpArrowOne.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Move Field Down</title>
					<description>Move the selected field down in the Selected Fieldslist.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_DownArrowOne.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Field to Bottom</title>
					<description>Move the selected field to the bottom of the Selected Fieldslist.  
</description>
					<figure><link>images/A_DownArrow.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Paste Property Value</title>
					<description>Paste current property value to multiple controls at once.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_Paste.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Search</title>
					<description>Search for Control Dialog.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_Search.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Field Number</title>
					<description>Go to field number.  </description>
					<figure><link>images/A_PointNumber.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title>Grid Lines</title>
					<description>Display grid lines in Working or Live Preview modes to help set the size of controls.  
</description>
					<figure><link>images/A_DisplayGrid.png</link></figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<title></title>
					<description></description>
					<figure><link></link></figure>
				</case>
				
				
			</cases>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
</group>

<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>The Eye Dropper</title>
			<description>The ' Eye dropper ' icon [eyedropper_img] allows you to paste the currently selected property in the Property Grid to selected controls. For example say that you want to repeat a Bubble Help property across multiple fields. Here is how you would do this:  
</description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Open the Grid Builder . Go to Design and under the Data Source page select either .dbf or SQL.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>On the Query(DBF) or Query(SQL) page connect to the table that you will pull your data from.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Go to the Fields page. Select a number of fields from the Available Fields: list and move them to the Selected: fields list using the right arrow between the two lists.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select one of the default Label controls in the Selected: fields list and then look at the Field Properties list to the right. Scroll down to the Column Properties. 
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click on the Bubble Help Text property and write some text next to this property. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_eyedropper.png</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click the ' Eye dropper ' [eyedropper_img] icon. The Select Controls dialog will open showing the selected property for all of the controls in the component. 
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the control(s) that you want to paste the Bubble Help property on to by clicking on them. Hold down Shift and click to select more than one control.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Set Properties and you are done. Go to Live Preview. You should see all of the columns in your grid have the same property 
</description>
				</step>

			</steps>
			
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
	
</group>
<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Background Grid Lines 
</title>
			<description>When you are designing a Grid with a Detail View, or a UX component, it can be helpful to turn on a background set of grid lines to see the dimensions of different objects. To turn grid lines on/off, click the icon highlighted in the screen below. See Video D25.  
</description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>Setting Grid units 
</description>
	<figure><link>images/01_backgroundlines.png</link></figure>
</section>	
<section>
	<description>In Working Preview 
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_backgroundlines2.png</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>

<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Field Properties </title>
			<description>As you select a field in the Selected Fieldslist, you will see its properties displayed in the Field Propertiescontrol. There are many properties for each field, which you can set. Here is where you define the presentation of your data. For more information, see Setting Grid Control Properties.  
</description>
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
</group>
<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Typical Properties Dialog
</description>
			<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Properties_menu.png</link></figure>
			
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group background="true">
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Grid Properties Menu</title>
			<description>The Grid > Properties Menudefines the formatting for the grid, including the style sheet, and enables some special features. For more information, see Setting Grid Properties. When you click on any given property, a detailed description of that property will be displayed below the Grid Properties menu.  </description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>


<group>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Grid > Properties Menu
</description>
			<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Grid_Properties_Menu.png</link></figure>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
	
</group>
<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Grid > Update Settings Menu</title>
		<description>The Grid > Update Settingsmenu only appears if the grid is updateable. This is where you control user delete, update, and insert operations. There are quite a number of security permissions that can be set in the update menu. These will allow certain users to edit, add, and delete records while restricting the ability of other users to do so. See the Setting Update Propertiespage as well as the Controlling Record Updatepage for more information about Update Settings.  
</description>	
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>
<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		
		<description>Grid > Update Settings Menu
</description>	
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Update_Settings.png</link></figure>
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>


<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Search Fields and Detail View > Fields Menus </title>
		<description>The Search > Fieldsand Detail View > Fieldsmenus are similar to the Grid > Fieldsmenus in function. The page for manipulating fields in Search and Detail are almost identical in their properties list and selection of tools. You might remember that on the Component Type page, discussed at the beginning of this guide, there were two check boxes below the Grid Layout menu, one asking if your ' Grid contains a 'Search' part? ' and the second if your ' Grid contains a detail 'View' part? '. Checking those boxes created a Search box and a detail view box in the preview pane. This is the place that you come to define what fields your Search and Detail View boxes will contain. For example you might only want a one field like Customer_IDto be one that users can search for; or you may want many fields to be searchable. To manipulate fields simply click the arrows between the Available Fields list and the Fields to Search in list. See the Grid Fields Menusection for more detail.  
</description>	
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>In the tree menu  </description>
		<figure><link>images/A_SearchFields.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>See also Adding a Detail View Form   
</description>
	</section>
	
</sections>	
</group>



<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Search > Properties and Detail View > Properties Menus</title>
		<description>Like Search and Detail View fields,  Search > Properties  and Detail View > Properties  menus are also similar to the Grid > Propertiesmenus in function. You can use them to create the look and feel of the Search and Detail View boxes in your grid. The Search and Detail View properties menus will not open if you do not first select the Read Only box on the Component Type page and then click the ' Grid contains a 'Search' part? ' and the ' Grid contains a detail 'View' part? ' check boxes. Properties fall into the categories of Display Settings, Lookup, Textbox Properties, Client Side Properties, Javascript, Time Picker Properties, and Row Properties. Refer to Customizing the Search Partand Customizing the Detail View.  
Search box properties  
</description>	
<figure><link>images/A_SearchProperties.png</link></figure>
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>





<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Code</title>
		<description>The Code menu allows you to add Server-side Events, Client-side Events, Xbasic Functions, and Javascript Functions to your grid. You can adapt your code to examine the contents of a grid, properties of a grid, and the data being submitted. You can then take action to modify values or even cancel the submission.  </description>	
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>


<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		
		<description>Server-side Xbasic Event Code 
</description>	
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Events.png</link></figure>
	</section>
		<section>
		
		<description>Client-side Javascript Event Handlers 
</description>	
		<figure><link>images/A_client-sidejs.png</link></figure>
	</section>
		
		<section>
		
		<description>The Xbasic Function Window 
</description>	
		<figure><link>images/A_XbasicFunc.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>The Javascript Function Window 
</description>	
		<figure><link>images/A_jsfunctions.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<description>Code editing within a grid has become easier and more powerful, both for Xbasic and JavaScript code. 
There are separate, modeless editing panes for Server-side Events, Client-side Events, Xbasic Functions, and JavaScript Functions. All four panes do syntax-coloring and auto-suggest as you type. All four pane have companion tabs for an Interactive Window for the appropriate language, Xbasic or JavaScript, and have links to dialog that help you insert commonly used expressions for the event context. The two Events panes have event selectors, and the Client-side Events pane has a filter for the event selector. 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/client-side_event_page_v11.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
		
	<section>
		<description>Each pane has its own editing toolbar. The Xbasic Functions and Server-side Events toolbars include a Check Syntaxbutton for Xbasic. All four toolbars have buttons for cut, copy, paste, undo, redo, find, replace, indent, outdent, left align, format code, transform code, comment out, and un-comment out.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/xbasic_editing_toolbar_v11.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
</group>

<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Information</title>
		<description>The Information  menu  allows you to add information about the grid. It also tracks the time of the grid's creation and last update. It is located at the very bottom of the Component Type tree menu in the Grid Builder.  
</description>	
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>


<group>
<sections>
	<section>
		

		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Information.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Xbasic Pane</title>
		<description>The Xbasicpane shows you the Xbasic code that the builder is creating in the background. You cannot edit this code, but you can copy it.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Xbasic_tab.png</link></figure>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
</group>


<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Live Preview Pane</title>
		<description>The Live Previewpane renders the grid using either Chrome or Internet Explorer. It provides a quick look at your work and a way to check its behavior with live data. The appearance of the grid may be different than you see in another vendor's browser. When you Live Preview the Component that you are editing, the Component is published to the special LivePreview folder in your web root. In order for the Component to execute, the CSS style sheet, Javascript files, any child Components that your Component references, images used in your Component, etc. must also be published to the LivePreview folder. It can take some time to publish all of these files.  

Once these files have been published you can speed up the time taken to Live Preview your Component by skipping the step that publishes all of the support files. Generally, the first time you do a live preview, you should choose the Full Preview option, and then subsequently, you should choose the Fast Preview option. This will get you into Live Preview quickly, as the only file that gets published is the Component that you are editing. If your Component does not appear to be styled correctly, just go back and choose the option to publish all support files.  
</description>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>Live Preview Options  </description>
		<figure><link>images/A_LivePreviewOption.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>


<group>
<sections>
	<section>

		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Live_Preview_tab.png</link></figure>
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>


<group background="true">
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Working Preview Pane</title>
		<description>The Working Preview is like the Live Preview in that it shows an actual working version of your grid. Unlike the Live Preview,  doesn't require the Alpha Anywhere application server to be turned on. Instead, the Working Preview talks directly to Xbasic using an Alpha Anywhere protocol, not the http protocol. The Working Preview has two main benefits, speed and the ability to easily debug into your xbasic event handlers. If you want an example of how you might go about doing this see the example below or watch this  "Working Preview"  video.  
</description>	
	</section>
	<section>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Go to Component Type and check Updatable to make a grid you can update.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>In the Grid > Data Source page Select .dbf Tables.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Under Grid > Query(DBF) add  the customer table from Alpha Sports.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Go to the Grid > Fields page and select the first four fields ( Customer_id, Firstname, Lastname,and Companyin this case) in the Available Fields list and move them to the Selected list on the right.  </description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Now go to Working Preview and you will see a full working copy of your grid that you can interact with.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Now go back to Grid > Fields and select the Companyfield under the Selected list. Move over to Field Properties and select Validation Xbasic and click the button at the end of the Validation Xbasic row. Go to Validation Xbasic to alter the Xbasic script  .  
</description>
	<figure><link>images/A_Validation.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>In the Validation Xbasic for: Dialog that loads add the following code. This states that if the Company is blank and if the Lastname is Smith than we will generate an error message that says the 'Company can not be blank'. Put a debug(1) in your script to run the debugger.</description>
<example><![CDATA[function validate_Company as p (e as p)  
if e.data.Company = "" then  
debug(  1  )  
    if e.data.Lastname = "Smith" then 
        validate_Company.hasError = .t. 
        validate_Company.errorText = "Company cannot be blank." 
    end if 
end if 
    end function  ]]></example>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Now go back to Working Preview and Choose the Lastname field and write 'Smith' over an existing name, then go the the Company field on the same row and erase the company name. You should end up with something like the image below.</description>
			<figure><link>images/A_Smith.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Still in Working Preview , hit the Submit at the bottom of your Grid, since your grid is updatable it should have a submit button all ready to go. Go back and look at the fields you changed. You should see the debugger open and also an error warning in the Company field whose name you erased. In the debugger you should be able to hover over the variables that cause the error warning you made and see that they correspond to the changes you made. For example by hovering over Lastname you will see that you entered 'Smith' as the last name.  </description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<figure><link>images/A_SmithLastname.png</link></figure>
					</case>
					<case>
						<figure><link>images/A_SmithError.png</link></figure>
					</case>
					
					
				</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Remember to remove your debug statement before you look at your grid in Live Preview. Also you will need to turn on the Alpha Anywhere application server. If you don't like the working preview you can go to Options Preferences and turn off the working preview from there.  </description>
			</step>
			
			
			
		</steps>
		
		
		
	</section>
</sections>	
</group>
</groups>	
<links>
	<link href="images/A_Paste.png">eyedropper_img</link>
</links>	
	
	
</page>