<page>
	<topic>Placing Unrelated Grids in a Tabbed GridLinker
</topic><description>A tabbed gridlinker contains and displays a parent grid component and multiple child grid components. The presumption is that the table behind the parent grid is linked one-to-one or one-to-many to the tables behind the child grids.
However, it is possible to place multiple grids that have no relationship to each other into a tabbed gridlinker.
</description>
	<sections>
<section>
	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Create the Parent Grid</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Create a new table named dummy with a single character field. Name the field "test".</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Enter a single record into the table.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create a tabular grid based on the dummy table.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create a calculated field with the following expression: link = "1".
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place the "link" calculated field on the grid. The parent grid looks like this: 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Dummy_Grid.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
		
<section>
	<title>Create the Child Grids</title>
	<description>The child grids may be based on any table and have individual formatting. This example created these two grids based on the AlphaSports sample database.
For each grid:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Create a calculated field with the following expression: link = "1".
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place the "link" calculated field on the grid.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the "link" calculated field in the Selected fields list and set the Column Properties > Hide column property to TRUE (checked).
</description>
		</step>
		
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>		



<section>
	<title>Create the Tabbed gridlinker</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Create a new tabbed gridlinker.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Add, select the parent grid, and click OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Add the child grids.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>For each child grid:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Select the grid and click Link.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select the parent grid in the Parent list.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select the "link" field in the Linking Fields Parent Field list.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select the "link" field in the Linking Fields Child Field list.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description><![CDATA[Set the Grid Properties > Tab button (selected) property to: <font face=Verdana size=4><b> Tab Title </b></font>.
]]></description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description><![CDATA[Set the Grid Properties > Tab button (not selected) property to: <font face=Verdana size=3> Tab Title </font>.
]]></description>
	</case>
	
	
	
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Save the gridlinker.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place the gridlinker on a page and publish it. The result should look something like this. Note the parent grid at top. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Unrelated_Grids_1.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Reopen the gridlinker component
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the parent grid.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Set the Grid Properties > Customize page layout property to TRUE (checked).
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the Grid Properties > Page layout template property and click the '..' button to display the Tabbed Grid Layout dialog. You will find code that looks like this at the top of the editor.
</description>
<example><![CDATA[<table><!-- begin table for parent Grid -->
<tr>

<td>{ParentGrid_Echo_Part}</td>
</tr>
<tr>

<td>{ParentGrid_UpdateErrors_Part}</td>
</tr>
<tr>

<td>{ParentGrid_Search_Part}</td>
</tr>
<tr>

<td>{ParentGrid_Grid_Part}</td>
</tr>
<tr>

<td>{ParentGrid_DetailView_Part}</td>
</tr>
</table><!-- end table for parent Grid -->
 ]]></example>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Delete all this code and click OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Save the gridlinker component and republish it. The result should look something like this. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Unrelated_Grids_2.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>		
<section>
	<description><![CDATA[If you look at the source of the A5W page that contains the modified gridlinker component, you will note that there is code both above and below the <body> tag. The code above the <body> tag loads the parent grid component and remains unchanged. However, it is not necessary to display the parent grid component. You just removed the code below the <body> tag that normally would display the grid component. ]]></description>
	
</section>

	</sections>
	
</page>