<page>
	<topic>Single Parent Style GridLinker Component</topic>
	<description>The gridlinker has been deprecated.</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<note>The GridLinker is deprecated in Version 10 and above in favor of tabbed linked content sections (video) and row expanders (video). 
This lesson shows how to make a GridLinker component that displays a single record from a parent table and a grid from a child table in the following format. 
</note>
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<figure><link>images/WPT_Single_Parent_Style_4.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>
<section>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Create a new tabular grid based on the AlphaSports Invoice_Header table.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Display the Grid Fields page of the Grid Component Builder.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Move the "Invoice_Number", "Customer_ID", "Date", "Sales_Rep", "Delivery_By", "Pay_Method", "Sales_Tax", "Discount", "CC_Number", and "CC_Expiration" from the Available Fields list to the Selected Fields list.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Make choices under Display Settings > Display Format for fields that need special formatting (such as Currency fields).
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Check the Column Properties > Hide Column property for all but the first field that you will display on the grid.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Erase the Column Properties > Column heading property for the first (and only) field that is not hidden.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Check the Column Properties > Freeform layout property for this field.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click '...' in Column Properties > Freeform template property field to display the Freeform Column Layout dialog. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Single_Parent_Style_6.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select the fields that you want to display from the Available Fields list.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place the fields (illustrated above) into an HTML table. Either add the table code here manually or click HTML Editor and add the appropriate HTML styling (illustrated below). 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Single_Parent_Style_7.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Save > Close > OK to return to the Grid Component Builder.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create a second grid component for the child table. Remember the child table has to include (but does not need to display) the field that links it to the parent table. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Single_Parent_Style_1.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create a gridlinker component that associates the two tables with their linking fields. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/WPT_Single_Parent_Style_8.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Place the grid linker component into an A5W page and publish it.</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>
	
</sections>

	
	
</page>