<page>
   <topic>table.EXPORT Function</topic>
   <syntax>V Export()</syntax>
   <description>Export records in table to specified output file.</description>
   <discussion>
      ...put discussion here....
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
...put example code here....
]]></example>
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>put description here</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
      ...put example here....
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Table Functions and  Methods</ref>
      <ref>Table Operation  Methods</ref>
   </see>
   <original><![CDATA[&ltTBL>.EXPORT()
Syntax
Specify the required values in the Export dot variable, then use the following command:
&ltTBL>.EXPORT()
VariableTypeDescription
export.fileCThe path and name of the file being created.
export.typeNA code that specifies the type of file being created.
CodeNumberDescriptionExt
FILE_FORMAT_ASCII0Character-Separated ASCII.ASC
FILE_FORMAT_TABLE_ASCII1Table ASCII.TBL
FILE_FORMAT_RICH_TEXT2Rich Text Format (RTF).RTF
FILE_FORMAT_EXCEL_VERSION_33Microsoft Excel, Version 3.0.XLS
FILE_FORMAT_EXCEL_VERSION_44Microsoft Excel, Version 4.0.XLS
FILE_FORMAT_123_VERSION_15Lotus 1-2-3, Version 1.0/1A.WKS
FILE_FORMAT_123_VERSION_26Lotus 1-2-3, Version 2.0.WK1
FILE_FORMAT_123_VERSION_37Lotus 1-2-3, Version 3.0.WK3
FILE_FORMAT_SYMPHONY_VERSION_18Lotus Symphony, Version 1.0.WRK
FILE_FORMAT_SYMPHONY_VERSION_29Lotus Symphony, Version 2.0.WR1
export.namesCSpecifies whether or not the field names should be exported along with the data.

TRUE (.T.) = export fieldnames

FALSE (.F.) = do not export fieldnames. 
export.optionsCThe format for a character-separated ASCII file can vary. The default character-separated ASCII file is a comma-delimited file, with character fields in quotation marks, and a carriage return and line feed to separate records. If you want a different format for a character-separated ASCII file, you can adjust the export settings using one or more of the codes in the Options String:
Option CodeFunction
QQuote character fields
LStrip leading blanks from fields
TStrip trailing blanks from fields
SSuppress trailing separators
NPreserve line breaks. Converts line breaks in exported memo fields to "\N". If this option is not specified, then line breaks are converted to spaces.
export.field_sepCThe Field Separator String and the Record Separator String parameters are also used with character-separated ASCII files to define how to denote the end of fields and records. These strings can include any characters, including the following special separator characters:
export.rec_sep
Carriage return and line feed combination
Carriage return
Line feed
Escape
Tab
export.fetch_parentLUsed only parent tables in sets.

TRUE (.T.) = When exporting data from a set with one-to-many links, only exports data from the parent table, and one-to-one links off the parent table.

FALSE (.F.) = Exports a parent record for each matching one-to-many child record. 
export.fieldsNSpecifies how many fields are to be exported.
export.field1 ...
export.fieldNCThe names of the fields to be exported.

Description
The .EXPORT() method is a high-level utility function you use to export the records of a table or set to a file of a different format. Most parameters passed to export through the export function variable correspond directly with the prompts and options appearing on the Export Builder.
You perform an Export operation on the table referenced by the object pointer, .
Example
This script exports 4 fields from the Customer table to 'an ASCII table file. The export of field names is optional.
dim tbl as P
tbl = table.open("customers")
filename = ui_get_file("Destination File", "ASCII(*.ASC)", "customer.asc","N")
if filename = "" then
    end
end if
response = ui_get_radio("Export Fieldnames To File? ",1,"Yes","No")
if response = "Yes" then
    export_names = .T.
else
    export_names = .F.
end if
export.file = filename
export.type = 1
export.names = export_names
export.options = "Q"
export.field_sep = ","
export.rec_sep = ""
export.fields = 5
export.field1 = "cust_id"
export.field2 = "salutation"
export.field3 = "first_name"
export.field4 = "last_name"
export.field5 = "home_phone"
tbl.export()

See Also
Table Functions and  Methods, Table Operation  Methods]]></original>
</page>