<page>
   <topic>TABLE.CURRENT Function</topic>
   <syntax>P Current([N slot])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>slot</name>
         <description>Numeric</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Returns the current table.</description>
   <discussion>
      ...put discussion here....
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
...put example code here....
]]></example>
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>put description here</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
      ...put example here....
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Table Functions and  Methods</ref>
   </see>
   <original>TABLE.CURRENT()
Syntax
 as P = TABLE.CURRENT( [ Slot_Number as N ] )
ArgumentDescription
Slot_NumberOptional. Refers to other open tables in the current session. A slot number ranges from 1 to the number of open tables in a session. If your current table is part of a set, Slot 1 is the primary table, Slot 2 is the first child, Slot 3 is the grandchild or the primary table's second child, and so on. All open tables, whether or not they are part of a set, will occupy slots in the session.

Description
The TABLE.CURRENT() method returns an object pointer to an open table in the current session. Use TABLE.CURRENT()without a parameter to return a pointer to the session's primary table.
If no table is found in a particular slot, TABLE.CURRENT()creates an invalid object pointer. You can test the validity of an object pointer using the IS_OBJECT() function.
You can also get a pointer to an open table using the TABLE.GET() method. For example, if you have opened a set and you want to get a pointer to one of the child tables in the set, (say "Invoice_Items"), you could use this command:
child = table.get("invoice_items")

Contrasting TABLE.OPEN()with TABLE.CURRENT()and TABLE.GET()
See TABLE.OPEN() for information on the difference between TABLE.CURRENT()and TABLE.OPEN().
Example
Count the number of open tables.
count = 1
while .T.
    tbl = table.current(count)
    'Check to see if the table pointer, tbl, is valid.
    'If not, then there are no more open tables.
    if .not. is_object(tbl)
      count = count - 1
        exit while
    else
        count = count + 1
    end if
end while
trace.writeln("Open tables = " + ltrimcount-1?)

See Also
Table Functions and  Methods</original>
</page>