<page>
   <topic>table.FETCH_FIND Function</topic>
   <syntax>N Fetch_Find(A key)</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>key</name>
         <description>Any type</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Using the current index, find specified key value, return record number.</description>
   <discussion>
      ...put discussion here....
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
...put example code here....
]]></example>
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>put description here</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
      ...put example here....
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Table Functions and  Methods</ref>
   </see>
   <original><![CDATA[&ltTBL>.FETCH_FIND()
Syntax
Record_Number as N = &ltTBL>.FETCH_FIND( Matching_Expression as A )
ArgumentDescription
Matching_ExpressionAn expression used to select a record. The Matching_Expression and the table's or set's primary index key must have the same data type. Alpha Anywhere will automatically pad the Matching_Expression with trailing blanks if necessary so that the length of Matching_Expression matches the index key length. If the table's or set's primary index is record number order, then Matching_Expression is the record number that you want to find.

Description
The &ltTBL>.FETCH_FIND() method retrieves the first record in the table or set referenced by &ltTBL> with a primary index key equal to the Matching_Expression parameter.
If &ltTBL>.FETCH_FIND()is successful, the found record is retrieved and its Record_Number is returned. If no exact match is found, a negative number corresponding to the record number of the closest matching record is returned.
Example
This script is on a button on a form for a set in which the inv_item table is a child table. The script opens the product table. It then finds the record that matches product_id in the inv_item table, and assigns the value from the qty_stock field in product to the on_hand variable.
dim tbl_product as P
dim indx_1 as P
tbl_product = table.open("c:\data\product.dbf")
indx_1 = tbl_product.index_primary_put("id_index")
rec = tbl_product.fetch_find(inv_item->product_id)
if (rec > 0) then
    on_hand = tbl_product.qty_stock
else
    ui_msg_box("Record not found", "The closest match is record number " + abs(rec)")
end if
tbl_product.close()

This script opens a table and finds record 100.
dim tbl as P
dim indx_1 as P
tbl = table.open("d:\data\product.dbf")
'Select record number order
indx_1 = tbl.index_primary_put()
rec = tbl.fetch_find(100)

See Also
Table Functions and  Methods]]></original>
</page>