<page>
    <shortlink>form layout tab properties properties</shortlink>
    <topic>FormView Tab Properties</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring a Tab Control in the Form View Builder.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Accordion style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if only one pane at a time can be open, or if multiple panes can be shown.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Single</name>
                    <description>Only one pane can be expanded at a time.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Multiple</name>
                    <description>Allow multiple tab panes to be expanded at the same time.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Id</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Tab Control ID in the Form.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Initial open panes</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Initial open panes]* property defines the accordion panes that are shown when the Tab Control with a type of 'Accordion' is initially shown in the FormView. The first accordion pane is always pane '1'.</p>
                <p>The open panes are specified as a comma delimited list of numbers. For example, specifying a value of *[ui:1,2]* indicates that both the first and second accordion pane should be open when initially rendered.</p>
                <p>If the [Accordion style] is set to 'Single' enter a single value. If no panes should be open, leave this property blank.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example: Pane 2 is initially open</title>
            <description>
                <p>To specify a singe open pane, set the value of *[ui:Initial open panes]* to the pane number to render open. In the example below, accordion pane 2 is specified as open when the FormView control is initially rendered:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPane2.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPane2Result.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example: Pane 1, 4, and 6 are initially open</title>
            <description>
                <p>If the *[ui:Accordion style]* is set to 'Multiple', multiple panes can be open when initially rendered. The example below demonstrates setting pane 1, 4, and 6 to open when the FormView is initially rendered:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPane146.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPane146Result.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example: All panes are initially closed</title>
            <description>
                <p>To specify all accordion panes should be closed, leave the *[ui:Initial open panes]* property blank. EG:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPaneNone.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <link>images/initPaneNoneResult.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Initial tab</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Initial tab]* property defines the tab pane shown when the Tab Control with a type of 'Tab' is initially shown in the FormView. The first tab pane is always pane '1'.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Tab buttons position</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify where tabs should appear for a Tab Control.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Top</name>
                    <description>Display tabs along the top.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bottom</name>
                    <description>Display tabs along the bottom.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Tab type</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the Tab Control should be rendered as a Tab or Accordion control.</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Tab</name>
                    <description>Tab control is rendered as a set of tabs.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Accordion</name>
                    <description>Tab control is rendered as a list of collapsible sections that are shown when the main heading for a section is clicked.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="form layout tab properties accordion style property">Accordion style</link>
    </links>
</page>
