<page build="5303">
    <shortlink>action javascript actionsheet</shortlink>
    <topic>ActionSheet</topic>
    <description>Display a menu styled as an iOS 'Action Sheet'.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A common user interface design in iOS mobile applications is the Action Sheet. An action sheet is a series of menu options that animates into display from the bottom of the screen. The menu can be divided into logical sections.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/actionsheet1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Menu items</name>
                    <description>Defines the menu items shown in the Action Sheet. The menu items are defined as a JSON string (see "Defining Menu items" below.) Use the *[ui:Sample JSON definition]* link in the "Action Sheet - Menu Definition" dialog to insert a sample menu.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Width</name>
                    <description>The width of the Action Sheet defined using CSS units. If left blank, the Action Sheet will automatically fill the available width..</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Menu items</title>
            <description> 
                <p>The Action Sheet *[ui:Menu items]* is used to define the menu. The Action Sheet menu is defined as an array of arrays of JSON. </p>
                <p>Each array within the outer array defines a menu group. Each item within the nested arrays is an object that defines either a menu item or a comment. The objects have an 'html' property and an optional 'action' property. If an item does not have an 'action' property it is rendered as a label. The 'action' property is a Javascript function to call when the menu item is tapped.</p>
                <p>For example:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="json"><![CDATA[[
    [
        {html: 'This is the help text above the Action Sheet. It does not have an action'},
        {html: 'Save', action: function(){alert('save')} },
        {html: 'Save As...', action: function(){alert('saveas')} }
    ],
    [
        {html: 'New', action: function(){alert('new')}},
        {html: 'Open...', action: function(){alert('open')}}
    ],
    [
        {html: 'Cancel', action: function(){alert('cancel')}}
    ]
]]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>This creates the Action Sheet shown below:</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/actionsheet2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Displaying an "Action Sheet"</title>
                <description> A common user-interface technique in iOS applications is an Action Sheet - a popup menu with a series of options. In this video we show how easy it is to add an Action Sheet style menu to a UX component.</description>
                <date>2018-08-29</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/d9cdfe9a</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux component action sheet">{dialog.object}.actionSheet()</ref>
    </see>
</page>