<page build="7144">
    <shortlink>aj circular progress indicator</shortlink>
    <topic>Circular Progress Indicator</topic>
    <description>Displays progress for an event using a circular progress bar.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Circular Progress Indicator]* action creates and displays a numeric value as a circular progress indicator, or gauge. This value can be read from a control. The progress indicator can be placed in a [Placeholder] control or DIV defined in the component.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/circularprogress.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Circular Progress Builder</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Circular Progress Builder]* allows you to customize the progress indicator, including:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Defining color ranges to indicate progress.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Customize the size and width of the control.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Configure the start and end angle for the progress bar.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Add labels, units, and more.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Color - complete</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The color for the completed portion of the progress indicator. The color can be a single color (e.g. *[css:#834187]*) or a range of colors. A color range is specified as a CR-LF delimited list of pipe separated value-color pairs. Values that fall within a range will use the specified color. For example:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example><![CDATA[20|red
30|yellow
green]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>In the above example, values less than or equal to 20 will be red, between 20 and 30 yellow, and above 30 green.</p>
                    </description>
                    <tip>
                        <p>Use the *[ui:Insert color...]* URL to insert a color using the Color Picker.</p>
                    </tip>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Color incomplete</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The color shown for the portion of the progress indicator representing the remaining progress.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Thickness (pixels)</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The width of the circular progress bar.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Size (pixels)</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The diameter of the progress indicator. This is the height and width of the control.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Start angle</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The angle of the starting position of the progress indicator. The 12 o'clock position is 0. A positive value specifies an angle in the clockwise direction from 0. A negative value specifies an angle in the counterclockwise direction from 0.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">End angle</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The angle of the ending position of the progress indicator. The 12 o'clock position is 0. A positive value specifies an angle in the clockwise direction from 0. A negative value specifies an angle in the counterclockwise direction from 0.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Value show</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, the value of the progress indicator is shown in the center of the control.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Value suffix</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Shown when *[ui:Value show]* is checked.</p>
                        <p>Text shown after the value.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Value style</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Shown when *[ui:Value show]* is checked.</p>
                        <p>The CSS to apply to the value.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control label show</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, a label is shown for the control.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control label text</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Shown when *[ui:Control label show]* is checked.</p>
                        <p>The control's label text.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Control label style</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Shown when *[ui:Control label show]* is checked.</p>
                        <p>The CSS to apply to the label. This property can be used to position the label.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Placeholder or div</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The name of a Placeholder control or DIV id where the progress indicator will be displayed. To specify a DIV, use this syntax:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example><![CDATA[DIV:div_id]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>For example, to display the progress indicator in a DIV tag with the id "progress":</p>
                        <p>
                            <example><![CDATA[DIV:progress]]></example>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Read control value from</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The control that contains the value to display in the progress indicator.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Displaying progress using a circular progress display</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in many applications is to display progress for some task. The circular progress indicator, or gauge, is a very easy and attractive way to display progress.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to add progress indicator controls to a UX component.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2020-10-19</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=67FFA2q62Mw</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/circularProgress.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <terms>gauge,progress bar,wait cursor</terms>
    <see>
        <ref link="xb%20a5wcbcircularprogressbuilder">a5wcb_circularProgressBuilder Function</ref>
    </see>
</page>