<page>
    <shortlink>Clear a Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component</shortlink>
    <topic>Clear a Search on a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component</topic>
    <description>Clears the search filter for an embedded Grid component that was filtered using the 'Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX' action.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>For use in conjunction with the *[ui:Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component]* action. Clears the search form in the UX and removes the filter from the embedded Grid.</p>
        <p>If the *[ui:Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component]* action applied a Base Filter, this action cannot be used to clear the search.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Table Filter/Order Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Embedded Grid name</name>
                    <description>The name of the embedded Grid component to clear the search.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Component alias name</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>(Read only) This is the component alias name. You cannot edit the alias here. You must edit is as part of the embedded Grid definition.</p>
                        <p>*[VERY IMPORTANT:]* If you change the Grid component's alias, you MUST edit and save this action to regenerate the underlying JavaScript for the action.</p>
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Controls to clear</name>
                    <description>Specify the controls on the UX component that should be cleared. (These are the controls were the user entered the search criteria).</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Searching a Grid Embedded in a UX Component</title>
                <description>
                    <p>While it is easy to add a Search Part to a Grid, there may be situations where you want to create a much more sophisticated Search Part for the Grid than the built-in Search Part allows.</p>
                    <p>For example, you might want your 'search part' to be organized into collapsible 'accordion' panes and you might want users to be able to use sliders and calendar controls to enter their search criteria.</p>
                    <p>Using the layout power that the UX component offers, it is very easy to create extremely sophisticated layouts to prompt for search criteria. These videos shows how you can use Action Javascript to search a Grid that has been embedded in the UX component. The net result being the ability to create an extremely powerful and flexible 'power search' part for your Grids.</p>
                </description>
                <date></date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch - Overview</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/wFjKacpki7xXp8VH9ay1cY</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch - Configuring the Action</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/aPdPdakkN7K1QXqRU2m6zz</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>components/searchEmbeddedGrid.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <note>
                <p>The Action Javascript to search a Grid embedded in a UX component was originally released as a Power Search Feature Pack addon for Alpha Five Version 11. These features are included automatically as part of Alpha Anywhere and do not require a feature key.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>UX Component Only</limitations>
    <terms>power search</terms>
    <see>
        <ref link="search%20a%20grid%20component%20that%20is%20embedded%20into%20a%20ux%20component">Search a Grid Component that is Embedded in a UX Component</ref>
        <ref link="list%20control%20actions">List Control Actions</ref>
        <ref link="filter%20records%20in%20a%20list%20control">Filter Records in a List Control</ref>
    </see>
</page>