<page>
   <topic>Client-side Data Cache Actions</topic>
   <description>Perform some action on an item in the Client-side Data Cache (e.g. read the data, refresh the data, etc.).</description>
   
   <sections>
     
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component.</description>
       </section>
       
 <section>
            <title>Client-side Data Cache Action Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Action name</name>
                    <description>Specify the Client-side Data Cache Action that you want to execute.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data cache items Id(s)</name>
                    <description>Specify the data cache items you want to perform an action on. You can enter a comma delimited list of data-items if you want to refresh the data in more than one data-item in a single Ajax callback.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data cache items to read</name>
                    <description>Data cache items to read property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data cache item to delete</name>
                    <description><![CDATA[Specify the name of the Data Cache item to delete (or '<all>' to delete all items). If the item is defined to persist (either in LocalStoragte or the filesystem) and it has been persisted, it will be removed (from either LocalStorage or the filesystem).]]></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data item</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the data item you want to read</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Filter</name>
                    <description>You can specify a filter expression to filter the data in the data item.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Order</name>
                    <description>You can specify an order expression to order the data in the data item.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Javascript Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>onComplete</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once all of the data items have been refreshed.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onComplete</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once all of the data items have been read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onSuccess</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once the data has been read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onSuccess</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once the action has completed.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onSuccess</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once the data has been read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onFail</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run if the action fails.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
   </sections>
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
   
</page>