<page build="5022">
    <shortlink>phonegap touchid faceid action</shortlink>
    <topic>PhoneGap - TouchID/FaceID</topic>
    <description>Adds TouchID/FaceID functionality to a mobile app built using Cordova.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>On some iOS devices, TouchID and FaceID can be used to authenticate the user before allowing them to use the app. The *[ui:PhoneGap - TouchID/FaceID]* Action Javascript action makes it easy to test for and utilize TouchID or FaceID in a Cordova application to verify the user's credentials before allowing them to access the application.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pgTouch1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Properties</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:PhoneGap TouchId/FaceId Login]* action is configured using the following properties:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Type</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The action to perform. The action can be one of the following:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Type</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>VerifyAvailable</name>
                            <description>Checks to see if TouchID or FaceID is available on the device.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Login</name>
                            <description>Activates TouchID or FaceID to perform a login.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Message</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The message shown on the fingerprint scanner. This option is only available if *[ui:Type]* has been set to "Login".</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">onSuccess</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An event that contains JavaScript to execute if the operation succeeds.</p>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Type]* is set to "VerifyAvailable", the onSuccess event will be executed if TouchID or FaceID is available on the device.</p>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Type]* is set to "Login", the onSuccess event is executed if login succeeds.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">onFailed</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An event that contains JavaScript to execute if the operation fails.</p>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Type]* is set to "VerifyAvailable", the onFailed event will be executed if TouchID or FaceID is not available on the device.</p>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Type]* is set to "Login", the onFailed event is executed if login fails -- either because the user failed to provide valid credentials or the action was cancelled.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Cordova Applications Only</limitations>
</page>