<page>
    <shortlink>PhoneGap - Notifications</shortlink>
   <topic>PhoneGap - Notifications</topic>
   <description>Display or initiate a native notification (for example, beep, native alert/prompt/confirmation, vibrate, etc.)</description>
   
   <sections>
     
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component.</description>
       </section>
       
    
  <section>
            <title>Display Or Initiate A Native PhoneGap Notification Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Notification Type</name>
                    <description>Displays a native alert, confirmation or prompt dialog, or initiates an audio beep or causes the mobile device to vibrate. Choices include *[ui:Alert]*, *[ui:Confirm]*, *[ui:Prompt]*, *[ui:Beep]*, *[ui:Vibrate]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Dialog Title</name>
                    <description>Optional, set the title of the pop up dialog. If left blank the default value is used
Default values are Alert, Confirm or Prompt dependent upon the selected notification type.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Dialog Message</name>
                    <description>Specify the message. The message text must be in the form of a Javascript expression, or it may reference a JavaScript variable which means that text must be enclosed in single quotes. For example: 'You are now logged on'  This example shows a message that contains a variable: 'Your user name is:' + userName. You can call a Javascript function to define the message text. For example, specify this as the message text: myJsFunction()</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Default Value</name>
                    <description>Enter the default textbox input value (string), this is optional. The default text must be in the form of a Javascript expression, or it may reference a JavaScript variable which means that text must be enclosed in single quotes. For example: 'Anonymous User'. You can call a Javascript function to define the message text. For example, specify the default value: setDefaultValue(). You can also simply reference a predefined JavaScript variable, for example _thisUser.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>JavaScript Callback Function Name</name>
                    <description>Enter the JavaScript callback function name that will be used to process the button selection(s) and the prompt input result if applicable.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Button Label</name>
                    <description>Text to display within the button. The default value is 'OK'.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Button Labels</name>
                    <description>Enter a character string of values separated by commas.
You are entering a one based index array so element 1 is referenced in the callback as result.buttonIndex(1).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Beep Count</name>
                    <description>Set the number of times a beep will sound on the device.
This value is ignored on iOS devices</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Time Duration</name>
                    <description>Sets the period of time (in milliseconds)for the device to vibrate.
This value is ignored on iOS devices.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
   </sections>
   
    <see>
   <ref link="action javascript for the ux">Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   
   </see>
   
   
</page>