<page build="4238">
    <shortlink>action javascript data series multiple actions</shortlink>
    <topic>DataSeries Actions... (multiple actions)</topic>
    <description>Perform actions on a DataSeries, including refreshing a data series or reading a data series.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:DataSeries Actions... (multiple actions)]* Action Javascript action is used to manipulate DataSeries defined in a UX Component. This action is useful with client-side DataSeries.</p>

    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>*[ui:DataSeries Actions... (multiple actions)]* can be used to perform the following actions:</description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Refresh the data in one or more Data Series. The action is only meaningful if you specified that your Data Series data should be published to the client-side. An Ajax callback is made and the SQL query or custom Xbasic code that gets the data for the Data Series is executed. The new data is then published to the client-side</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Read the data in a Data Series and assigns it to a Javascript variable.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Client-side DataSeries</title>
            <description>
                <p>If client-side DataSeries are enabled, the DataSeries data is stored in a JavaScript variable in the UX Component's JavaScript object. The *[ui:Refresh DataSeries]* stores the data in the *[js:{dialog.object}._dataSeriesData]* object. The data in a DataSeries can be referenced from JavaScript as follows:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[// if the DataSeries has subseries:
{dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.SeriesName.SubSeriesname

// if the DataSeries has no subseries:
{dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.SeriesName]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For example, suppose a DataSeries called *[ui:Series1]* has two subseries, *[ui:Country]* and *[ui:Population]*. The following JavaScript can be used to get the data for each subseries:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var country = {dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.Series1.Country;
var population = {dialog.object}._dataSeriesData.Series1.Population;]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>DataSeries Action Properties</title>
            <description>The following properties are used to configure the *[ui:DataSeries Actions... (multiple actions)]* Action Javascript:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Action name</name>
                    <description>Specify the DataSeries Action to execute. Can be one of the following actions:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Refresh DataSeries</name>
                            <description>Refresh one or all DataSeries. Only applies if you have published the DataSeries to the client-side.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Read DataSeries</name>
                            <description>Sets a variable to the data in the specified DataSeries and sub-series.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>DataSeries Name</name>
                    <description>The DataSeries to refresh or read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Sub-series name</name>
                    <description>The sub-series to read. Used with the *[ui:Read DataSeries]* action.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Variable Name</name>
                    <description>The name of the JavaScript variable to populate with the DataSeries data. Used with the *[ui:Read DataSeries]* action.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Ajax failed Javascript</name>
                    <description>(Optional) The JavaScript to execute if the Ajax callback to refresh the DataSeries fails (i.e. if the server doesn't send a response.) Used with the *[ui:Refresh DataSeries]* action.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Offline Javascript</name>
                    <description>(Optional) The JavaScript to execute if the device is offline. If the device is offline, no Ajax callback will be made to refresh the DataSeries, and the *[ui:Ajax failed Javascript]* function will not be called. Used with the *[ui:Refresh DataSeries]* action.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>onComplete Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the JavaScript to run once the data has been downloaded. Used with the *[ui:Refresh DataSeries]* action.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux properties publish data to client side property">Publish data to client-side Property</ref>
    </see>
</page>