<page>
    <shortlink>Dial Telephone Open SMS client</shortlink>
   <topic>Dial Telephone Open SMS client</topic>
   <description>Dial a telephone number or open the SMS client application to send a SMS message.</description>
   
   <sections>
     
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
<description>The number to dial can either be static (i.e. specified at design time), or it can be read from controls on the UX, columns in a List, or returned by a Javascript function.</description>
</section>
       <section>
         
          <title>Dial Telephone Number</title>
          <list>
              <item>
                  <name>Action type</name>
                  <description>Specify the action</description>
              </item>
              <item>
                  <name>Javascript function</name>
                  <description>Specify the name of a Javascript function to call. This function must return the number to dial (including the country code. e.g. +15551231234</description>
              </item>
               <item>
                  <name>List name</name>
                  <description>The name of the list to use.</description>
              </item>
              
               <item>
                  <name>Method for specifying the telephone number</name>
                  <description>The method for specifying the telephone number. Options are 'Static', 'Read from controls on UX', 
                      'Read from columns in a List', 'Javascript'.
                  </description>
              </item>
            
              <item>
                  <name>Number template</name>
                  <description>The template allows you to specify the fields to read for the phone number and country code. For example assume you have a control (or List column) called 'CountryCode' and a control (or List column) called 'PhoneNumber' you could specify the template as: +{CountryCode}{PhoneNumber}. If you only have a PhoneNumber field and all of your numbers are in the US, you could define the template as: +1{PhoneNumber}. Note that the control name you want to read is enclosed in curly brackets.
IMPORTANT: Placeholder names are case-sensitive. For example, {Phone} and {phone} are not the same!</description>
              </item>
                 <item>
                  <name>Number to dial</name>
                  <description>Specify the number. Include the country code. For example, 
                      +15551234444. (In this case the country code is 1 -US).
                  </description>
              </item>
          </list>
          
          
          
       </section>
       
       
       
   </sections>
   
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>