<page>
    <shortlink>Export to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format</shortlink>
    <topic>Export to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format</topic>
    <description>Export data to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format. The Custom format option allows you to define an Xbasic function that creates the file.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>Action Javascript action available in the Grid Component that exports records in the Grid Component to Excel, Ascii, or a Custom File format.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/exportExcelAsciiCustom.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
  <section>
            <title>Export Data Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Export type</name>
                    <description>Specify the format of the exported data. If you select Custom, you can define your own Xbasic function to create the export file in any format that you want. For Excel select 'Excel' to create a .xls file and 'Excel-XLSX' for a .xlsx file. Choices include *[ui:Excel]*, *[ui:Excel-XLSX]*, *[ui:Comma delimited ascii]*, *[ui:Tab delimited ascii]*, *[ui:Custom]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Custom format Xbasic function</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Xbasic function that will create the custom file you want to export. This function must be defined in the Xbasic Function Declarations property. 
TIP: Click the hyperlink at the bottom to get the correct function prototype.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Source</name>
                    <description>Specify what fields should be exported.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Client-side filename</name>
                    <description><![CDATA[Specify the default filename to use when saving the file on the user's computer. The user can override the suggested name. If you set the name to <Default>, Alpha Anywhere will generate the filename.]]></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Zip file</name>
                    <description>Specify if the exported file should be zipped before it is downloaded to the user's computer.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Export hidden fields</name>
                    <description>Should 'hidden' fields be exported? ('Hidden' fields are not necessarily actually hidden when the Grid is displayed  - they could be shown in another column's Free-form layout section).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Use Grid column headings</name>
                    <description>Should the column headings in the export file be the same as the Grid Column Headings? If unchecked, the field name is used.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Field list</name>
                    <description>Select fields to export.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Record selection</name>
                    <description>Specify if only the records in the current Grid query should be exported, or all records in the Grid. Choices include *[ui:Records in current query]*, *[ui:All records]*, *[ui:Current record only]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum number of records</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum number of records to export. Set to 0 for no limit.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Custom Export Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Custom type</name>
                    <description>Specify if the query is against DBF tables or a SQL database. Choices include *[ui:DBF]*, *[ui:SQL]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>DBF Table</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the DBF table.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Field names</name>
                    <description>Specify the names of the fields in the DBF table that you want to export</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Filter - DBF</name>
                    <description>Specify the filter expression.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Order - DBF</name>
                    <description>Specify the filter expression.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Connection string</name>
                    <description>Specify the connection string.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SQL Select</name>
                    <description>Specify the SQL Select statement.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Filter - SQL</name>
                    <description>Specify the filter expression. (This is in addition to any WHERE clause defined in your SELECT statement.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Order - SQL</name>
                    <description>Specify the filter expression.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Arguments</name>
                    <description>You can use arguments in the filter expressions that you define. Using arguments for variable data makes it easier to write your filter expressions.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Argument bindings</name>
                    <description>Specify where each argument that have defined gets its value. Arguments can get their values from a value in the current Grid row, a session variable, or a literal value.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Events - Server-Side Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>After export</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Xbasic function to call after the records have been exported and the export file has been created, but before the file has been sent to the browser. Function is defined in Xbasic Function Declarations section.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Events - Client-Side Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Before export</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript function to call before records are exported. This function must return true, or false. If false, export is aborted. Function is defined in Javascript Function Declarations section.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>After export</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript function to call before after the records have been exported and the file has been downloaded to the browser.  Function is defined in Javascript Function Declarations section.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Grid Component Only</limitations>
    <see>
        <ref>Action Javascript in the Grid</ref>
    </see>
</page>