<page>
   <topic>Geolocation Functions</topic>
   <description>Get geolocation information from the browser and store information in the current Grid/UX component object (e.g. if you are in a Grid, the data is stored in the {grid.object}.geoLocation object). (Requires an HTML5 browser).</description>
   
   <sections>

    <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid and UX components. The option 'Get accurate position within a designated radius' can be found the Action JavaScript Geolocation functions. 
                When enabled, you may specify a desired accuracy radius.</description>
       </section>
        <section>
      <description>The returned lat/lon will fall within the desired accuracy radius if at all possible. This option calls a new custom method that has been added to the navigator.geolocation object called getAccuratePosition(). This method uses the geolocation watchPosition() method to attempt to get position data within a specified accuracy radius. The method will time-out at the maximum wait time and will return the last known location, even if the accuracy does not meet the desired accuracy target. 
</description>
      <figure><link>images/geolocationMods.png</link></figure>
      
  </section>     
  <section>
      <description>The maximum wait time defines the maximum amount of time in ms to wait for a geolocation change event.
If Ignore first result is checked, the first geolocation point returned will not be used. Some devices return cached location data for the first result, which is, in most cases, inaccurate. 
The returned geolocation data can be accessed through the {dialog.object}.getGeolocation() method. 
Example code for the 'Callback function' in the above image:

</description>
<example><![CDATA[function gotResults() {
       var e = {dialog.object}.getGeolocation();
       alert('Lat = '+e.latitude+' Lon = '+e.longitude);
     }]]></example>
  </section>     

       <section>
          <title>Javascript placed in 'OnPush' attribute</title>
          <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}._ajs.rowNum = {grid.object}._selectedRow;
navigator.geolocation.getCurrentPosition({dialog.object}.geoLocateSuccess_5c7b349bfc2c441d80f7fb40ab4071fd,{dialog.object}.geoLocateFailed_5c7b349bfc2c441d80f7fb40ab4071fd,{enableHighAccuracy : true, timeout:15000, maximumAge:30000});]]></example>
       </section>
       
      

   </sections>
   <links>
       
       <link href="images/open.png">...</link>
       
   </links>
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>