<page build="4169">
    <shortlink>get server side data action javascript</shortlink>
    <topic>Get Server-side Data</topic>
    <description>The purpose of the action is to get server-side data and return the data to the client where you can then further process the data with Javascript code. For example, you might use the data returned to populate a List control, a dropdown box, a SpinList etc.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/getserversidedata1.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The builder for the action is shown below:</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/getserversidedata2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The server-side data can be obtained by performing a query against a SQL database, or by executing a Xbasic function (which can, in turn, call web services - REST or SOAP) to get the data that should be returned to the client.</p>
                <p>The options for the Query type parameter are:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>SQL query</name>
                    <description>A single query against a SQL Database.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Nested SQL query</name>
                    <description>A query against a SQL database that will return a complex JSON document with nested arrays. For example an array of customers, for each customer, a nested array of orders, for each order, a nested array of order details.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Xbasic</name>
                    <description>An Xbasic function that will execute when the action is run. The Xbasic function will return an array of data (in JSON format). The JSON might come from a REST or SOAP API called by the Xbasic function. </description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The *[ui:onSuccess]* property allows you to define Javascript to execute once the data is received by the client. The data that is received by the client will be stored in a variable called:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{dialog.object}._serverSideData]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>