<page>
    <shortlink>Global Search and Replace</shortlink>
    <topic>Global Search and Replace</topic>
    <description>Search and replace values in a field in all currently visible rows in the Grid.</description>

    <sections>

        <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid component</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search and Replace Operation Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Field to update</name>
                    <description><![CDATA[Specify the field to update. You can use <CurrentField> to indicate the field that currently has focus.]]></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Read 'search' value from</name>
                    <description>Specify the ID of an element from which the 'search' value will be read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Read 'replace' value from</name>
                    <description>Specify the ID of an element from which the 'replace' value will be read.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>All instances in field</name>
                    <description>Replace all instances of the search phrase. If unchecked, only the first instance is changed.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Case insensitive</name>
                    <description>Specify if the search should be case insensitive.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Rows to update</name>
                    <description>Specify which rows should be updated. 'AllVisibleRows' - all visible existing record rows and all new record rows, 'AllVisibleExistingRecordRows' - all visible existing record rows, but not new record rows. 'AllNewRecordRows' - only new record rows. 'CheckedRows' - only rows that have been checked. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Prompt for confirmation</name>
                    <description>Before updating a non-blank value, prompt for confirmation?</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Confirmation message</name>
                    <description>Specify the template to use for the confirmation message. The message can include these placeholders: [row] - row number, [old] - old value in field, and [new] - new value for field.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Global Search and Replace in a Grid Component</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When doing data entry into a Grid there may be times when the user wants to perform a search and replace operation on the data the currently visible rows in the Grid. Using Action Javascript, it is easy to make a button does a 'global search and replace' on all visible rows in the Grid.</p>
                    <p>It is important to recognize that the action shown in this video is a 'client-side' action. No data is actually written to the database until the user clicks the 'Submit' button.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/8fb12d44</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>

        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>

    </links>
    <see>


        <ref link="action javascript in the grid">Action Javascript in the Grid</ref>
    </see>


</page>