<page>
   <topic>Image Upload</topic>
   <description>Upload an image file too the server.</description>
   
   <sections>
           <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid and UX components</description>
       </section>
       
       <section>
           <description>First it is necessary to add an image to the component.</description>
           
       </section>
       
         <section>
        <title>Thumbnails</title>
        <description>The Action Javascript builder has an option in the Thumbnail Definition Builder 
            that allows you to specify if the thumbnail file that is created should overwrite an existing file, 
            or be renamed, so as not to conflict with existing files.

</description>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>When you define how thumbnails are to be created, you can specify if the thumbnail is to be stored as a 
            file on disk, or as binary data in a record. In the case where you specify a file on disk, the builder allows
             you to specify a 'suffix' that is automatically added to the filename. For example if the suffix is 'thumb1', 
             then the file on disk might called 'image_thumb1.jpg'. 
             However, there may be situations where you don't want the suffix. If you set the suffix to a blank value, the file on disk has no suffix at all (e.g. 'image.jpg').
             </description>
        <note>Prior to Alpha Five Version 12, setting the suffix to a blank value would result in the file on disk being created as 'image_.jpg'.</note>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Of course, if you set the suffix to a blank value, the upload folder for the thumbnails needs to be 
            different than the upload folder for the main image you are uploading, or else when the thumbnail is created,
             it will overwrite the main image.
</description>
    </section>
    
    
     <section>
        <title>File Rename</title>
        <description>When you upload images or files and store the uploaded images or files in a filename on a server, there is an option to rename the file if there is an existing file with the same name on the server. Here is how the algorithm that computes the filename in the case of a conflict works. If a filed called "c:\myimages\image1.jpg" exists and you want to create a new file called 'image1.jpg', the new file will be called "c:\myimages\myimage1_1.jpg".
</description>
        
    </section>
    
       
   </sections>
   
   
   
   
</page>