<page>
    <shortlink>Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library</shortlink>
   <topic>Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library</topic>
   <description>This action is used exclusively for image fields in a List Detail View. Capture an image using the camera, or from the photo library. 
       On devices that don't support a camera, select an image from the filesystem.
   </description>
   
   <sections>
        <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component</description>
       </section>
       <section>
           
            <description>You can build mobile, disconnected applications, that include the ability to capture images using the camera on the device.  When running on a device that does not have a camera, the image to use can be selected from the file system.</description>
 
       </section>
          <section>
      <description>To create a button to capture a new image for an Image control in a List Detail View use the 'Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library' action.
</description>
     <figure><link>images/cameraaction.jpg</link></figure> 
    </section>
    <section>
      <description>For more information on capturing images in the List Detail View, see Creating Disconnected Mobile Applications and search for 'camera'.
</description>
      
    </section>
    
       <section>
           <description></description>
           
           <title>Javascript used in 'onPush' attribute:</title>
          
          
       </section>
       <section>
            <title>Image Capture Properties Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Image control</name>
                    <description>Specify the Detail View image control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript to execute when image has been captured</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to call once the image has been captured. Your Javascript can reference e.data. In the case where PhoneGap is used, you can also reference e.fileSystemURL, the file system URL of the image.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bound field type</name>
                    <description>Data type of the field in the List to which this control is bound.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bound List name</name>
                    <description>Name of List control for the data field that is bound to this control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bound field name</name>
                    <description>Name of the List control field to which this control is bound.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bound control type</name>
                    <description>Type of the control in the List to which this control is bound.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Image capture method</name>
                    <description>Specify the method for optaining the image. If the component is running in a PhoneGap shell, then you can use PhoneGap to access the camera (if you are not in a PhoneGap shell, user will get an error if they try to capture an image). If you select 'PhoneGapPreferred' then the PhoneGap method will be used if the component is running in a PhoneGap shell, otherwise the HTML5 method will be used. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Move file to permanent storage after capture</name>
                    <description>When an Image file is captured using PhoneGap the captured file in placed in a temporary storage location that could be cleared when the app is terminated. Therefore, it is advisable to move the file to a permanent location.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>File system part</name>
                    <description>on iOS: 'public' - the application's "Documents directory" - accessible in iTunes file sharing and backed up to iCloud, 'private' - application's private persistent data - deleted when application is uninstalled, 'sved' - similar to 'private', but backed up to iTunes. Choices include *[ui:saved]*, *[ui:private]*, *[ui:public]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>File system part</name>
                    <description>on iOS: 'public' - the application's "Documents directory" - accessible in iTunes file sharing and backed up to iCloud, 'private' - application's private persistent data - deleted when application is uninstalled, 'sved' - similar to 'private', but backed up to iTunes. Choices include *[ui:saved]*, *[ui:private]*, *[ui:public]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Folder</name>
                    <description>Specify the folder in the file system where the file should be stored.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Folder</name>
                    <description>Specify the folder in the file system where the file should be stored.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Data capture mode</name>
                    <description>(Only applies when the image is captured using PhoneGap) Specify if the image should be captured as Base64 data or as a filename on the mobile device. In applications that are designed for disconnected usage, capturing images as filenames will allow for many more images to be captured while you are disconnected. 
NOTE: You can only use the 'Filename' option if the image is stored to a character field. If the image is stored in an binary field, you can only use the Base64 option. Choices include *[ui:Base64]*, *[ui:Filename]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum image size exceeded Javascript</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to execute if the user selects an image that exceeds the maximum size. Your Javascript code can reference e.controlName and e.imageSize.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Upload Target (when using PhoneGap)</name>
                    <description>Specify if the image should be uploaded to the Alpha Anywhere server, or to a cloud storage provider (e.g. Amazon S3).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>More properties...</name>
                    <description>(Does not apply if the Upload Target is set to Amazon S3.) The additional properties for this field are stored in the List definition (see the 'Fields' tab in the List builder). As a convenience, you can also edit this properties here.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Amazon S3 Storage Properties Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Method for specifying Amazon S3 credentials and bucket</name>
                    <description>Should the Amazon S3 credentials and bucket be read from a named storage connection string, or do you want to specify explict values for the access key, secret and bucket. Choices include *[ui:Named Storage Connection String]*, *[ui:Explicit]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Storage connection string</name>
                    <description>Specify the named storage connection string. IMPORTANT: The storage connection string MUST NOT BE ENCRYPTED. TIP: To define a storage connection string, go to the Tools menu in the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Access key</name>
                    <description>Specify the access key.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Secret</name>
                    <description>Specify the secret.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Bucket</name>
                    <description>Specify the bucket.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Authenticated read</name>
                    <description>Specify if authentication is required to read the object once it has been uploaded to S3</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image Upload Target Settings Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Upload target settings</name>
                    <description>Specify if the image should be uploaded to the Alpha Anywhere server or to Amazon S3. 
NOTE: These settings are stored in the List definition. You can also edit the settings by opening the List builder, going to the 'Detail View' tab and then editing the 'Media and Other Linked Files' property.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image Thumbnails Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Create image thumbnails</name>
                    <description>When the List is synchronized with the server should thumbnails be created for the image? 
NOTE: The Thumbnail definition is stored in the List definition. (Open the List builder and go to the 'Fields' tab.) 
IMPORTANT: THIS FEATURE IS NOT AVAILABLE IF THE IMAGE IS UPLOAD TO AMAZON S3 STORAGE.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Thumbnail definition</name>
                    <description>Define what thumbnails should be created. 
NOTE: The Thumbnail definition is stored in the List definition.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Store Image EXIF Info Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Store EXIF info</name>
                    <description>When the List is synchronized with the server should EXIF data stored in the image be saved to the database?
NOTE: The EXIF info definition is stored in the List definition.  (Open the List builder and go to the 'Fields' tab.)
IMPORTANT: THIS FEATURE IS NOT AVAILABLE IF THE IMAGE IS UPLOAD TO AMAZON S3 STORAGE.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>EXIF Info definition</name>
                    <description>Define the type of EXIF info to store in the database. 
NOTE: The EXIF info definition is stored in the List definition.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        
        
        <section>
            <title>HTML5 Options Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Resize image (if greater than max allowed size)</name>
                    <description>Specify if the captured image should be resized before it is saved to the List (if it exceeds the maximum allowed size). (RECOMMENDED).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Resize image</name>
                    <description>Specify the policy for resizing the image. 'Always' -  the image will always be resized - regardless of its raw size. 'Only If Image Exceeds Max Size' - the image will only be resized if the raw image size exceeds the maximum size. Choices include *[ui:Always]*, *[ui:Only If Image Exceeds Max Size]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum image size (bytes)</name>
                    <description>If the image that is captured is bigger than this size, the image will be resized.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Image compression</name>
                    <description>Specify the image compression factor to use when capturing an image using HTML5. 1 - no compression, 0 - maximum compression</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Max image height</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum image height (in pixels)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Max image width</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum image width (in pixels)</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Video Options Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Duration</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum length of the video in seconds. Set to -1 if you don't want to specify a maximum value</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Store Image EXIF Info Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Store EXIF info</name>
                    <description>When the image is captured, should EXIF data stored in the image be captured?</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>EXIF Info definition</name>
                    <description>Define the type of EXIF info capture.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>PhoneGap Options Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Maximum image size (bytes)</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum image size (in bytes) that can be captured. Set to -1 for no limit (NOT RECOMMENDED!).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Picture source</name>
                    <description>Specify if the image should be captured by using the camera to take a picture, or if the user should select the image from the Photo Library on the device. Choices include *[ui:Camera]*, *[ui:Photo Library]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Type</name>
                    <description>Specify if the user should select a picture or video from the Photo Library Choices include *[ui:Pictures]*, *[ui:Videos]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Save picture to photo album</name>
                    <description>When enabled, the image is saved to the device's photo library.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Image quality</name>
                    <description>Specify the image quality when using PhoneGap</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Allow picture editing after capture</name>
                    <description>Can the user edit the picture after capturing it?</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Max image height</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum image height (in pixels)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Max image width</name>
                    <description>Specify the maximum image width (in pixels)</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>PhoneGap Message Customization Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Image selection canceled message</name>
                    <description>Image selection canceled message property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Image selection message close button</name>
                    <description>Image selection message close button property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Camera canceled message</name>
                    <description>Camera canceled message property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Camera canceled message close button</name>
                    <description>Camera canceled message close button property.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Client-side events Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Before image capture</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run before the image is captured. If your code contains 'return false;' then the image capture is cancelled.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>On image capture</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run once the image has been captured. Your Javascript can reference e.data which is the base64 encoded image. In the case where PhoneGap is used, you can also reference e.fileSystemURL, the file system URL of the image.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>On video capture failed</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run if the video capture failed.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
       

       
   </sections>
   
          
<see>
  <ref>Creating Disconnected Mobile Applications</ref>

       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
  
</see>
   
   
</page>