<page>
   <topic>Link a Grid that has been embedded into a UX component</topic>
   <description>Unlike the 'Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX' action which applies a filter to an embedded Grid,
       this action Links the embedded Grid.
   </description>
   
   <sections>
     
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component.</description>
       </section>
       
<section>
            <title>Table Filter/Order Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Embedded Grid name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the embedded Grid you want to execute a search on. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Component alias name</name>
                    <description>(Read only) This is the component alias name. You cannot edit the alias here. You must edit is as part of the embedded Grid definition.

VERY IMPORTANT: If you change the component alias, you MUST edit this action and then resave it in order to regenerate the correct Javascript!!</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Define link fields</name>
                    <description>Specify the controls on the Dialog that will be used to compute the Link to apply to the embedded Grid.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Filter type</name>
                    <description>Specify the filter type. In most cases, you UserFilter will be appropriate. This is the same type of filter that the Search Part in a Grid would apply. The 'BaseFilter' option applies the filter as a 'base filter' which means that the user can't remove the filter by clicking a 'Clear filter' button in the Grid. Choices include *[ui:UserFilter]*, *[ui:BaseFilter]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Combine multiple search conditions with</name>
                    <description>If the user defines a search on more than one field, combine the search criteria with either an AND or OR keyword. Choices include *[ui:AND]*, *[ui:OR]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Controls to clear</name>
                    <description>Specify the controls on the Dialog that should be cleared. (These are the controls were the user entered the search criteria).</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
   </sections>
   
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>