<page>
    <shortlink>Lock unlock a container DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it</shortlink>
    <topic>Lock/unlock a container, DIV or entire page (by showing an overlay over it)</topic>
    <description>Lock a container, DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it so that the user can't click on the controls under the overlay, or unlock the element.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid and UX components.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Lock/Unlock Element Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Lock/Unlock type</name>
                    <description>Specify if you want to lock/unlock the entire page, or just an element (Container or arbitrary DIV). Choices include *[ui:Page]*, *[ui:Element]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Mode</name>
                    <description>Specify if you want to lock an element, or unlock a previously locked element. Choices include *[ui:Lock]*, *[ui:Unlock]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Automatically unlock after duration</name>
                    <description>Specify if the element should be automatically unlocked after a specified number of milliseconds. Enter 0 to never automatically unlock the element. For example, enter 1000 to automatically unlock after 1 second.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Lock class</name>
                    <description>Specify the CSS class for the overlay that is used to lock the specified object.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Object type</name>
                    <description>Specify if the object you want to lock/unlock or is a Container control, or an arbitrary DIV. Choices include *[ui:Container]*, *[ui:DIV]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>DIV ID</name>
                    <description>Specify the ID of the DIV.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Container ID</name>
                    <description>Specify the ID of the container. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Using Action Javascript to Lock the Page or a Portion of the Page During an Ajax Callback</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in Ajax applications is to 'lock' the screen, or a portion of the screen, for the duration of the callback. This prevents the user from performing some action that is not appropriate during a callback. A transparent overlay is displayed over the screen or element to 'lock' it. </p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can use Action Javascript to lock either the entire screen, or a portion of the screen.</p>
                    <p>This technique can be used in both the Grid and UX Component.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/SkduYY5sR1gFWm7YgBVxAv</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>

        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>

    </links>

    <see>
        <ref link="action javascript for the ux">Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
        <ref link="action javascript in the grid">Action Javascript in the Grid</ref>
    </see>

</page>