<page>
    <shortlink>Menus</shortlink>
   <topic>Menus</topic>
   <description>Display a dropdown menu.</description>
   
   <sections>
        <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid and UX components.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
            <title>Menu Choices Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Method for defining menu</name>
                    <description>Specify how the menu will be defined. If the menu choices are not dynamic, then you can use the 'Menu Builder' or 'Static JSON String'. If you want the choices to be dynamic, use Xbasic function. Choices include *[ui:Menu Builder]*, *[ui:Static JSON String]*, *[ui:Xbasic Function]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Static JSON String</name>
                    <description>Specify the JSON menu definition.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Menu definition</name>
                    <description>Define the menu choices</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Xbasic function</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Xbasic function to call to generate the menu choices</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript function</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript function to call to generate the menu choices</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Menu Properties Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Menu position</name>
                    <description>Specify where the menu will be shown.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Menu name</name>
                    <description><![CDATA[(Optional) Specify a name for the menu. If you specify a name you will be able to use Javascript to get a pointer to the menu object. You can leave this blank or use <Default> to use a system generated name. If you specify a name, it must be unique to this menu.]]></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Icon column width</name>
                    <description>Specify the width of the icon column. This is the column to the left of the menu choices where optional menu icons are shown.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Has pointer icon</name>
                    <description>Specify if the window has a pointer icon that points to the element that was clicked to show the window.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Pointer position</name>
                    <description>Specify the window edge that has the pointer icon. If you select 'Auto' the most appropriate edge is automatically selected. Choices include *[ui:Auto]*, *[ui:Top]*, *[ui:Bottom]*, *[ui:Left]*, *[ui:Right]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item build="5445">
                    <name>Menu height</name>
                    <description>The height of the menu window. The height is defined using CSS units (200px, 1.5in, etc). This property is optional. If not defined, the menu height will be computed automatically.</description>
                </item>
                <item build="5445">
                    <name>Menu width</name>
                    <description>The width of the menu window. The width is defined using CSS units (200px, 1.5in, etc). This property is optional. If not defined, the menu width will be computed automatically.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        
        <section>
            <title>Menu Animation Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Animation</name>
                    <description>Specify if the window should be animated when it is shown or hidden.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Show animation style</name>
                    <description>Select the animation method to use when the window is shown. Fade and Slide use methods in jQuery core. Other options require jQueryUI.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Show animation speed</name>
                    <description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Hide animation style</name>
                    <description>Select the animation method to use when the window is closed. Fade and Slide use methods in jQuery core. Other options require jQueryUI.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Hide animation speed</name>
                    <description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
       <section>
         
           
           <title>Javascript</title>
           <example><![CDATA[{grid.componentName}_G__1(this);]]></example>
          
       </section>
     
       <section>
           <title>Create a Dropdown Action:</title>
           <steps>
               <step>
                   <description>Click the [...] button next to the Menu Definition Property</description>
                   <figure><link>images/dropdown3.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Create a list of choices for the dropdown using the Tree Data Genie.</description>
                   <figure><link>images/dropdown2.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               <step>
                   <description>Javascript Functions page click on the Action Javascript genie and add the dropdown action to the component.</description>
              <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}.runAction('dropdown');]]></example>
               </step>
               <step>
                  <description>Dropdown list in Working Preview</description>
           <figure><link>images/dropdown.png</link></figure>
               </step>
               
               
           </steps>
           
       </section>
 
   </sections>
   <links>
       
       <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
       
   </links>
   
    <see>
   <ref link="action javascript for the ux">Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
       <ref link="action javascript in the grid">Action Javascript in the Grid</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>