<page build="0">
    <shortlink>Open a Report, Label or Letter layout</shortlink>
    <topic>Open a Report, Label or Letter layout</topic>
    <description>Displays a report, label or letter layout as a PDF file using the Acrobat PDF reader. The report is displayed in either a pop-up window or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Properties</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Layout Print Definition</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report name</title>
                    <description>The name of the Report, Label, or Letter to open.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Initial view</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>How to render the report. The report can be rendered as a PDF or HTML.</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Option</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>PDF</name>
                                    <description>The report is rendered as a PDF.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>HTML</name>
                                    <description>The report is rendered as HTML. This option is *[not]* supported for Letters, Labels, or reports that were not created using the Layout Table editor.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>HTML-Paged</name>
                                    <description>The report is rendered as paged HTML. This option is only supported for Reports created using the Alpha Anywhere Report engine.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item build="6945">
                                    <name>PDFDirect</name>
                                    <description>Deprecated. Identical to *[ui:PDF]*. The report is rendered as a PDF.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item build="6945">
                                    <name>DocX</name>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>The report is generated as a Microsoft Word document.</p>
                                        <p>If this option is selected, the *[ui:target]* property must be set to either *[ui:Download]* or *[Xbasic]*.</p>
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                    <important>
                        <p>*[How to report PDF reporting issues to Alpha Software]*</p>
                        <p>If your report does not render correctly when printed as a PDF, right click on the report in the Web Project Control Panel and select the Create Bug Report menu option under the Datasources menu. Select a location to store the .zip file and be sure to check the Include Raw Pages option. Send the zip file to [bugs@alphasoftware.com].</p>
                    </important>
                    <note>
                        <p>For best performance, *[ui:HTML]* is recommended for Layout Table reports.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Filter</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An optional filter applied to the report. *[ui:Filter]* is defined using DBF syntax. The filter is in addition to any filter that was defined as part of the report layout.</p>
                        <p>This property is only shown if the report, letter, or label is based on a DBF table.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Order</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An optional order applied to the report. *[ui:Order]* is defined using DBF syntax. The order overrides the order defined in the report layout.</p>
                        <p>This property is only shown if the report, letter, or label is based on a DBF table.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">SQL Filter</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An optional filter applied to the report. *[ui:SQL Filter]* is defined using SQL syntax. It is executed on the Database Server. (This filter is in addition to any filter that was defined as part of the report layout).</p>
                        <p>If the report is being created in a Grid component, you can use the function *[xb:currentGridFilter()]* to filter the Report using the Grid filter.</p>
                        <p>If the report is being created for a List control, you can use the function *[xb:currentListFilter("LIST_NAME")]* to filter the Report using the List's filter.</p>
                        <p>This property is only shown if the report, letter, or label is based on a SQL data source.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">SQL Order</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>An optional order applied to the report. *[ui:SQL Order]* is defined using SQL syntax. The order overrides the order defined in the report layout.</p>
                        <p>You can use the function *[xb:currentGridOrder()]* to order the Report using the Grid order.</p>
                        <p>If the report is being created for a List control, you can use the function *[xb:currentListOrder("LIST_NAME")]* to order the Report using the List's order.</p>
                        <p>This property is only shown if the report, letter, or label is based on a SQL data source.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Local Filter</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In addition to the *[ui:SQL Filter]*, you can define a local filter. The local filter is executed after the data is retrieved from the SQL database but before the report is generated.</p>
                        <p>The local is defined using Xbasic syntax. For example:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[firstname="Anise" .AND. lastname="Riggins"]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>The local filter will have a performance impact on report generation. You should only use a local filter if it's not possible to define the filter as a SQL Filter.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Local Order</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The local order is applied after the data is retrieved from the SQL database. *[ui:Local Order]* is defined using Xbasic syntax. For example:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[companyname+contacttitle]]></example>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">PDF Options</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Available if the *[ui:Initial view]* is set to *[ui:PDF]*.</p>
                        <p>The following options are available for configuring a PDF:</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="4">PDF Options</title>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Multilingual support</name>
                                    <description>Adds support for international character sets.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Embed fonts</name>
                                    <description>Include required fonts in the PDF instead of allowing them to be resolved externally. </description>
                                    <note>If the font is protected, it can't be embedded; this is often the case for bar code fonts, such as Code39.</note>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Linearize</name>
                                    <description>If the PDF file will be displayed in a web application, linearization allows the browser to display pages from the PDF file before the entire PDF file has been downloaded. See also Linearize.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Black and white</name>
                                    <description>Converts all colors to black, white, and gray.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Convert hyperlinks</name>
                                    <description>Converts all hyperlinks started with "http://" into live links in the resulting PDF document.
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>JPEG Image Quality</name>
                                    <description>Set the quality of JPEG images; this is a trade-off between image fidelity and size. Low quality uses the highest compression and produces the smallest images. No Compression produces the largest, highest-quality images.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="4">Watermark Options</title>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Watermark</name>
                                    <description>If enabled, prints a watermark on every page in the report. The properties below are also exposed.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Watermark type</name>
                                    <description>Specifies how to create the watermark. The options are:</description>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>Text</name>
                                            <description>Watermark is defined as text, including the font, color, orientation, and position.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>PDF</name>
                                            <description>Watermark is defined as a PDF. Use this option to display a logo or other image as a watermark.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Text</name>
                                    <description>The text to use as a watermark. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Font name</name>
                                    <description>The font to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Font size</name>
                                    <description>The font size to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Orientation</name>
                                    <description>The rotation of the watermark text in 0.1 degree increments. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Font color</name>
                                    <description>The font color to use for the watermark text. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Horizontal position</name>
                                    <description>The horizontal position of the watermark text in 0.1 inch units. This positive value measured from the left edge of the page should take into account the minimum printer margin. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Vertical position</name>
                                    <description>The vertical position of the watermark text in 0.1 inch units. This negative value measured from the top of the page should take into account the minimum printer margin. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:Text]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Watermark file name</name>
                                    <description>The name of a PDF file to use as the watermark. Optionally, click *[ui:Click to create PDF from Bitmap]* to display the Create PDF File from Bitmap dialog. This property is only available if *[ui:Watermark Type]* is set to *[ui:PDF]*</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Foreground</name>
                                    <description>When enabled, places the watermark above the page text, partially obscuring page content. When disabled, places the watermark below the page text.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="4">Encryption Options</title>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Encrypt PDF file</name>
                                    <description>Check this property if you want to require a password to open the PDF file or set file permissions for the PDF. If enabled, the properties below are also exposed.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Owner password</name>
                                    <description>Specifies the text to use as the owner password. Only the owner can change the User password and the document other settings.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>User password</name>
                                    <description>Specifies the text to use as the read password.
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Can print</name>
                                    <description>Specifies whether the reader can print the document.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Can modify document</name>
                                    <description>Specifies whether the reader can edit the document.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Can copy</name>
                                    <description>Specifies whether the reader can select text in the document and copy it.
                                    </description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Can add notes</name>
                                    <description>Specifies whether the reader can add notes.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Use 128 bit key</name>
                                    <description>Selects between 40 bit and 128 bit encryption. Readers will need Adobe Acrobat version 5 or higher to read 128 bit encrypted files.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="4">Other Options</title>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>PDF Title</name>
                                    <description>The title of the PDF. This title is shown in some browser PDF viewers.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Local argument definitions</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Optional local arguments. These arguments can be used in the SQL Filter or SQL Order for the report.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/reportLocalArguments.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Argument bindings</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If the report includes arguments, the arguments are set in *[ui:Argument bindings]*. Arguments can be bound to a constant value (e.g. *[xb:Smith]*), a field in the component (e.g. *[xb:{customer_id}]*), a session variables (e.g. *[xb:context.session.clientID]*), or computed by calling a JavaScript function (e.g. *[xb:(Javascript:myFunctionName)]* where *[em:myFunctionName]* is the name of the JavaScript function.)</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/reportArguments.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">PDF open parameters</title>
                    <description>Specify parameter to control how the PDF is displayed when it is initially rendered. You can set properties such as the zoom level. Not all PDF readers support these properties.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">HTML Report Viewer Options</title>
            <cases>
                <case build="5227">
                    <title nested="3">Has window close button</title>
                    <description>If checked, displays a close button on the window toolbar for the HTML report. It is recommended to add a close button if the Window title bar has been turned off.</description>
                </case>
                <case build="5227">
                    <title nested="3">Close button text</title>
                    <description>The text shown in the close button. This property is only available if *[ui:Has window close button]* has been checked.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Print as PDF</title>
                    <description>Show a button on the HTML Report viewer to make a callback and render the report as a PDF document.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Export to Excel</title>
                    <description>Show a button to export the Report to Excel</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Export to Word</title>
                    <description>Show a button to export the Report to Word</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Export to Text</title>
                    <description>Show a button to export the Report to text file</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Print</title>
                    <description>Show a button to print the HTML report.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report Bookmarks button type</title>
                    <description>If the report you are viewing has bookmarks, the bookmarks are shown in a Panel. If the report container is too narrow to show the Bookmarks Panel, the Panel is automatically collapsed, and a button is shown to display the Bookmarks Panel. Specify the button style. Choices include *[ui:Text]*, *[ui:Image]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report Bookmarks button text</title>
                    <description>Specify the text for the Bookmarks button.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report Bookmarks button image</title>
                    <description>Specify the text for the Bookmarks button.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report Bookmarks panel width</title>
                    <description>Specify the width for the Bookmarks Panel. Use CSS syntax (not %). If there is insufficient space to show the Panel, it will be automatically collapsed and can then be shown by clicking on the Bookmarks button.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Maximum records to display</title>
                    <description>Specify the maximum number of records to display in the HTML report. Enter 0 to see all records. Limiting the number of records will allow the report to display faster.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">'More records' message</title>
                    <description>Specify the message to show if there are more records in the report than the number in the display limit. The message will not show if the total records in the report is less that the number set in the display limit. [DisplayRecords] is a placeholder for the number of records to display. [TotalRecords] is a placeholder for the total number of records in the report.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">'More records' message container style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the container that holds the 'More records' message.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Target Window, DIV, Tabbed UI Pane or Panel</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Target</title>
                    <description>Defines what happens to the report after it is generated. Options include:
                        <p></p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Target Option</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Window</name>
                                    <description>Report will be opened in a modeless or modal popup window after it is generated. Not supported for *[ui:DocX]*.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>DIV</name>
                                    <description>Report will be opened in a DIV on the page. Not supported for *[ui:DocX]*.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>TabbedUIPane</name>
                                    <description>Report will be opened in a new pane in a Tabbed UI. If the component is not running inside a Tabbed UI, the report will be opened in a modeless popup window. Not supported for *[ui:DocX]*.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Download</name>
                                    <description>Report will be downloaded to the client.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Xbasic</name>
                                    <description>Report will be sent to an Xbasic function, defined in the *[ui:Xbasic function]* property.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Panel</name>
                                    <description>Report will be opened in an existing Panel Card. Not supported for *[ui:DocX]*.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>DynamicPanel</name>
                                    <description>Report will be opened in a new dynamic Panel Card inside a Panel Navigator. Not supported for *[ui:DocX]*.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Target Panel</title>
                    <description>The id of an existing Panel Card where the report will be shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Target DIV ID</title>
                    <description>Specify the ID of the target DIV. This DIV can be in the Grid component (for example, in a free-form edit region), or on the .a5w page that contains the Grid component.</description>
                    <tip>
                        <p>If you want to specify a DIV that is inside a freeform edit region in a Grid cell, use the *[js:{grid.rowID}]* placeholder in the DIV id. For example:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example><![CDATA[div1_Row{grid.rowID}]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>This will ensure that each row has a uniquely named DIV in which the target page can be displayed.</p>
                    </tip>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Parent Panel Navigator</title>
                    <description>Specify the Id of the parent Panel Navigator. The dynamic Panel will be added to this Panel Navigator.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Dynamic Panel Title</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The title for the dynamic panel added to a Panel Navigator where the report will be displayed. The panel title can be dynamically generated at runtime using JavaScript. To call a JavaScript function to generate the panel title, set the *[ui:Dynamic Panel Title]* property to the following:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example><![CDATA[javascript:myFunction]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>Where *[em:myFunction]* is the name of your JavaScript function. The JavaScript function must return a string.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">User can close dynamic panel</title>
                    <description>(Only applies if the target Panel Navigator has been configured to use a Tab Band) Specify if the label for the dynamically added Panel has a 'close' icon that allows the user to close the dynamically added Panel.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Working message placement</title>
                    <description>Specify the panel where the wait message should be shown. You should chose a Panel that is currently visible, not a Panel that will be animated into view when the component is rendered.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Working message uses CSS3 animation?</title>
                    <description>Specify if the working message should be displayed using a CSS3 animation?</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Working message animation size</title>
                    <description>Specify the size of the animation in pixels.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Can hide target DIV?</title>
                    <description>Specify the DIV can be hidden (to remove from view the target page after it has been opened in the DIV).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">DIV hide hyperlink</title>
                    <description>Specify text for the hyperlink that hides the DIV where the target page is shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Target IFrame style</title>
                    <description>The target page will be opened in an IFrame inside the target DIV. Specify the inline style for the IFrame. You can set the IFrame's height and width in the style.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report height</title>
                    <description>Specify the height of the report. The report container DIV will be resized to this height. Use CSS units.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Report width</title>
                    <description>Specify the width of the report. The report container DIV will be resized to this height. Use CSS units.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window name</title>
                    <description>Set to &lt;Default&gt; to give the window a default name. If you give the window an explicit name (which must be unique), then you can easily get a pointer to the window to execute methods of the window object. Click the smart field for tips on how to name your window and for information on how to get a pointer to the window object.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window type</title>
                    <description>Specify the window type. Popup windows will show in a moveable window on the page. Dropdown windows have no title bar and cannot be moved. By default, Dropdown windows open directly below the control that you click to open the window.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>An Ajax window will NOT be blocked by a browser's internal protection against popup windows.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Lock overlay CSS class name</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify the CSS class name to use for the overlay that is displayed behind the window. The overlay prevents the user from clicking on controls that are outside the window. Leave blank, or specify &lt;Default&gt; to use the default style. Specify &lt;Invisible&gt; to create an invisible overlay (has no color, but user is still prevented from clicking on controls off the window). By specifying a class that has a 'background' attribute, you can control the color of the overlay. For example:</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="css"><![CDATA[background: rgba(0,0,0,0)]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>to create a transparent overlay.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Sub-theme</title>
                    <description>An optional sub-theme for the window. The sub-theme can select a different pre-defined window 'look'. If you leave this property blank, the 'base' sub-theme is used.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Dock window</title>
                    <description>Docked windows 'stick' to an edge of the screen and remain in place even when the page is scrolled.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Dock location</title>
                    <description>Specify which edge of the screen the window is docked to. Choices include *[ui:Left]*, *[ui:Right]*, *[ui:Top]*, *[ui:Bottom]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window position</title>
                    <description>Specify where the window will be shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Re-use existing window</title>
                    <description>Specify if multiple modeless windows can be opened, or only a single modeless window.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window title</title>
                    <description>Specify the window title. The window title can contain data from fields in the current record. Enclose field values in curly braces. E.g. Customer - {lastname}. To reference values from a column in a List control use this syntax: {LIST::ListName::ColumnName} (e.g. {LIST::MYLIST1::LASTNAME} )</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window title show</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window title should be shown or hidden.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window title position</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window title should appear at the top or bottom of the window. Choices include *[ui:Top]*, *[ui:Bottom]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window title direction</title>
                    <description>Specify if the direction is 'ltr' (left-to-right) (title on left, close button on right) or 'rtl' (right-to-left) (close button on left and title on right). Choices include *[ui:ltr]*, *[ui:rtl]*.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window title has close button</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window title has a Close button.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Disable window move</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window cannot be moved by the user.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Pane title</title>
                    <description>Specify the tab pane title. The pane title can contain data from fields in the current record. Enclose field values in curly braces. E.g. Customer - {lastname}. To reference values from a column in a List control use this syntax: {LIST::ListName::ColumnName} (e.g. {LIST::MYLIST1::LASTNAME} )</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window height</title>
                    <description>Specify the window height. Use CSS syntax. For example: 3in, 10cm, 200px. If you do not set the height, the window will resize automatically to accommodate the window contents.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window width</title>
                    <description>Specify the window height. Use CSS syntax. For example: 3in, 10cm, 200px. If you do not set the width, the window will resize automatically to accommodate the window contents.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Window is resizable</title>
                    <description>If checked, the user can resize the window.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Working message</title>
                    <description>Specify the text of the message to show in the window while the window waits for its contents to be generated. You can use this placeholder in the message: {reportName}</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Working message icon</title>
                    <description>Specify the image to show in the window while the window waits for its contents to be generated.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Client-side file name</title>
                    <description>Specify the default filename on the user's computer (when they download the file). If you leave this blank, the filename of the server will be used as the default client-side filename.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Xbasic function</title>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Xbasic function to call after the report has been created.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">DIV Id for progress messages</title>
                    <description>Specify the ID of a DIV where the 'working...' message, and any error messages, should be shown. This DIV can be in the Grid component (for example, in a free-form edit region), or on the .a5w page that contains the Grid component. TIP: If you want to specify a DIV that is inside a freeform edit region in a Grid cell, use the '{grid.rowID}' placeholder in the DIV id. For example: 'div1_Row{grid.rowID}'. This will ensure that each row has a uniquely named DIV in which the messages can be displayed.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Has pointer icon</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window has a pointer icon that points to the element that was clicked to show the window.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Pointer position</title>
                    <description>Specify the window edge that has the pointer icon. If you select 'Auto' the most appropriate edge is automatically selected. Choices include *[ui:Auto]*, *[ui:Top]*, *[ui:Bottom]*, *[ui:Left]*, *[ui:Right]*.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Window Buttons</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Has custom toolbar buttons</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window has custom buttons in the window toolbar (at the bottom of the window).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Define buttons</title>
                    <description>Define the buttons that appear in the window toolbar (at the bottom of the window).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Buttons in-line style</title>
                    <description>In-line style for the buttons. TIP: To display the buttons left justified, enter an in-line style of: text-align:left;</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Optional Window Parts</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show top bar</title>
                    <description>Specify if a top bar should be shown. (Displayed above the window body inside the body container).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Top bar HTML</title>
                    <description>Specify the HTML to show in the top bar.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Top bar style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the top bar.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show bottom bar</title>
                    <description>Specify if a top bar should be shown. (Displayed below the body inside the body container).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Bottom bar HTML</title>
                    <description>Specify the HTML to show in the top bar.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Bottom bar style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the top bar.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show header</title>
                    <description>Specify if a header should be shown. (Displayed above the window body inside the body container).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Header HTML</title>
                    <description>Specify the HTML to show in the header.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Header style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the top bar.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show footer</title>
                    <description>Specify if a footer should be shown. (Displayed below the body, the bottom bar, and below any user-defined buttons).</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Footer HTML</title>
                    <description>Specify the HTML to show in the footer.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Footer style</title>
                    <description>Specify the in-line style for the footer.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Client-side Events</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Before execute event</title>
                    <description>Specify the name of a Javascript function to call before the callback is made to open the target Report. This Javascript function will take 'ro' as an input parameter. 'ro' contains all of the settings for the target Report to be opened. The purpose of this function is to allow you to override any of the  properties of the passed-in 'ro' object.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">After execute Javascript</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to run after the Report has been printed.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Window Animation</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Animation</title>
                    <description>Specify if the window should be animated when it is shown or hidden.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>If the window contains an iframe that contains a PDF viewer, animation should not be used.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show animation style</title>
                    <description>Select the animation method to use when the window is shown. Fade and Slide use methods in jQuery core. Other options require jQueryUI.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Show animation speed</title>
                    <description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Hide animation style</title>
                    <description>Select the animation method to use when the window is closed. Fade and Slide use methods in jQuery core. Other options require jQueryUI.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Hide animation speed</title>
                    <description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Window Javascript Events</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onInitialize</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute the first time the window is shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onBeforeShow</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute before the window is shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onShow</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute when the window is shown.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onBeforeHide</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute before the window is hidden.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onHide</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute when the window is hidden.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onFocus</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute when the window gets focus.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onMove</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute when the window is moved.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">onResize</title>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript code to execute when the window is resized.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Ajax Failed/Offline Javascript</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="3">Offline Javascript</title>
                    <description>JavaScript to execute if the device is offline. Since the device is offline, the Ajax callback is not made. Therefore the code in the 'Ajax failed Javascript' property will not get executed.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Action Javascript - Binding an Argument Value to Result of a Javascript Function</title>
                <description>
                    <p>This video is aimed at advanced developers.</p>
                    <p>When you use Action Javascript to open a Grid, Report, Dialog, Custom Component, etc., you often need to bind the value of an argument to a value from the parent Component. For example, you might bind the value of "arg1" to the value of the Lastname field in the current grid row.</p>
                    <p>Instead of binding an argument to the value of a field in the Grid, you can specify an arbitrary JavaScript function to execute. The argument is bound to the value returned by the JavaScript function.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/16ce015c</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Printing the Currently Selected Records or Opening a Grid Showing Currently Selected Records</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Putting a button on a Grid to open another Grid or a Report is easily accomplished using Action Javascript. This video shows how you can use the special Alpha Anywhere functions CurrentGridFilter() and CurrentGridOrder() to print the records that are currently selected in the Grid. You can also use these functions to open another Grid showing the same selection of records in the current Grid.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/92ad0803</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>HTML Reporting Action Scripting</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you add a Report to a Tabbed UI, or you display a report when a button is clicked, you now have the option of setting the "initial view" of the report to HTML. A benefit of HTML reporting is the ability to export the report to Excel or Word. You can also generate a PDF report from an HTML report if you still want a PDF version of the report.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how HTML reporting can be used in a Tabbed UI, and when a button in a Grid is clicked to show a report.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/e3b775fe</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
            <note>
                <p>This video also applies to the Grid and UX Component</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using the IN Clause in the Report Filter - Understanding 'Array Arguments'</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you use Action Javascript to display a report, you specify the report filter. In the case of reports that are based on SQL data sources, you can now use the SQL IN clause in your filter expression. When you use the IN clause, the argument you pass the SQL statement must be defined as an "array argument".</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to configure the Action Javascript to display a report filtered using an IN clause and how to create an array argument.</p>
                    <p>This video applies to the Grid and UX Component.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/292ff107</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/reportsInClause.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
            <note>
                <p>The sample component requires a connection string called "Northwind" to sample Northwind database.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>HTML Reporting in Tabbed UI</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you add a Report to a Tabbed UI, or you display a report when a button is clicked, you now have the option of setting the "initial view" of the report to HTML. A significant benefit of HTML reporting is the ability to export the report to Excel or Word. You can also generate a PDF report from an HTML report if you still want a PDF version of the report.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how HTML reporting can be used in a Tabbed UI, and when a button in a Grid is clicked to show a report.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/7edb0ae8</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/e3b775fe</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
            <note>
                <p>This video also applies to the Grid and UX Component</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using HTML Reporting in a Mobile Application</title>
                <description>
                    <p>HTML Reporting is ideal for Mobile Applications because the HTML report can easily be displayed in one of the "Panels" in a UX component.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how a UX component with a Panel Navigator is built. The Panel Navigator has two Panel Cards. The first Panel Card has buttons to print various reports. The second Panel Card is used to display the HTML report.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/2efc35d4</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>HTML Reporting - Reports with Bookmarks</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you design reports, you can turn on the 'bookmarks' and 'table of contents' features. The 'bookmark' feature creates a tree control of all of the 'bookmarks' in the report and allows you to navigate to any section of the report by clicking on a appropriate item in the 'bookmark tree', which is displayed to the left of the report itself. The 'table of contents' section, on the other hand, is shown before the first page of the report. You can also navigate to any particular section of the report by clicking on an entry in the table of contents.</p>
                    <p>In HTML reports, the 'bookmarks' tree is automatically rendered in a Panel as is shown in this video. In a mobile application, the Panel Card that contains the bookmark tree is automatically hidden if there is not enough space on the device. In the case where it is hidden, a button is automatically added to the Panel Header to reveal the bookmarks.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/e7888a65</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
            <note>
                <p>This video applies to the Grid and UX Component.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <!--
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Emailing a Report</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common pattern in both the UX and Grid component is to place a button on the component to print a Report and display the Report in a window, div or TabbedUI pane. However, instead of displaying the Report, you might want to send it as an email.</p>
                    <p>The Action Javascript action to Print a Report has an option to call an Xbasic function when the Report has printed.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can use this option to email the report using the Mandrill email service.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/44ce8661</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        -->
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Printing a Report Using Same Filter/Order as a List Control</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common pattern in Grids is to have a button on a Grid that prints a report showing the same records that are in the current Grid query. You can use a similar pattern for List controls on a UX component.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show a UX with a List control. The List control is based on a SQL query and the UX has a button that allows you to perform a server-side filter on the List (for example, search for all records in France or Denmark).</p>
                    <p>The UX has a button that prints a report that is based on the same SQL tables as the List and automatically uses the same filter for the report as the List.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/b9086826</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>HTML-Paged Output Option</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you render reports in a Web application you can choose whether the report should be rendered as PDF or HTML. The HTML option is only available for Layout Table reports - not Freeform reports.</p>
                    <p>The HTML-Paged option will work with all report types -- Freeform and Layout Table and can be rendered in any browser (including mobile device browsers that do not have the ability to render PDF files.</p>
                    <p>This video compares the different report output options.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/81252e53</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Using SQL Server Reporting Services Reports in an Alpha Anywhere Project</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Many organizations who use SQL Server also use SQL Server Reporting Services (SSRS). Using reports created in SSRS in an Alpha Anywhere project is possible.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how reports defined in SSRS can be used in Alpha Anywhere applications.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/415ce582</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="mailto:bugs@alphasoftware.com">bugs@alphasoftware.com</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="reporting pdfreports pdfdirect">Generating Reports with "Direct to PDF"</ref>
    </see>
</page>