<page>
    <shortlink>Panel Actions</shortlink>
   <topic>Panel Actions</topic>
   <description>Perform some action on a Panel (e.g. setting focus to the next or previous Panel, 
       or to a particular named panel). </description>
   
   <sections>
      <section>
         
          <figure><link>images/navigateaction.jpg</link></figure>
          
         
       </section>
       
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component. The options with the 'History' prefix allow you to navigate through
        the Panel Navigator's history (much list the way a browser's history button works).</description>
       </section>
       
  <section>
            <title>Panel Action Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Action name</name>
                    <description>Specify the Panel Action that you want to execute. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Action Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Navigator name</name>
                    <description>Specify the Panel Navigator in which the target Panel exists.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Direction</name>
                    <description>Specify the direction in which you want to navigate. Option with the 'History' prefix navigate within the context of the Navigator's history of prior navigations. Choices include *[ui:First]*, *[ui:Previous]*, *[ui:Next]*, *[ui:Last]*, *[ui:HistoryFirst]*, *[ui:HistoryLast]*, *[ui:HistoryBack]*, *[ui:HistoryForward]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Target Panel name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name (Id) of the Panel that you want to set focus to.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel to scroll</name>
                    <description>Specify the name (Id) of the Panel that you want to scroll.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Animate</name>
                    <description>Specify if the Panel should be animated as it comes into view.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the panel for which you want to get the Id of. You can specify which part of the Panel you want the Id for (e.g. Body, Header, Footer).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Part</name>
                    <description>Specify the Panel part that you want the Id of. You can use this id to set the InnerHTML property of the Panel part (does not apply if part is 'Panel'). Choices include *[ui:Header]*, *[ui:Body]*, *[ui:Footer]*, *[ui:Panel]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Name (IFrame)</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the IFrame Panel Card that you want to set the URL for.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript variable name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript variable to set.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Layout Name</name>
                    <description>Panel Layout Name property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>IFrame URL</name>
                    <description>IFrame URL property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Container id</name>
                    <description>(Optional) Specify the Panel Navigator or Panel Layout for which you want to get the active Panel. If you leave this blank, the top level Panel is returned.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Layout Name</name>
                    <description>(Optional) Specify the Panel Layout for which you want to get the active Docked Panel.</description>
                </item>
                  <item>
                    <name>Action</name>
                    <description>Specify the action. NOTE: If you have not added a header or footer to the Panel in the UX design, the 'show' action is meaningless. Choices include *[ui:Show]*, *[ui:Hide]*.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Panel Size Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the panel for which you want to get the size. You can specify which part of the Panel you want the size for (e.g. Body, Header, Footer).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Panel Part</name>
                    <description>Specify the Panel part that you want the Id of. You can use this id to set the InnerHTML property of the Panel part. Choices include *[ui:Header]*, *[ui:Body]*, *[ui:Footer]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript variable for height</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript variable to set with the height value.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript variable for width</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Javascript variable to set with the width value.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Scroll Position Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Scroll - x position</name>
                    <description>Specify the scroll position in pixels.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Scroll - y position</name>
                    <description>Specify the scroll position in pixels.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
       
   </sections>
   
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>