<page>
   <topic>Video Player Control Actions</topic>
   <description>Perform some type of action on a video player control.</description>
   
   <sections>
     
           <section>
            <description>Used with the UX component.</description>
       </section>
       
   <section>
            <title>Panel Action Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Action name</name>
                    <description>Specify the Video Player Control action you want to execute. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Video player control id</name>
                    <description>Specify the video player control Id.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Type</name>
                    <description>Type property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Method for specifying the video id to play</name>
                    <description>How should the video to play should be specified.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Video id</name>
                    <description>Video id property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>JavaScript function</name>
                    <description>JavaScript function property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Control id</name>
                    <description>Control id property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List id</name>
                    <description>List id property. Choices include.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List control column</name>
                    <description>List control column property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List control columns</name>
                    <description>List control columns property.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>MP4 Video URL</name>
                    <description>Set the url to the MP4 video source. The MP4 format is suported by current versions of IE, Chrome and Safari.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>WebM Video URL</name>
                    <description>Set the url to the WebM video source. The WebM format is suported by current versions of Chrome, Firefox and Opera.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>OGG Video URL</name>
                    <description>Set the url to the Ogg video source. The Ogg format is suported by current versions of Chrome, Firefox and Opera.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Poster Image</name>
                    <description>Set the url to the video poster image. This will display in the player prior to the video loading.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Automatically Size The Video Player</name>
                    <description>When enabled, the video player will be automatically sized to fit to the max width and height of the panel card. A 16:9 aspect ratio will be maintained.	On device orientation change, the player will be resized.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Use CSS For Responsive Video Player Sizing</name>
                    <description>When enabled, the video player will be automatically sized to the max width of the device using CSS which is fluid, responsive and fast. The onOrientationChange event is not used. A 16:9 aspect ratio is maintained. The height may overcome the available panel card height however the panel card may include scrolling.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
       
   </sections>
   
   
    <see>
       <ref>Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
   </see>
   
</page>