<page>
    <shortlink>Web-sockets Server Actions</shortlink>
   <topic>Web-sockets Server Actions</topic>
   <description>Performs an action on the web-socket server, such as 'Send a message to the web-sockets server'. 
       The message will be received by all UX and Grid components that are listening for web-socket messages and the 
       'webSocketOnMessage client-side event in all listening components will fire.</description>
   
   <sections>
          <section>
            <description>Used with the Grid and UX components</description>
       </section>
  <section>
            <title>Web-sockets Server Action Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Action name</name>
                    <description>Specify the web-socket server action to execute.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Send Message Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Method for creating message text</name>
                    <description>You can enter the text for the message now, or you can execute Javascript code at run-time that returns the message text. Choices include *[ui:Text]*, *[ui:Javascript]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Message</name>
                    <description>Specify the message. You can either enter a string of text or you can specify a Javascript function by entering: javascript:name_of_your_function</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Message type</name>
                    <description>Specify the message type. There are certain 'built-in' message types that Alpha Anywhere supports (such as 'messageboard'). If you just want to send a simple text message (not one of the built-in types) select the 'Simple' option.  To define your own built-in message types, you need to add a new .js file to the 'node_services\ws_queue' folder in the Alpha Anywhere executable folder. If you want to call a Javascript function to specify the message type enter: javascript:yourfunctionname</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript for message</name>
                    <description>Specify the Javascript to run to get the message text. Your Javascript must include the 'return' command to return the text to use in the message. For example: return messageText;</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Start Web-socket Server Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Start listening once server is started</name>
                    <description>Should the client start listening for messages once the web-socket server has been started?</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Message subscriptions</name>
                    <description>Specify if you want to subscribe to all messages, or to a subset of the messages broadcast by the web-socket server. If you leave this blank then you will be subscribed to the list of message types defined in the component. Enter a comma delimited list of message types, or to specify the types using Javascript, enter javascript:yourfunctionname.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Server-side Send Message Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Xbasic function to generate message</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Xbasic function to call to generate the message. This message will then be broadcast to all of the connected clients.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Message Subscriptions Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Message subscriptions</name>
                    <description>Specify if you want to subscribe to all messages, or to a subset of the messages broadcast by the web-socket server. If you leave this blank then you will be subscribed to the list of message types defined in the component. Enter a comma delimited list of message types, or to specify the types using Javascript, enter javascript:yourfunctionname.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
   </sections>
   <links>
       
       <link href="images/open.png">...</link>
       
   </links>
    <see>
   <ref link="action javascript for the ux">Action Javascript for the UX</ref>
       <ref link="action javascript in the grid">Action Javascript in the Grid</ref>
   </see>
   
   
</page>