<page>
    <topic>Static JSON</topic>
    <description>If you set the Data Source type property to be Static JSON then you will be prompted to define this data using the Static JSON property.
    </description>
<sections>
    <section>
        <title>Creating and Viewing Static JSON</title>
       <description>This is a simple example for displaying JSON data defined inside a form view.</description>
<steps>
    <step>
        <description>In the UX Controls page open the Other Controls menu and click the [Form View] 
            option to add a Form View control to the component.
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/static.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>In the control properties list click the [...] button next to the Form properties property to open the Form Builder.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static2.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Open the Data Source tab and set the Datasource type property to 'Static JSON', then click the [...] button 
            next to the Static JSON property to define the data.
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/static3.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>In the Static JSON Data dialog click the 'Sample Data' button and select 'Names'. Click OK.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static4.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Go to the Form Layout pane and click the Add item button.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static5.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Select Data Controls in the Category menu, select [Label] in the Control menu, then highlight all of the Fields from the JSON data using Shift + click. Then click OK. </description>
        <figure><link>images/static6.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Close the Form View Builder. On the Controls page go to the Other Controls menu and click on [Button] to 
            add a button control to the component.
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/static7.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Highlight the button control. Scroll down its control properties list to the Javascript section, then click the 
            [...] button next to the onClick property.
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/static8.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Click Add New Action.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static9.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Type "Form" into the "Filter list:", Highlight Form View Control Actions, and click OK.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static10.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>The FormView Control Actions dialog will open. Click the [...] button next to the Action name property and select Refresh from the list.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static11.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>For the Form View Control Id property click the dropdown and select the form view control you defined. Click OK and then 'Save' in the Edit onClick Event dialog.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static12.png</link></figure>
    </step>
       <step>
        <description>Go to the Live Preview pane and click on the button. The JSON data in the Form View will be displayed.</description>
        <figure><link>images/static13.png</link></figure>
        
    </step>
</steps>
       
       
        
    </section>
    
    
</sections> 

</page>