<page>
	<shortlink>api alphacloud applicationdeploymentschedule class method</shortlink>
	<topic>AlphaCloud::ApplicationDeploymentSchedule Class</topic>
	<description>A Deployment Schedule describes an occurrence of a deployment with a start and (optionally) stop time.</description>
	<properties>
		<property generated="true">
			<name>LocalStartTime</name>
			<type>T</type>
			<description>
				<p>The local time the schedule line should be effective.</p>
				<p>The deployment will be updated to the values set after this date and time.</p>
				</description>
		</property>
		<property generated="true">
			<name>LocalEndTime</name>
			<type>T</type>
			<description><p>The ending time of the schedule.  Leave empty for perpetual.</p>
			<p>Note: If you omit the end time, the next schedule added after this one will automatically terminate this schedule line at the start time of the new one.</p>
			</description>
		</property>
		<property generated="true">
			<name>ApplicationVersion</name>
			<type>N</type>
			<description>The version number of the application to deploy.</description>
		</property>
		<property generated="true">
			<name>SecurityPublishOption</name>
			<type>C</type>
			<description><p>The security publish option should be one of the following:
				Preserve, Ignore, Merge, Merge Roles, Replace, Replace Roles</p>			
				</description>
		</property>
		<property generated="true">
			<name>ApplicationLoggingOption</name>
			<type>C</type>
			<description>Must be one of the following: None, Basic, Complete, Diagnostic, Debugging</description>
		</property>
	</properties>
	<!--list:.-->
	<discussion>
	<p>A deployment associates an application with a web site (and optionally a path) and a security configuration.  
		While the web site, path, and security application do not generally change over time, it is more common
		to change the version of the application and/or the build of Alpha Anywhere being deployed.</p>
		
		<p>Each occurence of a deployment schedule has a start and (optionally) an end time.</p>
		
		<p>Each schedule represents a redeployment of the application.</p>
		
		<p>Each schedule is assigned a specific version of the application, 
			a specific build of Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS.</p>
	</discussion>	
		
	<see>
		<ref link="api alphacloud namespace">AlphaCloud</ref>
	</see>
</page>