<page>
    <shortlink>ux list builder list properties no records html</shortlink>
    <topic>No records HTML</topic>
    <description>You can alter the HTML in the no records message using the 'No records HTML' property.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The 'No records HTML' property</title>
                <link>images/noprop.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Clicking the [...] button next to the No records HTML property opens the HTML editor. Here you can alter the font type, size, color, and text of the message.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Customized message</title>
                <link>images/norecord.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You can also use the HTML Editor load an image as the message.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Adding an image to the Project</title>
                <link>images/norecord4.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Using an image for the 'no records'' message</title>
                <link>images/norecords3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Here is the html example used in the video, "Displaying a Custom Message in the List if the List has No Records" (see [Videos] section below.) The example below is run against some static CR-LF delimited field names without any records included as data.</description>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[<span style="color: red;"><b>There are no records in the list</b></style>]]>
            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>And here is the result:</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/norecords2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section build="4693">
            <title>Specifying the 'No Records' Message Using JavaScript</title>
            <description>
                <p>JavaScript can be used to dynamically generate the message shown. To specify that the message to display is calculated using JavaScript, the message must be prefixed with *[ui:javascript:]* directive.</p>
                <p>For example, assume a local function called *[js:norecordsmessage]* was defined in the List Builder's [Javascript tab].</p>
                <p>You would set the *[ui:No Records HTML]* to:</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>The [Javascript tab] can be turn on in the List Builder to define functions at *[ui:This object level]*. Functions defined on the List's Javascript tab will be stored with the List.</p>
            </note>
            <example><![CDATA[javascript:this.norecordsmessage()]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can also include a5-item attributes in the message text. For example, assume you wanted to display a message if the user tapped on the no records message. Assume also that the message was to be returned by a local function called norecordsmessage(). Here is how this could be done:</p>
                <p>First, define an item in the List Builder's Items tab (by turning on the optional [Template Items tab] (check the box at the bottom of the List Builder window.) For example, you could define an item called 'norecords' that displayed a message when clicked.</p>
                <p>Then define the norecordsmessage function as follows:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var norecordsinlist = function () {
    return '<span a5-item="norecords">List has no records</span>';
};]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Displaying a Custom Message in the List if the List has No Records</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A common requirement in a List is to show a custom message if the List has no records.</p>
                    <p> The List control has built-in properties to make this easy. You can also automatically center the message horizontally and vertically in the List.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/oQTgFLtoTZG3MikaU6iRkm</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_Videos">Videos</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="uxlist javascriptpane">Javascript tab</link>
        <link link="uxlist templateitemspane">Template Items tab</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux list builder list properties no records message">Has 'no records in list' message</ref>
        <ref link="ux data controls list control">List Control</ref>
        <ref link="list control ux api">List Control JavaScript Methods</ref>
    </see>
</page>