<page build="4331">
    <shortlink>ux list properties persist where</shortlink>
    <topic>Persist list data where</topic>
    <description>Defines where data should be persisted in an application. Data can be persisted to Local Storage or a device's file system (Cordova applications only.)</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Specify if data should be persisted to the file system (rather than Local Storage) if running a Cordova application. When data is stored to 'LocalStorage', a maximum of 5MB of data can be stored. Cordova applications can take advantage of the device's file system using the 'FileSystem' option, allowing more than 5MB of data to be stored when the application is offline.</p>
        <p>If 'FileSystem' is chosen and the application is not running in Cordova, the data will be persisted to Local Storage.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>The *[ui:Persist where]* property can be set to one of the following options:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>LocalStorage</name>
                    <description>Persist data to Local Storage. Local Storage can store up to 5MB of data total for an application.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>FileSystem</name>
                    <description>Persist data to the File System. This option is only available for Cordova applications and Alpha Launch applications. If you are building a mobile Cordova or Alpha Launch application, persisting data to the File System is recommended.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>IndexedDB</name>
                    <description>Persist data to [IndexedDB]. IndexedDB offers significantly more storage space than Local Storage, up to 1GB or more depending on the browser. This option is recommended for web apps, mobile web apps, and progressive web apps.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux data controls list control">List Control</ref>
        <ref link="list control ux api">List Control JavaScript Methods</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20list%20builder%20list%20properties%20persist%20to%20local%20storage#section1_Using%20IndexedDB%20to%20Persist%20List%20data">IndexedDB</link>
    </links>
</page>