<page>
 <topic>Has 'no records in list' message</topic>
<description>A common requirement in a List is to show a custom message if the List has no records.
  The List control has built-in properties to make this task easy. 
  You can automatically center the message horizontally and vertically in the List.
</description> 
<sections>
  <section>
  <description>To see how this is done watch [this video] or follow the example below.</description>

  
 </section> 
 <section>
   <title>Delete all Records in a List and Display a Message</title>
   <description>In order to show a 'no records in list' message, this example will first create a list control with a button to delete all records.</description>
   <steps>
     <step>
       <description>In the UX Controls page go to the Data Controls menu and click [List] to add a list control.</description>
       <figure><link>images/hlight3.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Scroll down the control Properties list to the List Properties section. Click the [...] button next to the 'List properties' property 
         to open the List Builder.
       </description>
       <figure><link>images/hlight4.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>In the Data Source pane click the 'Static' option in the Data Source Type menu. Then click the [...] button next to the 
         Static data property.
       </description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess2.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Click the Sample data button at the bottom of the Static Choices dialog.</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess3.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Click the CR-LF format "Name and addresses" option and click OK and OK again.</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess4.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>In the List Builder, open the List Properties pane. Check the "Has 'no records in list' message property.</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess5.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Open the List Layout pane. Use the blue > arrow to move the four static fields (Firstname, Lastname, City, and State) 
         from the Available Fields list into the 'Columns in List' area. Click OK to close the List Builder.</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess6.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>On the UX Controls page click on [Button] in the Other Controls menu to add a button control to the component. Give it the name "Delete all Records".</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess7.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Highlight the button control and scroll down the control properties to the OnClick property in the Javascript section.</description>
       <figure><link>images/recmess8.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Select Text mode and add the following code to the OnClick event:</description>
       <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('list1');
 lObj.populate([]);]]></example>
       <figure><link>images/recmess9.png</link></figure>
     </step>
      <step>
       <description>Click Save and run the component in Live Preview. When you click the 'Delete all Records' button you should get a 'No records in List' Message.</description>
      
       <cases>
         <case>
            <figure><link>images/recmess10.png</link></figure>
         </case>
            <case>
            <figure><link>images/recmess11.png</link></figure>
         </case>
         
         
       </cases>
     </step>
     
     
     
   </steps>
   
   
   
   
 </section>
 
 
 
</sections> 
 
 <links>
   <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_list_norecordsinlistmessage.swf">this video</link>
   
 </links>
</page>