<page>
    <shortlink>form layout data bound field properties properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Data Bound Field Properties Properties</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring data bound fields placed in the FormView's layout. A data bound field is a field from the FormView's data source.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Allow editing</title>
            <description>
                <p>Determines whether or not a field is editable. If the *[ui:Allow editing]* property is checked, the field's value can be edited by tapping or clicking the field to open an Editor for the field. The associated Editor is defied on the 'Fields' tab.</p>
                <p>If no Editor is defined for the field, the field cannot be edited as no interface has been defined to use to edit the field.</p>
            </description>
            <note>If this box is not checked, the 'a5-item' attribute will not be included in the HTML that is generated for this control. If a control does not include the 'a5-item' attribute, the control will not be included in the list of control that are navigated through using .formViewNavigate() method.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Bound data field name</title>
            <description>
                <p>The field from the data source that is bound to the control.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Control Type</title>
            <description>
                <p>The control type used to display the data for the field. The following control types are available for data bound fields:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Label</name>
                    <description>Displays the field using a label control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Image-DataBound</name>
                    <description>Displays an image. The image name is specified by the value in the field.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Switch</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>Displays the field value using a switch control which can be used to edit the field's value. The switch control can be customized to display a custom 'on' and 'off' icon rather than the standard 'switch'. You can also define a multi-state switch that allows you to toggle between multiple values.</p>
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Ink-DataBound</name>
                    <description>Displays the value of the field rendered as Ink.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>CustomItem</name>
                    <description>Displays the field using a user-defined custom item control type.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Field name full path</title>
            <description>
                <p>The full path for the field name. If the data source contains hierarchical data (with nested arrays of data), the field name includes the parent field's name. For example, *[ui:Children[].Name]*. This property is readonly.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Friendly name</title>
            <description>
                <p>If defined, the friendly name is used as the default label for the field.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Show/hide expression</title>
            <description>
                <p>An expression that determines whether or not the data bound control is visible in the FormView's layout.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Template</title>
            <description>
                <p>A template to create unique styling for a given field in form view control.</p>
                <p>For a visual example watch [this video]. To define a template to cover all of the fields on a form view see the '[Default template]' property on the Form Properties tab.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="https://www.viddler.com/v/5278ed0a">this video</link>
        <link link="Form View Builder Properties/Other Form Properties/Default template Property">Default template</link>
    </links>
</page>
