<page>
    <shortlink>UX Properties Style name</shortlink>
    <topic>Style name</topic>
    <description>Click the button to select a new style, or edit the existing style. You can also use <![CDATA[<ProjectStyle> or <Session:varname>]]></description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure><link>images/styleName1.png</link></figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The 'Style name' property in the UX Builder is the same as the [Grid Component's 'Style name' property]. Existing styles are mostly defined using CSS. The 'Alpha' style is built using Sass, a scripting language that outputs code which looks like CSS and that is parsed as such. The name of each tab indicates where the CSS styles for the component is stored.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/styleName2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:Local]* styles are stored in the same folder as a web project and can only be seen by components in that project. In contrast, *[ui:Global]* styles are stored in a folder that contains all of the web projects in the current open Alpha Anywhere Workspace (.abd file). Components in any web project inside the current workspace can see global styles.</p>
                <p>*[ui:Tweaks]* are user-defined classes and styles for the specified system style. [Style tweaks] are recommended over copying a style to add customizations to an Alpha Anywhere system style.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>*[ui:System]* styles are styles are stored in a CSS folder contained in the executable folder. During publishing this CSS file is sent from the executable folder to a root folder that outputs the stylized controls.</p>
                <p>Every web project you create has access to System styles. System styles can be customized for each project using the '[Customize style colors and fonts]' property. This makes it easy to change the colors and fonts defined using Sass used with a given style. If you make any alterations to a style using this property then those changes will be implemented across all of the components in a project that also make use of that style.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to customizing the Sass variables for a system style, you can also define [Style tweaks] to extend or modify a system style for a project.</p>
            </description>
            <tip>
                <p>See [Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'] to extend or customize a system style.</p>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Copying a Style</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can create your own custom styles using the [Style Builder]. You can access the Style Builder through the [Edit style in Style Builder] property on the UX Properties page. It is recommended that you start by copying a system style as the baseline for a new style. This copy can be stored in either the 'Local' or 'Global' in scope and can be assigned to a component from the 'Style name' property's 'Local' or 'Global' tab.</p>
                <p>Because these custom styles are based on a copy of a System style, if the system style changes then the copy will not. Therefore, if new CSS classes for new controls are added to a 'System' style, then the styling for these controls will not be available in a customized style designed before the classes were created. The CSS classes would need to be added to the new style by hand.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Project Styles</title>
            <description>The *[ui:Use ProjectStyle]* button defers to a default project style for all of the components in a project. The default style can be set using the '[Project style]' property in the Project Properties page off the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>The define a default style open the Project Properties from the Web Projects Control Panel</description>
                    <figure><link>images/sn3.png</link></figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click on the button next to the 'Project style' property.</description>
                    <figure><link>images/sn4.png</link></figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Assign a style. The project style dialog looks exactly like the 'Project name' dialog</description>
                    <figure><link>images/sn5.png</link></figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Sub-themes</title>
            <description>
                <p>Once you have selected a style you can assign [sub-themes] based on that style to individual controls. This can be done by setting the sub-theme property in a highlighted control's properties list on the UX Controls page.</p>
                <p>You can also define custom sub-themes by taking the javascript that calls the CSS classes for the sub-theme for a given control and creating a new sub-theme name and new CSS class names. This can be done using the [Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'] property to define sub-themes for the project. The [Local sub-theme definitions - CSS] and [Local sub-theme definitions - Javascript] properties can be used to define sub-themes local to a UX Component.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Sub-themes can be set on the UX Controls page in a control's properties list.</title>
                <link>images/sn6.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="style name">Grid Component's 'Style name' property</link>
        <link link="subthemes in alpha">sub-themes</link>
        <link link="UX Properties style subtheme and tweaks">Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'</link>
        <link link="UX Properties style subtheme and tweaks">Style tweaks</link>
        <link link="customize style colors and fonts">Customize style colors and fonts</link>
        <link link="css style builder">Style Builder</link>
        <link link="edit style in style builder">Edit style in Style Builder</link>
        <link link="project style - web project properties">Project style</link>
        <link link="ux properties local subtheme definitions css">Local sub-theme definitions - CSS</link>
        <link link="ux properties local subtheme definitions javascript">Local sub-theme definitions - Javascript</link>
    </links>
</page>