<page>
    <topic>FOR EACH ... NEXT</topic>
    <description>The FOR EACH ... NEXT operators allow you to step through a list, collection, or array without knowing the number of elements that it contains.</description>	
    <syntax>FOR EACH Placeholder IN List [ statements ] [ CONTINUE ] [ statements ] [ EXIT FOR ] NEXT</syntax>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>Placeholder</name>
            <description>An arbitrary name. When referring to the placeholder value inside the loop, reference the variable's *[xb:.value]* property. See examples below.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>List</name>
            <description>The name of a CR-LF delimited list, an array, or a collection.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>	
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[xb:FOR EACH ... NEXT]* operator loops through a list, collection, or array, allowing you iterate over each element. As you iterate through the list, collection, or array the element for the current position in the list is stored in a *[xb:Placeholder]*. The *[xb:Placeholder]* contains information about the element, including its value. In order to reference the value for the current position in the list, you must use the *[xb:value]* property for the place holder. For example, *[xb:Foo.value]*.</p>
        <p>The example below demonstrates iterating over a CR-LF delimited list containing the letters 'a' through 'e' and displays a message box for each letter, skipping the letter 'c'.</p>
    </discussion>
    <note>This example will only run in Desktop applications or the Interactive Window in Alpha Anywhere as the [ui_msg_box function] only works in Desktop applications.</note>
    <example><![CDATA[dim letters as C = <<%txt%
a
b
c
d
e
%txt%
     
FOR EACH letter IN letters
    'refer to the placeholder .value property to get the value of the current element in letters.
    if (letter.value = "c") then
        CONTINUE
    end if
    
    ui_msg_box("", letter.value)
NEXT]]></example>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=ui_msg_box function">ui_msg_box function</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=Xbasic Language Reference">Xbasic Language Reference</ref>
    </see>
</page>