<page>
    <shortlink>ux control properties scrolling</shortlink>
    <topic>Scrolling</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring the scroll behavior for a Panel.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Body can scroll</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the Body can be scrolled.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Body scroll axis</title>
            <description>
                <p>Body scroll axis has three settings: 'Horizontal', 'Vertical', and 'Both'. When set to 'Vertical', the panel body can only be scrolled up and down (top to bottom). When set to 'Horizontal', the panel body can only be scrolled left and right. When set to 'Both', the panel body can be scrolled in all directions.</p>
            </description>
            <tip>
                <p>If you have built an application where swiping left or left navigates to other panels, you should set the *[ui:Body scroll axis]* to 'Vertical'.</p>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Body stop drag propogation</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if drag events should be propagated to containing elements.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Scroll to top on focus</title>
            <description>
                <p>If enabled, the panel body will automatically scroll to the top of the panel card when the panel receives focus.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>'Pull past end' settings and events</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the user can drag the contents of the Panel Card beyond any of its boundaries. If enabled, the content will snap back to its natural position when the user releases, and 'pull' events (which you can define) are fired.</p>
                <p>The following settings are available for configuring the 'Pull past end' behavior:</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Vertical direction</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify under what conditions the user can 'pull' (i.e. drag) the Panel Card beyond its *[top]* or *[bottom]* end point. When the user stops pulling on the Panel Card, the Panel animates back to its natural position.</p>
                        <p>Available options are:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Option</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>auto</name>
                                    <description>Drag past end will only be allowed if there is any scrollable content in the control.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>always</name>
                                    <description>Drag past end will always be allowed.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>never</name>
                                    <description>Drag past end will never be allowed.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Horizontal direction</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Specify under what conditions the user can 'pull' (i.e. drag) the Panel Card beyond its *[left]* or *[right]* end point. When the user stops pulling on the Panel Card, the Panel animates back to its natural position. </p>
                        <p>The options available are *[ui:auto]*, *[ui:always]*, and *[ui:never]*. See *[ui:Vertical direction]* above for an explanation of each option.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">onPull event</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Fires repeatedly while the user is pulling on the content.</p>
                        <p>See [onPull Event] for more information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">onPullRelease event</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Fires when the user releases the 'pulled' content if the content is in a 'pulled past end' state.</p>
                        <p>See [onPullRelease Event] for more information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">onPullEnd event</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Fires when the user has 'pulled' content beyond an end point but has then restores the content to its 'non-pulled' state. Fires when the content is restored to its 'non-pulled' state. The use case for this event is to allow the user to cancel an action that would be triggered by some 'pull past end' action.</p>
                        <p>See [onPullEnd Event] for more information.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Custom scroll indicator settings</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can customize the position and appearance of the scroll indicator that is shown when the Panel Card is scrolled</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/customScrollIndicatorSettings.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>

        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Configuring a Horizontal Scroller</title>
            <description>
                <p>The horizontal scroller lets the user scroll content along the x-axis (left to right). If the horizontal scroller is disabled (*[ui:Show Horizontal scroll indicator]*), the horizontal scroller is not shown when the panel is scrolled horizontally.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>*[Disabling the horizontal scroll indicator does not disable horizontal scrolling.]* To disable horizontal scrolling, see the [Body can scroll] and [Body scroll axis] properties.</p>
            </note>
            <figure>
                <title>Horizontal Scroller layout with *[ui:Horizontal scroll indicator location]* set to 'bottom'</title>
                <link>images/horizontalScroller.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Options include:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Show Horizontal scroll indicator</name>
                            <description>Enables or disables a scroll indicator shown when the Panel is scrolled horizontally (left to right/right to left.) Enabled by default.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal indicator classname</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The classname applied to the area where the scroll indicator moves.</p>
                                <p>If you are using the system Alpha web theme, the default classname for the horizontal indicator is *[css:scrollIndH]*.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal scroll bar classname</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The classname applied to the scroll position indicator.</p>
                                <p>If you are using the system Alpha web theme, the default classname for the horizontal scroll bar is *[css:scrollIndHBar]*.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal scroll indicator location</name>
                            <description>The location of the horizontal scroll indicator. The indicator can be position at the 'top' or 'bottom' of the Panel card. Default is 'bottom'.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the scroll indicator and the edge of the panel (either top or bottom as defined by the *[ui:Horizontal scroll indicator location]* property.) The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal left offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the left edge of the scroll indicator and the left edge of the Panel. The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Horizontal right offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the right edge of the scroll indicator and the right edge of the Panel. The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Configuring a Vertical Scroller</title>
            <description>
                <p>The vertical scroller lets the user scroll content along the y-axis (top to bottom). If the vertical scroller is disabled (*[ui:Show Vertical scroll indicator]*), the vertical scroller is not shown when the panel is scrolled vertically.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>*[Disabling the vertical scroll indicator does not disable vertical scrolling.]* To disable vertical scrolling, see the [Body can scroll] and [Body scroll axis] properties.</p>
            </note>
            <figure>
                <title>Vertical Scroller layout with *[ui:Vertical scroll indicator location]* set to 'right'</title>
                <link>images/verticalScroller.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Options include:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Show Vertical scroll indicator</name>
                            <description>Enables or disables a scroll indicator shown when the Panel is scrolled Vertical (top to bottom/bottom to top.) Enabled by default.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical indicator classname</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The classname applied to the area where the scroll indicator moves.</p>
                                <p>If you are using the system Alpha web theme, the default classname for the vertical indicator is *[css:scrollIndV]*.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical scroll bar classname</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The classname applied to the scroll position indicator.</p>
                                <p>If you are using the system Alpha web theme, the default classname for the vertical scroll bar is *[css:scrollIndVBar]*.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical scroll indicator location</name>
                            <description>The location of the vertical scroll indicator. The indicator can be position at the 'left' or 'right' of the Panel card. Default is 'right'.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the scroll indicator and the edge of the panel (either left or right as defined by the *[ui:Vertical scroll indicator location]* property.) The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical top offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the top edge of the scroll indicator and the top edge of the Panel. The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Vertical bottom offset</name>
                            <description>The space between the bottom edge of the scroll indicator and the bottom edge of the Panel. The offset is defined using CSS units. Default is 0px.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_Body can scroll">Body can scroll</link>
        <link href="#section1_Body scroll axis">Body scroll axis</link>
        <link link="ux%20list%20clientside%20event%20onpull">onPull Event</link>
        <link link="ux%20list%20clientside%20event%20onpullrelease">onPullRelease Event</link>
        <link link="ux%20list%20clientside%20event%20onpullend">onPullEnd Event</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="how%20to%20refresh%20list%20data%20with%20%22pull-to-refresh%22">How to Refresh List Data with "Pull-to-Refresh"</ref>
    </see>
</page>