<page build="8602" api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 u element setscrollto method</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.u.element" parentType="namespace" elementName="setScrollTo Method" >A5.u.element.setScrollTo Method</topic>
	<prototype>A5.u.element.setScrollTo(element[,settings])</prototype>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name>element</name>
			<types><type>element</type><type>string</type></types>
			<description>A pointer to a DOM element or the ID of an element.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument optional="true" >
			<name>settings</name>
			<type>object</type>
			<description>Scroll setting.</description>
		<properties>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>recurse</name>
				<type>boolean</type>
				<description>If a value of true is passed in then the each scroll parent element will also be scrolled into view with the same settings as the initial scroll.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>mode</name>
				<type>string</type>
				<description>How the child element should be scrolled to. The default value is "into-view", which will scroll the child element into view with the least amount of scrolling (child element aligned to the nearest edge). A value of "top" will scroll the element so that it is at the top of the scrollable area. A value of "bottom" will scroll the element so that it is at the bottom of the scrollable area.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>view</name>
				<type>object</type>
				<description>Optional edge scrolling settings for when the target element overflows the scrollable area.</description>
				<properties>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>x</name>
						<type>string</type>
						<description>The horizontal edge to scroll to when the target element is wider then the scrollable area. Values can be "left" (the default), "right" or "nearest". A value of "none" will not scroll the "x" axis if any of the target element is visible.</description>
					</property>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>y</name>
						<type>string</type>
						<description>The vertical edge to scroll to when the target element is wider then the scrollable area. Values can be "top" (the default), "bottom" or "nearest". A value of "none" will not scroll the "y" axis if any of the target element is visible.</description>
					</property>
				</properties>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>offset</name>
				<type>object</type>
				<description>Optional offset for the scrolling.</description>
				<properties>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>x</name>
						<type>number</type>
						<description>The number of pixels extra to add to the X axis. For example, a value of 10 will mean that the element will be scrolled so that it is 10 pixels away from the edge of the scrollable area.</description>
					</property>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>y</name>
						<type>number</type>
						<description>The number of pixels extra to add to the Y axis. For example, a value of 10 will mean that the element will be scrolled so that it is 10 pixels away from the edge of the scrollable area.</description>
					</property>
				</properties>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>fireEvent</name>
				<type>boolean</type>
				<description>Set to true to fire the native scroll event once the scrolling has been set. The default is false.</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>axis</name>
				<type>string</type>
				<description>What axes to scroll on. Values can be "both", "x" or "y".</description>
			</property>
			<property optional="true" >
				<name>animation</name>
				<type>object</type>
				<description>If the A5 frameworks custom scrolling is being used, whether to preform the scroll with an animation from the current location to the new location.</description>
				<properties>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>allow</name>
						<type>boolean</type>
						<description>Set to true to allow the animation. The default is false.</description>
					</property>
					<property optional="true" >
						<name>duration</name>
						<type>number</type>
						<description>The duration (in milliseconds) the that the animation should take.</description>
					</property>
				</properties>
			</property>
		</properties>
		</argument>
	</arguments>
	<description> Scrolls the scrollable parent of the passed in element to show that element.</description>
	<discussion>
<p>
A5.u.element.setScrollTo can be used to scroll to an element whether the scrollable parent element is using the A5 frameworks custom scrolling (drag scrolling for mobile), or the browser native scrolling.
</p>
</discussion>
	<example code="js">
// assume "id" is the ID of an element inside of multiple scrollable element
A5.u.element.setScroll(id,{
	recurse: true,
	mode: 'top', // scroll element to top
});
// the element should now be at the top of the screen</example>
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/u_namespace/element_namespace/A5.u.element.setScrollTo Method.xml</annotations>
</page>
