<page>
    <shortlink>How to Add a Google Chart to a UX Component</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Add a Google Chart to a UX Component</topic>
    <description>The Google visualization libraries offer an alternative to creating and displaying charts in a UX Component.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>To add a Google Chart to your app, you need a DIV in your UX Component that can be used to display the chart. For example, the following code when added to a Static Text control creates a DIV called "mychart" that can be used to load a Google Chart:</description>
            <example code="html"><![CDATA[<div id="mychart" style="width: 6in; height: 6in; border: solid 1px blue;">Chart goes here</div>]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The following function creates an Area Chart that is then displayed in the "mychart" DIV:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[function chart1 () {
    var data = google.visualization.arrayToDataTable([
        ['Year', 'Sales', 'Expenses'],
        ['2004', 1000, 400],
        ['2005', 1170, 460],
        ['2006', 660, 1120],
        ['2007', 1030, 540]
    ]);

    var options = {
        title: 'Company Performance',
        hAxis: {title: 'Year', titleTextStyle: {color: '#333'}},
        vAxis: {minValue: 0}
    };

    var chart = new google.visualization.AreaChart($('mychart'));
    chart.draw(data,options);
}]]></example>
        <note>The Area Chart is part of the *[ui:corechart]* Google Chart Library. To use the Area Chart, you will need to check the *[ui:corechart]* option for the [Google visualization libraries property] of the UX Component.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The last step is to call the *[js:chart1()]* function to display the Area Chart. This can be done by adding JavaScript to the click event for a button to call the *[js:chart1()]* function. For example:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[chart1();]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Charts can be rendered on demand using buttons or dynamically using ajax callbacks, server-side events, or client-side events. For example, the [afterGoogleVisualization client-side UX event] fires after the Google Visualization library has loaded. Calling *[js:chart1()]* in this event will load the chart immediately after the Google Visualization API is loaded and ready.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To learn more about how to use Google Charts in your applications, watch the video below:</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Using Google Charts as an Alternative to the Build-in Chart Controls</title>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/googleCharts.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/2adc8a6f</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <important>It is no longer necessary to go to the Web Project Properties dialog to specify that the Google JSAPI library should be loaded. The Visualization libraries are now loaded automatically by the UX as needed.</important>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="aftergooglevisualization">afterGoogleVisualization client-side UX event</link>
        <link link="ux properties google visualization libraries">Google visualization libraries property</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="how to use sql data in google chart">How to Use SQL Data in a Google Chart</ref>
        <ref href="https://developers.google.com/chart/interactive/docs/">Google Chart API Documentation</ref>
        <ref link="ux javascript chart control">Javascript Chart Control</ref>
    </see>
</page>