<page>
    <shortlink>how to base a chart on cross sectional data</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Base a Chart on Cross-sectional Data</topic>
    <description>When a data series must be based on multiple fields in a record rather than a single field across multiple records, a Cross-Sectional data series can be created to map multiple columns in a table to one or more sub-series.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A Cross-Sectional data series specifies a mapping between columns in a table and one or more sub-series. This is useful when series data spans multiple columns instead of multiple rows. EG, a table that stores quarterly sales data for two years in a single record.</p>
        <p>Cross-Section data series can be created for SQL or DBF databases. The *[ui:Data extraction template]* defines how to map each row of data from the table into one or more subseries in the data series definition. </p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>

        <section>
            <description>To create a Cross-Section data series, follow the steps below:</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In the *[ui:UX Builder]* Properties, open the Data Series builder by clicking the [...] button for the *[ui:Data series]* property.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/dataSeriesEdit.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Create a new Data Series or Edit an Existing one.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/dataSeriesCrossSectional1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Choose the "CrossSection" data series for your database. The cross-sectional data series available are described below:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Cross-Sectional</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>SQL-CrossSection</name>
                            <description>Create a Cross-Sectional data series for a query against a SQL Database.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>DBF-CrossSection</name>
                            <description>Create a Cross-Sectional data series for data from one or more DBF tables.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Define the data query to extract the data from the database. Your query can use arguments to filter the results. Specify an order clause to sort the results.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/dataSeriesCrossSectional2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Define the *[ui:Data extraction template]* for the data series. The extraction template can define multiple sub-series. For example, the Data extraction template below defines a mapping of a table row that holds quarterly sales information for the current year and previous year into three subseries: 'Quarter', 'Sales', and 'SalesPrevious'.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/dataSeriesCrossSectional3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <example><![CDATA[Quarter|Sales|SalesPrevious
1st|{Q1_sales}|{Q1_prev_sales}
2nd|{Q2_sales}|{Q2_prev_sales}
3rd|{Q3_sales}|{Q3_prev_sales}
4th|{Q4_sales}|{Q4_prev_sales}]]></example>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Save the Data Series.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For a comprehensive guide to create a cross-sectional data series, watch the video below.</description>
            <note>The videos demonstrate using a DBF data source. The concepts shown here also apply to the *[ui:SQL-CrossSection]* Data Source Type.</note>
            <videos>
                <title>Understanding the "CrossSectional" Data Series Type</title>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/dbfCrossSection.a5wcmp</link>
                    </resource>
                    <resource>
                        <name>Download DBF Table for Component</name>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/SalesData_XSection.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/53743d97</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux javascript chart control">Javascript Chart Control</ref>
    </see>
</page>