<page>
    <shortlink>how to base a chart on a custom series</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Base a Chart on a Custom Series</topic>
    <description>An Xbasic function can be used to create a Custom data series that dynamically computes sub-series data from a SQL database.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The data series used in a Chart control can be generated using a Custom data source. Custom data series are generated using Xbasic. The Xbasic function can return a static set of data or query a SQL database or Web service to generate the data in the data series.</p>
        <p>The Xbasic function that defines the Custom data series must return a CR-LF delimited list of values. This list contains one or more sub-series. For example, the following Xbasic function returns two sub-series, defining 'sales'' for individual 'regions':</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[function getData() as c (e as p)
    ' return data for sub-series "sales" and "region"
    ' Data format: <sales>|<region>
    getData = <<%txt%
12|east
23|west
17|south
23|north
%txt%
end function]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When returning a sub-series, the name of the each sub-series must be specified in the *[ui:Subseries names]* property for the data source. The order that sub-series are defined is the order defines the order that they must appear in the data returned by your Xbasic function. Each sub-series value must be separated by the pipe "|" delimiter.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The data returned by the Xbasic function can be dynamically generated using data in a SQL database or web service. In addition, you can pass additional data to the Xbasic function with JavaScript. To learn more, watch the videos below:</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <resources>
                <resource>
                    <name>Download Custom Series from Static Data Example</name>
                    <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/simpleCustomSeries.a5wcmp</link>
                </resource>
                <resource>
                    <name>Download Custom Series Created from SQL Database Example</name>
                    <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/northwindProductsCustom.a5wcmp</link>
                </resource>
            </resources>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Overview of the Custom Series Type</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/dtg1ew6GrJLiTu7UfC66eY?</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/SMMmY9eA9oVXMo1ENXqFTj?</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/cQMA2ZWapSDnHyfaYqBKy3?</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 3</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/V98G1buaCi1jKe1VDfP9ei?</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux javascript chart control">Javascript Chart Control</ref>
    </see>
</page>