<page>
	<topic>Create SQL Connection String Dialog</topic>
	
	<description>The SQL Connection String dialog helps you define the connection string that you need to open a connection with an external database. There are several ways to access the SQL Connection String Dialog if you are not entirely familiar with it.</description>
					
	
	<groups>
		
		
		<group background="true">
			<sections>
				<section>
					<steps>
						<step>
							<description>You can reach the SQL Connection String Dialog dialog by clicking on the Tools tab at the top of the screen. Under Tools, select External Databases and under External Databases select AlphaDAO connections. This should load the AlphaDAO connections dialog, if you have nothing to connect click the New button at the bottom of the screen. This will load the New AlphaDAO connection Dialog. Type in the name of your connection and click Build. This should take you to the Create SQL Connection String Dialog. </description>
						</step>
						<step>
							<description>Alternatively, with the Web Projects Control Panel open, you can click Edit and scroll down to Manage Connection Strings option on the cascading list. Click on AlphaDAO Connection Strings option. This will load the AlphaDAO Connection Strings  Dialog. Click New, or choose an existing connection and click Edit, this will load the New AlphaDAO connection Dialog. Type in or approve the name of your connection and click Build. This should take you to the Create SQL Connection String Dialog. </description>
						</step>
						<step>
							<description>The SQL Connection String Dialog also appears via the Grid Builder. To get to the grid builder Click the Create a new grid component button at the top of the Web Projects Control Panel. This will bring you to the Select Grid Component Template Dialog. Here you have the option of working with a blank grid component or choosing from a list of pre-existing templates. Choose an option and click OK. This will bring you to the Grid Builder Dialog. Go to Query (AlphaDAO) under grid. Select 'Specify Connection String' under the Connection type drop down and click Build. This will load the SQL Connection String Dialog as well.</description>
						</step>
						
					</steps>
					
				</section>
				
			</sections>
			
		</group>
		
		
		<group>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<steps>
						<step>
							<description>Select one of the following database types:</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>"Access"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"DB2"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"Excel"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"MySQL"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"OCI"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"ODBC"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"Oracle"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"OracleLite"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"QuickBooks" (requires QOBC license)
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"SQLAnywhere"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"SQLServer"
</description>
								</case>
									<case>
									<description>"Sybase"</description>
								</case>
								
							</cases>
						</step>
						
						
						<step>
							<description>Some data sources first require that you select a file.</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>1. If the File Name control appears, click 'open folder' icon to navigate to and select a database.
</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>2. If the User control appears, and a login is required, enter your user name. 
</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>3. If the Password control appears, and a login is required, enter your password. 
</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>4. If the Additional Parameters control appears, enter any additional parameters that may be required to connect with the database. 
</description>
									<figure><link>images/SQR_Create_SQL_Connection_String_Ad_Hoc.png</link></figure>
								</case>
								
								
							</cases>
						</step>
						
						
						<step>
							<description>Some data sources first require that you select a server.</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>1. If the Hostname control appears, enter the URL of the server.</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>2. If the Port control appears, enter the port number that the database monitors.</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>3. If the User control appears, and a login is required, enter your user name.</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>4. If the Password control appears, and a login is required, enter your password.</description>
									
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>5. If the Database list appears, click Refresh and select a database.</description>
									
								</case>
							</cases>
							
						</step>
						
						
						
						
						
						
						
						
						
					</steps>
					
				</section>
				
			</sections>
			<see>
				<ref>Enterprise Reporting</ref>
			</see>
		</group>
		
		
		
		
	</groups>
	
	
</page>