<page>
    <topic>Action type</topic>
    <description>Specify the action to be performed when the user taps on the hyperlink. 
        'Telephone' and 'Email' use the 'tel' and 'mailto' protocols in the generated 'href'
        attribute to dial a phone number, or send an email with the associated telephone or mail 
        client.
    </description>


<sections>
    
    
    <section>
        <figure><title>The Action type property.</title><link>images/hyper.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <description>The Action type property has a number of options: Javascript, Href, Telephone, SMS, 
            and Email</description>
        
        
    </section>
    <section>
         <title>Href</title>
        <description>When you add a hyperlink control to a List, you can define standard HTML hyperlinks with an 'href'
             attribute that specifies the hyperlink target, as an alternative to using Javascript code. </description>
    </section>
    <section>
       
        <description>To specify a hyperlink target, set the 'Action type' to 'Href' and then specify the 'Hyperlink address'. 
             You can use a placeholder for the address. For example if your List has a field called 'address', 
             you can specify the 'Hyperlink address' as {address}. The hyperlink address must include the protocol if the target is not a page in the application webroot. 
             For example, to display bing.com, you would need to set the target to 'http://www.bing.com', 
             but to display a page called 'page1.a5w' in the current webroot, you would just need to set the target 
             to 'page1.a5w'.</description>
        <figure><link>images/hyper4.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <section>
        <title>Telephone</title>
         <description>You can configure a hyperlink control in a List to dial a telephone number. 
             This is particularly useful in mobile applications that are run on a phone.</description>
               </section>
               
               
               
      <section>
     <videos>
       <video>
         <description>Watch Video</description>
         <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_list_dialPhone.swf</link>
       </video>
       
     </videos>
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
      <description>Assume you have a List control with this data:
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[name|phoneDisplay|phoneDial
John Smith (home)|(555) 555-5555|+15555555555
John Smith (mobile)|(555) 555-5556|+15555555556]]></example>
      
    </section>
    
    
       <section>
      <description>The List data contains both the phone number to display in the List and the phone number to actually dial. 
          Notice that the phone number that should be dialed includes the +1 prefix to indicate that this is a U.S. phone number. The phone number to be dialed must start with + and then the country code (1 in the case of the U.S.). 
The phone number to be dialed can also include special directives. For example you can insert 'p' in the number to indicate a one-second pause and 'w' to indicate 'wait for dial tone'.
Using the sample data shown above, to configure the hyperlink to dial the telephone number in the 'phoneDial' field, but display the number shown in the 'phoneDisplay' field, you would set the 'Action type' property to 'Telephone', the 'Phone number' field to '{phoneDial}' (note that the placeholder is case-sensitive) and the 'Hyperlink text' property to '{phoneDisplay}', as shown in the image below.
It is permissible for the value passed in as the phone number to dial to include spaces and parentheses. For example, +1(555) 555-5555 is a valid number to dial.
</description>
   <figure><link>images/hyper3.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    
    
     <section>
      <description>If, for example, your List data had separate fields for the phone number (called 'phone' for example) and country code (called 'code' - without the leading + in the data), you could set the 'Phone number' field to:
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[+{code} {phone}
]]></example>
      
    </section>
        

    
    
    
    
    <section>
        <title>Email</title>
         <description>You can configure a hyperlink control in a List control 
             to open the associated e-mail client and fill in the 'to' address with a field.</description>

        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>To configure a hyperlink to open an e-mail client, set the 'Action type' to 'Email' 
            and the 'Email address' to the value you want to put into the email client's 'to' address field. 
            You can use placeholders in the 'Email address' property to refer to data in a field in 
            the current row of the List.</description>
            <figure><title>Placeholders for an email address</title><link>images/hyper2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    
</sections>


</page>