<page build="7730">
    <shortlink>tabbed ui compact style parts</shortlink>
    <topic>Apply compact style which parts?</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Defines which part of the Tabbed UI to apply the compact style.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>If the [Use compact theme] is enabled, you can specify which parts of the TabbedUI Component should use the compact theme. The compact theme is available in the Alpha Web Theme and all themes that inherit from Alpha. When Use compact theme is enabled, the compact theme is usually applied to all parts of the Tabbed UI, including all child components.</p>
        <p>*[ui:Apply compact style which parts?]* lets you choose which parts of the TabbedUI should use the compact theme. For example, you could apply the compact theme to just the menu. This gives you more control over which version of the theme (full or compact) is used by components loaded in the Tabbed UI.</p>
        <p>The compact theme can be applied to the following areas:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Entire component</name>
                    <description>The compact theme used throughout the entire Tabbed UI, including child components.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Menu section</name>
                    <description>The compact theme is applied to the menu section of the Tabbed UI.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Tab Band section</name>
                    <description>The compact theme is applied to the section were the tabs for open pages and components are shown.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Client area</name>
                    <description>The compact theme is applied to the area where child components are displayed.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </discussion>
    <links>
        <link link="tabbed ui properties tabbed ui properties use compact theme property">Use compact theme</link>
    </links>
</page>