<page>
    <shortlink>ux list builder multilayout properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Multiple Layouts</topic>
    <description>Create multiple List layouts to customize data presentation when the device's orientation changes from landscape to portrait.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Multiple layouts can be defined for a List control. You may want to create separate data presentations for the List based on the device's orientation. To enable multiple layouts, check the *[ui:Has multiple layouts]* tab. This will expose the [Multiple Layouts] pane, where you can define layouts for the List.</p>
        <p>You can also specify the default layout to use when a device is in landscape or portrait orientation. If a default layout is defined, the List will automatically switch layouts when the orientation changes.</p> 
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Properties</title>
            <description>The following properties are used to enable multiple layouts for a List control and assign the default layout to use when a device is in portrait or landscape orientation.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Has multiple layouts</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, allows you t to define multiple layouts for the List control.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Auto-select layout on orientation change</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can specify which layout to use when the device orientation is landscape and which layout to use when the device orientation is portrait. Enabling the *[ui:Auto-select layout on orientation change]* property allows you to assign a default layout for the device when the orientation changes.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Layout for landscape</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The layout to use when the device's orientation is in Landscape mode.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Layout for portrait</title>
                    <description>The layout to use when the device's orientation is in Portrait mode.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>List Control - Multiple Layouts</title>
                <description>When you design a List control, you can specify multiple Layouts. A Layout is just the manner in which the data in the List is shown. You can switch from one layout style to another at run-time.</description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/1cd1421c</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/list_MultipleLayouts.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Automatically Changing the List Layout on an Device Orientation Change Event</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The List control allows multiple layouts to be designed. For example, you might have one layout design that you would like to show when the device in in landscape mode and another when the device is in portrait mode.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can automatically switch from one List layout to another when the device orientation is changed.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/bc4a22f5</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/list_selectLayoutOnOrientationChange.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux list builder multilayout properties">Multiple Layouts</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux list builder multilayout properties">Multiple Layouts</ref>
        <ref link="ux data controls list control">List Control</ref>
        <ref link="list control ux api">List Control JavaScript Methods</ref>
    </see>
</page>