<page>
   <topic>FILE.SEND Function</topic>
   <syntax>L File.Send(C filenames [,C emailaddress[,C options[,C zipname[,C comment[,L use_A5_email_client [,L store_in_outbox [,L show_client ]]]]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>filenames</name>
         <description>A string of comma-delimited file names. You must specify the full drive and path of each file in filenames. Wildcard specifications can be used in the list of file names.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>emailaddress</name>
         <description>Optional. Destination email address.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>options</name>
         <description>Optional. If you specify more than one file, you must use the "C" or "Z" option flag to compress the files into a single zip file. If wildcards are used, the "C" option flag must be specified.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>zipname</name>
         <description>Required if wildcards are used. The name of the zip file to create. Otherwise the zip file has the same name as the first file in the list.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>comment</name>
         <description>A comment about the files that goes into the subject line.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>use_A5_email_client</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .F. (FALSE)

.T. = Use Alpha Five email client.

.F. = Use default MAPI email client. </description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>store_in_outbox</name>
         <description>Optional. Only if Use_A5_Email_Clien t is .T.

.T. = A copy of the message is stored in the Alpha Anywhere email outbox (typically A_EMAIL.DBF in the Alpha Anywhere program folder).

.F. = A copy of the message is not stored in the Alpha Anywhere email outbox. </description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>show_client</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .T. (TRUE). Only if the optional Email_Address is specified and Use_A5_Email_Client is .T.
Determines whether the Alpha Anywhere email client is displayed before sending files in the case where you select the Alpha Anywhere email client option.

.T. = Show Alpha Five email client before sending email.

.F. = Do not show Alpha Anywhere email client. </description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Send one or more files to an address. Options: C or Z = compress (i.e. zip) files before sending.</description>
   <discussion>
The FILE.SEND() method sends multiple files via the current MAPI email client, or the built-in Alpha Anywhere email client.
If, for example, Use_A5_Email_Client is .F., and the current MAPI email client is Microsoft Outlook, Alpha Anywhere will open Outlook. Similarly, if the email client is Eudora, or Netscape Mail, Alpha Anywhere will open the appropriate email program.
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>This script will send two files. It compress the files first into a zip file called myfiles.zip.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim filelist as C
Filelist = "c:\data\file1.txt,c:\data\file2.txt"
file.Send_FILEs(filelist,"","C","myfiles")

]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Objects/Table/TABLE.SEND Method.xml">TABLE.SEND()</ref>
      <ref>File  Functions and Methods</ref>
      <ref>Email  Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
<terms>file,case,email,function,list,script,string</terms>
</page>