<page>
    <shortlink>flying start genie global properties tab</shortlink>
    <topic>3:&#160;Global&#160;Properties</topic>
    <description>Specify global properties for both the Grid and Tabbed UI Components generated by the Flying Start Genie. These properties apply to all components created by the genie.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/setGlobalProps.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Grid Part Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Grid is editable</name>
                    <description>Specify if the Grid components that are created should be editable. If editable, then the Detail View must be on. You can override this setting for any particular Grid component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Grid part fields</name>
                    <description>Specify which fields should be included in the Grid Part. Primary key fields are always included. You can specify &lt;AllFields&gt; or count:Number (e.g. count:5)  to include the first specified number of fields.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Grid name prefix</name>
                    <description>For each Grid component that is created, a default name will be used that is based on the table/view name from which the Grid is constructed. You can specify a prefix that should be used for the Grid name.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Overwrite option</name>
                    <description>If a Grid with the specified name already exists, what action should be taken? Prompt - prompt for action, Skip - do not create Grid, Rename - give the Grid a new name so that it does not overwrite the existing Grid, Overwrite - overwrite the existing Grid. Choices include *[ui:Prompt]*, *[ui:Skip]*, *[ui:Rename]*, *[ui:Overwrite]*.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search Part Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Has Search Part</name>
                    <description>Specify if the Grid components that are created should have the Search Part turned on. You can override this setting for any particular Grid component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Search part fields</name>
                    <description>Specify which fields should be included in the Search Part. Primary key fields are always included. You can specify &lt;AllFields&gt; or count:Number (e.g. count:5) to include the first specified number of fields.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Can be hidden</name>
                    <description>Specify if the Search Part can be hidden.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Initial display state</name>
                    <description>Specify the Search Part initial state Choices include *[ui:Open]*, *[ui:Closed]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Search part title</name>
                    <description>Specify the Search Part title when it is shown.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Search part title (hidden)</name>
                    <description>Specify the Search Part title when it is hidden.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Detail View Part Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Has Detail View Part</name>
                    <description>Specify if the Grid components that are created should have the Detail View Part turned on. You can override this setting for any particular Grid component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Detail View part fields</name>
                    <description>Specify which fields should be included in the Detail View Part. Primary key fields are always included. You can specify &lt;AllFields&gt; or count:Number (e.g. count:5) to include the first specified number of fields.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Detail View title</name>
                    <description>Specify the title for the Detail View.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Detail View position</name>
                    <description>Specify where the Detail View should be shown. Choices include *[ui:PopupWindow-Modal]*, *[ui:PopupWindow-Modeless]*, *[ui:InGrid]*, *[ui:OnPage]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Pre-fetch data</name>
                    <description>Specify if the data for the Detail View should be pre-fetched. This will speed up the display of the Detail View for an individual record, but will slow down the initial display of the Grid.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Tabbed UI Component Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Tabbed UI Component name</name>
                    <description>Specify the name of the Tabbed UI component that should be created.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Style name</name>
                    <description>Specify the default style for each component that will be created. You can override this setting for any particular component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Header</name>
                    <description>Specify the header text for the Tabbed UI component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Footer</name>
                    <description>Specify the footer text for the Tabbed UI component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>A5ContainerClass class padding</name>
                    <description>Every control is wrapped in a div with the class of 'a5container'. The padding specified here is the minimum space between adjacent controls. Use CSS syntax to specify padding. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Left padding</name>
                    <description>Specify the padding between the left edge of page and the buttons in the Tabbed UI component. Use CSS syntax to specify padding. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Top padding</name>
                    <description>Specify the padding between the top edge of the Button section and the first button in the Tabbed UI component. Use CSS syntax to specify padding. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Button width</name>
                    <description>Specify the width of each button in the Tabbed UI component. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Button spacing</name>
                    <description>Specify the vertical spacing between each button in the Tabbed UI component. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="flying start genie select tables tab">2: Select tables</ref>
        <ref link="flying start genie finish tab">4: Finish</ref>
    </see>
</page>