<page>
	<topic>Workspaces and Projects</topic>
<description>The files, code, connection strings and other elements of your application are kept in a workspace. When the Alpha Anywhere Developer is started, you are prompted to create a new workspace or open one that already exists. 
</description>	
<sections>
<section>
	
	<description>Within a workspace, you can have multiple projects, which can be helpful if you want to keep separate versions of your application in the same workspace. When a workspace is created, a project is already created for you called Default, which appears in a drop-down in the top left of the Web Projects Control Panel. The Web Projects Control Panel also has a button for creating new a new project. </description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Workspace Properties</title>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere has a Workspace Properties dialog box that you can use to configure the behavior of the workspace. These properties mainly apply to Windows desktop applications and are included the software for backwards compatibility with Alpha Five. They are typically not used when building a mobile or desktop/web application. </description>
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Project Properties</title>
	<description>The [Project Properties] dialog box, which is accessed by clicking the Project Properties button on the Web Projects Control Panel. It allows you to define settings that apply to the project such as whether to include jQuery, what the default style for the application should be, email settings, and other properties. The dialog is divided into runtime properties and design time properties. Runtime properties affect how your application behaves when it is run. Design time properties affect how the Alpha Developer IDE behaves when creating your application. </description>
	
</section>			
</sections>	
	<links>
		<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/help/Server/Guide/Design/View/Component/Project%20Style%20-%20Web%20Project%20Properties.xml">Project Properties</link>
		
	</links>
	
</page>