<page>
    <shortlink>howto add web2cal serverside events</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Add Server-side Event Handlers to the Web2Cal Calendar to Respond to Event Changes</topic>
    <description>Event handlers can be added to the Web2Cal Calendar when an event is added, edited, moved, or deleted.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>When using the Web2Cal calendar control you might want to execute server-side code for the following events:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>an event is added</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>an event is edited</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>an event is moved</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>an event is deleted</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>There are no built-in hooks for these events, but you can easily define you own. </p>
                <p>For the event added, edited, or deleted cases, you can add event handlers as follows:</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Edit the UX component used to edit events and add the functions shown below to the Xbasic function declarations</p>
                    </description>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[function onEventDelete as v (e as p)
end function

function onEventUpdate as v (e as p)
end function

function onEventAdd as v (e as p)
end function]]></example>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Edit the UX component used to edit events and modify the server-side afterDialogValidate event to add calls to the onEventUpdate and onEventAdd functions. See below.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Edit the UX component used to edit events and modify the deleteEventXbasic Xbasic function by adding the following at the end of the function: onEventDelete(e)</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How to Update the afterDialogValidate Event Handler Function</title>
            <description>
                <p>In the UX Component used to edit events, update the code in the afterDialogValidate event to call the *[xb:onEventUpdate()]* function:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA['update the event on the calendar
dim javascriptUpdateCalendar as c
dim po as p
if pv.eventsMode = "EditEvent" then
    po.eventId = convert_type(e.dataSubmitted.eventId,"N")
    
    'add call to onEventUpdate:
    onEventUpdate(e)

else
    po.eventId = eventId

    'add eventId to e and call to onEventUpdate:
    e.eventId = po.eventId
    onEventAdd(e)

end if ]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To handle the event is moved case, edit the Web2Cal component and add this code to the onComponentExecute server-side event:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="xb"><![CDATA[if eval_valid("request.variables._XbasicFunction") then 
    if request.variables._XbasicFunction = "updateEvents" then 
        'event was moved
        'event data can be found in request.variables._calEvent_eventId, etc.
    end if 
end if ]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>