<page>
    <shortlink>return status codes from ajax callbacks</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Return Status Codes from Ajax Callbacks</topic>
    <description>You can manually set the status code in an Ajax response.</description>
    <discussion>Setting the status code is a good technique to use if you need to test how your application will behave when the server returns status codes indicating a problem as occured, such as a 401 or 403 status. You can manually set the status code in an Ajax response by setting the [Context.Response.StatusCode] property in the Xbasic function that handles the Ajax callback.</discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Suppose you have a UX Component that has enabled client-side security events. When client-side security events are enabled in a UX Component, the [securityNotAuthenticated] and [securityPermissionsDenied] client-side events are available to you to add your own messages or error handling when the server returns a 401 or 403 status code. To test code you have added in these client-side events, you need to be able to emulate or trigger a 401 and 403 status code response from the Alpha Anywhere Application Server.</p>
                <p>You can manually set the status code for the Ajax response in the Xbasic function that handles the Ajax callback. This could be done as follows:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[function myXBFunction as c (e as p)

    Context.Response.StatusCode = 401

end function]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=context.response object">Context.Response.StatusCode</link>
        <link href="/documentation/index?seach=ux client side events securityNotAuthenticated">securityNotAuthenticated</link>
        <link href="/documentation/index?seach=ux client side events securitypermissionsdenied">securityPermissionsDenied</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=context.response object">Context.Response.StatusCode</ref>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=ux properties other security permissions denied action">UX Property: Security permissions denied action</ref>
    </see>
</page>