<page>
    <shortlink>ux textbox special type settings property</shortlink>
    <topic>Special type settings</topic>
    <description>Specifies optional mapping between the selected address and controls in the UX Component.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Special type settings]* property defines how the selected address is mapped to controls in the UX Component. Clicking the [...] button opens the *[ui:Map Address Parts to Individual Controls]* dialog that is used to define the relationship between the controls and the selected address.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Map Address Parts to Individual Controls dialog</title>
            <description>Addresses can be broken into individual parts and mapped using either the 'long' or 'short' form of the address string. For example, when mapping the state field, the long form may be 'Massachusetts' while the short form would use the state's abbreviation, 'MA'.</description>
            <note>Defining mapping between the address and controls is *[not]* required.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The Map Address Parts to Individual Controls dialog</title>
                <link>images/googleaddresssuggestbuilder.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>There are multiple address parts available for mapping:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>street_address</name>
                    <description>The street address, e.g. "1234"</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>route</name>
                    <description>The name of the "route" or "street. For example, "Massachusetts Avenue".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>sublocality_level_1</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>sublocality_level_2</name>
                    <description></description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>locality</name>
                    <description>The city or town. E.g. "Arlington".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>administrative_area_level_2</name>
                    <description>In the United States, this value would be the county.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>administrative_area_level_1</name>
                    <description>In the United States, this value would be the state. For example, "Massachusetts".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>country</name>
                    <description>The country.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>postal_code</name>
                    <description>The postal code used in mailing addresses. For example, "02476".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>postal_code_suffix</name>
                    <description>In the United States, this is the 4 digit code immediately following the zip code.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
            <note>
                <p>The examples provided here are for addesses in the United States. Some addresses may not include values for the properties listed above. Visit Google's *[extlink:Address Component Types documentation@https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/intro#Types]* for more information.</p>
                <p>The address parts listed above are from the Address Component Types defined by the Google Maps Javascript API. The entire place object, including these address parts, are also avaiable in the UX Component's [afterGoogleAddressSelect] client-side event.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Google API Key</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In addition to defining address mapping, you can also specify the Google Maps API Key that should be used. If the *[ui:Google API Key]* property is blank, Alpha Anywhere will use the API key defined in Web Project Properties.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>If there is no API key defined in Web Project Properties, Alpha Anywhere will look for a file called *[ui:GoogleMapsAPIKey.txt]* which should contain the API key.</note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Bias address suggestions to the user's current location?</title>
                    <description>The *[ui:Bias address suggestions to the user's current location?]* option, if checked, will use the user's current location to look up address suggestions. Addresses that are close to the user's location will be shown first in the list of suggestions.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <note>*[ui:Special type settings]* are only available if the [Special type] property has been set to *[ui:GoogleAddressSelect]*.</note>
    <note>Google Address auto-suggest is not supported for textbox controls in Repeating Sections.</note>
    <links>
        <link link="ux textbox special type property">Special type</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="ux client side event aftergoogleaddressselect">afterGoogleAddressSelect</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux textbox special type property">Special type Property</ref>
    </see>
</page>