<page build="3522">
    <shortlink>howto create addin controls</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Create Add-in Controls</topic>
    <description>Custom controls can be created and added to the Alpha Anywhere environment or the UX Component.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Add-in controls are defined by entries in the 'uxCustomControls' folder in the executable folder. To add an add-in control to your UX component, click the [More...] item in the UX toolbox and select the control to insert into the component.</p>
        <p>You can create your own add-in controls and add them to the dialog by placing the definition files for the control int he 'uxCustomControls' folder in the executable folder.</p>
        <p>All of the definition files for the add-in control must be placed inside a folder in the 'uxCustomControls' directory. The folder name is the name of the add-in control shown in the [More...] dialog. Inside the sub-folder there should be three files:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>define.xbasic</name>
                    <description>Xbasic script the defines the 'builder' for the custom control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>generate.xbasic</name>
                    <description>Xbasic script that generates the settings for the custom control based on properties defined in the builder.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>info.json</name>
                    <description>A settings object that defines the icon and help text for the control that are shown in the dialog where the user selects the control.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>For examples of how to define the contents of these three files, please refer to any of the sample controls that are shipped with Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                <p>Here is an example of how the IntegerValue control looks:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/integervalue.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The IntegerValue control is used for a field that only allow integer values and the value can be set by clicking buttons to increment/decrement the integer value.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Add-in Controls</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The UX Builder allows you to define add-in data bound controls. These are control that are defined externally and are available in the UX Builder just like any of the built-in controls.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2016-03-15</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/6e22ef58</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20data%20controls%20more%20controls">More...</link>
    </links>
</page>