<page>
    <shortlink>ux controls data controls textbox index</shortlink>
    <topic>TextBox</topic>
    <description>TextBox controls provide an means to create new text that can be entered into other controls, such as a list control. Through its 'Lookup' properties, in the control properties list, a Textbox can also be used to create Edit-Combo boxes that display a list of choices that users can select from. You can also add buttons to a textbox that will allow you to clear entered data, search for entries in a list, filter a list, or run some customized javascript code or action.</description>
    <!--list:.-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>See also the [TextBox Properties] section of the documentation for information on TextBox settings. 
            If you are creating a component with a Form View control see also the pre-defined [Editor-Textbox] control under the
            'Defined Controls' menu on the UX Controls page.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>In-control Buttons for Textbox Control</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Textbox controls can have "in-control" buttons and icons. This is a very common pattern seen in mobile applications, but it is also quite useful in desktop web applications.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/1Yh71ympoQiBoATwQKsUZo?</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Customizing The Date Picker and Edit-Combo Behavior on a Phone</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The UX component allows you to customize the behavior of certain controls based on the screen size of the device. For example, normally, the 'picker' for a date control, or an edit-combo control opens in a drop-down window, immediately under the control.</p>
                    <p>However, on a phone, which has a narrow screen, there is not enough room to display the control's 'picker' in a dropdown window. Instead, you are likely to want the control to appear in a window that is docked to the bottom of the screen, centered horizontally.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you can define Javascript to override the behavior of certain controls, depending on the screen size.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2013-11-28</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/RnasgfaCmavLYvXknWRZtZ</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Google Address Auto-complete</title>
                <description>
                    <p>Address auto-complete is a common feature in may web and mobile applications. Address auto-complete is where you provide suggestions for an address as the user types an location into a textbox. Google Maps provides an API that can be used to generate a suggestion list, which has been integrated into the Alpha Anywhere textbox control.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to enable the Address Suggest feature for a textbox in a UX component.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2016-09-16</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/yhCaSZJ5VkB9urV5ZjFqAx</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>

    <links>
        <link link="ux component textbox properties">TextBox Properties</link>
        <link link="ux defined controls editor textbox">Editor-Textbox</link>
    </links>
</page>