<page>
    <shortlink>ux list definition panel navigator</shortlink>
    <topic>List definition</topic>
    <description>Defines the list of items to display Only available if the *[link:Navigator type@ux panel navigator type]* for the Panel Navigator is set to *[ui:List]*.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:List definition]* property defines the items that appear in the List shown for navigating the Panel Navigator. The List can be defined as a tree structure, allowing you to specify a cascading List to navigate the application. Selecting a 'leaf' item in the List navigates to the corresponding Panel defined in the *[ui:Target Panel]* property for the leaf.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/listTreeGenie.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Branch Properties</title>
            <description>Branch items can be configured using the following properties:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Item</name>
                    <description>The text shown in the List or button collection for the Branch item.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Icon</name>
                    <description>The Icon shown for the Branch item.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Child list style</name>
                    <description>Specify the style for the child list. You can use either a List or a collection of buttons. when you use the 'buttons' option, you can group the buttons into categories and put arbitrary HTML text between buttons.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Security Groups</name>
                    <description>Select which security groups can see this the Branch item. If no groups are selected, all users can see the object.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Server-side Show/hide expression</name>
                    <description>Specify an expression to determine if the Branch item should be shown. Session variables may be used in the expression. The item is shown if the expression is blank or evaluates to *[xb:.t.]*. If the expression cannot be evaluated or evaluates to *[xb:.f.]*, ,the Branch item is not shown.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Leaf Properties</title>
            <description>Leaf items can be configured using the following properties:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Item type</name>
                    <description>Specify if the item is a List item, which can be clicked to navigate to a Panel, or a heading. Options are *[ui:Item]* or *[ui:Heading]*.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Item</name>
                    <description>The text shown in the List or button collection for the Leaf item. Available only if the *[ui:Item type]* is set to "Item".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Icon</name>
                    <description>The Icon shown for the Leaf item. Available only if the *[ui:Item type]* is set to "Item".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Target Panel</name>
                    <description>Specifies the Panel that should be shown when the Leaf item is clicked. Available only if the *[ui:Item type]* is set to "Item".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Heading text</name>
                    <description>Text to display in the heading. Available only if the *[ui:Item type]* is set to "Heading".</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Security Groups</name>
                    <description>Select which security groups can see this the Leaf item. If no groups are selected, all users can see the object.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Server-side Show/hide expression</name>
                    <description>Specify an expression to determine if the Leaf item should be shown. Session variables may be used in the expression. The item is shown if the expression is blank or evaluates to *[xb:.t.]*. If the expression cannot be evaluated or evaluates to *[xb:.f.]*, ,the Leaf item is not shown.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>List Properties</title>
            <description>
                <p>The List can be displayed as a list of buttons or a List. To set how the List options are displayed, click *[ui:Set List Properties...]* and select from the list of options.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Panel Navigator List configured to display as buttons.</title>
                <link>images/listButtons.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>The Panel Navigator List configured to display as a List.</title>
                <link>images/listList.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>