<page>
    <shortlink>ux tab buttons panel navigator</shortlink>
    <topic>Tab buttons</topic>
    <description>Specify the buttons that, when clicked, will navigate to specific Panels in the Panel Navigator.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Tab buttons]* property is used to define a button that shows a Panel in the Panel Navigator when the button is clicked.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Tab Buttons</title>
            <description>Tab buttons are defined using the *[ui:Navigator Tab Buttons]* genie. For each Panel in the Panel Navigator, the ID of the button that, when pressed, gives focus to a Panel must be defined. :</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] smart field button to open the *[ui:Navigator Tab Buttons]* genie.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:Add Button Controller]* to assign a Button to a Panel.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/tabButtons1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the Button and the Panel that will be shown when the button is clicked and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/tabButtons2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If a button or panel for a button controller definition is missing, a red dot will appear next to the button ID. If a button does not use Advanced Button Styling, which is recommended for Button controls that will be used as tab buttons, a blue dot will appear next to the button ID in the *[ui:Navigator Tab Buttons]* dialog. Use the *[ui:Delete Button Controller]* or *[ui:Edit Button Controller]* buttons to remove or update the selected button controller.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <description>
                <p>If no Button controls are defined in the UX Component, you may see the following error message when you click the [...] smart field button to open the *[ui:Navigator Tab Buttons]* genie to define a tab button. To resolve this, add a Button control to the UX Component. Then, click the *[ui:Tab buttons]* [...] button to define a tab button.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/tabButtonsErr.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
</page>