<page>
   <topic>{dialog.object}.deleteRecord Method</topic>

   <description>Applies only to a component that has been bound to one or more tables.</description>
  
   <syntax>{dialog.object}.deleteRecord();</syntax>
  
 
 
  <discussion>Applies only to a component that has been bound to one or more tables. Deletes the current record in the 'primary' table. (If the component is bound to a single table, the 'primary' table is the table to which the component is bound. However, if the component is bound to multiple (linked) tables, the 'primary' table is the top-most parent table of the linked tables.) 
IMPORTANT: This action can only be used if you have loaded primary keys for the primary table. You can load primary keys using the 'Get Primary Keys for Parent Table' server-side action in the onDialogInitialize event, or in an Ajax callback, using the 'Get Primary Key values for Records in a Query' action in Action Javascript. 

After the record is deleted, focus will move to the next record in the primary key list that has been loaded. 

A confirmation dialog will be displayed before the callback is made. 

An optional JSON object can be passed in. This object can have these properties:
nextRecordToShow - if blank, then the next record in the keylist is shown. if 'newrecord', the new record is shown
confirmation - true/false - controls if the confirmation dialog is shown
serverSideCanDeleteFunction - name of the Xbasic function to call before the delete is executed 
serverSideAfterDeleteFunction - name of the Xbasic function to call after the delete is executed </discussion>
  
  <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord();]]></example>
  
  <sections>
    <section>
      <title>Example</title>
      <description>To give focus to a new record (not the next record in the key list) after the delete:</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord({nextRecordToShow :'newrecord'});
]]></example>
      
      
    </section>
    <section>
      
      <description>To delete without displaying the confirmation dialog:</description>
      <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.deleteRecord({confirmation: false});
]]></example>
      
      
    </section>
  </sections>
  
  
   <see>
      <ref>{dialog.object}</ref>
   </see>

<terms>ux component,ajax,components,confirmation,control,delete,function,list,load primary keys,move,new record,object,primary key,record,xbasic</terms>


</page> 
