<page api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 d date calendar abbreviated templates namespace</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.d.date.calendar.abbreviated" parentType="namespace" elementName="templates Namespace" >A5.d.date.calendar.abbreviated.templates Namespace</topic>
	<description> Templates to use in abbreviated calendar dates. Used by *[link:Date.toCalendar]*.</description>
	<properties>
		<property>
			<name>last</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that was within the last week. The calendar date is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "last {data}".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>yesterday</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that was yesterday. The time is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "yesterday {data}".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>today</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that is also today. The time is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "today {data}".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>tomorrow</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that will be tomorrow. The time is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "tomorrow {data}".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>next</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that is within the next week. The calendar date is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "next {data}".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>weekFrom</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when referring to a calendar date that is within the week following the next week. This can be blanked out (set to "") in order to not be used. The calendar date is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "week from {data}".</description>
		</property>
	</properties>
	<note> Any properties in this namespace can be replaced in order to support other languages or formats.</note>
	<!--list:.-->
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/d_namespace/date_namespace/calendar_namespace/abbreviated_namespace/templates_namespace/index.xml</annotations>
</page>
