<page build="0">
    <shortlink>wpcp customizecolumns</shortlink>
    <topic>Customizing Columns Shown in the Project Control Panel</topic>
    <description>
        <p>If components or a5w pages contain comments and descriptions, you can display these in the Web Projects Control Panel by customizing the columns shown.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The columns shown in the Web Projects Control panel can be customized using the *[ui:Customize the columns shown in the Web Control Panel]* tool found in the *[ui:More...]* menu.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Projects Control Panel More menu</title>
                <alt>The Web Projects Control Panel More menu</alt>
                <link>images/CustomizeWebControlPanelMenu.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can customize column widths and additional columns to display in the Web Projects Control Panel in the *[ui:Customize Web Control Panel]* dialog. The "Headings" option in the left-hand column is the general settings for the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
                <p>You can define column widths using the *[code:{width=x}]* prefix before the column name. For example, to specify the width of the Comments column as 4 inches:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[{width=4}Comments]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>Changes to the columns are applied the next time you launch Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/CustomizeWebControlPanel.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section build="7888">
            <title>Adding Comments and Descriptions to A5W pages</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can use the HTML markup shown below to add a comment or description to an A5W page. The comment and description will be shown on the Web Projects Control Panel in the Comment and Description columns.</p>
                <p>To add a comment or description to an A5W page, open the A5W page in the HTML editor. Then, on the source tab, add your comment and description using the markup shown below:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[<!-- comment -- this is the comment -->
<!-- description -- this is the description -->]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>If the Comments and Description columns are not already shown in the Web Projects Control Panel, you will need to add them using the *[ui:]* tool under the More menu. You must restart Alpha Anywhere for the column changes to take effect.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>