<page>
    <shortlink>Web Project Profile Properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Web Project Profile Properties</topic>
    <description>A Web Project Profile is used to publish the web application to the local webroot, a remote server or computer on a local area network (LAN), or to an IIS server. The properties you can configure in a Web Project Profile are listed below.</description>
    <discussion>This article lists all properties for all Web Project Profile publishing types. Some properties may not be available for the Web Project Profile you create. For example, a profile with a Publishing Type of *[ui:Publish Locally]* will have very few options available. Similarly, settings for configuring an IIS publishing profile will not be available for FTP or HTTP publishing types.</discussion>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>General</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Name</title>
                            <description>The name of the Web Project Profile.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publishing Type</title>
                            <description>The Web Project Profile publishing type.</description>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                   <name-title>Publishing Type</name-title>
                                   <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Publish Locally</name>
                                    <description>Select this option to publish your project to the Application Server that is running on the local computer.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Publish on LAN</name>
                                    <description>Select this option to publish your project to another computer on your local area network. The target computer must be running the Application Server. *[Note]*: You can also use this option to publish to a computer on a different network as long as that network is accessible through Windows file sharing.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Publish via FTP</name>
                                    <description>Select this option to publish your files using FTP. While most commonly used to publish to an Application Server at a remote location (e.g. your ISP), this option can also be used to publish to a local computer if an FTP server has already been configured on the target computer.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Publish via HTTP</name>
                                    <description>Select this option to publish your files using HTTP. While most commonly used to publish to an Application Server a ta remote location (e.g. your Web Server), this option can also be used to publish to a local computer if the target server has been configured for HTTP publish. [Watch videos explaining the HTTP option].</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Publish to IIS</name>
                                    <description>Select this option to publish your files directly to IIS.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">FTP Program</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify if you want to use the built-in Alpha Five FTP feature to publish your files, if you always want to use an external FTP program, or if you want to be prompted at publish time.</p>
                                <p>If you use the built-in FTP program, you can specify the 'Optimize' option which will zip all of the files to be published into a single file, then unpack the zip file on the server. This can be substantially faster than publishing individual files.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">FTP Publish with CURL</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify if you want to use the built-in Alpha Five FTP feature using CURL to publish your files. CURL FTP uses passive mode by default and has additional error checking and may be considerably slower that the regular internal FTP.</p>
                                <p>If the FTP upload portion of publishing does not run to completion using the regular internal FTP (which does not support passive mode), this option can be selected to use passive mode for the upload.  It is recommended that 'InternalOptimized' is used with this option.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">FTP CURL Use Active Mode</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify if you want to use the Active Mode using CURL to publish your files (the default for CURL is passive mode).</p>
                                <p>Some FTP servers will not accept FTP uploads using passive mode.  Try this option if the default passive mode does not upload correctly.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">FTP Warning</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The internal FTP does not support passive mode transfers.</p>
                                <p>This may cause problems with some firewalls and routers. If the FTP upload portion of publishing does not run to completion, try using an external FTP client.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Application Variables</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify application variables. These variables can be seen when any .a5w page is executing.</p> 
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Aliases</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Specify aliases for the paths to your data files and your connection strings. Aliases make your Web application portable, allowing it to function correctly when published to another server.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Named AlphaDAO connection strings</title>
                            <description>For each profile, you can specify what ADO connection string to use for each named connection string that you have defined.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Named Storage connection strings</title>
                            <description>For each profile, you can specify values for any named resource providers. If you don't specify values, the named resource provider keys resolve to their design-time values.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Web Socket Settings</title>
                            <description>For each profile, you can specify values for any named resource providers. If you don't specify values, the named resource provider keys resolve to their design-time values.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Lock Publish</title>
                            <description>The profile can be locked to prevent publishing using this property (useful to prevent accidental publishing to a production application). At publish time, if you select a locked profile, a warning message will be shown. If the 'Locked with password' option is selected, you will be prompted for a password before publishing can continue.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Lock Publish Password</title>
                            <description>Enter a password to unlock this profile at publish to allow the publish to continue.  The password is case sensitive.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2"></title>
                            <description></description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2"></title>
                            <description></description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2"></title>
                            <description></description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2"></title>
                            <description></description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Folder in Webroot</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Target Folder</title>
                            <description>Specify the folder within the webroot where the project will be published. Leave this setting blank to publish directly in the webroot folder. Specify <![CDATA[<Default>]]> to publish to a folder called Workspace name\Project in the webroot.</description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Publish using FTP</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">FTP Address</title>
                            <description>Specify the address of the FTP site.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Username</title>
                            <description>Specify the user name to log into the FTP site.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Password</title>
                            <description>Specify the password to log into the FTP site.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Folder</title>
                            <description>Specify the folder where the files should be published. If this setting is blank, files are published to the FTP root folder.</description>
                            <note>The path entered must be relative to the FTP root folder, which may not be a webroot folder.</note>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Publish using HTTP</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Server URL</title>
                            <description>Specify the host name of the target web server. e.g. http://www.mydomain.com, or http://serverMachine (where 'serverMachine' is the network name of the server computer).</description>
                            <note>
                                <p>If the web server uses a port other than 80 (HTTP) or 443 (HTTPS), the port number must be included as part of the URL.</p>
                                <p>Example: http://localhost:8080 if using port 8080.</p>
                            </note>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Username</title>
                            <description>Specify the user name in log into the HTTP publish system.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Password</title>
                            <description>Specify the password to log into the HTTP publish system.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Target Folder</title>
                            <description>Specify the folder within the webroot where the project will be published. Leave this setting blank to publish directly in webroot folder.</description>
                            <note>The HTTP Publish settings for this user may only allow publishing to specified folders. The selection form may show a dropdown list of allowed target folders, and a folder must be selected from the list.</note>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Publish to IIS</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publishing Subtype</title>
                            <description>Publish directly to an IIS server.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Site Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the site name. This is an internal name to identify the site in IIS. The site name cannot contain the following characters <![CDATA[\/?;:@&=+$,|"<>]]>*</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Application Name</title>
                            <description>The application name within the IIS site. This is optional. Leave empty to publish as the root application for the site. The root application is what will be used when no path is specified with the host name. e.g. http://www.alphasoftware.com/. When an application name is used the application is accessed with the host name and a path with the application name. e.g. http://www.alphasoftware.com/MyApplicationName/. The application name cannot contain the following characters <![CDATA[\/?;:@&=+$,|"<>]]>*</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use Custom Physical Path</title>
                            <description>Manually set the destination folder for published files when publishing directly to an IIS server.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Physical Path</title>
                            <description>Enter the destination folder for published files when publishing directly to an IIS server.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Show error detail in remote responses</title>
                            <description>Allow detailed error messages to be returned in error pages. This should only be used for testing or for a limited time since potentially sensitive information could be included in the detailed error messages.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Preserve web.config elements</title>
                            <description>Enter web.config elements to be preserved that are not configured through project or publish settings.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Application Pool Type</title>
                            <description>Select the type of application pool to use.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Application Pool Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the name of the application pool to be used by this web application. If it does not exist it will be created.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Application Pool Processes</title>
                            <description>The default value of 5 makes the server more responsive under load. The value should be no less than 5 if the web application uses PDF printing to allow handling of multiple simultaneous PDF report requests.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Location of Alpha Anywhere Application Server</title>
                            <description>Select the location of the Alpha Anywhere application server. Default means the application server was installed in the default location "c:\Program Files (x86)\A5V12 Application Server for IIS". Build number means a specific version of the application server was installed separate from the default installation. An additional prompt for the build number will be made. Custom means the application server was installed in a non default location. Contact your server administrator for that location.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build Number of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server</title>
                            <description>Enter the build number of the Alpha Anywhere Application Server installation</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Path to Alpha Anywhere Application Server</title>
                            <description>Enter the full path to the Alpha Anywhere Application Server installation</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Folder</title>
                            <description>Specify the folder and file name for the IIS web deployment package. Ex: c:\temp\deploymentPackage.zip</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">IIS Management Service URL</title>
                            <description>This is the URL the IIS server's Web Deploy Management Service. If the IIS server's Web Deploy Management Service is a default install you should only need to enter the host name. Ex: www.mysite.com. This will result in the default URL of https://www.mysite.com:8172/MsDeploy.axd being used. If the IIS server's Web Deploy Management Service is not a default install you will need to enter the entire URL. Ex: https://www.mysite.com:9283/MsDeploy.axd.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use Integrated Windows Authentication</title>
                            <description>Select this option if your current credentials have local administrator privileges on the IIS Server and your current credentials have permission to publish to the IIS Server.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Username</title>
                            <description>Specify the user name for the IIS Manager user.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Password</title>
                            <description>Specify the password for the IIS Manager user.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Password Confirm</title>
                            <description>Re-enter the password for the IIS Manager user.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Ignore HTTPS Certificate Errors</title>
                            <description>Normally production environments require valid server certificates and you would only use this option when working in a development environment.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Log Path</title>
                            <description>This is the path where log files will be stored. Ensure the user that the IIS web application runs as has read/write access to this folder.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Enable Xbasic Logging</title>
                            <description>Select this to enable Xbasic logging.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Enable Grid Caching</title>
                            <description>Select this to enable grid caching.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Grid Cache Path</title>
                            <description>This is the path to the grid cache. Ensure the user that the IIS web application runs as has read/write access to this folder.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Grid Cache Size (MB)</title>
                            <description>This is the size in megabytes of the grid cache.</description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Publish Workspace/Database Files</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publish data files</title>
                            <description>Specify if Workspace or Database files should be copied to a folder on the server. In the case of Alpha Anywhere tables, these files include .dbf, .fpt, .cdx .ddd, .ddm, .ddx, .set, .sem and .sex files. In the case of Microsoft Access, this is the .mdb file.)</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Files to publish</title>
                            <description>Specify the list of Workspace files to publish.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Folder</title>
                            <description>Specify the physical folder on the server computer where datafiles should be copied. If publishing to a FTP site, specify the name of the folder within the FTP root.</description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Open Page after Publish</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Base URL</title>
                            <description>Specify the host name of the target web server. e.g. http://www.mydomain.com, or http://serverMachine (where 'serverMachine' is the network name of the server computer).</description>
                            <note>This need only be supplied if you want to open a page on the target server after publishing pages.</note>
                            <note>
                                <p>The URL should include the directory that includes the project default page. The URL should not have a trailing slash.</p>
                                <p>*[Correct]*: http://www.mydomain.com</p>
                                <p>*[Incorrect]*: http://www.mydomain.com/</p>
                            </note>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Server Port</title>
                            <description>Specify the port that the Application Server is using.</description>
                            <note>This need only be supplied if you want to open a page on the target server after publishing pages.</note>
                            <note>If the Base URL property includes a server port, then this setting is ignored.</note>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default Page</title>
                            <description>This is the default (main) page of the project</description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Right Click Publish</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publish New or Modified Files Only</title>
                            <description>Check this option to check the publish history when publishing from the right click menu on the Web Projects Control Panel. Unchecking this option will publish files even if they have been previously published.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publish Support Files</title>
                            <description>Support files are CSS style sheet files, images, and JavaScript files that are used by components and pages. Check this option to always include any support files for the selected file when publishing from the right click menu on the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publish Selected Only</title>
                            <warning>ONLY FOR ADVANCED USERS</warning>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>Check this option to ONLY publish the selected file or files. Normal publishing automatically adds files such as embedded or linked components, support files such as images, CSS and JavaScript files, and other files such as system files for Ajax support to the list of selected files to publish. Selecting this option will not add these files to the list for publishing. A few required system files will still be added.</p>
                                <p>Used incorrectly this may break the application as some required files may not have been previously published or they may have been modified since the last publish.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use Right Click Publish in Builders</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Check this option to use the settings for the 'Right Click Publish' when publishing from the component builders and the HTML editor.</p>
                                <p>The default publish settings for the component builders and the HTML editor check the publish history when publishing and include all support files in the publish process.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Check Security Status before Publish</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Check this option to verify the selected pages, components, or reports have security permission set before publishing.</p>
                                <p>The security status will only be checked for pages, components, and reports in the publish list.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Miscellaneous</title>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Publish Workspace Library' flag</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If your project includes SQL Reports, it is necessary to publish the 'Workspace Library' files when you publish your application.</p>
                                <p>The Publish dialog has a checkbox that allows you to publish these files.  You can specify a default value for this checkbox.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Publish New or Modified Files' flag</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>This option will set the default value for the option 'Publish new or modified files only'. If the option is not checked when publishing, files are published even if they have been previously published.</p>
                                <p>You can specify a default value for this checkbox.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Publish Support Files' flag</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>Support files are CSS style sheet files, images, and JavaScript files that are used by components and pages.</p>
                                <p>The Publish dialog has a checkbox to include these files when publishing. You can specify a default value for this checkbox.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Publish Selected Only' flag</title>
                            <warning>ONLY FOR ADVANCED USERS</warning>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <description>
                                <p>The Publish dialog has a checkbox for this option. Selecting this option will ONLY publish the selected file or files. Normal publishing automatically adds files such as embedded or linked components, support files such as images, CSS and JavaScript files, and other files such as system files for Ajax support to the list of selected files to publish. Selecting this option will not add these files to the list for publishing. A few required system files will still be added.</p>
                                <p>Used incorrectly this may break the application as some required files may not have been previously published or they may have been modified since the last publish.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Check Security Before Publish' flag</title>
                            <description>This option will check if all elements in the publish have a security permission set.  Selecting this option will show a list of pages, components, and reports in the publish that do not have any security set and are therfore 'Not Allowed' by the web security.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Default for 'Compile functions into an .AEX file' flag</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If any of your components contain Xbasic event handlers, these event handlers might call 'global' functions that you have defined. 'Global' functions are defined in the 'Code' tab of the main Control Panel. In order to use any of these 'global' functions in your Grid components, they must be compiled into an .AEX file.</p>
                                <p>The Publish dialog has a checkbox to create an .AEX file when publishing. You can specify a default value for this checkbox.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Security Store Type</title>
                            <description>Security Store Type property</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Configure Active Directory</title>
                            <description>Configure active directory server and credentials.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Type</title>
                            <description>Select the provider type to be used for membership data.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Version</title>
                            <description>Select the version of the MySql Connector/NET to be used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the MembershipProvider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Application Name</title>
                            <description>Multiple web applications that require different users and groups can use the same security database. The security application name partitions the security database for those different users and groups. Web applications that use the same users and roles use the same security application name.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Auto Generate Schema</title>
                            <description>This provider type can automatically generate and update the necessary schema on first usage. Select this to allow it to do so.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Connection String Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the name for connection string needed by the membership provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Class Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the assembly-qualified name of a class that implements the MembershipProvider abstract class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Class Parameters</title>
                            <description>Enter parameter names and values needed for the custom membership provider class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use a Different Connection String for Membership Provider Create/Publish</title>
                            <description>A connection string with create/update access neeeds to be used when creating provider database tables and updating membership data. If the connection string used by the provider does not have this access check this and enter a connection string that does have access.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Membership Provider Create/Publish Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the MembershipProvider with access to create and update tables.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Type</title>
                            <description>Select the provider type to be used for role data.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Version</title>
                            <description>Select the version of the provider to be used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the role provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Application Name</title>
                            <description>Multiple web applications that require different users and groups can use the same security database. The security application name partitions the security database for those different users and groups. Web applications that use the same users and roles use the same security application name.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Auto Generate Schema</title>
                            <description>This provider type can automatically generate and update the necessary schema on first usage. Select this to allow it to do so.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Connection String Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the name for connection string needed by the role provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Class Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the assembly-qualified name of a class that implements the RoleProvider abstract class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Class Parameters</title>
                            <description>Enter parameter names and values needed for the custom role provider class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use a Different Connection String for Role Provider Create/Publish</title>
                            <description>A connection string with create/update access neeeds to be used when creating provider database tables and updating role data. If the connection string used by the provider does not have this access check this and enter a connection string that does have access.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Role Provider Create/Publish Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the RoleProvider with access to create and update tables.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Type</title>
                            <description>Select the provider type to be used for session state data.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Type</title>
                            <description>Select the provider type to be used for session state data.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Version</title>
                            <description>Select the version of the provider to be used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the session state provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Auto Generate Schema</title>
                            <description>This provider type can automatically generate and update the necessary schema on first usage. Select this to allow it to do so.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Connection String Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the name for connection string needed by the session state provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Class Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the assembly-qualified name of a class that implements the SessionStateProvider abstract class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Session State Provider Class Parameters</title>
                            <description>Enter parameter names and values needed for the custom session state provider class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">State Server Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the state server.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use a Different Connection String for SessionState Provider Create/Publish</title>
                            <description>A connection string with create/update access neeeds to be used when creating provider database tables for session data. If the connection string used by the provider does not have this access check this and enter a connection string that does have access.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">SessionState Provider Create/Publish Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the SessionStateProvider with access to create and update tables.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Type</title>
                            <description>Select the provider type to be used for profile data.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Version</title>
                            <description>Select the version of the provider to be used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the profile provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Application Name</title>
                            <description>Multiple web applications that require different users and groups can use the same security database. The security application name partitions the security database for those different users and groups. Web applications that use the same users and roles use the same security application name.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Auto Generate Schema</title>
                            <description>This provider type can automatically generate and update the necessary schema on first usage. Select this to allow it to do so.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Connection String Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the name for connection string needed by the profile provider if a connection string is used.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Class Name</title>
                            <description>Enter the assembly-qualified name of a class that implements the ProfileProvider abstract class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Class Parameters</title>
                            <description>Enter parameter names and values needed for the custom profile provider class.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Use a Different Connection String for Profile Provider Create/Publish</title>
                            <description>A connection string with create/update access neeeds to be used when creating provider database tables. If the connection string used by the provider does not have this access check this and enter a connection string that does have access.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Profile Provider Create/Publish Connection String</title>
                            <description>Enter the connection string needed by the ProfileProvider with access to create and update tables.</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Users and Roles Publish Action</title>
                            <description>Select how users and groups are published to security providers</description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Web Security Data Published</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>This option will be checked if the web security users and groups data files have been published.</p>
                                <p>This can be checked by the user to indicate the web security data files have been previously published.  Unchecking the option will indicate the web security data files have NEVER been published.</p>
                                <p>If this is NOT checked, the web security data files can be published without any restrictions, regardless of the selection for 'Restrict Web Security Data Publish'.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Restrict Web Security Data Publish</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>If the security configuration allows a web user to edit security information on line, the user information in the published location will be different than in the local files.  If the web security users and groups data files in this project are re-published, the data in the published location will be completely over-written and ALL changes made to that data will be lost.</p>
                                <p>When this option is checked, re-publishing the web security data files will be prevented after they have been published once for this profile.  A warning message will be displayed if the files are selected for re-publish.  This option must be unchecked in this profile to allow the web security data files to be re-published with this profile.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Auto-Restrict Web Security Data Publish</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>This option will automatically check the 'Restrict Web Security Data Publish' option every time the web security data files are published.  This will help to prevent accidental re-publish of the web security users and groups data.</p>
                                <p>The web security users and groups data in the published location is not the same as the data in this project folder.  If the web security data files in this folder are re-published, the data in the published location will be completely over-written and all changes made by any user activity to the published web security data will be lost.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Publish Page Security Table as Binary</title>
                            <description>
                                <p>The web security 'Pages.Securitysettings' file is normally published as a text file.  If this file is very large, it may be slow to load when security is refreshed in an Application Server.</p>
                                <p>Select this option to publish the file as a binary file, which will load much faster.</p>
                            </description>
                        </case> 
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Appendix</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Appendix A: Publishing using HTTP</title>
                    <description>In order to publish a web application to an Alpha Anywhere server using the HTTP method, you must configure the Alpha Anywhere server to allow HTTP publishing and create a publishing profile that uses the HTTP method. Watch the videos below to learn more:</description>
                    <videos>
                        <video>
                            <name>How to configure your Alpha Anywhere server to allow HTTP Publishing</name>
                            <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/HTTP_Publish_ConfigureServer.swf</link>
                        </video>
                        <video>
                            <name>How to create a publishing profile that uses the HTTP option</name>
                            <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/HTTP_Publish_profile.swf</link>
                        </video>
                    </videos>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_Appendix A: Publishing using HTTP">Watch videos explaining the HTTP option</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=create a publish profile">Publishing to IIS</ref> 
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=alpha cloud alpha anywhere developers guide publishing publishing your application">Alpha Cloud: Publishing Your Application</ref>
    </see>
</page>