<page>
	<topic>A5.ControlBar.showDisclosure Method</topic>
	<prototype>A5.ControlBar.showDisclosure(settings[,element])</prototype>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name>settings</name>
			<type>object</type>
			<description>The disclosure settings.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>name</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>Either the name of a disclosure to show (defined in A5.ControlBar.disclosures), or the name of a layout to dynamically show in the layout disclosure. In order to show a layout, start the string with "layout:". If a layout named "menu" was to be shown, the value would be "layout:menu".</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>type</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The type of disclosure. The values can be "expand-before", "expand-after", "expand-element", "expand-element-cover", "extend", "extend-element", "extend-element-cover", "cover", "outside-before", "outside-after", "screen-left", "screen-right", "screen-top" and "screen-bottom".</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>size</name>
			<type>string:optional</type>
			<description>The size to make the disclosure. Options are a CSS size value (like "300px"), or "fill". A value of "fill" will make the disclosure fill the available area. For an "extend" type this will be to the far side of the screen, for an "expand" type this will be to the far edge of the control bar.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>animation</name>
			<type>boolean|object:optional</type>
			<description>Whether or not to animate the showing of the disclosure. If an object, animation specifics can be set.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>duration</name>
			<type>number:optional</type>
			<description>The number of milliseconds the disclosure should take to animate in or out.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>tween</name>
			<type>string:optional</type>
			<description>The CSS "tween" for the disclosure animation. The default is "ease-in-out".</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>autoHide</name>
			<type>boolean:optional</type>
			<description>Whether or not to automatically close the disclosure when the user clicks/taps off the disclosure.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>className</name>
			<type>string:optional</type>
			<description>Optional override to the class name to place on the disclosure element.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>coverClassName</name>
			<type>string:optional</type>
			<description>Optional override to the class name to place on the element that covers the screen when the disclosure is shown.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>rectangle</name>
			<type>object|function:optional</type>
			<description>For an "explicit" type, either an object that contains the definition of the rectangle on the screen to render the disclosure in, or function that returns a rectangle object that will be called any time the disclosure is resized so that the rectangle can be recalculated.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>left</name>
			<type>number</type>
			<description>The left edge of the clip rectangle in pixels.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>right</name>
			<type>number</type>
			<description>The right edge of the clip rectangle in pixels.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>top</name>
			<type>number</type>
			<description>The top edge of the clip rectangle in pixels.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>bottom number)</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The bottom edge of the clip rectangle in pixels.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>edge</name>
			<type>number</type>
			<description>The edge of the clip rectangle from which to show the disclosure.</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>fill</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>How the disclosure should fill the clip rectangle. Options are "width", "height" and "both".</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>element</name>
			<type>element:optional</type>
			<description>The element to use as reference for "extend" and "expand" types that use elements.</description>
		</argument>
	</arguments>
	<description> Show a disclosure. The "expand" family of types will expand the disclosure over the control bar area. In a horizontal layout "before" is left and "after" is right, in a vertical layout "before" is top and "after" is bottom. The "expand-element" type will expand the disclosure for the optionally passed in element, and "expand-element-cover" will do the same only covering the element. The "extend" family will extend the disclosure away from the "edge" defined in A5.ControlBar.edge. By default "extend" will show the disclosure without occluding the control bar. For instance if the "edge" is "top" then the disclosure will dropdown from the bottom edge of the control bar. The "extend-element" type will extend the disclosure for the optionally passed in element, and "extend-element-cover" will do the same only covering the element. The "cover" type will show the disclosure from the "edge" defined in A5.ControlBar.edge, sized to cover the entire control bar. The "outside" family of types will show the disclosure over the area outside the control bar on the opposite side from the edge of the control bar. The "screen" family of types will show the disclosure from the specified edge of the screen.</description>
	<note> Only a single disclosure may be shown at a time. If A5.ControlBar.showDisclosure is called when a disclosure is already shown, the first disclosure will hide before the second is shown. Since the second disclosure might have been shown by an item on the first disclosure, the element used in showing the second disclosure will be the same as the one used on the first disclosure.</note>
</page>
