<page>
    <shortlink>ux list builder condrowstyle properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Conditional Row Style</topic>
    <description>Conditional styling applied to each row in the list. Styling can be computed using a server-side or client-side expression.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The conditional styling lets you format list data conditionally, depending on its value. For example, you might want to set the background color to red for an overdue invoice or apply different font weights to each record based on a field containing state information.</p>
        <p>Conditional styling can be computed either on the server or the client. If computed on the server, the styling is applied before the List data is sent to the client.</p>
        <p>If computed on the client, the styling is applied after List data has been downloaded to the client.</p>
        <p>Conditional styling is only applied if the condition evaluates to true. A condition can reference one or more values in the List row, as well as summary data (if it is available.)</p>
    </discussion> 
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Server-side computation</title>
            <description>
                <p>A *[ui:Server-side computation]* is done on the server. The condition is specified using Xbasic syntax. To recompute conditional row styling done using a server-side computation, an ajax callback must be made to refresh the List.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Client-side computation</title>
            <description>
                <p>A *[ui:Client-side computation]* is done on the client. Because the computation is made in the client, you do not need to make a callback to the server to re-compute the styling.</p>
                <p>The condition can be specified using either Intermediate Syntax or JavaScript Syntax.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/conditionalrowstyle.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Intermediate syntax</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Intermediate syntax is a special syntax that gets converted into JavaScript. The syntax is similar to Portable SQL Syntax. To use Intermediate syntax, select the *[ui:Intermediate syntax - gets converted to Javascript]* radio button.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case build="5445">
                    <title nested="2">JavaScript syntax</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The alternative to Intermediate syntax is to use JavaScript syntax directly to define the condition. To do this, select the *[ui:Pure Javascript syntax]* radio button.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>