<page>
    <topic>Getting Started With Alpha Anywhere - Build Your First Mobile App</topic>
    <description>Follow this step-by-step guide to your first Alpha Anywhere application to run in a mobile web environment.</description>
    <groups>
        <group background="true">
            <title>Overview</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>In this guide, Getting Started with Alpha Anywhere - Build Your First Mobile App, you will build a mobile application from scratch. You will create the *[ui:MobileAppFramework_Sample_Disconnected_app]* template starting with a blank UX Component. Components are the basic building blocks of any Alpha Anywhere application. For many components in Alpha Anywhere, new components can be created using a template. Templates make building some types of applications faster. You can even create your own templates (watch *[extlink:Grid Templates@http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library/?v=3070]* for more details.)</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The mobile app you are building.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>This Guide is broken into three parts: [First Things First - Setting Up Your Workspace], [Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality], and [Part 2 - Creating the Responsive Mobile Layout].</p>
                        <p>[First Things First] covers creating a new Alpha Anywhere workspace and setting up the data source that will be used in this Guide.</p>
                        <p>[Part 1] shows you how to use the List Genie to create the bare-bones functionality required to do CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations against a data source.</p>
                        <p>[Part 2] details how to add the layout elements and navigation controls for creating a responsive mobile layout that will look great on smartphones and tablets.</p>
                        <p>At the beginning of each lesson, a component may be available for download. The downloadable component contains a snapshot of the mobile app as it would look if you had built the component following the previous lessons. Not all lessons will have a component for download. Specifically, [Part 1] does not have component downloads since this section is a step-by-step guild through setting up the *[ui:List Contol - Quick Setup Genie]*, which cannot be saved mid-setup.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>The components available for download in each lesson *[require a connection string to the Northwind database]*. Follow the instructions in [Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String] to learn how to setup the Northwind database on your system and create the "Northwind" connection string that the List control requires for communicating with the Northwind database.</p>
                        <p>[NoConnectionString]</p>
                    </note>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>First Things First - Setting Up Your Workspace</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 1: Create a new Web Project</title>
                    <description>
                        To create a new mobile application with Alpha Anywhere, you must create a new workspace. A workspace contains all of the files that your application needs, including files such as UX components, javascript libraries, images, HTML or .a5w pages, or css stylesheets. Let's create a new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Launch Alpha Anywhere. Under the *[ui:File]* menu, select *[ui:New Workspace...]* to create a new Alpha Anywhere project.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Create a New Workspace from the File menu.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Create a new directory called "HelloAlpha". This directory is where you will save your project.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Create a new directory where your workspace will be saved.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Navigate inside the "HelloAlpha" directory. Type "HelloAlpha" into the *[ui:File name:]* text box. Click the *[ui:Save]* button to create your new workspace.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Naming your workspace.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When the *[ui:Startup Control Panel]* appears, check the box for *[ui:Open the Web Control Panel when this Workspace is opened.]* You will be creating a mobile application. The Web Control Panel is where all of the resources for a web or mobile application are listed. Click *[ui:OK]* to finish creating your new workspace.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Specifying the Web Control Panel should be opened when the Workspace is opened.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You have created a new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace. You can now start building your mobile application.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String</title>
                    <description>The mobile application you will be creating will interact with the Northwind database. A Microsoft Access version of the Northwind database ships with Alpha Anywhere. If you prefer to use a different database system, you can follow the instructions below to setup the Northwind database in SQL Server or MySQL. Choose one of the options below -- Acces, SQL Server, or MySQL -- to start creating a Connection String for the Northwind database.</description>
                    <cases>
                        <case><description>[Build an Access Connection String]</description></case>
                        <case><description>[Build a SQL Server Connection String]</description></case>
                        <case><description>[Build a MySQL Connection String]</description></case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build an Access Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guildes you through the process of setting up an Access connection string to the Northwind database. In order to perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the Access Northwind database that ships with Alpha Anywhere, it must be copied from the installation directory to a directory in which you have read/write access. This is typically the Users directory.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Locate the *[Northwind.mdb]* Access database. It can be found in the installation directory for Alpha Anywhere inside the MDBFiles directory. EG, *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\a5v12\MDBFiles\]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The MDBFiles folder in the Alpha Anyhwere installation directory is where you can find the Northwind Access database</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring0.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Select the *[Northwind.mdb]* file and copy the file to a directory in your Users directory. Your Users directory is typically located in *[bold:C:\Users\Your_Windows_UserName]*.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]* <![CDATA[>]]> *[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connecton string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind Access database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>The Connection Type for your new connection string is "Access" and should be selected by default for new connection strings when the Create SQL Connection String dialog is opened.</p>
                                        <p>For the *[ui:File Name]* option in the Create SQL Connection String dialog, navigate to where you copied the Northwind database and select the database.</p>
                                    </description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Select the Northwind database you copied to the Users directory.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind database is correct by clicking the "Test Connection" button. If everything is configured properly, it will display the "Success!" message.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The connection string works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <note>On some systems where Office 365 is installed, you may receive a *[Can't Load ODBCJI32.dll Error]* message. To fix this error, you will need to install the Microsoft Access Database Engine. You can download the Microsoft Access Database Engine Installer *[extlink:here@https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=13255]*. If the Microsoft Access Database Engine is already installed, running a 'Repair' on the engine should fix the issue.</note>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the Access connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The connection string dialog listing the Northwind connection</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the Northwind connection string and return to the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title></title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring8.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created a connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your mobile application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality] to start building your mobile application.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title></title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring9.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build a SQL Server Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guides you through the process of creating a SQL Server version of the Northwind database and setting up a Server connection string to communicate with the SQL Server Northwind database.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Follow the tutorial, [Importing the Northwind Access Database into SQL Server], to create a Northwind SQL Server database. When you are finished, return to this guide and proceed to the next step.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind SQL Server database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]* <![CDATA[>]]> *[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connecton string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind SQL Server database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>The *[ui:Connection Type]* defaults to "Access". However, you are building a connection string for a SQL Server database. Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[SQLServer]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Select SQLServer to change the Connection Type.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>Enter the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]* name, *[ui:Port]*, and *[ui:Credentials]* information for your SQL Server instance.</p>
                                        <p>Server names should be in the form *[server\instanceName]*. If you omit the instance name, the default instance is assumed.</p>
                                        <p>You can click the *[ui:How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?]* to open the help popup (shown below) to find more information on the server name.</p>
                                    </description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Help popup for "How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?"</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Test the connection by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. You should see a success message. If you receive an error message, verify the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]*, *[ui:Port]* and *[ui:Credentials]* are correct.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The SQL Server connection works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:Refresh]* button to populate the *[ui:Database]* dropdown box. Select the *[Northwind]* from the list of options. Click *[ui:OK]* to create the SQL Server connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Configuring SQL Server connection string. This is image shows a configuration for connecting to a SQL Server Express instance. The Northwind database in this SQL Server instance is named "northwindSQLServer".</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created a connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your mobile application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality] to start building your mobile application.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Northwind connection string for SQL Server.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build a MySQL Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guides you through creating a MySQL version of the Northwind database and setting up a connection string to communicate with the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Download *[extlink:northwindmysql.zip@http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v12Download/northwindmysql.zip]* and unzip the file. This zip file contains a self-contained file of the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Contents of the northwindysql.zip archive.</title>
                                        <link>images/northwindMySQL.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Import the self-contained Northwind database into MySQL. You can find instructions *[extlink:here@https://dev.mysql.com/doc/workbench/en/wb-admin-export-import-management.html#wb-mysql-connections-navigator-management-data-import-restore]* for using MySQL Workbench to Import the database. Use the "Import from Self-Contained File" option for the Data Import.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Doing a Data Import using MySQL Workbench</title>
                                        <link>images/mySQLDataRestore.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <note>*[Backup any existing MySQL databases]* before importing the Northwind database.</note>
                                    <warning>*[There is no schema specified in the northwindmysql.sql file.]* You must specify the target schema, otherwise the tables will be imported into the active schema. *[This may result in data being overwritten]* if the active schema contains table names matching tables in the Northwind database!</warning>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind MySQL dataase by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]* <![CDATA[>]]> *[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connecton string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to construct the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind MySQL database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>The *[ui:Connection Type]* defaults to "Access". However, you are building a connection string for a MySQL database. Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[MySQL]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Select MySQL to change the Connection Type.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Creat SQL Connection String dialog Options for a "MySQL" Connection Type.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, you must configure the *[ui:Options]* for the connection. For *[ui:Hostname]*, enter "localhost".</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter *[ui:Port]* number. If you used the default port number for your MySQL install, the port should be "3306".</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter the *[ui:User]* for accesing the MySQL database. On your development machine, this can be "root" or a user account you create.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter the password for the *[ui:User]* account you specified.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind datbase is correct by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. If everything is configured properly, it will display the "Succeeded" message. If you do not get a "Succeeded" message, verify taht the Hostname, Port, user, and Password are correct.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The connection string to the MySQL database works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Select the Northwind database from the *[ui:Database]* list. If *[ui:Database]* does not have any options, click the *[ui:Refresh]* button. If it still does not list any databases, verify the User you have chosen has access to the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Selecting the Northwind database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the MySQL connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the MySQL Connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created a connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your mobile application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality] to start building your mobile application.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Northwind connection string for MySQL</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>In Alpha Anywhere, there are two approaches you can use to build your application: Layout First or Functionality First.</p>
                        <p>The Layout First approach involves building the shell of the application's layout, adding all the navigation buttons and layout elements with temporary data or placeholder methods, if they are needed. Once the shell looks like the end product, the CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) features are built and hooked into the interface.</p>
                        <p>Functionality First approach focuses on getting CRUD features working with a rudimentary interface. After this core functionality is built, the interface is added, including creating any additional navigation necessary for using the app in a mobile environment.</p>
                        <p>You will use a *[Functionality First]* approach in this guide. You will create a *[List control]* with a *[Detail View]* for editing data and *[Search Part]* for retrieving the records of interest from the data source. The List control is the core building block of any Alpha Anywhere mobile app. It handles displaying records from a database and tracking any changes to that data. The Detail View is an interface for creating, editing, and deleting records in a List control. The Search Part is used to select the records of interest from the data source that will populate the List control.</p>
                        <p>By the end of Part 1, you will have a fully functional app that could be deployed as a web application, shown in the image below.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality</title>
                        <link>images/newlist8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 1: Adding a New UX Component to the Web Project</title>

                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add a new UX Component to your project by clicking the *[ui:[FileNew]New]* button in the Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Web Projects Control Panel toolbar.</title>
                                <link>images/newFile1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the New File dialog, select *[ui:Web Component]* and click the *[ui:Next >]* button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The New File dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/newux1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[ui:UX]* from the components listed and click *[ui:Next >]*. This will create a new UX Component.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the type of component to create.</title>
                                <link>images/newux2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>A number of templates for the UX Component are available. These templates make building some types of applications faster. You will be creating a blank UX Component to start. Select *[ui:Start with a blank UX Component]* option and click *[ui:OK]*. This creates a new, blank UX Component.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select UX Component Template</title>
                                <link>images/newux3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The UX Builder</title>
                                <link>images/newux4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Finally, save your new component by clicking the *[ui:[FileSave]Save]* button on the toolbar at the top of the screen.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Save Your UX Component</title>
                                <link>images/newux5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Next, you will start adding controls to the UX Component, creating the core controls needed to view, add, and modify data in the the Northwind database.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 2: Adding a New List Control</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 1 Lesson 2]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>The List Control is one of the core building blocks in most mobile applications. Using the *[ui:[ListGenie]List Control - Quick Setup Genie]*, you will create a List with a Detail View and Search part for interacting with the Customers table in the Northwind database.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>The interface for the UX Component is designed on the *[ui:[UXControls] Controls]* pane. Insert a new List control into the UX Component by clicking *[ui:[ListCtrl] [List]]*</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Insert a new List Control</title>
                                <link>images/newlist0.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When a control is inserted into the component, Alpha Anywhere presents you with the option to insert multiple controls at once. The application you are building only needs one List control. If it is not selected, choose *[ui:Create a new Single Control]* and enter a *[ui:Name]* for your List. Once you have given the List a name, click the *[ui:[ListGenie]List Control - Quick Setup Genie]* button at the bottom of the *[ui:New Control]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Create a new List Control</title>
                                <link>images/newlist1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 3: Connecting the List to a Database</title>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, you will configure your List control to connect to the Northwind database using the connection string created earlier (See [Build a Database Connection String].) Select the [...] button for *[ui:Connection string]* to open the *[ui:Connection String]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The List Control - Quick Setup Genie.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Connection String]* dialog, select *[ui:Use a named connection string]*. Open the list of named connection strings by clicking the *[ui:Select...]* button. </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting a named connection in the Connection Strng dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/selectConnStr1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[[db]Northwind]* connection string from the list and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting Northwind from the AlphaDAO Connection Strings dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/selectConnStr2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Now that the *[ui:Connection string]* is configured, you can setup the *[ui:Table name]* and *[ui:Fields list]* for the List control.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Connection string is now configured in the List Control - Quick Setup Genie.</title>
                                <link>images/selectConnStr4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the [...] button for the *[ui:Table name]* property to choose the table that will be used to populate the data in the List control. Choose the *[[tbl]Customers]* table from the Northwind database.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select the Customers table.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Next, configure the *[ui:Field list]* property. The *[ui:Field list]* property determines what fields will be available for displaying, searching, and editing in the List. If you plan on editing table data, you must select the table's ID field must be included in the *[ui:Selected Fields]*. The ID field for the Customers table is *[CustomerID]*.</p>
                                <p>Select the *[CustomerID]*, *[CompanyName]*, *[Address]*, *[City]*, and *[Country]* fields from the Customers table and click *[ui:OK]*.</p></description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Fields that will be available in the List control to view and modify.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The *[ui:List Data Source Definition]* completely configured to work with the Customers table in the Northwind database.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 4: Setting Up the Detail View</title>
                    <description>Next, you will configure the List control's Detail View. The Detail View is used for editing or adding data to the Customers table in the Northwind database.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Check the *[ui:Has Detail View]* box to add a Detail View to the List control.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add a Detail View to the List control.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist_dv1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>That's it! Now we'll add a Search part to the List Control so you can search the Customers table for specific records.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 5: Adding a Search Part</title>
                    <description>Now, you will add a *[ui:Search Part]* to your List control.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Search Part]* Properties section, click the checkbox for *[ui:Has Search Part]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a *[ui:Search Part]* to the List control.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist_s1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>You will be creating a Keyword search part. For the *[ui:Search Part type]* property, click the [...] button and select *[ui:SingleKeywordControl]* in the *[ui:Select Search Style]* dialog and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The *[ui:Select Search Style]* dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist_s2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, select the fields to search in the List control when a seach is executed. Click the [...] button for the *[ui:Search Part fields]* property and select all of the fields and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select all of the fields in the List control to search.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist_s3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Finally, check the box for *[ui:Delay populate List till active search]*. This option indicates that the List control should not be populated with any data from the Customers table until a search is performed.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The *[ui:Search Part]* configured to add seach capabilities for the List control.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist_s4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 6: Adding Disconnected Support</title>
                    <description>The final step in setting up the List control with Detail View and Search Part is to add Disconnected support. This allows your mobile app to continue to work when a connection to the internet or network where a database may be stored is lost.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Disconnected Operation]* properties, check the box for *[ui:Persist List data to Local Storage]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Enabiling offline capabilities for your mobile application.</title>
                                <link>images/newlist6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 7: Generate the Controls</title>
                    <description>The List Control - Quick Setup Genie confguration is now complete. Next, you will generate the controls and preview the UX Component to see what you created.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:OK]* button in the *[ui:List Control - Quick Setup Genie]*. This will generate all of the controls necessary for the List, Detail View, and Search Part. Your UX Component should have a list of controls similar to the ones shown in the image below:</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The controls created by the *[ui:List Control - Quick Setup Genie]*</title>
                                <link>images/newlist7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:[FileSave] Save]* button to save your UX Component.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Congratulations! You have a working application!</p>
                            </description>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 8: Previewing Your App</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 1 Lesson 8]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The controls for the app have been created. Let's preview the app and try using it.</p>
                        <p>To preview what your application looks like, click on the *[ui:[WPreview] Working Preview]* tab located next to the *[ui:[Design] Design]* and *[ui:[LPreview] Live Preview]* tabs at the top of the *[ui:UX Builder]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Search Part, List control, and Detail View.</title>
                        <link>images/newlist8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>You should see a layout similar to the image above. On the left, you will see the Search Part and List control. The Search Part should appear above the List control. To the right of the List control, you should see several text boxes and several buttons. This is the Detail View.</p>
                        <p>The List control at this point should be empty. This is because there is no data in the List control. Remember that you enabled "Delay populate List till active search" in the List Genie. This means that no records will be available until a search is done. Let's do a search to populate the list with some data.</p>
                        <p>Type "Spain" into the Search box and click the *[ui:Search]* button. Several records should appear in the List control. When you click on a record, the Detail View, which is to the right of the List and Search Part, will be populated with data from that record. Select a record and edit it in the Detail View.</p>
                        <p>After making some edits to a record, click the *[ui:[FileSave] Save]* button to save your changes. A little yellow icon will appear next to the record in the List control indicating that it has been modified but has not been persisted to the Northwind database.</p>
                        <p>If there are any modifications to the data in the List control, you cannot perform any searches to pull data from the data source. If you tried to do a search now, say for "Germany", the Northwind database will not be searched. Instead, the records in the List control will be searched. This is done to prevent losing modifications to the data in the List control.</p>
                        <p>If you want to perform a new search to retrieve other records from the Northwind database, you'll need to synchronize the changes in the List control. To synchronize the changes back to the Northwind database, click *[ui:[FileSave] Synchronize]*.</p>
                        <p>Because disconnected application features are enabled, the List control will remember both the records in the List control and any changes you have made to those records when you exit *[ui:[WPreview] Working Preview]*. Click on the *[ui:[Design] Design]* tab and then back on the *[ui:[WPreview] Working Preview]* tab. The List control will remain populated with the data that was in it when you navigated away from *[ui:[WPreview] Working Preview]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Searching for "Spain" yeilds several records in the List control.</title>
                        <link>images/newlist9.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The List control remembers not only what records were displayed but keeps track of changes to records that haven't been saved back to the Northwind database.</title>
                        <link>images/newlist10.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Now that you have the functional components of the mobile application working, let's configure the UX Component to look and feel like a mobile application.</description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Part 2 - Creating the Responsive Mobile Layout</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>All mobile applications built in Alpha Anywhere use Panels. Panels group controls into "screens" and provide the navigation between "screens" of your application. You will be adding the Panel Cards, Panel Layouts and Panel Headers and Footer that will define the flow of content in the mobile environment.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 1: Adding Panel Cards and Panel Layouts</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 1]</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select all of the Search Part controls in the UX Component. Click *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card]]* listed in the *[ui:Panels]* section. Click *[ui:OK]* to insert the Panel Card around the selected controls.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Place the Search Part in a Panel Card.</title>
                                <link>images/panel1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, wrap the List control in a Panel Card. Select the List control in the Tree View and click *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card]]*. When prompted, click the *[ui:Insert Around]* button to place the List inside the Panel Card.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Wrapping the List control in a Panel Card.</title>
                                <link>images/panel2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Check the *[ui:Fill container]* option so the List control will fill the Panel Card. This ensures the List control will take full advantage of the screen realestate available on the mobile device.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Configuring a List control to Fill container.</title>
                                <link>images/panel3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add a Panel Card around the Detail View the same way as you did for the Search Part. Select all the Detail View controls and click *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card]]*. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Card around the Detail View.</title>
                                <link>images/panel4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Now you must remove the Container controls from the UX. Select the the *[ui:[Container:CONTAINER_1]]* and *[ui:[Container End:CONTAINER_1]]* controls and delete them by clicking the [DelObj] *[ui:Delete selected objects]* UX Builder toolbar button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Removing CONTAINER_1.</title>
                                <link>images/panel5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the the *[ui:[Container:CONTAINER_1_2]]* and *[ui:[Container End:CONTAINER_1_2]]* controls and delete them as well by clicking the [DelObj] *[ui:Delete selected objects]* UX Builder toolbar button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Removing CONTAINER_1_2.</title>
                                <link>images/panel6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The Search Part should appear above the List control. Select PANELCARD_1 and PANELCARD_2, including all of the controls they contain and PANLELCARD_2's *[Panel Card End]* control. Click *[ui:[PLayout][Panel Layout]]* in the *[ui:Panels]* section to wrap the selected controls in a Panel Layout.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Layout to contain the Search and List.</title>
                                <link>images/panelLayout1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, change the layout direction for PANELLAYOUT_1 from Left-To-Right (LTR) to Top-To-Bottom (TTB). The Top-To-Bottom layout will position the Search Part above the List control.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Panel Layout from LTR to TTB.</title>
                                <link>images/panelLayout2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, add a Panel Layout that will contain both the Panel Layout for the Search Part and List as well as the Panel for the Detail View. Select all of the controls in the UX Component. Click *[ui:[PLayout][Panel Layout]]* in the *[ui:Panels]* section to wrap all the controls in a Panel Layout.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Layout for the entire UX Component.</title>
                                <link>images/panelLayout3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 2: Adding Panel Headers and Footers</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 2]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Next, Panel Headers and Panel Footers need to be added. The Panel Headers and Panel Footers will contain the Detail View buttons and any other buttons that need to be added to navigate the mobile app.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[[PLayout][Panel Layout: PANELLAYOUT_1]]* control. Click *[ui:[Cont][Container]]*, which is listed in the *[ui:Containers]* controls to open the *[ui:Insert Container]* dialog. Select *[ui:Panel Header]* from the list of container choices and click the *[ui:Insert After]* button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Header to the Search Part.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>This Panel Header will hold the New Record and Synchronize buttons. Select the New Record button and click the [MoveTo] *[ui:Move to a specified location]* button on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the New Record button for moving into the Panel Header for the Search Part.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[[PHead][PanelHeader: PANELHEADER_1]]* in the *[ui:Move Selected Control(s) To..]* dialog. Choose *[ui:After]* for the *[ui:Move]* action. Click *[ui:OK]* to move the New Record button inside the Panel Header.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Moving the New Record button into the Search Part Panel Header using the Move Selected Control(s) To dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Now, move the Synchronize button into the Panel Header. Select the Syncrhonize button and click the [MoveTo] *[ui:Move to a specified location]* button on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Synchronize button for moving into the Panel Header for the Search Part.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[[CtrlBtn][Button: New Record]]* in the *[ui:Move Selected Control(s) To..]* dialog. Choose *[ui:After]* for the *[ui:Move]* action. Click *[ui:OK]* to move the Synchronize button after the New Record button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Moving the Synchronize button into the Search Part Panel Header after the New Record button.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, add a Panel Header to the Detail View to hold the Delete Record button for the Detail View. Select the *[[PCard][Panel Card: PANELCARD_3]]* control. Click *[ui:[Cont][Container]]* in the *[ui:Containers]* controls to open the *[ui:Insert Container]* dialog. Select *[ui:Panel Header]* from the list of container choices and click the *[ui:Insert After]* button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Header to the Detail View.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Move the Delete Record button into the header for the Detail View. Select the Delete Record button and click the [MoveTo] *[ui:Move to a specified location]* button on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Delete Record button for moving into the Panel Header for the Detail View.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[[PHead][PanelHeader: PANELHEADER_1]]* in the *[ui:Move Selected Control(s) To..]* dialog. Choose *[ui:After]* for the *[ui:Move]* action. Click *[ui:OK]* to move the New Record button inside the Panel Header.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Moving the Delete Record button into the Detail View Panel Header.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, add a Panel Footer to the Detail View. Select the Save and Reset buttons. Click *[ui:[Cont][Container]]* in the *[ui:Containers]* controls to open the *[ui:Insert Container]* dialog. Select *[ui:Panel Footer]* from the list of container choices and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Panel Footer to the Detail View around the Save and Reset buttons.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[ui:[PFoot] [Panel Footer: PANELFOOTER_1]]* control. In the *[ui:Container Begin Properties]*, change the *[ui:Container alignment]* from *[Left]* to *[Center]*. This will center the Save and Reset buttons in the footer.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Centering the Save and Reset buttons in the Detail Viewl Panel Footer.</title>
                                <link>images/headerFooter10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>The controls in the UX Component have been organized into a Panel structure, with Panel Cards, Panel Layouts, Panel Headers, and Panel Footers. Next, you will add a mobile stylesheet and enable mobile emulation for the application so you can visualize how the application will look and behave on a mobile device.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>How the app looks after controls are organized into Panel Cards, Panel Layouts, Panel Headers, and Panel footers.</title>
                        <link>images/headerFooter11.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 3: Using a Mobile Stylesheet</title>
                    <description>Now that the Panel structure and navigation has been established, the next step is to start styling the UX Component to look like a mobile application. Alpha Anywhere ships with a number of styles that allow you to build apps that look like iOS or Android appliactions in addition to some generic mobile styles.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 3-1: Chosing a New Style</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-1]</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Start by changing the stylesheet used by the UX Component. On the UX Component's *[ui:[Prop]Properties]* pane, click the [...] button for the *[ui:Style name]* property to select a new style.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Style name UX Component Property.</title>
                                <link>images/style1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Select Style]* dialog, choose the *[[style]iOS7]* style from the list of options and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Choosing the iOS7 style in the Select Style dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/style2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 3-2: Installing the Style's Icon Fonts</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-2]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>To preview this style you will need to install a few Fonts on your system. At this point, if you try to open *[ui:[WPreview]Working Preview]*, you will see several dialogs informing you that you need to install several fonts in order for your UX Component to render correctly in *[ui:[WPreview]Working Preview]*. Let's install the fonts for the *[iOS7]* style.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Open Windows Explorer and navigate to the *[CSS\iOS7]* directory in the executable folder where you installed Alpha Anywhere. This is usually *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\a5v12]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Finding the A5_iOS7Icons.ttf file in the CSS\iOS7 directory.</title>
                                <link alt="The iOS7 directory.">images/fontInstall1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Double-click the *[A5_iOS7Icons]* file with a .ttf extension. If file extensions are not configured to display, search for the *[A5_iOS7Icons]* with "TrueType" in the Type description. Windows will prompt you to install the font. Click the *[ui:Install]* button to install the font.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Installing the A5_iOS7Icons.ttf font.</title>
                                <link alt="The installation window for the A5_iOS7Icons.ttf file.">images/fontInstall2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Once the install completes, close all windows and return to Alpha Anywhere.</description>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, you need to install the *[font-awesome]* font library that ships with Alpha Anywhere. On the *[ui:Web Projects Control Panel]*, click the [FolderOpen] *[ui:Open Project Folder in Windows Explorer]* button on the toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Opening the project directory using the Open Project Folder in Windows Explorer tool.</title>
                                <link alt="The Open Project Folder in Windows Explorer toolbar button.">images/fontInstall3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Navigate to the *[fonts]* folder inside the *[CSSIcons/font-awesome]* directry inside the *[css]* directory inside the project folder in Windows Explorer. Search the folder for the *[fontawesome-webfont]* file with a .ttf file extension, or if extensions are not shown, the *[fontawesome-webfont]* file with a "TrueType" Type. As you did with the *[A5_iOS7Icons]*, double-click the *[fontawesome-webfont]* TrueType file. Click the *[ui:Install]* button to install the font.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Finding the fontawesome-webfont.ttf file in the css\CSSIcons\font-awesome\fonts directory.</title>
                                <link  alt="The fonts directory.">images/fontInstall4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>As you did with the *[A5_iOS7Icons]*, double-click the *[fontawesome-webfont]* TrueType file. Click the *[ui:Install]* button to install the font.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Installing the fontawesome-webfont.ttf font.</title>
                                <link alt="The installation window for the fontawesome-webfont.ttf file.">images/fontInstall5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When the install is complete, close all windows and return to Alpha Anywhere.</description>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 3-3: Enabling Mobile Preview</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-3]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Alpha Anywhere includes the built-in tools for simulating your application on a Mobile device. Let's enable mobile device simulation for the UX component and preview your app in *[ui:[WPreview]Working Preview]*.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>To preview your app on a variety of Mobile devices, first check the Mobile checkbox [Mob] on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>UX Builder toolbar</title>
                                <link>images/mobileEmulate1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The Mobile device emulation tools will now be enabled when you test your app. Click on the *[ui:[WPreview]Working Preivew]* or *[ui:[LPreview]Live Preview]* tab to preview your mobile app using the mobile stylesheet with the mobile emulator turned on.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Previewing with the mobile device emulator.</title>
                                <link>images/mobileEmulate2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>You can choose from a list of devices. Each device has an option for portrait or landscape orientation. Click on the dropdown box and select a different device option.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Available device emulation options.</title>
                                <link>images/mobileEmulate3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Now that your app has a mobile stylesheet and can be previewed using the mobile emulator, the next step is to configure the controls so they fit comfortably on a small screen.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>How the app looks emulated on an iPhone 4 in portrait (vertical) orientation after adding the iOS7 stylesheet.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileEmulate4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 4: Configuring the UX Controls for a Mobile Fit</title>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 4-1: Sizing Panels</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-1]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>When you previewed your app in the mobile emulator, you may have noticed that the List, Detail View, and Search Part were squished together on one screen. This is because none of the Panel Cards or Panel Layouts have any size information. Let's add some size information to the UX Component so the List, Detail View, and Search Parts are readable.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[ui:[PLayout][Panel Layout: PANELLAYOUT_1]]* control. In the *[ui:Panel Size and Dock Options]*, set the *[ui:Layout size]* to 300px.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Setting the Layout size for the Search Part and List Panel Layout to 300px.</title>
                                <link>images/panelSize1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, select the List's Panel Card, *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card: PANELCARD_2]]*, and set the *[ui:Minimum size]* to 300px in the *[ui:Panel Size and Dock Options]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Setting the Mimium size for the List's Panel Card to 300px.</title>
                                <link>images/panelSize2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Finally, select the Detail View's Panel Card, *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card: PANELCARD_3]]*, and set the *[ui:Minimum size]* to 300px in the *[ui:Panel Size and Dock Options]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Setting the Minimum size for the Detail View's Panel Card to 300px.</title>
                                <link>images/panelSize3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 4-2: Styling the List Buttons</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-2]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Next, you will modify the Detail View buttons to use images from the UX Component's style instead of text to fit in the headers and footer of the mobile layout.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the New Record button and change its *[ui:Button layout]* to *[Image only]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the button layou for the New Record button to Image only.</title>
                                <link>images/styleButtons1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click on the label for the *[ui:Button layout]* property for the New Record button to select the property. Then, click on the [pasteProp] *[ui:Paste Properties]* button on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Button layout for the New Record button so it can be copied to multiple controls using the Set Multiple Properties tool.</title>
                                <link>images/styleButtons2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Synchronize and Delete Record buttons in the *[ui:Select Controls]* dialog and click *[ui:Set Properties]* to set the selected controls' *[ui:Button layout]* property to Image only.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Synchronize and Delete Record buttons to set their Button style to Image only using the Set Multiple Properites tool.</title>
                                <link>images/styleButtons3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 4-3: Dock the Search Panel</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-3]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Some mobile devices have very little screen space. The Search Part can be docked, allowing the user to view the List control full screen. A button will be added that can be tapped to show the Search Part.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Panel Card that contains the Search control and change the *[ui:Dock]* property to *[collapse-before]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Dock property from none to collapse-before for the Search Part's Panel Card.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, set the *[ui:Layout Size]* of the Panel Card to 100px.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Layout size of 100px to the Search Part's Panel Card.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Panel Header Begin control for the header for the Search Part and List control. Click [CtrlBtn] *[ui:[Button]]* in *[ui:Other Controls]* to insert a new button in the Panel Header. This button will be used to toggle the display of the Search Part.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add a button to the component by clicking [CtrlBtn] [Button] listed in Other Controls.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Name the button you just inserted. Select the button and click the [...] button for the *[ui:Id]* property. Type "TOGGLESEARCH" into text box for the button's Id.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Id for a control using the Specify New Id dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>When specifying a new Id for a control, the New ID must be unique among the controls in the UX Component.</note>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Remove the break after the Toggle Search button. Select the Toggle Search button and click the [breakTool] *[ui:Toggle break]* button on the UX Builder toolbar.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Toggle break tool will add or remove a break after the selected control(s).</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Toggle Search button. In the *[ui:Button Appearance]* settings for the Toggle Search button, change the *[ui:Button layout]* to *[Image only]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Button layout to Image only for the Toggle Search button.</title>
                                <link alt="Button layout options">images/searchDock6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add the Search icon image to the Toggle Search button by clicking on the [...] button for the *[ui:Image name]* property. This will open the Specify Image dialog. In the *[ui:Specify Image]* dialog, select *[ui:Image in Web Project or Style]* to pick an image from the UX Component's style. Then, click the *[ui:Select]* button and choose the *[ui:Select from the Style]* option.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Specify Image dialog.</title>
                                <link alt="The Specify Image dialog">images/searchDock7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Using the *[ui:Filter]* text box, search for the *[{images.SearchPart.RunSearch}]* option. Select *[{images.SearchPart.RunSearch}]* and click the *[ui:OK]* button. Click *[ui:OK]* in the *[ui:Specify Image]* dialog to set the *[ui:Image name]* property to the style image you selected.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the image to display from the images in the UX Component's style.</title>
                                <link alt="The Select a Style Image dialog">images/searchDock8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[ui:[PLayout][Panel Layout: PANELLAYOUT_1]]* and click the [...] button for *[ui:Dock Panel controller buttons]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open Docked Panel controller buttons property by clicking the [...] button for the property.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Add Button Controller]* button to add a new Docked Panel Controller Button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add a new Button Controller on the Docked Panel Controller Buttons dialog by clicking Add Button Controller.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Add New Dock Panel Controller Button]* dialog, set *[ui:Button Id]* to *[TOGGLESEARCH]* and *[ui:Panel Id]* to the Panel Card for the Search Part, *[PANELCARD_1]*. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Add New Dock Panel Controller Button dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock11.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the changes in the *[ui:Docked Panel Controller Buttons]* dialog. The Search Part will now be shown when the TOGGLESEARCH button is clicked.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Linking the Toggle Search button (TOGGLESEARCH) to the Panel Card for the Search Part (PANELCARD_1.)</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock12.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Search and Clear Filter buttons. Click *[ui:[Cont] [Container]]*. Select *[ButtonGroup]* from the list of options and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding a Button Group around the Search and Clear Filter buttons for the Search Part. The Button Group will apply special styling to the button controls within it.</title>
                                <link>images/styleButtons4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Change the *[ui:Button text]* for the Search Part's clear button to "Clear":</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Button text for the Clear button for the Search to "Clear".</title>
                                <link>images/styleButtons5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[LIST1_KEYWORDSEARCH]* control. Click the [%] *[ui:Set control width]* UX Builder toolbar button. Choose *[100%]* from the list of options to resize the Search text box to 100% wide.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Setting the Search text box width to 100% wide.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock16.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>For the *[LIST1_KEYWORDSEARCH]* control, change the *[ui:Position]* for the *[ui:Field Label]* to *[None]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Removing the label for the search box.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock17.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
               <section>
                   <title>Lesson 5: Adding Navigation Between List and Detail View</title>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Next, you need to add javascript to navigate to the Detail View when a record in the List control is selected. On devices with more screen space, such as an iPad, the Detail View and List will be shown side by side. However, on smaller screens, such as phones, the Detail View is hidden on another "screen". You need to add javascript to show the Detail View when a record in the List control is selected or the New Record button is clicked.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 5-1: Adding Javascript to Show the Detail View</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-1]</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Open the List Builder for the List control by selecting the list and clicking the [...] button for the *[ui:List Properties]* in the *[ui:[Prop]Properties]* pane.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the List Builder by clicking the [...] button for List properties.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:[Events]List Events...]* button in the toolbar at the bottom of the List Builder to open the List Events Editor.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The [Events]List Events button provides quick access to all of the Client-Side events for the List control.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Search for the onClick event by typing "click" in the *[ui:Filter]* text box.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Use the Filter box to quickly find the event you're looking for in the List Control System Events editor.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:Insert method...]* link at the bottom of the *[ui:Javascript code]* editor. This opens the *[ui:Insert Method]* dialog. The *[ui:Insert Method]* dialog lists javascript methods available for the UX Component and objects (List controls, maps, button lists, etc) in the UX Component. The placeholder, *[ui:{dialog.object}]*, represents a javascript object for the UX Component. It has methods and properties that can be utilized to interact with the interface elements in the UX Component.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Insert Method dialog for the UX Component</title>
                                <link>images/listnav8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>To show the Detail View panel when a List control record is clicked, you need to call the *[js:{dialog.object}.panelSetActive]* method. Search for "panelSetActive" in the *[ui:Filter]* text box. Select *[{dialog.object}.panelSetActive(UXPanelName [, flagAnimate]);]* from the Method list and click *[ui:Insert]*</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Insert Method dialog for the UX Component</title>
                                <link>images/listnav7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the Javascript code editor, delete the text "*[js:UXPanelName [, flagAnimate]]*" from between the opening and closing parentheses for the panelSetActive method. Type a single quote (') between the parentheses to activate the autocomplete system in Alpha Anywhere. Press the "Ctrl+Down key" on the keyboard to open a popup menu of available Panel objects that can be activated using the *[js:panelSetActive]* method. You can also right-click on the text in the popup to activate the menu. Select *[PANELCARD_3]* from the list of choices to set the *[js:UXPanelName]* parameter for the *[js:panelSetActive]* method.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Autocomplete is available for most methods in the Javascript code editor.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>A dropdown menu is available for some methods, listing available controls a UX Component's method can access. Follow the instructions in the popup help for a method to access any dropdowns and genies that may be available.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>For the second parameter, *[js:flagAnimate]*, type in *[js:false]*. The *[js:flagAnimate]* parameter defines whether or not an animation should be used when activating the panel. A value of *[js:false]* means that no animation will be used.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Set the animation flag to false.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The javascript to activate the Detail View in the List control's onClick should like the code in the example below. Click *[ui:OK]* to save your changes and exit the List Builder.</description>
                            <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.panelSetActive('PANELCARD_3',false);]]></example>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, click the [...] button to open the editor for the New Record button's *[ui:click]* event.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the Event editor for an event by clicking the [...] button.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add code to the click event for the New Record button to navigate to the Detail View's pane when the button is clicked. There are already 2 lines of Javascript code in the button's click event. Add the same call to *[js:<![CDATA[{dialog.object}.panelSetActive()]]>]* at the end of the script. Click *[ui:[FileSave] Save]* to save your changes and close the Edit Event dialog.</description>
                            <example><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('LIST1');
lObj.newDetailViewRecord();
{dialog.object}.panelSetActive('PANELCARD_3',false);]]></example>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Event Editor is where you can add Action Javascript, Javascript, or even Server-side Xbasic to perform actions when client-side events occur for controls in the UX Component.</title>
                                <link>images/listnav6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 5-2: Adding a Back Button</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-2]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Now that you can navigate to the Detail View from the List control, a Back button needs to be added so that you can return to the List and Search Part from the Detail View.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[ui:[PHead][PanelHeader: PANELHEADER_2]]* control. In the *[ui:Other Controls]* section, click *[ui:[CtrlBtn][Button]]* to add a new button. </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Inserting a button into the UX Component.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>While the new button is selected, click the [breakTool] *[ui:Toggle break]* button on the UX Builder toolbar to remove the break after the button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The UX Builder toolbar.</title>
                                <link>images/mobileEmulate1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Button text]* property, type "Back". </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add text to a new button by changing the Button text property.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Change the button's *[ui:Id]* to "BACK". Click the [...] button for the *[ui:Id]* property to open the *[ui:Specify New Id]* dialog. Type in "BACK" in the *[ui:New ID]* text box. Click *[ui:OK]* to save the changes.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Id for the Button using the Specify New Id dialog.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>When specifying a new Id for a control, the New ID must be unique among the controls in the UX Component.</note>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Under *[ui:Button Appearance]*, change the *[ui:Button layout]* to *[Image follwed by text]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Button layout from Text only to Image followed by text.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the [...] for the *[ui:Image name]* property to open the *[ui:Specify Image]* dialog. With *[ui:Image in Web Project or Style]* select, click *[ui:Select]* and select *[ui:Select from the Style]* from the list of options. Search for "prev" and select the *[{images.dv.prevRecord}]* image from the style. Click *[ui:OK]* to select the image. Click *[ui:OK]* again to close the *[ui:Specify Image]* dialog and save your changes.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the image to display on the button.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Add an enable expression to the Back button to prevent the user from going back to the List control if any changes have been made in the Detail View. In the *[ui:Client Side Properties]* for the Back button, click the [...] button for *[ui:Enable expression]*</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Open the Define Client-Side Enable Expression editor by clicking the [...] button for the Enable expression property.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Define Client-Side Enable Expression]* dialog, click the *[ui:Insert Field]* button. Select *[{dialog.listDetailView.LIST1.isDirty}]* from the list to insert it into the expression.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Click Insert Field to insert a control or UX Component variable into an Enable Expression.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p> *[js:{dialog.listDetailView.LIST1.isDirty}]* is a logical variable that is true if the Detail View has been modifed and false if no changes have been made. The Back button should only be enabled when the Detail View is modified, or when  *[js:{dialog.listDetailView.LIST1.isDirty}]* is false.</p>
                                <p>After  *[js:{dialog.listDetailView.LIST1.isDirty}]*, type *[js: = false]* into the Enable Expression builder. You're Enable Expression should match the expression shown in the code example below. Click *[ui:OK]* to save the Enable Expression.</p>
                            </description>
                            <example><![CDATA[dialog.listDetailView.LIST1.isDirty = false]]></example>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The complete Enable Expression for the Back button.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Panel Card that contains the Detail View, *[ui:[PCard][Panel Card: PANELCARD_3]]*. In the *[ui:Parent Navigation Buttons]* properties, check the *[ui:Has 'Previous card' button]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Check the box for Has 'Previous card' button to enable display of the 'Previous card' button Id property.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>For the *[ui:'Previous card' button Id]*, select *[BACK]* from the dropdown.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Setting the 'Previous card' button Id to BACK.</title>
                                <link>images/backButton10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 5-3: Right Aligning Buttons in the Panel Header</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-3]</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the New Record and Synchronize buttons. Click *[ui:[Cont] [Container]]* to insert a Container around the selected buttons. Choose *[ui:None]* and click *[ui:OK]*</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add a container around the New Record and Synchronize buttons.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock13.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add "float:right;" to the *[ui:Container style]* property for the Container. This will align the New Record and Synchronize buttons on the right side of the Panel Header.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding float:right; to the Container's style will align the New Record and Synchronize buttons to the right-hand side of the Panel Header.</title>
                                <link>images/floatButtons1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the Delete Record button. Click *[ui:[Cont] [Container]]* to insert a Container around the Delete Record button. Select *[None]* and click *[ui:Insert Around]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Add a container around the Delete Record button in the Detail View's Panel Header.</title>
                                <link>images/searchDock15.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Add "float:right;" to the *[ui:Container style]* property for the Container. This will align the Delete Record button on the right side of the Panel Header.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Adding float:right; to the Container's style will align the Delete Record button to the right-hand side of the Panel Header.</title>
                                <link>images/floatButtons2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 6: Styling the List Control and Detail View</title>
                    <description>The final steps are to add a few styling elements to the List Control and Detail View so the controls are easier to read and use on a mobile device.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 6-1: Adding a Freeform Layout to the List</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 6-1]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You will now add the layout and styling necessary to make it readable on a mobile device. This starts with converting the List's layout from a Column Layout to a Freeform layout, allowing you to take advantange of Client-side Templates to render the data in a more mobile-friendly fashion.</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Open the List Builder for the List control. On the *[ui:List Properties]* tab, change the Layout from *[ui:Column]* to *[ui:Freeform]*</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the layout type for a List control.</title>
                                <link>images/freeform1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the List Layout tab, click the *[ui:Pre-defined Templates]* link located along the bottom of the Template editor. This will open the List Template Picker. Select the template with Level1, Level2, and Detail on the left and Context on the right.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>One of the pre-defined templates availalbe in the List Template Picker</title>
                                <link>images/freeform3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Assign the fields from the List control to the placeholders in the pre-defined template. You can select the fields from the dropdown controls or type them in manually. You can assign multiple fields to the same placeholder by typing them in.</p>
                                <p>Assign the *[ui:[[Context]]]* placeholder to *[{CustomerID}]*</p>
                                <p>Assign the *[ui:[[Level1]]]* placeholder to *[{CompanyName}]*</p>
                                <p>Assign the *[ui:[[Level2]]]* placeholder to *[{Address}]*</p>
                                <p>Assign the *[ui:[[Detail]]]* placeholder to *[{City} {Country}]*</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Assigning fields to template placeholders.</title>
                                <link>images/freeform4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The placeholders in the list template will be replaced with the fields you picked. This will produce a template that will look similar to the following:</description>
                            <example><![CDATA[<div style="display: table; width: 100%;">
	<div style="display: table-cell;">
		<div class="{dialog.style}ListItemLabelContext" style="float: right;">{CustomerID}</div>
		<div class="{dialog.style}ListItemLabelMain">{CompanyName}</div>
		<div class="{dialog.style}ListItemLabelSub">{Address}</div>
		<div class="{dialog.style}ListItemContent">
			{City} {Country}<br/>

		</div>
	</div>


	<div style="display: table-cell; width: 40px; text-align: right; vertical-align: middle;">
		<img src="{images.dialog.listNav}" />
	</div>
</div>]]></example>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Lesson 6-2: Mobilize the Detail View Controls</title>
                    <description>[Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 6-2]</description>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the CustomerID, CompanyName, Address, City, and Country text controls in the Detail View. Click *[ui:[Cont][Container]]*. Select *[ui:ControlGroup]* and click *[ui:OK]*</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select the text boxes in the Detail View to place them inside a ControlGroup.</title>
                                <link>images/detail1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the same group of controls again and click the [%] *[ui:Set control width]* UX builder toolbar button. Choose *[100%]* from the list of options to resize the controls to 100% wide.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Change the width of all of the text boxes in the Detail View to 100% wide.</title>
                                <link>images/detail6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the CustomerID control. Change the *[ui:Position]* in the *[ui:Field Label]* properties to *[Left]*. </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Change the Label Position to Left for the CustomerID control.</title>
                                <link>images/detail2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>While the CustomerID control is selected, select the *[ui:Position]* property. Click the [pasteProp] *[ui:Paste Properties]* UX Builder toolbar button to open the *[ui:Set Multiple Properties]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the Position property for the CustomerID control so it can be copied to multiple controls using the Set Multiple Properties tool.</title>
                                <link>images/detail4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the *[ui:Select Controls]* dialog, select the CompanyName, Address, City, and Country controls. Click *[ui:Set Properties]* to copy the label position from the CustomerID control to the selected controls.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Selecting the other text box controls in the Detail View so their Label Position can be set to Left.</title>
                                <link>images/detail5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the CompanyName control. Change the *[ui:Label]* in the *[ui:Field Label]* properties from "CompanyName" to "Company".</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Change the CompanyName title to "Company".</title>
                                <link>images/detail7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Congratulations! You have built your first Mobile App!</title>
                    <description>[Download Completed App]</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You have completed building your first mobile app. This app is ready to be deployed and will support a variety of mobile layouts. This app can be distributed as a mobile web application or published as a PhoneGap application and distributed through a private or public app store. Read the Publishing PhoneGap tutorials to learn how to deploy an app using PhoneGap.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Searching for records.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal0.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Search results in the List.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Viewing a Record.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A record after the City field was edited.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The List indicating a change is ready to synchronize with the server.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The same app in an iPhone 6 Horizontal layout.</title>
                        <link>images/mobileFinal_h1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="../../images/$$generic.link.png">ManageConnStr</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$file.new.png">FileNew</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$file.save.png">FileSave</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$control.edit.png">UXControls</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$control.browse.png">ListCtrl</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$mini.generic.lamp.png">ListGenie</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$database.unavailable.png">db</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$table.png">tbl</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$code.execute.blue.png">WPreview</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$code.execute.png">LPreview</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$generic.tools.png">Design</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$web.panel.card.png">PCard</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$web.panel.navigator.png">PNav</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$web.panel.layout.png">PLayout</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$web.panel.header.png">PHead</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$web.panel.footer.png">PFoot</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$edit.delete.png">DelObj</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$generic.styleSheet.png">style</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$generic.properties.png">Prop</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$folder.open.png">FolderOpen</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$layout.hierarchy.goto.nextSibling.png">MoveTo</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$control.button.png">CtrlBtn</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$format.border.style.dash.png">Cont</link>
        <link href="../../images/$$code.aScript.png">Events</link>
        <link href="images/pasteProp.png">pasteProp</link>
        <link href="images/enableMobile.png">Mob</link>
        <link href="images/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link href="images/sizeCtrls.png">%</link>
        <link href="images/breakTool.png">breakTool</link>
        <link href="#group_Build%20a%20Database%20Connection%20String">Build a Database Connection String</link>
        <link href="#group_First%20Things%20First%20-%20Setting%20Up%20Your%20Workspace">First Things First - Setting Up Your Workspace</link>
        <link href="#group_First%20Things%20First%20-%20Setting%20Up%20Your%20Workspace">First Things First</link>
        <link href="#group_Part%201%20-%20Building%20Basic%20Functionality">Part 1 - Building Basic Functionality</link>
        <link href="#group_Part%201%20-%20Building%20Basic%20Functionality">Part 1</link>
        <link href="#group_Part%202%20-%20Creating%20the%20Responsive%20Mobile%20Layout">Part 2 - Creating the Responsive Mobile Layout</link>
        <link href="#group_Part%202%20-%20Creating%20the%20Responsive%20Mobile%20Layout">Part 2</link>
        <link href="#section1_Lesson%202:%20Build%20a%20Database%20Connection%20String">Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20an%20Access%20Connection%20String">Build an Access Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20a%20SQL%20Server%20Connection%20String">Build a SQL Server Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20a%20MySQL%20Connection%20String">Build a MySQL Connection String</link>
        <link href="images/connectionstringMissing.png">NoConnectionString</link>
        <link href="./northwindSQLServer.xml">Importing the Northwind Access Database into SQL Server</link>
        <link href="./components/Part1Lesson2.zip">Download Component for Part 1 Lesson 2</link>
        <link href="./components/Part1Lesson8.zip">Download Component for Part 1 Lesson 8</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson1.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 1</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson2.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 2</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson31.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-1</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson32.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-2</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson33.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 3-3</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson41.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-1</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson42.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-2</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson43.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 4-3</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson51.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-1</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson52.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-2</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson53.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 5-3</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson61.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 6-1</link>
        <link href="./components/Part2Lesson62.zip">Download Component for Part 2 Lesson 6-2</link>
        <link href="./components/HelloAlpha.zip">Download Completed App</link>
    </links>
</page>