<page build="4491">
    <shortlink>MobileAppFramework_Data_driven_forms</shortlink>
    <topic>MobileAppFramework_Data_driven_forms</topic>
    <description>
        <p>This example shows how a ViewBox control can be used to implement a data-driven form, a form whose fields are dynamically computed at run-time.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A *[link:data-driven@https://www.alphasoftware.com/blog/build-data-driven-apps/]* form is a form with fields that are determined at run-time rather than design-time. The form can be generated by querying a database, web service, or executing a client-side or server-side function to determine the fields to display. Once the field definitions have been acquired, Xbasic is executed to generate a dynamic form definition.</p>
        <p>In the *[ui:MobileAppFramework_Data_driven_forms]* sample template, the form is implemented using a ViewBox control, an Editor Set and several Editors.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The image below shows how the sample component renders a particular data-driven form. The actual fields shown in the form are easily controlled by editing a JSON object that defines the fields, the field types and the editor to be used to edit the field value.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/datadrivenform.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Data-driven Forms</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A data-driven form is a form whose fields are determined at run-time (typically by querying a database) to get a list of the fields to display in the form.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how a ViewBox control and an Editor Set with multiple Editors can be used to implement a data driven form.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2017-07-26</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/HDUVdKJJDnB4BHszK9ihJP</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/dataDrivenForms.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>