<page build="4130">
    <shortlink>phonegap sound effects using native sounds template</shortlink>
    <topic>PhoneGap - Sound Effects using Native Sounds</topic>
    <description>This Cordova template application shows how to add sound effects to an application. It requires the 'Low Latency Audio' and the 'Status' bar plugins.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Sound effects can be integrated in to applications using the 'Low Latency Audio' plugin which is integrated into Alpha Anywhere. The Low Latency Audio plugin enables multi-channel and multi-voice playback and uses caching to minimize playback latency by leveraging the native audio APIs available on mobile devices. While HTML5 offers audio in mobile browsers, the quality is poor.</p>
        <p>The *[ui:PhoneGap - Sound Effect using Native Sounds]* template demonstrates using the 'Low Latency Audio' plugin to take advantage of native audio on a mobile device. The template uses several sound files that must be downloaded and added to the project. The sound files can be downloaded from the link below:</p>
        <p>*[extlink:Download Sound Files@https://download.alphasoftware.com/MiscFiles/soundFilesForNativeSoundsUX.zip]*</p>
        <p>When the sound file have been downloaded, unzip the sound files to the project folder.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Template tree.</title>
                <link>images/mobSound1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Building the App</title>
            <description>
                <p>When building the Cordova application, make sure to select the *[ui:Additional files]* property to add the sound files to the project. For example, if the sound files are in a folder called *[sounds]* in the web project, the entry to add to the *[ui:Additional files]* property would be:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[sounds/*.mp3]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>When the app is launched, it will programmatically play some sounds. All sounds can also be played using the buttons.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>In Live Preview.</title>
                <link>images/mobSound2.png</link>
            </figure>
            <note>Sounds will not work in Live or Working Preview. The app must be installed on a mobile device in order to play sounds.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>