<page>
    <topic>SecurityFramework-ChangePassword</topic>
    <description>An interface for changing the password for an account.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Controls in the Change Password template</title>
                <alt>Controls in the Change Password template</alt>
                <link>images/anyuser.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This template can be used to create an interface for users to change their password. The password fields include [in-control buttons] to toggle display of the contents of the field. The component requires the existing user password in order to reset the password.</p>
                <p>It's strongly recommended that this component require login and restrict access to only those users who should be able to access the interface to reset their password.</p>
                <p>The User Name field is automatically populated with the current logged in user's user name. This component can be used to reset passwords for other users, however it requires that you know the user's existing password in order to change it.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Preview of the Change Password interface</title>
                <alt>Preview of the Change Password interface</alt>
                <link>images/anyuser2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>A static text control is included in the template that explains what the UI is for. The control is for information purposes only and can be removed if desired.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Compacting the UI</title>
            <description>
                <p>If using the Alpha or any Alpha-based web theme with the component, you can check the [Use compact theme] option in the UX properties. The compact theme reduces the size and margins of the controls, making it ideal for mouse and keyboard interaction.</p>
                <p>The *[ui:SecurityFramework-ChangePassword]* template defaults to the iOS7 web theme, which does not have a compact variant. You will need to change the component's theme to Alpha or one of the Alpha-based web themes to take advantage of the compact theme. Or, use with your own branded web theme by simply changing the UX component's *[ui:Style name]*.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Preview of the Change Password interface using the compact Alpha theme</title>
                <alt>Preview of the Change Password interface using the compact Alpha theme</alt>
                <link>images/current3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Requires the Security Framework</limitations>
    <terms>ux component,component templates,security,user password</terms>
    <links>
        <link link="use%20compact%20theme">Use compact theme</link>
        <link link="ux%20textbox%20inctrl%20properties">in-control buttons</link>
    </links>
</page>