<page build="5244">
    <shortlink>uxadhocsqlquerybuilder template</shortlink>
    <topic>UX_Ad_Hoc_SQL_QueryBuilder</topic>
    <description>Allow users to execute ad-hoc SQL SELECT statements against any table in a database. Queries can be saved for future use and query results can be exported to Excel.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The purpose of this component is to allow a user to perform arbitrary queries against any table in a database and export the resulting data to Excel.</p>
        <p>The component supports the following:</p>
        <p>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Select the connection string</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Select the table</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Select the fields from the table</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Define sort orders</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Execute the query</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/adhoc_query.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Once the user execute the query focus is automatically given to the Results pane (shown below) which shows the query results.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Results pane displaying the records for the user's query.</title>
                <link>images/adhoc_queryresult.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The user can choose to do the following:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Show the SQL for the query</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Export the query results to Excel</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Save the query definition for future use</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>In order to save and load queries you must configure a Repository table. This is done by going to the Project Properties dialog when the Web Control Panel has focus and setting properties for Repository Settings. (See [Defining a Repository Table] below.)</p>
                <p>The list of connection strings that the user can select from is controlled by the choices you define for the ConnectionString dropdown box control on the UX. (See [Populating the Connection String Dropdown] below.)</p>
                <p>For more information about how this template works, watch the [Videos] below.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining a Repository Table</title>
            <description>
                <p>In order to save or load saved queries, you must configure the Repository table. The Repository table is defined in the Web Project Properties:</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Go to the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the *[ui:[props] Project Properties]* button in the toolbar to open the Web Project Properties.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the *[ui:Repository Settings]* section, define the Table type and connection properties for the database where the repository table will be created and stored:</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/repositorySettings.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>See [Repository Settings] for more information.</note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save your settings when you are done.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Populating the Connection String Dropdown</title>
            <description>
                <p>When the UX Component based on this template is created, the connection string dropdown box will be blank. In order to use this component, one or more connection strings need to be added to the list of options in the *[ui:connectionString]* Dropdownbox control. To do this, follow the steps below:</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the *[ui:connectionString]* control located inside the CONTAINER_QUERY container.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/adhoc_cs1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the [...] smart field button for the *[ui:Choices]* property</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/adhoc_cs1b.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Enter the connection strings to display in the Dropdown control - one per line. The connection strings listed must be defined in the web project.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/adhoc_cs2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>
                        <p>If you do not have access a data source to use with this template, you can use the Northwind database, which ships with Alpha Anywhere. See [Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings] to learn how to create a connection string to this database.</p>

                    </note>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:OK]* to save your list when you are done.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Ad-hoc SQL Query Builder</title>
                <description> This video shows a sample UX component that allows users to perform ad hoc SQL Select queries against any table in a database. The results can be viewed in a tabular format or exported to Excel.</description>
                <date>2018-08-03</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/ad1a8cee</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/$$generic.properties.png">props</link>
        <link link="server%20ref%20web%20project%20settings#section1_Repository Settings">Repository Settings</link>
        <link href="#section1_Defining a Repository Table">Defining a Repository Table</link>
        <link href="#section1_Populating the Connection String Dropdown">Populating the Connection String Dropdown</link>
        <link href="#section1_Videos">Videos</link>
        <link link="gettingtarted%20creating%20alphadao%20connection%20strings">Creating AlphaDAO Connection Strings</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
    <terms>ux template</terms>
</page>