<page>
    <topic>Generating QR Codes on the Client-side Using Javascript</topic>
    <description>QR Codes are simply data. As with other data controls, you can the setValueFrom() to set the value 
        of a QR Code.
    </description>
   
<sections>
    
    <section>
        <title>Setting a URL in a QR Code</title>
        <description>To see a video explanation of this example watch [this video].</description>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <description>In the UX Builder on the UX Controls page open the 'Data Controls' menu and click on the 
                    [TextBox] option to add a textbox control to the component. Set the textbox name and label to read 'code'.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>

            <step>
                <description>Open the Containers menu and click on the [Frame] option to add a frame container.</description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Highlight the Frame container and go back to the Data Controls menu. Click on the 
                    [QRCode] option to add a QR code inside the frame. Give it the name and label 'qrcode'.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            
            
            
            <step>
                <description>Highlight the QR Code control. Open the 'Other Controls' menu and click the [Button] option 
                    to add a button underneath the QR Code control. 
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>In the properties list under 'Button Properties' change the Button text to read 'Set QR Code'.</description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Scroll down the buttons properties list to the 'Javascript' section. Click the [...] button next to 
                    the onClick property.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Click the 'Text mode' radio button and add the following javascript. Then click 'Save'.</description>
                <example><![CDATA[{dialog.object}.setValueFrom('qrcode','code');]]></example>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Run the component in Live Preview. Enter a URL into the Code textbox and click the 'Set QR Code' button. 
                    you should see the QR Code change to incorporate the new data.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Scan the QR Code using QR Code on a phone using a QR code Reader, this should take you to the set url.</description>
                <figure><link>images/qrc.png</link></figure>
            </step>

        </steps>
        
    </section>
    
    
</sections>
<links>
    <link href="">this video</link>
    
    
</links>
</page>