<page>
	<topic>Calendar Component Properties</topic>
	<description>A list of calender component properties.</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Calendar Views Displayed</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Show Day View</title>
				<description>The Day view shows events for a specific date.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Week View</title>
				<description>The Week view displays events for a certain week. Events are displayed within vertical timelines. If you have an "All Day" event, it will be displayed at the top of the "Week" view.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Month View</title>
				<description>Month view displays events for a particular month. Only a few events for a given date are displayed. Other events are hidden and are shown when a "View All" link is clicked.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Custom View</title>
				<description>Month view displays events for a particular month. Only a few events for a given date are displayed. Other events are hidden and are shown when a "View All" link is clicked.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Agenda View</title>
				<description>Agenda view displays events in a list view. They are grouped by a day. You can scroll backwards and forwards to view your list of events.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Work Week View</title>
				<description>The Work-Week View displays events for the working days in a particular week (monday thru friday)</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Workshift View</title>
				<description>Workshift view displays events / task for a person. Persons can be grouped. For example: they can be grouped by departments like Managers, Sales, Trainers, etc.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Show Groups/Events View</title>
				<description>The Groups / Events view displays groups on x axis and events on vertical timelines. Groups could represent Persons or a Resource like Conference Rooms.</description>
			</case>
			
		
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Calendar Options</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Set calendar to read only</title>
				<description>If the calendar is set to read only, the user cannot add new events or drag and drop to change events. The grids may still be used to modify events unless they are also set to read only.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Default view</title>
				<description>Default view displayed when the calendar is initialized and loaded.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>First day of week</title>
				<description>Defines the start day of the week, either Sunday or Monday.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Time zone offset in hours</title>
				<description>Offset(if required) from GMT in hours. The default value is 0.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Default language</title>
				<description>The calendar currently supports English, French, Italian and Spanish</description>
			</case>
			
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Referenced Grids and Modal Dialog Size</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>New event grid name</title>
				<description>Select a grid to display when adding a new event to the calendar. This grid will be displayed in a modal popup window when the user adds an event to the calendar by a click and drag event.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Update event grid name</title>
				<description>Select a grid to display when updating an event. This grid will be displayed in a modal pupup window when the user clicks on an existing event.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Popup grid window width</title>
				<description>Specify the required width of the modal popup window that contains the new event and update event grids.</description>
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<title>Popup grid window height</title>
				<description>Specify the required height of the modal popup window that contains the new event and update event grids.</description>
			</case>
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>License Information</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<name>Calendar license code</name>
				<description>Enter a valid calendar license code. The calendar is licensed per domain.</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>