<page>
	<topic>Google Map Properties</topic>
	<description>A list of Google map properties.</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Google Map Properties</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<name>Initial Map Type</name>
				<description>The type of Google Map to display. This can be changed by the user using the displayed controls.</description>			
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>HYBRID</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>ROADMAP</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>SATELLITE</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>TERRAIN</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
	
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Use Google Maps Premier</name>
				<description>Check this if you have a Google Maps Premier client ID and want to use it</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Google Maps Premier Client ID</name>
				<description>Enter your Google Maps Premier client ID</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Use SSL</name>
				<description>Check this if you want to call Google Maps using SSL (HTTPS:)</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Use Sensor</name>
				<description>Check this if you want to use a GPS or other geolocation method for any reason, or if this map is intended to be used on a mobile device.</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Set Initial Position from Sensor</name>
				<description>Check this if you want to use a GPS or other geolocation method to set the initial map center. This works best on mobile devices.</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Initial zoom factor</name>
				<description>The initial zoom factor on the map. This can be changed by the user using the displayed controls. 0 shows the whole world; 20 shows a few square yards. Displaying a circle will override this setting.</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Create marker at initial center</name>
				<description>Check this if you want a push pin and/or polygon vertex created at the initial map center</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Initial marker is draggable</name>
				<description>Check this if you want the initial push pin to be draggable by the user</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Show markers</name>
				<description>Check this if you want push pins displayed.</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Added markers are draggable</name>
				<description>Check this if you want any user-added push pins to be draggable by the user</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Show polygon</name>
				<description>Check this if you want a polygonal area displayed</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Polygon color</name>
				<description>The color used for displaying the Polygon, as hex RGB, e.g. #FF0000</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Maximum number of points</name>
				<description>The maximum number of markers or vertices to display</description>			
			</case>
			
				<case>
				<name>Show circle</name>
				<description>Check this if you want a circle displayed</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Circle color</name>
				<description>The color used for displaying the circle, as hex RGB, e.g. #00FF00</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Circle radius</name>
				<description>The radius of the circle to display, in meters. 1 mile is roughly 1609 m. Note that displaying a circle resets the map size.</description>			
			</case>
			<case>
				<name>Geocoding source</name>
				<description>The service to use for geocoding addresses.</description>			
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Google</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Nominatim</description>
					</case>
				</cases>
			</case>
			<case>
				<name>Reinitialize on Geocode</name>
				<description>Check this if you want to reinitialize the map if the user geocodes an address. Otherwise, the geocoded point will be added to the map.</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Cluster bulk markers</name>
				<description>Check this if you want to display bulk markers in clusters (useful if you have a lot of markers to display)</description>			
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>HTML Properties</title>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<name>Map Width</name>
				<description>The width of the map, e.g. "400px" or "3in"</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Map Height</name>
				<description>The height of the map, e.g. "500px" or "4in"</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Toolbar HTML</name>
				<description>HTML that defines the controls for the toolbar</description>			
			</case>
			
			<case>
				<name>Toolbar position</name>
				<description>Specify whether the HTML toolbar is above or below the map.</description>	
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Below</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Above</description>
					</case>
				</cases>		
			</case>
			
			
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>