<page>
	<topic>Grid Component Search Part</topic>
<groups>
	<group>
		<title>Hide Grid Part Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Hide Grid when no search active</title>
				<description>If no search is active, should the 'Grid' part of the component be hidden? If you check this option, the initial load of the component will be faster.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Text to display when grid is hidden</title>
				<description>Specify the text be be shown in place of the Grid part when no search is active</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Search Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Show title</title>
				<description>Show a title above the Search part? (Note: To enable the 'Show/Hide of Search part' prompt, you MUST display the search title.)</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Title</title>
				<description>Specify the title to be shown above the Search part.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Title when hidden</title>
				<description>Specify the title to show when the Search part is hidden</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enable show/hide of Search part</title>
				<description>Can the user click on the Search part's title to hide/show the Search part?</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show/hide button icon</title>
				<description>Specify the icon for the show/hide button. This button appears in the title bar above the row selector column</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show/hide button bubble help</title>
				<description>Specify the bubble help for the icon for the show/hide button. This button appears in the title bar above the row selector column</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Animation</title>
				<description>Specify if the Search Part should be animated when it is shown or hidden. You can choose different effects.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Initial state</title>
				<description>Initial state of the Search part when the page is displayed.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search button label</title>
				<description>Specify the label for the 'Search' button.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use icon for search button</title>
				<description>Should an icon be used for the search button? (To customize the icon, go to Grid, Properties, Customization, Customize icons).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Orientation</title>
				<description>Specify if the Search fields are laid out vertically or horizontally</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Has 'Clear Search' link</title>
				<description>Specify if the Search part has a link to clear the search criteria and requery showing all records.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>'Clear Search' label</title>
				<description>Specify the text to show on the 'Clear Search' link.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>'Clear Search' bubble help</title>
				<description>Specify the text to show on the 'Clear Search' link or button.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use icon for clear search link</title>
				<description>Should an icon be used for the clear search link? (To customize the icon, go to Grid, Properties, Customization, Customize icons).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search style</title>
				<description><![CDATA[Specify the type of search to perform. 1 = 'Exact Match' (may or may not be case sensitive - depends on the database), 2 = 'Is Contained In', 3 = 'Starts with' 4 = 'Wildcard' - user must explicitly enter wildcard characters '*', '%' or '?'. (If QBE syntax is turned on you can enter multiple wildcard criteria, delimited with either a comma or && - use && to combine criteria with an AND clause). For databases that are case-sensitive, you can use 11, 12, 13 or 14 for case-insensitive versions of the 1, 2, 3, or 4 option.]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search rules</title>
				<description>Specify rules when Grid supports multiple types of searches (e.g. Quick search, Alphabet button, Search Part, and Query by Example searches).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show single 'Keyword' search field</title>
				<description>Instead of showing individual search fields, show a single search field. If a match is found in any of the search fields, the record is returned.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Allow 'Query By Form' syntax</title>
				<description><![CDATA[Support Alpha Five's QBF syntax. For example: CA,MA to search for "CA" and "MA", 123..345 to search for >=123 and <=345, ..12/3/2004 to search for dates <=12/3/2004.]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>QBF Operator Exceptions</title>
				<description><![CDATA[The 'Query By Form' operators are: .. (two dots), , (comma), >, >=, <, <= and =. You can specify that you want to treat some of these operators as literal strings. Enter a pipe delimited list of exclusions. For example, if you enter ..|=, this indicates that the .. (two dots) operator and the = sign should be treated as literal strings, not search operators.]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Combine search criteria using</title>
				<description>If user enters search criteria into multiple fields, combine using 'AND', or 'OR'. Select 1 for 'AND', or 2 for 'OR'.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Keyword search field label</title>
				<description>Specify the label for the search field.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Disable browser auto-complete feature</title>
				<description>In most browsers, when you type into a search field, the browser will try to auto-complete your entry. You can disable this behavior in the browser.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Toolbar position</title>
				<description>The Search Toolbar contains the 'Search' and 'Clear Search' buttons. Specify if the toolbar should be shown above or below the search fields. If you select 'None', the toolbar is not shown. The 'None' choice is only appropriate if you are using cascading DropdownBoxes and you have set the last DropdownBox to 'Auto-Submit' the search, or you have designed a free-form search with your own custom button to submit the search. Your custom button must have this Javascript in its 'onClick' event: {Grid.object}.submitSearchForm(); return false;.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Help window</title>
				<description>Specify if an icon should be shown in the Toolbar to open a window that displays help for this component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Help ID</title>
				<description>Specify the ID of the help text to display in the window.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Help button icon</title>
				<description>Help button icon property</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Help button bubble help</title>
				<description>Specify the bubble help for the help button icon.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search highlighting</title>
				<description>Specify whether, when the user does a Search, Quick Search, or QBE Search, if the search strings should be highlighted in fields in the Grid in which they were found. NOTE: Search highlighting only applies to Label controls.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Embed search in Grid part</title>
				<description>Specify if the search part should be embedded in the Grid part</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Position in Grid</title>
				<description>Specify where in the Grid the Search part should be embedded.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Above titles</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Below titles</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Has free-form layout</title>
				<description>Specify if the embedded Search Part uses a free-form layout. If you check this you can define a single free-form region, or a free-form region above each column. If you do not check this, the standard Search Part that you have defined is embedded in the Grid (with these excpetions: the 'sort by' and 'records per page' listboxes that optionally appear in the Search Part are turned off).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Free-form search style</title>
				<description>Specify if there is a free-form region above each column in the Grid for search fields, or a single free-form region with a colspan that spans all of the Grid columns.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Free-form region for each column</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Single free-form region</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Free-form search template</title>
				<description>Specify the free-form search template.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Display search/clear icons in row selector</title>
				<description>Specify if 'Search' and 'Clear Search' icons shold be shown in the row selector column. If you do not include these buttons here then you will need to include them in at least one of the free-form search areas above each column.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search button icon</title>
				<description>Specify the icon for the search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Search button bubble help</title>
				<description>Specify bubble help for the icon for the search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Clear search button icon</title>
				<description>Specify the icon for the clear search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Clear search button bubble help</title>
				<description>Specify the bubble help for the icon for the clear search button that is displayed in the row selector column.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Save and Load Searches</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Allow user to save search criteria</title>
				<description>Specify if the user can save search criteria in the Search Part form. The search criteria are saved in the Repository. To configure the Repository, go to Project Properties on the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Allow user to load search criteria</title>
				<description>Specify if the user can load previously saved search criteria into the Search Part form. The search criteria are loaded from the Repository. To configure the Repository, go to Project Properties on the Web Projects Control Panel.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Load search prompt</title>
				<description>Specify the prompt to display on the dialog where the user is prompted for the name of the saved search to load.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Save search prompt</title>
				<description>Specify the prompt to display on the dialog where the user is prompted for the name to give the search criteria when they are saved to the Repository.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Load search button bubble-help</title>
				<description>Specify button bubble-help</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Execute search on load</title>
				<description>When loading a saved search, should it be immediately executed?</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Save search button bubble-help</title>
				<description>Specify button bubble-help</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Listbox heading</title>
				<description>Specify the text to show above the listbox where the existing saved searches are shown.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Listbox height</title>
				<description>Specify the height of the listbox that shows the existing saved searches. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 1in, 100px, etc.)</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Dialog width</title>
				<description>Specify the approximate width of the dialog. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 2in, 300px, etc).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Auto-load choices</title>
				<description>When the user opens the dialog to load/save a search, should the list of existing saved searches be populated, or should this be deferred until the user explicitly requests that the list be populated.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Prompt to load text</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the prompt to populate the listbox showing existing saved searches.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Load search button</title>
				<description>Load search button property</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Save search button</title>
				<description>Save search button property</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Cancel button</title>
				<description>Cancel button property</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Warning message - blank name</title>
				<description>Specify the warning message to show if the user tries to save search criteria without specifying the name to assign to the save criteria.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Warning message - duplicate name</title>
				<description>Specify the error message to show if the user tries to save search criteria using a duplicate name.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Sort Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Include 'Sorting' listbox</title>
				<description>Specify whether the Search part includes a listbox to allow users to select the sort order for the data.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Label for 'Sorting' listbox</title>
				<description>Specify the label for the 'Sorting' listbox.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Label position</title>
				<description>Specify the position for the label for the 'Sorting' listbox.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Left</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Above</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Inline style for 'Sorting' label</title>
				<description>Specify the inline style for the row label.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>'Sort' listbox default</title>
				<description>Specify the option to show in the listbox when the user has not selected a value.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Use column headings in sort listbox</title>
				<description>Specify if column headings should be used listbox instead of field names.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>'Order' listbox options</title>
				<description>Specify the choices that appear in the 'Order' listbox. The first option is for Ascending order, and the second option is for Descending order.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>'Order' listbox default</title>
				<description>Specify the option to show in the 'Order' listbox when the user has not selected a value.</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>		<title>Records per Page Listbox Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Include 'Records per Page' listbox</title>
				<description>Include a listbox that allows the user to select how many records should be displayed on each page if a search returns more than one record./description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Label for 'Records per Page' listbox</title>
				<description>Specify the label for the 'Records per Page' listbox.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Label position</title>
				<description>Specify the position for the label for the 'Records per Page' listbox.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Left</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Above</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Inline style for 'Records per Page' label</title>
				<description>Specify the inline style for the row label.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>'Records per Page' listbox choices</title>
				<description>Specify the choices that appear in the 'Records per Page' listbox. Enter a comma delimited list of values. For example: 1,5,10</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>'Records per Page' listbox default</title>
				<description>Specify the option to show in the listbox when the user has not selected a value.</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Freeform Edit Regions</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Above search part</title>
				<description>You can enter any HTML to appear above the Search part of the component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Below search part</title>
				<description>You can enter any HTML to appear below the Search part of the component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Left of search part</title>
				<description>You can enter any HTML to appear left of the Search part of the component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Right of search part</title>
				<description>You can enter any HTML to appear right of the Search part of the component.</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Customization</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Inline style</title>
				<description>Specify the inline style for the Search part's tag.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Table tag attributes</title>
				<description>Specify optional attributes to insert into the Search part's tag.</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Javascript - Other</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Watch events</title>
				<description>Watch events are executed whenever a value in a 'watched' control in the Search part is changed.</description>
			</section>
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	
	
</groups>	
	
	
</page>