<page>
	<topic>Grid Field Properties</topic>
<groups>
<group>
	<title>Display Settings</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	<case><title>
Control type</title><description>

Control type property</description></case>
<case><title>
Map properties</title><description>

Specify the map properties.</description></case>
<case><title>

Proximity search properties</title><description>

Specify the proximity search control properties.</description></case>
<case><title>

Control Javascript</title><description>

Specify any Javascript code that should be emitted for this control. You can use the special {Grid.ControlId} and {Grid.ControlIdEscaped} placeholders to reference the control's Id. This is an advanced feature typically used by developers who are using a 3rd party Javascript library, such as JQuery, to style a control using Javascript.</description></case>
<case><title>

Search style</title><description>
<![CDATA[
Specify the type of search to perform. 0 = Use default setting specified on Search Properties tab, 1 = 'Exact Match' (may or may not be case sensitive - depends on the database), 2 = 'Is Contained In', 3 = 'Starts with' 4 = 'Wildcard' - user must explicitly enter wildcard characters '*', '%' or '?'. (If QBE syntax is turned on you can enter multiple wildcard criteria, delimited with either a comma or && - use && to combine criteria with an AND clause) For databases that are case-sensitive, you can use 11, 12, 13 or 14 for case-insensitive versions of the 1, 2, 3, or 4 option. You can use negative values (e.g. -1,-2,-3 or -4 to invert the search result (e.g. 'not equals'). For multi-valued fields (e.g. Checkbox and Dropdownbox controls that allow multi-select), 20=combine selections with OR, 21=combine selections with AND. For example, if a Checkbox control has 'Red', 'Green' and 'Blue' as its choices, if you check 'Red' and 'Green' and select option 20, the search is for 'Red' or 'Green' in the field, and if you select 21, the search is for 'Red' and 'Green' in the field. Instead of specifying 20, you can specify 201, 202 or 203. These all combine selections with OR, but allow you to control whether to search for an exact match (201), an 'is contained in' search (202, which is same as 20), or 203 a 'starts with' search.
]]></description></case>
<case><title>
Search expression</title><description>

Specify the expression to search.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Range search</title><description>

Display two textboxes to prompt for a starting and ending value. Allows user to search for a range of values without having to use Query-by-Form syntax.
</description></case>
<case><title>
'From' label</title><description>

Specify the label that appears above the first search field. This is the search field that represents the start of the range.
</description></case>
<case><title>
'To' label</title><description>

Specify the label that appears above the second search field. This is the search field that represents the end of the range.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Initial value</title><description>

Specify the default value for this control when the Search Part is rendered. If this is a 'Range Search' enter two values, separated by || (two 'pipe' characters). For example: =date()||=date()+5 TIP: To enter an expression, enter a leading = sign. For example: =date(), =now() (today's date and time). You can use session variables as default values. For example: session.companyName. You can use Page Variables (i.e. the variables defined in the URL) by prefixing the variable name with 'PageVariable.' (e.g. PageVariable.lastname)
</description></case>
<case><title>
Keyword search</title><description>

Specify if this field is a keyword search. If so, then instead of searching in this field, Alpha Anywhere will search for a match in any of the keyword fields.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Keyword search fields</title><description>

Specify which fields to search when the user enters search criteria into this field.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Lookup</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Lookup</title><description>

Lookup data in a Table, or static data source.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Lookup type</title><description>

'Auto-Suggest List' - as users start typing, a list of suggestions is shown, 'Edit-Combo List' - users can either typing in a value, of click a button to show a drop-down list with choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Lookup definition</title><description>

Click the smart field button to define the lookup.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Display Settings</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Control type</title><description>

Control type property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Control Javascript</title><description>

Specify any Javascript code that should be emitted for this control. You can use the special {Grid.ControlId} and {Grid.ControlIdEscaped} placeholders to reference the control's Id. This is an advanced feature typically used by developers who are using a 3rd party Javascript library, such as JQuery, to style a control using Javascript.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Display format</title><description>

Specify how this field should be formatted. Enter an Xbasic expression that uses the  placeholder to format the data. It may be necessary to wrap the  placeholder in the convert_type() function to ensure that  returns the correct data type that your format expression expects.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Display unformat</title><description>

Specify how this field should be unformatted before changes are saved in the database. Enter an Xbasic expression that uses the  placeholder to un-format the data. It may be necessary to wrap the  placeholder in the convert_type() function to ensure that  returns the correct data type that your un-format expression expects.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Control Settings</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
	Name</title><description>

Name property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Scope</title><description>

Specify the variable scope. Session variables can be seen by other pages in your application. Local variables can only be seen by this page.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Control type</title><description>

Control type property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Data type</title><description>

Data type property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Validation rules</title><description>

Specify rules to test if the data in this field is valid.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Client side validation</title><description>

Should data in this control be validated before the form is submitted? Requires Javascript on the client browser.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Initial value</title><description>

Initial value property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Initial state</title><description>

Select True if checkbox initial state is checked.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Calculated Field Expression</title><description>

Define a calculated field expression. If not blank, the field will be considered a calculated field. Javascript must be enabled on the browser for this to work.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Enable Expression</title><description>

Define the Enabled Expression for the field. If the expression evaluates to true, the field will be enabled. Javascript must be enabled on the browser for this to work.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Show/Hide Expression</title><description>

Define the Show Expression for the field. If the expression evaluates to true, the field will be shown. Javascript must be enabled on the browser for this to work.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Link Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Display what in link?</title><description>

Specify what is displayed in the link (this is what the user clicks on). Options are: 'Value in field' - the actual value in the field, 'Value in other field(s)' - the value in one or more other fields in the Grid, 'Static text' - some text that is the same for all rows in the Grid (e.g. 'Send an email'), 'Static image' - an image that is the same for all rows in the Grid, 'Image in another control' - an image specified in an Image control on the Grid
</description></case>
<case><title>
Field(s) to display</title><description>

Specify the HTML to display in the link. Use field placeholders to include values from other fields in the Grid. Typically, the fields that you reference will have their 'Hide row' or 'Hide column' property checked.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Static text</title><description>

Specify the text to display in the link. Tip: You can include HTML markup in the text.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Static image</title><description>

Specify the name of the image to display.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Static image inline style</title><description>

Specify style attributes for the image.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Static image text</title><description>

Specify the text description for the image. Tip: To display the contents of a text field, enclose the field in curly parens. e.g. {description}
</description></case>
<case><title>
Dynamic image control</title><description>

Specify the image control on the Grid that contains the image to display in the link. Typically, the 'Hide row' or 'Hide column' property for this control will be checked.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Link address type</title><description>

Link address type property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Link address</title><description>

Click the button to open the Link Address builder. TIP: The address will be URL encoded. If you don't want to URL encode the address, prefix it with {nourlencode}
</description></case>
<case><title>
Target frame, window or DIV</title><description>

Specify the target frame, window or DIV. Leave blank to open in same window, type in an explicit window name, or use one of the pre-defined targets. Select 'Ajax Window' to open the target in a pop-up window on the current page. Select DIV to open the page in a window in the current page. The window will be inside a 'div' tag that you can place in a 'Freeform Edit Region', or in the .a5w page that contains this Grid.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Target DIV id</title><description>

Specify the DIV id where the target page will be shown. You can put the DIV in a Freeform Edit Region (recommended), or in the .a5w page that contains this grid. If you put the DIV in a Freeform Edit Region, is is recommended that you use the '{Grid.componentName}' placeholder in the DIV id. For example: {Grid.componentName}_DIVFORWINDOW.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Target IFrame style</title><description>

The target page will be opened in an IFrame inside the target DIV. Specify the inline style for the IFrame. You can set the IFrame's height and width in the style.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Can hide target DIV?</title><description>

Specify the DIV can be hidden (to remove from view the target page after it has been opened in the DIV).
</description></case>
<case><title>
DIV hide hyperlink</title><description>

Specify text for the hyperlink that hides the DIV where the target page is shown.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window type</title><description>

Specify the window type. Popup windows will show in a moveable window on the page. Dropdown windows will open directly below the control that you click to open the window. Note: An Ajax popup window will NOT be blocked by a browser's internal protection against popup windows.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window title</title><description>

Specify the window title.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window height</title><description>

Specify the window height. Use CSS syntax. For example: 3in, 10cm, 200px. If you do not set the height, the window will resize automatically to accommodate the window contents.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window width</title><description>

Specify the window height. Use CSS syntax. For example: 3in, 10cm, 200px. If you do not set the width, the window will resize automatically to accommodate the window contents.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window is resizable</title><description>

Specify if the window is resizable.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Window position</title><description>

Specify the window position. Note: The 'In-View' option has a different meaning for 'pop-up' and 'dropdown' window types. For a pop-up window, 'In-View' means that the window is initially centered and then its position it remembered for subsequent opens. For a dropdown, 'In-View' means that the window opens below the current control.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Working message</title><description>

Specify the text of the message to show in the window while the window waits for its contents to be generated.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Working message icon</title><description>

Specify the image to show in the window while the window waits for its contents to be generated.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Refresh Grid on window close</title><description>

When the window is closed, specify if the Grid should be refreshed. You can refresh the current row, or all rows in the Grid.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Clear Parameters</title><description>

Specify if target URL preserves existing parameters
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>TextBox Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
HTML5 type</title><description>

Specify an optional value for the textbox 'type' attribute. Leave blank to use 'text'.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Size</title><description>

Important: If the 'Lookup' property is checked, set the control size using the 'In-line style' property. E.g. width: 3in;
</description></case>
<case><title>
MaxLength</title><description>

Set to -1 for no limit on input length.
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Container in-line style</title><description>

(Only applies to controls that have a smart field button - e.g. Lookups, Date/Time pickers) Specify style attributes for the container for the control. The container encloses both the input control and the smart field button.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Is a password field</title><description>

Is this field a password field?
</description></case>
<case><title>
Watermark</title><description>

Specify if the field has a watermark. The watermark text appears in the textbox when there is no value in the textbox.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Watermark text</title><description>

Specify the watermark text. Set to  to use the field label as the watermark text. For Search Fields that have the Range search property checked, specify the watermark for the 'From' field and the 'To' field separated by double pipe characters. Example: Start date||End date.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Watermark class name</title><description>

(Optional) Specify the class name for the watermark text. Leave blank to use default class. This class is applied on top of any existing classes.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Watermark style</title><description>

(Optional) Specify the style for the watermark text.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Custom attributes</title><description>

Custom attributes property
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Client Side Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
<case><title>
Client side formatting</title><description>

Specify if the textbox has client side formatting, such as a mask, or custom display format
</description></case>
<case><title>
Format type</title><description>

Specify the format type
</description></case>
<case><title>
Format type</title><description>

Specify the format type
</description></case>
<case><title>
Format type</title><description>

Specify the format type
</description></case>
<case><title>
Format definition</title><description>

Specify the client side format
</description></case>
<case><title>
Calculated field expression</title><description>

Define a calculated field expression. The calculation is done in the Browser (i.e. on the 'client side') using Javascript.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Show/hide expression</title><description>

If the expression evaluates to true, the control will be shown, otherwise it will be hidden. The calculation is done in the Browser (i.e. on the 'client side') using Javascript.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Enable expression</title><description>

If the expression evaluates to true, the control will be enabled. The calculation is done in the Browser (i.e. on the 'client side') using Javascript.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Conditional style</title><description>

Specify if the style for the cell that contains this control is computed, based on the values of the fields in the row. Note: You can also define conditional styles at the row level (see Properties page). For example, you might want to display a cell with a red background if a value in the row is outside a certain range. Note: The calculation is performed in the Browser using Javascript. Contrast with 'server-side' conditional styles in the 'Display Settings' section.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Conditional style level</title><description>

Specify if the conditional style should be applied to the cell that contains the control, or to the control itself, or both. For input controls (e.g. Textbox), you must select 'Control' or 'Both'.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Lookup</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Lookup</title><description>

Lookup data in another Grid, Table, or static data source.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Lookup type</title><description>

'Grid Component' - shows a 'Lookup' link next to the field. Users can click this link to open another window which displays a Grid component from which they can select the value for this field. 'Auto-Suggest List' - as users start typing, a list of suggestions is shown. 'Edit-Combo List' - users can either type in a value, or click a button to show a drop-down list with choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Lookup definition</title><description>

Click the smart field button to define the lookup.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Custom Control Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
	Definition</title><description>

Specify the Xbasic code that computes the HTML for the custom control.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Advanced Button Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Button label</title><description>

Specify the button label
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Label Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>CheckBox Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Choices</title><description>

Specify the choices that appear in the CheckBox.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Orientation</title><description>

Are the check boxes laid our vertically, or horizontally?
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column flow</title><description>

Specify how the choices are organized. LRTB - left-to-right, then top-to-bottom. TBLR - top-to-bottom, then left-to-right
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column count</title><description>

Specify how many columns should be used to display the CheckBox choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row count</title><description>

Specify how many rows should be used to display the CheckBox choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Maximum choices</title><description>

Specify the maximum number of choices to show. Set to 0 to show all choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Not in list rule</title><description>

xp.help</description></case>

</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>DropDownBox Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Choices</title><description>

Specify the choices that appear in the DropDownBox.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Maximum choices</title><description>

Specify the maximum number of choices to show. Set to 0 to show all choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Height</title><description>

Specify the height of the box. If height is 1, then box appears as combo box. If height is greater than 1, then box appears as a list box.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Multi-select allowed</title><description>

Specify if user can select more than one choice
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Not in list rule</title><description>

xp.help
</description></case>
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	

<group>
	<title>RadioButton Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
Choices</title><description>

Choices property
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Orientation</title><description>

Are the radio button laid our vertically, or horizontally?
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column flow</title><description>

Specify how the choices are organized. LRTB - left-to-right, then top-to-bottom. TBLR - top-to-bottom, then left-to-right
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column count</title><description>

Specify how many columns should be used to display the radiobutton choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row count</title><description>

Specify how many rows should be used to display the radiobutton choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Maximum choices</title><description>

Specify the maximum number of choices to show. Set to 0 to show all choices.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Not in list rule</title><description>

xp.help
</description></case>
</cases>	
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	
<group>
	<title>Image Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
<cases>
	
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. You can specify attributes such as the image size, and border. For example, to set the image size to 1 inch by 1 inch, set style to the following (using CSS syntax): width: 1in; height: 1 in;
</description></case>
<case><title>
Text description</title><description>

Specify the text description for the image. Tip: To display the contents of a text field, enclose the field in curly parens. e.g. {description}
</description></case>
<case><title>
Image path</title><description>

The selected field is an 'Image File Reference Field'. Specify the folder where the images are stored (alternatively you can specify an 'image file transformation template' - click the Smart field for details). Tip: You can define an alias for this folder in your Profiles so that the images can be found on the server when you publish your project.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Embed image in HTML</title><description>

Specify if the image should be base64 encoded and embedded directly into the HTML. This reduces the number of server round-trips to get the image data, but results in a substantially larger initial payload being sent from the server to the browser. This option is generally only appropriate for 'small' images. Do not check this option if the image is specified by a URL.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Scale image on server</title><description>

Specify if the image should be scaled on the server before it is served. Scaling the image on the server can improve performance by reducing the amount of data that must be transmitted. IMPORTANT: Option does not apply if image is specified by a URL.
</description></case>
<case><title>
No image found image</title><description>

(Optional) If this field does not have any Image data for a particular row, specify an optional image to display instead of an empty image. Specify  for no image.
</description></case>
<case><title>
New record image</title><description>

(Optional) For new record rows (on Grids that allow inserts), specify an image to use instead of an empty image. Specify  for no image.
	</description></case>
	
</cases>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>
</group>	
<group><title>Time Picker Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
				
<case><title>
Time Picker</title><description>

Show a 'Time Picker' icon which can be clicked to open a time picker.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Open how</title><description>

Specify how the date picker will be opened. Can either be when user clicks the icon, or when user clicks in the field.
•ClickIcon
•Focus
</description></case>
<case><title>
Time format</title><description>

Specify the time format in which time will be returned when the user makes a selection from the Time Picker. If you specify , the format is controlled by the 'Date format' property in the 'Miscellaneous' section on the Grid Properties tab page.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Time picker Icon</title><description>

Enter a number between 1 and 6 to select the built-in date picker icon to display.
</description></case>
<case><title>
User must select from Time picker</title><description>

Specify if the user can type in a date/time value, or must select the value from the Date/Time picker. If this option is checked, then the Date/Time picker is automatically set to open when the control gets focus.
</description></case>
<case><title>
OK button label</title><description>

Specify the label of the OK button. You can use language tags -  and .
</description></case>
<case><title>
Cancel button label</title><description>

Specify the label of the Cancel button. You can use language tags -  and 
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group><title>Date Picker Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
				
<case><title>
Date Picker</title><description>

Show a 'DatePicker' icon which can be clicked to open a calendar. Users can click in the calendar to enter date values.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Open how</title><description>

Specify how the date picker will be opened. Can either be when user clicks the icon, or when user clicks in the field.
•ClickIcon
•Focus
</description></case>
<case><title>
Date format</title><description>

Specify the date format in which dates will be returned when the user makes a selection from the Date Picker. If you specify , the format is controlled by the 'Date format' property in the 'Miscellaneous' section on the Grid Properties tab page. The  setting allows you to easily configure the Grid to use US formats for users in the U.S.A and 'day/month/year' formats for users outside the US.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Date picker Icon</title><description>

Enter a number between 1 and 6 to select the built-in date picker icon to display.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Switch year</title><description>

Specify how the date picker will interpret 2 digit years. IMPORTANT: If you want to define how the server will interpret 2 digit years, you must set the Switch year in the Grid Properties, Miscellaneous section.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Use combo boxes</title><description>

Use combo boxes property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Low year</title><description>

Low year property
</description></case>
<case><title>
High year</title><description>

High year property
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group><title>Calendar Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
<case><title>
Date format</title><description>

Specify the format for dates.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Read only</title><description>

Specify if the calendar allows data entry.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Switch year</title><description>

If a date value has a two digit year, specify which year to switch from 1900 to 2000.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Use combo boxes</title><description>

Specify if the calendar should show combo boxes for the year and month picker.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Low year</title><description>

Specify the low year in the year picker.
</description></case>
<case><title>
High year</title><description>

Specify the high year in the year picker.
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>	

<group><title>Column Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
				
<case><title>
Hide column</title><description>

Do not display this column in the Grid. (Note: The control in this column can still be displayed in another column if you convert that column to a freeform layout.)
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security level</title><description>

If the user is logged in with a security level that is lower than the security level you specify here, the column will be hidden. Set the security level to 0 to always show this column regardless of the user's security level.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security Groups</title><description>

Select which security groups can see this column. If no groups are selected, all users can see the column.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column heading</title><description>

Specify the column heading
</description></case>
<case><title>
Heading in-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Heading prefix</title><description>

Specify text or an image that should be displayed to the left of the column heading. You can use HTML tags in the text.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Can sort</title><description>

Can sort property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Sort field</title><description>

Specify the field to sort on when user clicks on the column title. In the case of .DBF files, you can enter a field name, or expression. In the case of SQL databases, you can enter any valid SQL 'Order by' clause (e.g. 'Lastname, Firstname'). In the case of SQL databases, if the sort field is not the same as the fieldname, you must use the correct syntax. For example, if the sort field is 'customer name' and the target Database is SQL server, the correct syntax is '[customer name]'.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform layout</title><description>

Specify if this column should display just this field, or allow a free-form layout.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform template</title><description>

Specify the layout template for this cell.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform search template</title><description>

Specify the free-form search layout for the condition where the search part is embedded into the Grid
</description></case>
<case><title>
Cell in-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Bubble Help Text</title><description>

Enter the text to show up as Bubble Help when the user hovers over the table cell that contains this control.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Break</title><description>

Break property
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group><title>Row Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
				
<case><title>
Hide row</title><description>

Do not display this control in the Form. (Note: The control can still be displayed in another row if you convert that row to a freeform layout.)
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security level</title><description>

If the user is logged in with a security level that is lower than the security level you specify here, the row will be hidden. Set the security level to 0 to always show this row regardless of the user's security level.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security Groups</title><description>

Select which security groups can see this row. If no groups are selected, all users can see the row.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label</title><description>

Specify the row label
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label in-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label position</title><description>

Specify where the label is positioned relative to the control.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Label prefix</title><description>

Specify text or an image that should be displayed to the left of the row label. You can use HTML tags in the text.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Bubble Help Text</title><description>

Enter the text to show up as Bubble Help when the user hovers over the table cell that contains this control.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Label Bubble Help Text</title><description>

Enter the text to show up as Bubble Help when the user hovers over the label.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform layout</title><description>

Specify if this row should display just this field, or allow a freeform layout.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform template</title><description>

Specify the layout template for this row
</description></case>
<case><title>
Cell in-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Break</title><description>

Break property
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column Span</title><description>

Set the number of columns that the control will span.
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>

<group><title>Other Properties</title>
	<sections>
		
		<section>
			
			<cases>
				
<case><title>
Hide row</title><description>

Do not display this control in the Form.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label</title><description>

Specify the row label
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label in-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Row label position</title><description>

Specify where the label is positioned relative to the control.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Label prefix</title><description>

Specify text or an image that should be displayed to the left of the row label. You can use HTML tags in the text.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Label Bubble Help Text</title><description>

Enter the text to show up as Bubble Help when the user hovers over the label.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform layout</title><description>

Specify if this row should display just this field, or allow a freeform layout.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Freeform template</title><description>

Specify the layout template for this row
</description></case>
<case><title>
Column Span</title><description>

Set the number of columns that the control will span.
</description></case>
			</cases>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
</group>
<group>
	<title>Update Settings</title>
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
<case><title>
Updateable</title><description>

Specify if the field can be edited. TIP: If you want to be able to type text in the field, but still not update any table when the Grid is submitted, set 'Updateable' to true, and set the 'Table Alias' property to: *unbound.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Blank is NULL</title><description>

Treat blank values as NULL. IMPORTANT: You can only use this option if your database allows this field to be nullable.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security level</title><description>

Specify the minimum Security Level required to update this field. If all users can update this field regardless of their Security Level, set the Security Level to 0.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Security Groups</title><description>

Select which security groups can update this field. If no groups are selected, all users can update this field.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Table alias</title><description>

Specify the table alias for the field you want to apply the update to. TIP: If this field is not bound to a table, specify: *unbound (i.e. an asterisk followed by 'unbound')
</description></case>
<case><title>
Field to update</title><description>

Specify the name of the field you want to apply this update to.
</description></case>
<case><title>
Check for write conflicts</title><description>

When updating records, if 'Check for write conflicts' is turned on, should this field be included in the list of fields that are checked for write conflicts? (Certain SQL field types - e.g. 'ntext' - must be excluded.)
</description></case>
<case><title>
Geography field info (longitude,latitude)</title><description>

When an update, or insert is performed, the location value in this field can automatically be computed from the longitute and latitude value from the fields that contain these values. If you leave this field blank, then this field will not be automatically updated when you insert or update a record. If you want to automatically update this field, enter the longitude and latitude field name (comma delimited). For example: myLongitudeField,myLatitudeField
</description></case>
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>

<group>
	<title>Events</title>
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
<case><title>
Server</title><description>

Specify the Xbasic to run to when the form is submitted.
</description></case>
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>

<group>
	<title>Blurb Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
<case><title>
Text</title><description>

The text that will be displayed in the blurb.
</description></case>
<case><title>
In-line style</title><description>

Specify style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet.
</description></case>
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>


<group>
	<title>Heading Properties</title>
<sections>
	<section>
		<cases>
<case><title>
Text</title><description>

Specify the row label
</description></case>
<case><title>
Inline Style</title><description>

Set the Inline Style for the Heading
</description></case>
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	
</group>


	
</groups>	
	
	
	
</page>