<page>
	<topic>Page Layout Properties</topic>
	<groups>
		<group>
			<title>Button Properties</title>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<title>Button text</title>
							<description>Enter HTML text to appear in this control.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Bubble help</title>
							<description>Enter the bubble help for the button. For high order international characters, you must use unicode encoded text.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Class</title>
							<description>Specify the class name for the</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Style</title>
							<description>Specify the in-line style for the</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Id</title>
							<description>Specify the control id.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Width</title>
							<description>Specify the button width. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 2in, 40px). Leave blank to use a default width.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Height</title>
							<description>Specify the button height. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 2in, 40px). Leave blank to use a default height.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Break</title>
							<description>Force a column break before, after, or both before and after this control.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Break height</title>
							<description>Specify the vertical distance between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Horizontal spacer</title>
							<description>Specify the horizontal space between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Break height</title>
							<description>Specify the vertical distance between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Horizontal spacer</title>
							<description>Specify the horizontal space between this control and the next control. Use CSS syntax. e.g. 10px, .5in, 20pt.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Repeating section heading</title>
							<description>Specify the column heading for this control when it is displayed in a Repeating Section that shows labels on the first row only</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hide</title>
							<description>Specify if this control should be hidden. Controls are typically hidden so that they can be manually placed into the Dialog HTML in a 'Free-form Container'.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Advanced button styling</title>
							<description>Specify if you want more control over how the button appears. For example, you can put an image and text on the button. For touch applications (e.g. mobile applications), you should check this property.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Advanced button control type</title>
							<description>Specify if the button should be displayed as a standard button, hyperlink, or image.</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Button</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Hyperlink</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Image</description>
								</case>
							</cases>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Control container class name</title>
								<description>(Advanced/Optional) All controls are automatically wrapped in a div (with a class name of 'A5CWLayout' or 'A5container' ) (unless the control is in a 'NoFloat' container). You can specify a class name to use for the control container in addition to the 'A5CWLayout'
									or 'A5container' class that is automatically used. This allows you to have more control over the appearance of the control.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Control container prevent float</title>
								<description>(Advanced/Optional) All controls are automatically wrapped in a div (with a class name of 'A5CWLayout' or 'A5container' ) (unless the control is in a 'NoFloat' container). This container automatically 'floats' the control (so that your controls lay out automatically
									from left to right until a control with a 'break after' is encountered). In addition, the class adds padding around the control. By checking this property, the you are specifying that the div container that encloses this control will not have the 'A5CWLayout'
									or 'A5container' class applied.</description>
							</case>
					</cases>
				</section>
			</sections>
		</group>
		<group>
			<title>Button Appearance</title>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<title>Sub-theme</title>
							<description>Sub-theme property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button layout</title>
							<description>Button layout property</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Text only</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Image only</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Text followed by Image</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Image followed by text</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Image above text</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Text above image</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description><![CDATA[Text left & image right]]></description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description><![CDATA[Image left & text right]]></description>
								</case>
					
						</cases>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Has dropdown icon</title>
							<description>Specify if a small dropdown arrow should be shown on the button. (Typically only used if the button will open a dropdown window when clicked.)</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Display as split button</title>
							<description>Specify if the button should be split into two 'logical' buttons, with the button and the dropdown icon separated into two logical buttons. If you use this option you should define your event handler in the 'onClick' rather than the 'click' event. You will
								then be able to refer to arguments[1] in your code to see if the user clicked on the dropdown icon or the button. arguments[1] will be set to either 'normal' or 'split'.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button text</title>
							<description>Specify the text for the button. TIP:You can use the and language translation tags here.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Bubble help</title>
							<description>Specify the bubble help for the button. The bubble help is displayed when the mouse is over the button. TIP:You can use the and language translation tags here.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button class</title>
							<description>Specify the button class. You can use for no class. Use or blank for the default class.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button class hover</title>
							<description>Button class when the mouse is hovering over the button. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+' to use the specified class in addition to the default
								class. E.g. +myHoverclass.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button class pressed</title>
							<description>Button class when the user clicks on the button. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+' to use the specified class in addition to the default class.
								E.g. +myPressedclass.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button class disabled</title>
							<description>Button class when the button is disabled. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+' to use the specified class in addition to the default class. E.g.
								+myPisabledclass.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button inline style</title>
							<description>Button inline style property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button text class</title>
							<description>You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Button text inline style</title>
							<description>Button text inline style property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Image name</title>
							<description>Image name property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hover image name</title>
							<description>Image to display when mouse if hovering over the button. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Pressed image name</title>
							<description>Image to display when user clicks the button. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Disabled image name</title>
							<description>Image to display when the button is disabled. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Image class</title>
							<description>Image class property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Image inline style</title>
							<description>Image inline style property</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</section>
			</sections>
		</group>
		<group>
			<title>Hyperlink Appearance</title>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink text</title>
							<description>Specify the text for the hyperlink. TIP:You can use the and language translation tags here.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Bubble help</title>
							<description>Specify the bubble help for the hyperlink. The bubble help is displayed when the mouse is over the hyperlink. TIP:You can use the and language translation tags here.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink text class</title>
							<description>Hyperlink text class property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink text inline style</title>
							<description>Hyperlink text inline style property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink class</title>
							<description>Hyperlink class property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink inline style</title>
							<description>Hyperlink inline style property</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<title>Hyperlink image position</title>
							<description>Specify if the hyperlink has an associated image.</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>None</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Left of text</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Right of text</description>
								</case>
							</cases>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Image name</title>
								<description>Image name property</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Hover image name</title>
								<description>Image to display when mouse if hovering over the button. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Pressed image name</title>
								<description>Image to display when user clicks the button. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Disabled image name</title>
								<description>Image to display when the button is disabled. Leave blank to use the default image.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Image class</title>
								<description>Image class property</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<title>Image inline style</title>
								<description>Image inline style property</description>
							</case>
					</cases>
				</section>
			</sections>
		</group>
		<group>
			<title>Image Appearance</title>
			<sections>
				<section>
					<cases>Image name Image name property Hover image name Image to display when mouse if hovering over the button. Leave blank to use the default image. Pressed image name Image to display when user clicks the button. Leave blank to use the default image. Disabled image
						name Disabled image name property Image class Image class property Image inline style Image inline style property Button class Specify the button class. You can use for no class. Use or blank for the default class. Button class hover Button class when the mouse
						is hovering over the button. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+' to use the specified class in addition to the default class. E.g. +myHoverclass.
						Button class pressed Button class when the user clicks on the button. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+' to use the specified class in addition
						to the default class. E.g. +myPressedclass. Button class disabled Button class when the button is disabled. You can enter (or leave blank) to use the default class name. Specify for no class. If you specify your own class name here you can prefix it with '+'
						to use the specified class in addition to the default class. E.g. +myPisabledclass. Button inline style Button inline style property</cases>
				</section>
			</sections>
		</group>
	</groups>
</page>