<page>
	<topic>Tabbed UI Component Properties</topic>
<groups>
	<group><title>Tabbed UI Properties</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Default</title>
				<description>Specify the default layout style for this component.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>DesktopBrowser</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>MobileSencha</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Style type</title>
				<description>Style type property</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Alpha Anywhere</description>
					</case>
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Class map</title>
				<description>Specify how the abstract CSS class names used in this component map to physical CSS class names in your style sheets.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Resolve class map at runtime</title>
				<description>To optimize performance, the class map is resolved a design time. If you check this property you can dynamically change the appearance of the component at runtime by remapping all of the abstract classes used in the component to a different set of physical CSS class names.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Style name</title>
				<description>Click the button to select a new style, or edit the existing style. IMPORTANT If any of the Grids shown in the TabbedUI use a different style than this style, their styles must be listed in the 'Additional Grid styles' section below. You can also use  or  (V11 and above)</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Style overrides</title>
				<description>By default, the Tabs, Accordions, pop-up Windows, Lists (edit-combo, auto-suggest, etc.) are style using the selected Grid style. You can override the style for these elements. This might be necessary for certain styles where the default appearance for these elements do not work well.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Font size</title>
				<description>Specify if the fonts in Grid Components should be scaled to make the Grid larger or smaller. Select 'Medium' for no scaling (i.e. the fonts shown will match those defined in the style sheet).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Minimum height</title>
				<description>Specify the minimum height (in pixels) for the 'Content Area' (from below the 'Header' to above the 'Footer').</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Master template</title>
				<description>Specify an optional Master Template. This allows you to place arbitrary HTML surrounding the Tabbed UI component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Center TabbedUI on page</title>
				<description>Specify if the Tabbed UI component should be a fixed width and centered horizontally on the page. (This property is only shown if you have not defined a Master Template.)</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Component width</title>
				<description>Specify the width of the Tabbed UI component. Use CSS units.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Component border class name</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the border that surrounds the Tabbed UI component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Component border in-line style</title>
				<description>Specify the in-line style for the border that surrounds the Tabbed UI component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Header text</title>
				<description><![CDATA[Specify the HTML text for the header section. This appears above the tab panes. TIP: The HTML can include <%a5...%> Xbasic code blocks.]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Footer text</title>
				<description><![CDATA[Specify the HTML text for the footer section. This appears at the bottom of the page. TIP: The HTML can include <%a5...%> Xbasic code blocks.]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Page title</title>
				<description>Specify the page title for the .a5w page that will display the Tabbed User Interface.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Layout mode (Desktop or Mobile)</title>
				<description>Should the layout of the Tabbed UI component be optimized for a Desktop Browser, or a mobile device (phone or tablet)?</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>DesktopBrowser</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>MobileDevice</description>
					</case>
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hide tab buttons</title>
				<description>Should the tab pane buttons be hidden? If yes, then the only way to switch from one open tab to another is by clicking on a button in the Buttons Pane.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Mobile layout 'Menu' button text</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the button that shows the Tabbed UI menu choices.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Mobile layout 'Menu' title text</title>
				<description>Specify the text that appears in the title bar when the menu buttons are displayed.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Display Home page initially</title>
				<description>When the Tabbed UI Object is initially opened, should the Home Page be shown? If you uncheck this, then the Tabbed UI Menu Buttons pane is shown.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Buttons panel location</title>
				<description>Specify where the Button Panel (which contains the buttons to open the pages that are shown in the Tabbed User Interface) is located.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Buttons panel style</title>
				<description>The Button Panel is contained in a TD tag. Specify the style for the tag. You can specify the width of the Button Panel in the style. IMPORTANT: Do NOT specify a height for this Button Panel. The height of this section is automatically computed by the component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Buttons - padding left</title>
				<description>Specify the padding on the left side of the buttons. (Setting is ignored if Button Panel is on right).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Buttons - padding right</title>
				<description>Specify the padding on the right side of the buttons. (Setting is ignored if Button Panel is on left).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Buttons - padding top</title>
				<description>Specify the padding above the buttons.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Set button padding off if using Tree Control</title>
				<description>If the Tabbed UI buttons are in a Tree Control should the button padding be set to 0? (Tree looks better when padding is set to 0).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Prompt when navigate away from page</title>
				<description>When user navigates from the page that contains the Tabbed UI component, should a confirmation message be displayed?</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Navigation confirmation message (dirty Grids)</title>
				<description>NOT SUPPORTEC Specify the syntax of the warning message that is displayed when the user tries to navigate from the page that contains the Tabbed UI. This message is only displayed if any of the panes that contain Grid components are 'dirty'.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Navigation confirmation (no dirty Grids)</title>
				<description>NOT SUPPORTED Specify the message to display when the user tries to navigate from the page th at contains the Tabbed UI Component (and there are no Grids with unsaved data).</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab close image</title>
				<description>Specify the image for the close tab button. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab close image (on hover)</title>
				<description>Specify the image to display when the user is hovering over the close tab button. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab scroll - previous image</title>
				<description>If there are more tabs open that can be displayed, the tab band will scroll. Specify the image for the scroll left button. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab scroll - previous disabled image</title>
				<description>Specify the scroll previous image when the button is disabled. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab scroll - next image</title>
				<description>If there are more tabs open that can be displayed, the tab band will scroll. Specify the image for the scroll right button. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab scroll - next disabled image</title>
				<description>Specify the scroll next image when the button is disabled. Specify  or blank to use the default image. In V11 and above  indicates that the image is defined in the style. By editing the style you can change the image.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Collapse button bar icon (Left)</title>
				<description>Specify the icon to collapse the button panel. Set to , or blank, to use the icon specified in the style.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Expand button bar icon (Left)</title>
				<description>Specify the icon to expand the button panel after it has been collapsed. Set to , or blank, to use the icon specified in the style.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Collapse button bar icon (Right)</title>
				<description>Specify the icon to collapse the button panel. Set to , or blank, to use the icon specified in the style.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Expand button bar icon (Right)</title>
				<description>Specify the icon to expand the button panel after it has been collapsed. Set to , or blank, to use the icon specified in the style.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Can collapse buttons pane</title>
				<description>Specify if the button pane can be collapsed.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Initial state of buttons pane</title>
				<description>Specify the initial state of the Buttons pane. 'Open' - button pane is shown, 'Closed' - button pane is not shown, but the user can click the expand button to show the button pane, 'Closed-locked' - button pane is not shown - the button pane can only be shown programatically using this Javascript command: tbiObj.showTabbedUIMenuPanel(flagShowAnimation);</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Open</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Closed</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Closed-locked</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Auto hide buttons pane</title>
				<description>Specify if the buttons pane should be automatically hidden after the user moves the mouse out of the buttons pane area.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Auto hide delay</title>
				<description>Specify the delay in milliseconds before the button pane is automatically hidden/shown.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Permanently hide buttons pane</title>
				<description>Specify if the buttons pane should be permanently eliminated from the Tabbed UI. If you choose this option, then you must set then 'Auto launch on startup' property for the objects that you want to see in the Tabbed UI. You should also uncheck the 'Can close pane' property for each object, or else, if the user closes a pane, there will be no way to re-open the pane.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Class names</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band separator</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band separator. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab button off</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab buttons when not selected. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab button on</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for tab buttons when selected. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab button disabled</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for disabled tab buttons. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band left scroll</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band left scroll. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band right scroll</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band right scroll. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band left scroll disabled</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band left scroll when disabled. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Tab band right scroll disabled</title>
				<description>Specify the class name for the tab band right scroll when disabled. Specify  to use the default class associated with the Tabbed UI style you selected. Tip: You can specify a class to use in ADDITION to the default class by using this syntax:  YourClassName</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Container A5W page</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>A5W Page name</title>
				<description>If an .a5w page contains a Tabbed UI Component then that page cannot contain any other component. This is different from other component types. For example, an .a5w page might contain two Grid components. Because .a5w pages that contain Tabbed UI Components are special, they are created automatically for you when the Tabbed UI Component is saved. You can specify the name of the .a5w page that is automatically created or you can let Alpha Five name it for you (the builder will create a page called 'TabbedUI_.a5w').</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User defined 'head' content</title>
				<description>Specify any content you want to place in the 'head' section of the generated .a5w page.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Noscript Content for Search Engines</title>
				<description>Specify any content that you want to place in the Body section of the page in tags so that Search Engines can index this page.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Login</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Has login/logout links</title>
				<description>If you check this box, a login and logout hyperlink will be displayed in the top right corner of the page. Users will be able to login and logout directly from the Tabbed UI component.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login prompt
</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the login hyperlink.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Logout prompt
</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the logout hyperlink.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Customize login failure messages
</title>
				<description>Customize login failure messages
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login action
</title>
				<description>When the user logs in specify if a full reload of the page should occur (recommended), or if an Ajax Callback should be performed. Performing an Ajax Callback will be marginally quicker and will result in no screen flicker, but will NOT update any Xbasic code you might be evaluating in the header/footer or home page of the Tabbed UI.</description>	
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>FullReload
</description>
					</case>
						<case>
						<description>AjaxCallback
</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Has 'Register new account' link</title>
				<description>Specify that a link should be displayed to allow new users to register for an account. This link is only displayed when no one is logged in and will open the component specified in 'Component to display to register new account'. Optionally, it could be used to open any UX component, such as a UX component to change a password.</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Register new account prompt</title>
				<description>Specify the text to show on the 'Register new account' hyperlink.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>New account link location
</title>
				<description>Specify where the link to open the 'Register new account' dialog should be shown. It can be on the Menu Bar (next to the Login link), in the Login dialog, or both.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>MenuBar
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>LoginDialog
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Both
</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Component to display to register new account
</title>
				<description>Specify the name of the UX component to display where a user can register for a new account.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Register new account window title
</title>
				<description>Specify the title for the window in which the New Account component will be shown.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Custom menu bar HTML - left
</title>
				<description>(Optional) You can specify any text to add to the left side of the menu bar that appear at the top of the Tabbed UI. (This is the menu bar that contains the Login/Logout hyperlinks.)
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Custom menu bar HTML - center
</title>
				<description>(Optional) You can specify any text to add in the center of the menu bar that appear at the top of the Tabbed UI. (This is the menu bar that contains the Login/Logout hyperlinks.)
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Logged in message template
</title>
				<description>(Optional) You can specify a template to use for the message that is displayed in the menu bar after a user logs in. This message typically indicates the name of the logged in user. The template can include the '{userName}' placeholder for the user name. IMPORTANT: If the server-side 'onLogin' event sets a value for the 'friendly user name', the {username} placeholder will show the friendly user name. For example, the 'friendly user name' for the user 'john23@gmail.com' might be 'John Costansa'.
</description>	
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Login Window Customization</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>User name prompt</title>
				<description>User name prompt property</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password prompt</title>
				<description>Password prompt property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User name label style
</title>
				<description>User name label style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User name field style
</title>
				<description>User name field style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password label style
</title>
				<description>Password label style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password field style
</title>
				<description>Password field style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Has free-form layout
</title>
				<description>Not implemented because we have enough customization options already
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Free-form layout
</title>
				<description>Free-form layout property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Header text
</title>
				<description>(Optional) Specify any text you want to appear at the top of the login dialog.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Footer text
</title>
				<description>(Optional) Specify any text you want to appear at the bottom of the login dialog.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login button label
</title>
				<description>Login button label property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login button style
</title>
				<description>Login button style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Cancel button label
</title>
				<description>Cancel button label property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Cancel button style
</title>
				<description>Cancel button style property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Window width
</title>
				<description>Specify the width of the login window. Use CSS units. Leave blank for default size.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Window height
</title>
				<description>Specify the height of the login window. Use CSS units. Leave blank for default size.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Animate login window
</title>
				<description>Animate login window property
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show window animation method
</title>
				<description>Show window animation method property
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>none
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>slide
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>fade
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show window animation speed
</title>
				<description>Specify speed in milliseconds. You can use 'fast' or 'slow' (fast = 200 ms, slow = 600 ms)
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hide window animation method
</title>
				<description>Hide window animation method property
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>none</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>slide
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>fade
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Hide window animation speed</title>
				<description>Specify speed in milliseconds. You can use 'fast' or 'slow' (fast = 200 ms, slow = 600 ms)</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Disable auto-complete - User Name field</title>
				<description>Specify if the browser's auto-complete feature should be disabled for the User Name field.
</description>	
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Disable auto-complete - Password field
</title>
				<description>Specify if the browser's auto-complete feature should be disabled for the Password field.
</description>	
			</section>
			
		</sections>
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Session Timeout Warning</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Display warning before session timeout</title>
				<description>Specify if a warning dialog should be shown in advance of the session timeout. This will allow the user to take an action to extend the session.</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Advance warning timing</title>
				<description>Specify how many minutes in advance of the session timeout the warning should be displayed.
</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Check for session timeout every
</title>
				<description>Specify how often (in minutes) the check for session timeout should be performed.
</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>After session timeout action
</title>
				<description>After the session has expired what action should be taken. 'Nothing' - keep the warning dialog box visible, but change the message to the session expired message, or 'Redirect to Another Page' - redirect to another page. To redirect back to the Tabbed UI, specify as the target page.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Nothing
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Redirect To Another Page</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Target page after session timeout</title>
				<description>Specify the target page after session timeout. Set to to reload the Tabbed UI page.
</description>
			</section>
				<section>
				<title>Confirmation button Javascript
</title>
				<description>After the session has expired, the dialog has an OK button that dismisses the warning dialog. You can optionally specify Javascript to execute when this button is clicked. You can use a special placeholder, '' to automatically generate the Javascript to reload this page.
</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Session Timeout Warning Customization</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Warning message template</title>
				<description>Specify the message template to show in the warning dialog. The template should include the {secondsToSessionEnd} placeholder. This placeholder will display the number of seconds until the session expires.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Extend session button label
</title>
				<description>Extend session button label property
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Warning window title
</title>
				<description>Warning window title property
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Session expired message
</title>
				<description>Specify the message to show in the message box after the session has expired.
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Button label after session expired
</title>
				<description>After the session has expired, the button to 'Extend the session' is no longer valid and is replaced with an OK button that simply dismisses the window. Specify the label for this button.
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Warning window title - after session has expired
</title>
				<description>After the session has timed out, specify the text for the warning window title.
</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Home Page</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				
				<title>Home page tab title</title>
				<description>Specify the tab title for the Home Page.
</description>
			</section>
					<section>
				
				<title>Home page HTML source
</title>
				<description>Specify if the HTML that appears on the Home page tab comes from a URL, or is defined locally.
</description>
			</section>
					<section>
				
				<title>Home page HTML
</title>
				<description>Specify the HTML that appears on the Home Page. TIP: The HTML can include  Xbasic code blocks which can reference session variables.
</description>
			</section>
					<section>
				
				<title>Home page URL
</title>
				<description>Specify the URL for the Home page. You can specify a static HTML document or dynamic .a5w page in your web project, or an external URL. TIP: Certain browsers (e.g. I.E.) might cache the home page. You can force the browser to always load the current version of the home page by including the following two meta tags in the HTML 'head' section: 
</description>
			</section>
					<section>
				
				<title>Home page auto-refresh
</title>
				<description>Specify if the home page should be refreshed every time it gets focus. TIP: Certain browsers (e.g. I.E.) might cache the home page. You can force the browser to always load the current version of the home page by including the following two meta tags in the HTML 'head' section: 
</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Animation</title>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Animate</title>
			<description>Specify if the buttons panel should be animated when it is shown/hidden.
</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Hide speed</title>
			<description>Specify the duration of the animation. You can enter a value in milliseconds. 'Slow' = 600ms, 'Fast' = 200ms. To turn animation off, enter 0.
</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Show speed</title>
			<description>Specify the duration of the animation. You can enter a value in milliseconds. 'Slow' = 600ms, 'Fast' = 200ms. To turn animation off, enter 0.</description>
		</section>
		
	</sections>	
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>CSS</title>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>A5Container class padding</title>
			<description>Every control is wrapped in a div with the class of 'a5container'. The padding specified here is the minimum space between adjacent controls. Use CSS syntax to specify padding. e.g. 10px, .1in, etc.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Local CSS definitions</title>
			<description>Define any local CSS classes.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Additional Grid styles
</title>
			<description>Specify if any other styles (in addition to the primary style for the Tabbed UI component) must be included. Enter a comma delimited list of style names. e.g., GlassOlive,Airport IMPORTANT If any of the Grids shown in the TabbedUI use a different style than the TabbeUI, their styles must be listed here.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>CSS Linked files</title>
			<description>Specify any CSS files that should be linked (in addition to the primary style for the Tabbed UI Component). Enter a comma delimited list of filenames.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>CSS (Font) Icons</title>
			<description>Specify if any CSS Icon libraries should be loaded.</description>
		</section>
		
	</sections>	
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Javascript</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Javascript Linked files
</title>
				<description>Specify any Javascript files that should be linked. Enter a comma delimited list of filenames.
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>JavaScript function declarations
</title>
				<description>Define JavaScript functions for various client-side events.
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Javascript to run on startup
</title>
				<description>Specify any Javascript you want to run when the Tabbed UI component loads. This Javascript will run after the Tabbed UI object has been instantiated.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Xbasic</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Xbasic Linked files
</title>
				<description>Specify any Xbasic Function Library files that should be linked. Enter a comma delimited list of filenames. Defining Xbasic functions in a Function Library (that can be shared among multiple components) is an alternative to defining your Xbasic functions in this component (see 'Xbasic functions' on the toolbox).</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Other</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Linked resources
</title>
				<description>Specify if this component should include CSS defined in any of the child Grid components that this component will open.
</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date format
</title>
				<description><![CDATA[Specify the format that the user must use for entering date values. (Applies in the case of Reports that prompt for date or time argument values.) In V11 and above an optional time format can also be specified. The time portion of the format string is separated from the date portion by '&&'.\TIP: You can specify the date format dynamically by setting the format using this session variable: __protected__clientSideDateFormat]]></description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use legacy date picker</title>
				<description>Specify if you want to use the legacy date picker, or the new date/time picker for V11 or above. If using a V11 style, you cannot use the legacy date picker.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Language definitions</title>
				<description>Define strings for different languages.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Text dictionary tags</title>
				<description>Show Text Dictionary tags (...) used in this component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Active language</title>
				<description>Specify the active language to use for translatating strings tagged with .. tags. Setting the property here is useful for for testing purposes. In a real application you can set the 'session.__protected__activeLanguage' variable to specify the active language. To select the default language, enter or leave this property blank.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Remove un-consumed language tags</title>
				<description>Should any language tags that were not replaced (because they were not defined in the Language Definition) be removed from any output sent to the browser?</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - day names</title>
				<description>Specify the names of the days of the week to be shown when the pop-up date picker is used. First entry in list MUST be Sunday (even if you set the 'first day of week' property to another day). Enter a comma separated list. TIP: You can also set the day names in this special session variable: session.__protected__datePickerDayNames</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - first day of week</title>
				<description>Specify the first day of the week. 1=Sunday, 2=Monday, etc. IMPORTANT: Regardless of what value you set here, if you customize the day names, the list of day names always starts with the name for Sunday.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - month names</title>
				<description>Specify the month names to be shown when the pop-up date picker is used to prompt for argument values. Enter a comma separated list. TIP: You can also set the month names in this special session variable: session.__protected__datePickerMonthNames</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - 'Today' button text</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the 'Today' button. You can tag the text with .. for automatic language translation.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - 'Close' button text</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the 'Close' button. You can tag the text with .. for automatic language translation.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Date picker - 'OK' button text</title>
				<description>Specify the text for the 'OK' button. You can tag the text with .. for automatic language translation.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group>
		<title>Advanced</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Other properties</title>
				<description>Other properties property</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	
</groups>	
	
	
	
</page>