<page>
	<topic>Video Player Component Properties</topic>
<groups>
	<group><title>Video Player Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Video player type</title>
				<description>Select YouTube Video Player if your videos are hosted on YouTube. The component uses the YouTube OEmbed API to embed a hybrid HTML5/Flash video player. Select HTML5 / Flash Video Player if you host the video files or utilize a streaming video service.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>YouTube Video Player Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Show YouTube video title</title>
				<description>Controls the display of the title of the YouTube video referenced by the video URL. If you are using a playlist, you may want to turn this option off since the title only references the video specified in the video URL.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>YouTube video URL</title>
				<description>The default is a promotional video on YouTube. This is provided for testing only. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use SSL</title>
				<description>If checked will force a https:// prefix when requesting the file from YouTube from within the player. This overcomes a limitation of the YouTube oEmbed API.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Start video at offset</title>
				<description>This parameter causes the player to begin playing the reference video at the given number of seconds from the start of the video. The player will look for the closest keyframe to the time you specify. This value is exposed as an argument and may be bound to a data field in a parent component. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Autoplay</title>
				<description>Not recommended since autoplay is considered an annoyance to users however, the option is available on desktop browsers. Mobile browsers do not support autoplay.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show related videos on completion</title>
				<description>Show related videos upon completion. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show video player controls</title>
				<description>Show video player controls. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show fullscreen button</title>
				<description>Show the full screen button within the YouTube Player to allow full screen viewing. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Autohide controls</title>
				<description>Autohide the video player controls. Controls will slide out of view after a couple of seconds from video playback start. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Set default video resolution to HD</title>
				<description>Displays the highest definition video available. Resolution displayed is optimized for the container size. Has no effect on the Chromeless Player. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer. Remember, HD consumes bandwidth.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Show video info</title>
				<description>Controls the display of the video title and info when the video starts and when it is paused. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use modest branding</title>
				<description>This parameter controls the display of the YouTube logo within the player control bar. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title><![CDATA[Loop & replay video or video playlist on end]]></title>
				<description>Enables automatic looping and replay of the video or the video and the video playlist. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use light color theme</title>
				<description>Sets the color scheme for the YouTube Player to light colors. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Related video playlist</title>
				<description>You can provide a playlist of related videos. This is simply a comma delimited list of YouTube video ID's. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component. Option is ignored in HTML5 mobile viewer.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>HTML5 / Flash Video Player Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>HTML5 / Flash Player Type</title>
				<description>Enables the selection of a hybrid HTML5 / Flash video player, a HTML5 only video player or a Flash only video player.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>MP4 Video</title>
				<description>The default is a sample open source MP4 video. This is provided for testing only. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component. Spaces are not allowed in the video URI.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Ogg Video</title>
				<description>The default is a sample open source Ogg video. This is provided for testing only. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component. Spaces are not allowed in the video URI.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>WebM Video</title>
				<description>The default is a sample open source WebM video. This is provided for testing only. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component. Spaces are not allowed in the video URI.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Poster Image</title>
				<description>The default is a sample open source jpg. This is provided for testing only. Typically this control is bound by an argument to a field in an Alpha Five data driven component. Spaces are not allowed in this URI.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Flash Player</title>
				<description>Multple Flash players are supported, each has a unique skin.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Video Player Priority</title>
				<description>Sets the preferred video player, should the browser support both Flash and HTML5. Default is HTML5 video with Flash video fallback.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Fallback Title</title>
				<description>The fallback title is displayed if the poster image is missing.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Autoplay</title>
				<description>Not recommended since autoplay is considered an annoyance to users however, the option is available on desktop browsers. Mobile browsers do not support autoplay.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Video Player Display Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Video container aspect ratio</title>
				<description>Typical videographic aspect ratios are 16:9 (widescreen format) and 4:3 (standard format)</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Video container height</title>
				<description>Height is computed based on the width and aspect ratio. Default value is contained in the embed code, returned by the YouTube Oembed API. It is typically 295px through 390px.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Video container height</title>
				<description>Height is computed based on the width and aspect ratio.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Video container width</title>
				<description>Allows you to specify the width of the control in pixels. Default value is contained in the embed code, returned by the YouTube Oembed API. It is typically 425px through 480px.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Video container width</title>
				<description>Allows you to specify the width of the control in pixels. Minimum allowed is 200.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Center component in container</title>
				<description>Adds a CSS style to center the video controller within the container div.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
	</group>
	
</groups>	
	
	
	
</page>