<page>
	<topic>Web Security</topic>
<groups>
	<group><title>Security Policy</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Security active</title>
				<description>If security is not activated, all objects and actions will be available to all users without restriction. If security is active, the security system is based on membership in a group.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password required</title>
				<description>Select to require a password as well as a User ID for login. A User ID is always required if security is activate.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Redirect page - login</title>
				<description>This is the name of the page to go to if login is required to access a selected page. This would normally be the login page, or a menu or index page.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Redirect page - insufficient permission</title>
				<description>If a logged in user does not have permission to access a selected page, they will be redirected to this page. If this page is not specified, they will be redirected to the page specified for login.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Use Active Directory</title>
				<description>__activeDirectoryHelpText__</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Security Table Type</title>
				<description>Select the data type for storing the web security data. If the type is changed from 'DBF Files' to 'SQL Database', a genie will open when the security settings are saved to set the connection to the SQL database and define the tables to construct. If the type is changed from 'SQL database' to 'DBF Files', a prompt will display on save to confirm the conversion.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Security Table Type for Development and Testing</title>
				<description>Select the data type for storing the web security data that will be used during development and testing of the application. The production deployment of the application will use Active Directory for user authentication and authorization. If the type is changed from 'DBF Files' to 'SQL Database', a genie will open when the security settings are saved to set the connection to the SQL database and define the tables to construct. If the type is changed from 'SQL database' to 'DBF Files', a prompt will display on save to confirm the conversion.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Login Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Login expiration policy</title>
				<description>Policy to set a maximum login time period. All options other than 'Expires when current session expires' require the use of a cookie. If the user does not have cookies enabled, they will be logged out when the session expires.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login expiration time</title>
				<description>Allows setting an expiration time for a login. A user must login again when the login expires. The default expiration time is 1 day.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Remember me option</title>
				<description>This option is only available when using the login component. The Remember Me option gives the ability to provide an automatic login. If the option is active, the user can select to save their login information. This information will then be entered automatically whenever login is required. This is done by placing a tracking cookie on the user's computer.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Lockout after failed attempts</title>
				<description>The number of times a user can try to login unsuccesfully before they are locked out of the application. Set to 0 to allow unlimited attempts.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Locked out action</title>
				<description>The action that should be taken if a user is locked out of the system. 'Wait for period of time' will require the user to wait a specified time until they are allowed to login with same User ID. 'Redirect to another page' will send them to another page. 'Lockout user until reset by administrator' will lock out the User ID until lock is manually released.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Locked out message</title>
				<description>Message to show the user during login to indicate they are locked out of the system.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Locked out wait time</title>
				<description>Locked out wait time property</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Locked out redirect page</title>
				<description>This is the page to go to if the user is locked out after the defined number of attempts. This page may have some developer specified action or notice.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login activity file</title>
				<description>When enabled, will save all login activity to a text file in the specified folder</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login activity log save to</title>
				<description>Folder where activity log file will be saved. Select 'User defined function' to enter your own code to process log activity data.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login activity user defined function</title>
				<description>Specific values are available to a user defined function. These values can be used to save login activity data to a file or table.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login activity include failed</title>
				<description>When enabled, all failed attempts to log in will be recorded in the login activity log. If not checked, only successful logins are recorded in the log file.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login activity include logout</title>
				<description>When enabled, any user logged out by the 'a5ws_logoutuser()' function will be recorded in the login activity log. No log entry will be created if no one is logged on when the log out function is called.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Login redirect option</title>
				<description> Login redirect only applies when a login component is used for login. This determines the action to take after a successful login. Select 'Current page' if the user should stay on the page containing the login component. Select 'Same page for all logins' to send all users to the same page after login. Select 'Page assigned by user' to allow setting a specific page in the user profile.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Redirect page after login using login component</title>
				<description> Login redirect only applies when a login component is used for login. This is the name of the page to go to after a successful login. If the redirect option is 'Page assigned by user', this page will be used if a redirect page is not assigned in the current user profile.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Ignore return to page after login</title>
				<description>This option is only used when a login component is used for login. When a person attempts to open a page or component for which they do not have permission, they are redirected to the login page. The default action is to always redirect to the page specified by the 'Login redirect option' and the 'Redirect page after login using login component'. Uncheck this to return to the previous page. This option is automatically checked if component security is active.</description>
			</section>
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>User ID Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>User ID configuration</title>
				<description>A User ID can be configured to allow an email address or a field value that meets specified validation rules.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User ID error message</title>
				<description>Message to display if the User ID is configured as an Email address and the entered value is not a valid Email address. This message may be replaced with a message defined in a Login component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User ID validation rules</title>
				<description>Specify rules to test if the value for User ID is valid.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Password Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Password encryption</title>
				<description>Allows password data to be encrypted prior to saving in the user table.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password encryption key</title>
				<description>Enter the key to use to encrypt all password. A key is required if encryption is selected. Key must be a minimum of 8 characters and a maximum of 64 characters in length. The key can use characters, numbers, and special characters.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Allow password change at login</title>
				<description>This option is only used by the login component. Allow the user to change their password at login when using the login component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password validation rules</title>
				<description>Specify rules to test if the value for the password is valid.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password expires?</title>
				<description>Allows setting an expiration time for a password. A new password must be entered when the current password expires.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password expiration time</title>
				<description>The period of time a password will be active before it automatically expires. The expiration is re-calculated when a new password is entered. The default expiration time is 1 year.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password change on first use</title>
				<description>Require a user to immediately change their password at login after it has been reset. The login component must allow the user to change their password at login. NOTE: Some method to change the user password must be provided if using any login method other than the login component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password restricted re-use</title>
				<description>The number of old passwords that are saved in a restricted list and can not be re-used. A value of 0 will allow any password to be re-used without restriction. A value of 1 will only require that a new password does not match the current password</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password restricted re-use message</title>
				<description>Message to show if the user entered a restricted password. This message may be replaced during login with a message defined in a Login component.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Lost Data Recovery Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Allow user ID recovery</title>
				<description>Allow the user to recover their User ID if they have lost it.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Data required for recovery</title>
				<description>The information that must be entered to identify the user to recover the User ID</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Lost password action</title>
				<description>Allow the user to recover or reset a lost password. If 'reset' is selected, the system will automatically generate a new random password that meets the password validation rules.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Data required for password reset or recovery</title>
				<description>The information that must be entered to identify the user to recover or reset the password.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Lost data recovery method</title>
				<description>Method that is used to recover a lost user id or password. If 'Send Email to user' is selected and the Host computer is not configured to send Email, the alternative method will be used. 'Create Email link on page' will show an email link on the page that will allow the user to send a pre-configured email request for lost data to a defined address.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Lost data recovery alternative method</title>
				<description>Method that will be used to recover a lost user id or password if 'Send Email to user' is selected and the Host computer is not configured to send Email. 'Create Email link on page' will show an email link on the page that will allow the user to send a pre-configured email request for lost data to a defined address.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Email profile for sending emails</title>
				<description>Enter the name of an email profile that is configured on the application server in the published location. If no profile is specified, the send email process will attempt to use the current active email profile on the server. If the profile specified is invalid or not found on the server, the alternate recovery method will be used.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Send user ID with password?</title>
				<description>Should the lost data recovery Email being sent to the user include both their User ID and their Password in the same message? If not selected, 2 emails will be sent if the recovery process was used to find their User ID</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Configure email to send to user</title>
				<description>This is the Email configuration to create an email to send to the listed Email address for the user. The Host computer MUST be configured to send email. The email will include the User ID and Password in the same email and will be used if the user is requesting a lost User ID and a lost Password</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Configure email to send to user with user ID</title>
				<description>This is the Email configuration to create an email to send to the listed Email address for the user. The Host computer MUST be configured to send email. The email will only contain the User ID and will be used if the user is requesting a lost User ID</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Configure email to send to user with password</title>
				<description>This is the Email configuration to create an email to send to the listed Email adress for the user. The Host computer MUST be configured to send email. The email will only contain only the Password and will be used if the user is only requesting a lost Password</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Configure email request from user</title>
				<description>This is the Email configuration that will create an email request from the user. The user can send an email to the defined address to request login information.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Security questions</title>
				<description>This is a list of 'Security' questions that can be used to verify a user. The user can select a question and supply an answer as a means of identification</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title>Customize Options</title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title>Enable external user identifier field</title>
				<description>This option is no longer recommended. The security 'userid' should be stored in an external table if linking is required. User records may also exist in tables outside of the security system. This option will enable a special field named 'ulink'. The value entered in the 'ulink' field can identify a related user record in the external table.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Session variable for identifier field</title>
				<description>(Optional) Enter the name of a session variable to contain the value from the 'ulink' field. If the security framework is on, the session variable will always exist for every page. The variable value will be blank if no one is logged on, or contain a 'ulink' value from the logged in user record, if a value exists for that user.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Prompt to display for identifier field</title>
				<description>Enter the prompt to display on the Users and Groups form for the 'ulink' field. The text can describe the source of the value.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User verification field values required</title>
				<description>This option is only available when using the login component. You have enabled the feature that allows a user to recover lost login information. This option will determine if values in the User Verification Fields MUST be entered, or if they are OPTIONAL.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User recovery email invalid message</title>
				<description>Message to show if the email entered to identify a user for data recovery is not a valid email address</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User ID not unique error message</title>
				<description>Used ID values must be unique. This message will display if the User ID entered already exists in the user table. This message is only used in a web component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>User file - required data missing message</title>
				<description>This message is displayed if required data is missing when saving a new or changed user record. This message is only used in a web component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Password - confirm password doesn't match message</title>
				<description>This message is only displayed if an optional 'confirm_password' value doesn't match the entered password. This message is only used in a web component.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Enable component security for 'virtual pages'</title>
				<description>Some Ajax actions open grids and reports on virtual pages. The default security for virtual pages is 'Always Allowed'. Select this option to enable security at the component level. When selected, components and reports on virtual pages are 'Always Denied' by default and must be have permissions set. Grids on pages use the page permission.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Always enforce security at component level for AJAX grids</title>
				<description>AJAX grids on pages use the page permission. Checking this option will force all Ajax actions to use the component security permissions defined in the Web Security instead of the page permission. Grids opened on virtual pages always use the component security permissions if component security is enabled.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Ask browser to not cache requests requiring login</title>
				<description>Check this option to ask a browser to turn off caching for any item that requires login. This ONLY applies to requests for items that require login to view. This will normally cause the browser to make a new request for a page if the browser 'back' or 'forward' buttons are used. Caching will still be permitted if security is off, or the page or component requested is always allowed.</description>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Cache lifetime (in seconds)</title>
				<description>The security settings are cached on the server for improved speed and are not automatically updated when the new settings are published. The cache lifetime (in seconds) determines how often the server will check for updates. A value of 300 will allow the server to check for new published settings every 5 minutes. Set the value to 0 to never check for updates.</description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	<group><title></title>
		<sections>
			<section>
				<title></title>
				<description></description>
			</section>
			
			
		</sections>
		
		
	</group>
	
	
	
	
</groups>	
	
	
	
	
	
</page>