<page>
	<topic>Web Project Settings</topic>
	
<groups>
<group>
	<title>Run Time Properties</title>
</group>	
	
<group>
	<title>Project style</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Project style</title><description>

Specify the name of the style for all components in the project. NOTE: In each individual component, you must specify the style name as . Tip: You can perform a global update of your components to change the style name to  by selecting Edit, Bulk operations from the menu when the Web Projects Control Panel has focus.</description></case>

</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>		

<group>
	<title>Web site defaults</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Default page</title><description>

Select the default page to be returned when no page is specified in the request. This value is only used when publishing to an IIS server. See the Xbasic server settings for its list of default page names.
</description></case><case><title>
Session lifetime (minutes)</title><description>

Enter the number of minutes a session will remain active on the server without any requests from the user. A session will automatically end on the server if no requests are recieved from the user in this amount of time. This value is only used when publishing to an IIS server.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Aex files</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
File list</title><description>

Property name: aexFiles.fileNames Specify the name of any .aex files that you want to load when this project is run. AEX Files specified here are loaded automatically when the application is run. It is not necessary to use the a5w_load_aex() function.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>File Download</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Allowed filenames</title><description>

Enter a comma delimited list of allowed files that can be downloaded from the server. Enter filename patterns using wildcard characters (* and ?). To allow any type of file, enter *.* For example, if you enter: a5*.xls,a5*.pdf - Only .xls files and .pdf files that start with 'a5' can be downloaded. If you only want to specify a list of blocked filename patterns, leave this property blank, or enter *.*.
</description></case><case><title>
Disallowed filename</title><description>

Enter a comma delimited list of files that can not be downloaded from the server. Enter filename patterns using wildcard characters (* and ?).
</description></case><case><title>
Allowed folders</title><description>

Enter a comma delimited list of folder names from which files can be downloaded. You can use wildcard characters (* and ?) in the name. Specify  in the list to allow downloads from the user's session folder (NOT supported in V12 or above). Example: *\images,*\pdf - would allow user to download from a folder called 'images' or 'pdf' on any drive. d:\images would only allow download from the 'images' folder on drive D on the server. NOTE: In V12 and above,  is not supported. NOTE2: If you leave this blank (not recommended) then files can be downloaded from any folder. NOTE3: You can use the  placeholder in the folder name you specify. e.g. \DownloadFolder
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Javascript Libraries</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
jQuery Core</title><description>

Load jQuery core Javascript Library. You can choose where the library is loaded from. Alpha Anywhere has a built-in version of this library, or you can load it from the Google Content Delivery Network, or the jQuery Content Delivery Network. When you load from Google, you must specify the version you want to load. When you load from the jQuery CDN, the latest stable release is automatically loaded.
</description></case><case><title>
jQuery Core Version

Specify the version number you want to load
</description></case><case><title>
jQuery UI</title><description>

Load jQuery UI Javascript Library. Requires jQuery Core. You can choose where the library is loaded from. Alpha Anywhere has a built-in version of this library, or you can load it from the Google Content Delivery Network.
</description></case><case><title>
jQuery UI Version</title><description>

Specify the version number you want to load
</description></case><case><title>
Links</title><description>

Specify a list of Javascript libraries to link
</description></case><case><title>
Include Image Gallery</title><description>

Specify if the Image Gallery Javascript libraries should be loaded. If you use the Image Gallery anywhere in your application you must check this option. NOTE: If this option is checked, then you must also check the options to load jQuery core.
</description></case><case><title>
Include Google JSAPI library</title><description>

Specify if the Google Javascript API library should be loaded. This is needed if you use the Google visualization library in the UX component.
</description></case><case><title>
Cordova/PhoneGap libraries</title><description>

If you are building a hybrid mobile application that requires a Cordova/PhoneGap Javascript library, specify where the Javascript should be loaded from. 'BuiltIn' - use the built-in version of either the iOS or Android library, 'Local' - use a version that is loaded from a file in the web root. (The file must be loaded in a folder that follows the required naming convention: e.g. Javascript\Cordova\IOS\currentVersion\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\IOS\2.8.0\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\Android\currentVersion\cordova.js, Javascript\Cordova\Android\2.8.0\cordova.js
</description><cases>
	<case><description>
•BuiltIn</description></case><case><description>
•Local</description></case>
</cases>

<case><title>
Include CKEdit HTML Editor Javascript library</title><description>

If your component uses the CKEdit HTML editor you must check this box to load the necessary Javascript and CSS libraries.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	


<group>
	<title>CSS Libraries</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
jQuery CSS</title><description>

Specify which jQuery UI CSS library should be loaded. These libraries are loaded from the Google Content Delivery Network.
</description></case><case><title>
Links</title><description>

Specify a list of CSS libraries to link
</description></case>
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Resource Providers</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Named Providers</title><description>

Resource providers such as Google and Facebook can be used for user authentication or access to resources that are available from the provider, such as calendars and documents. A user can log onto a system using their credentials from the provider in place of the user name and password in the web security system. A named provider is used to configure the connection to a specific resource provider.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Webkit (Chrome/Safari) Specific</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Allow static text selection</title><description>

For mobile applications, this property should be set to .f. This will prevent static-text on a page from being selectable. For desktop applications you might want to set this property to .t. so that users can select static-text.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Stripe Checkout</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Define keys</title><description>

Define keys property
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	


<group>
	<title>E-mail Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
SMTP Server</title><description>

Specify the SMTP server for sending e-mail.
</description></case><case><title>
SMTP server port</title><description>

Specify the port.
</description></case><case><title>
SSL Option</title><description>

Specify the SSL option. If not using SSL, leave blank. Example settings: SSL, TLS.
</description></case><case><title>
E-mail account user name</title><description>

Specify the user name for the e-mail account used to send e-mail.
</description></case><case><title>
E-mail account password</title><description>

Specify the password for the e-mail account used to send e-mail.
</description></case><case><title>
From address</title><description>

Specify the default from address for e-mails sent from this application.
</description></case><case><title>
From alias</title><description>

Specify the default friendly name for the from address for e-mails sent from this application.
</description></case><case><title>
Mandrill key</title><description>

If you use the Mandrill web service to send email, you can set the key value here. If you set the value here you will not need to set the value each time you call the Mandrill web service (using the email_send_mandrill() Xbasic function).
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>E-mail Outbox</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

Specify if the e-mail outbox is a .DBF or SQL table. The e-mail outbox stores a copy of e-mail messages sent from this application.
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Sent e-mail can optionally be stored in an outbox. Specify the connection string to the SQL database where the outbox is stored.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name of the outbox.
</description></case><case><title>
Sequence name</title><description>

Specify the sequence name. Only needed for database such as Oracle and Posgres that use sequences for auto-increment fields.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the outbox table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Repository Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

Specify if the repository is a .DBF or SQL table.
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Specify the connection string to the SQL database.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the repository table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Work Queue Table Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

Specify the table type.
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Specify the connection string to the SQL database.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the Work Queue table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>		

<group>
	<title>Help Table Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

Specify if the Help Table is a .DBF or SQL table.
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Specify the connection string to the SQL database.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the Help Table table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Text Dictionary Table Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

Specify if the Text Dictionary Table is a .DBF or SQL table.
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Specify the connection string to the SQL database.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the Text Dictionary Table table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	


<group>
	<title>Offline Data Synchronization Log Table Settings</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Table type</title><description>

ALWAYS SET TO SQL
</description></case><case><title>
Connection string</title><description>

Specify the connection string to the SQL database.
</description></case><case><title>
Table name</title><description>

Specify the table name.
</description></case><case><title>
Field map</title><description>

Specify how the fields in the Data Synchronization Log table are mapped to the required fields. Only fields that are different from their 'system' value are shown in the map.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Application Global Variables</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Define application variables</title><description>

Specify any application global variables. These variables can be seen by every page and component in this application.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Calendar Component</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
License number</title><description>

Specify the license number for your Calendar component. The license number in the Calendar component itself should be set to: .
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>PDF Printing Options</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Use Microsoft XPS printer to generate PDF files</title><description>

Specify if the Microsoft XPS printer should be used instead of the Amyuni PDF printer driver to generate PDF files. When you use this option, you can specify if the resulting XPS files should be converted to PDF files before being sent to the browser, or if they should be sent to the browser as XPS files.</description></case><case><title>

Convert XPS files to PDF before sending to client</title><description>

Should XPS files be converted to PDF before being sen to the browser? IMPORTANT: If you choose to send the resulting XPS files to the browser without first converting them to PDF, only Microsoft Internet Explorer will be able to display the file directly in the browser. All other browsers will download the file and you will have to use the local XPS viewer application to see the file.
</description></case><case><title>
Print timeout (seconds)</title><description>

Large PDF reports may take a long time to build and you may want to cancel reports that take too long to create. The print timeout setting will cancel any report that has not completed in the allowed time (in seconds). Set the timeout to 0 to allow all reports to run to completion. An error will be reported back to the user if a report is cancelled because it exceeded the allowed time.
</description></case><case><title>
Print timeout message (optional)</title><description>

The system will generate an error message if a PDF report times out. Any optional message entered here will replace the system error message if the report times out.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Report Server</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Disable</title><description>

Specify if the Report Server (used for printing PDF Reports in Web Applications) should be disabled. By default (in V12 and above) a 4 core Report Server is automatically enabled. (To license a Report Server that uses more than 4 cores, contact Alpha Software).
</description></case><case><title>
Use For HTML Reports</title><description>

Offload HTML reports to the report server. This option should be used under conditions where your HTML reports are very large or complex.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Web-socket Applications</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Enable web-socket application</title><description>

Specify if web-socket applications are enabled.
</description></case><case><title>
Web-socket server port</title><description>

Specify the port that the web-socket server runs on. This must be a different port than the Alpha Anywhere server
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	
<group>
	<title>Design Time Properties</title>
</group>

<group>
	<title>Automatic Backups</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Backup folder</title><description>

When you edit your Components an automatic backup is created. If you leave this property blank, the backups are stored in a subfolder in your web project. You can specify a folder where you would like the backups to be stored.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>		

<group>
	<title>Create AEX for Live Preview</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Auto-create AEX for Live Preview</title><description>

When doing a Live Preview from a component builder, should all functions and classes defined in the Code tab of the Control Panel be compiled into an AEX file and automatically be published to the LivePreview folder? If you components do not reference any global UDFs, then this property can be turned off.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>Live Preview</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Prompt to start server for Live Preview</title><description>

When you select Live Preview while working in a Component Builder, if the server is not started, Alpha Anywhere will prompt if you want to start the server. In some cases you might have a server started in another Alpha Anywhere instance, so it would not be necessary to start the server in the current Alpha Anywhere instance. If you check this property, the prompt to start the server will be suppressed.
</description></case>
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	

<group>
	<title>A5_Application.A5I File</title>
<sections>
<section>
<cases><case><title>
Encrypt connection strings</title><description>

Specify if connection strings in the a5_application.a5i file should be encrypted. Encryption is recommended. Turn encryption off if you are trying to debug a connection problem and want to see what connection strings are getting published.
</description></case>
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</group>	


</groups>	
	
	
</page>