<page>
	<topic>Combo Boxes</topic>
	<sections>
<section>
	<description>Combo boxes are variants on the text box and radio button controls. Like a radio button, a combo box displays a list of values, but it displays the choices in a drop-down text box.
You can specify the choices for the combo in one of three ways:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Enclosing a comma separated list between  '{' and '}'  e.g. {Red,Green,Blue}
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>By referring to an array that contains the choices
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>By referring to a string variable that contains a CR-LF delimited list of choices
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<description>The syntax for a combo box object is:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[[.size variable_name^={choice1,choice2,choiceN}]     or,
[.size variable_name^=choice_variable]     or,
[.size variable_name^=choice_array] ]]></example>
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Where choice1, choice2, choiceN are the actual choices, or choice_variable is the name of a string that contains CR-LF delimited choices, or choice_array is the name of a array that contains the choices.
The value of variable_name is a base-1 index if the variable is declared as Numeric. If undeclared or left un-initialized, the variable is a string that returns the text of the choice that is selected.
The following script demonstrates a combo box in which the choices are explicitly stated by enclosing the choices between the '{' and '}' characters.
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[mode = "Shared"
result=ui_dlg_box("Title",<<%dlg%
Filename:| [.32filename];
Open as:;
Mode:| [.10 mode^={Shared,Read only,Exclusive}];

%dlg% ) ]]></example>
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>This script creates this dialog, Combo Boxes: 
</description>
	<figure><link>images/XD_combo_box.gif</link></figure>
	<note>Notice in the above script the use of the '|' character to line up the combo box and the text box.
</note>
</section>

<section>
	<title>Combo Boxes - Populated from a String
</title>
	<description>The following script is identical to the previous script, except that the choices displayed by the combo box come from a variable, which contains a CR-LF delimited list of choices. In addition, mode is declared as a numeric variable. Therefore, the dialog box will set its value to 1, 2, or 3.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[mode = 1
choices = <<%dlg%
Shared
Read only
Exclusive
%dlg%
result=ui_dlg_box("Title",<<%dlg%
Filename:| [.32filename];
Open as:;
Mode:| [.10 mode^=choices];

%dlg% ) ]]></example>
	
</section>		
		
	</sections>
	<limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
	<see>
		<ref>List Boxes</ref>
	</see>
</page>