<page>
   <topic>UI_GET_PATH Function</topic>
   <syntax>path as C = ui_get_path(C title ,C drive_list ,C default )</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>path</name>
         <description>The selected directory. The directory must exist. If the Starting_Folder does not exist, the first subfolder that does exist will be returned.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>title</name>
         <description>The title of the dialog box.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>drive_list</name>
         <description>The drive portion of the path to display. You can specify multiple drives separated by semicolons ("C:\;D:\"). Do not add spaces between drives. 
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>default</name>
         <description>The directory portion of the path to display. Note : The default directory must have a trailing backslash.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Prompt user for a file path. If drive_list is blank, shows all drives. Drive_list is a semi-colon delimited list of drives. TIP: You can also use ui_browse_for_folder() to use the standard Windows control.</description>
   <discussion>
UI_GET_PATH() displays a dialog box that allows the user to select a folder (i.e. sub-directory). The dialog displays all of the folders on Drive, starting in the Starting_Folder. 
</discussion>
<sections><section>
<figure><link>images/ui_get_path.gif</link></figure>

</section></sections>

<sections><section><description>
 Note : The Starting_Folder directory must exist. If you use the final "\" character after a path, either escape it with a second "\" character or add a final space " " character.
This function cannot be used to select the root folder of a drive. To do that, use the ui_browse_for_folder Function.  In addition, the ui_get_path function is written in Xbasic and is not a 'standard' way of prompting for a folder. The ui_browse_for_folder Function wraps the standard windows control for prompting for a folder name, and so this control might be more familiar to users. The ui_get_path() function allows the user to create new folders, whereas ui_browse_for_folder() does not. If you do not need the option to create new folders, prefer the ui_browse_for_folder Function.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.</description>
   </section></sections>

  
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>Display the dialog shown in the above diagram.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
path = UI_GET_PATH ("Enter Path","c\: ", "c:\windows\\")
ui_get_path("Folder Name", "C:\;D:\ ", "C:\documents\ ")
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>User Interaction Functions</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/System/Directory Functions/index.xml">Directory Functions</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/System/Directory Functions/UI_BROWSE_FOR_FOLDER Function.xml">ui_browse_for_folder Function</ref>
   </see>
<terms>directory,box,control,defaults,display,file,function,list,users,xbasic</terms>
</page>