<page>
    <topic>Defining Field and Menu Security</topic>
    <description>You may control access to a control of a Grid or UX component, or a menu entry of a Navigation System Component by specifying which groups are permitted to see it.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Access to individual controls and fields in components and menus can be restricted based on a user's Security Group. By default, access is allowed for all users in the security system. The *[ui:Security Groups]* property for a control or menu item can be used to restrict access to specific users in the system.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Assigning Security to Controls in UX Components</title>
            <description>
                <p>Individual controls can be assigned Security Groups in a UX Component. If assigned a Security Group, only users who are members of the groups specified in the Security Groups property will be allowed to use the control.</p>
            </description>
            <important>
                <p>If a user does not have permissions to access a control on a component, the control is removed from the HTML sent to the client's browser. If your component is pre-rendered at design time, controls that have restricted security access may not be included in the pre-rendered component unless security settings are applied on the client. See [How to Apply Security Settings Client-Side] to learn more.</p>
            </important>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] smart field button in the Row Properties &gt; Security Groups property for a control to display the Permissions dialog.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Check the groups that will be granted access and click OK to save the security settings.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Assigning Security to Fields in Grid Components</title>
            <description>
                <p></p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] smart field button in the Column Properties &gt; Security Groups property for a field to display the Permissions dialog.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Check the groups that will be granted access and click OK to save the security settings.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Assigning Security to Menus in a Navigation System Component</title>
            <description></description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>Click the [...] smart field button in the Node Settings &gt; Security Groups property for a menu item to display the Permissions dialog.</description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Check the groups that will be granted access and click OK to save the security settings.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref>Web Application Security Framework</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="applying%20client%20side%20security">How to Apply Security Settings Client-Side</link>
    </links>
</page>