<page>
   <topic>Sql_get_Values Function</topic>
   <syntax>c Values = sql_get_values(* conn ,C table ,C filter ,C result_Expression [,L flagDistinct [,N limit [,L flagDescendingOrder [,* args ]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
<argument>
         <name>Values</name>
         <description>A CRLF delimited string of data from the remote table or query. CRLFs  in the data are encoded as '\cr\lf'.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>conn</name>
         <description>An explicit AlphaDAO connection string, or a named connection string.  (e.g. ::name::myconnectionstring), or a pointer to an open connection.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>table</name>
         <description>The name of the table in the remote database from which to return  data.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>filter</name>
         <description>A filter expression to determine which records in the remote table to  find. The filter expression must use SQL syntax and must use portable AlphaDAO  functions. For example, strings must be single quoted, the AND,  OR and NOT  operators are not surrounded by periods. The filter expression can use  arguments. For example, customerid = :whatcustomerid. If  table_or_sql_statement is a SQL SELECT then filter is meaningless  and must be set to a null string.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>result_Expression</name>
         <description>A expression to determine what values gets returned. The expression  can be as simple as a single column name in the remote table, or it can be a  complex expression. The expression must be written using portable AlphaDAO  syntax.
r</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>flagDistinct</name>
         <description>Logical. Default for this if .f.. Specify if only unique values should be  returned.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>limit</name>
         <description>Numeric. Default for this is 1,000. Specify the maximum number of values to  return.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>flagDescendingOrder</name>
         <description>Logical. Default for this is .f.. Specify if values should be returned in  descending order.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>args</name>
         <description>If the filter expression includes arguments, you must supply  argument values using a SQL::arguments object.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Returns a CRLF delimited string with data from a table in a remote database using AlphaDAO. Connection can be explicit, or a named connection (e.g. ::name::myconnection).</description>
   
   <terms>sql helper,column,database,filter,function,number,pointer,set,sql,string</terms>
</page>