<page>
    <shortlink>Current and Pre Release Notes</shortlink>
    <topic>Release Notes</topic>
    <description>Follow the links below to read the release notes for the current release and pre-release versions of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Alpha Anywhere 4.6 Now Available!</title>
            <description>
                <p>*[link:This release@https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index?search=aav4_6_0%20overview]* includes dozens of new features across the board for web and mobile applications, as well as new tools for working with Alpha TransForm and speed enhancements for deploying your Alpha Cloud applications.</p>
                <p>Features in Alpha Anywhere 4.6 include integrated Two-factor Authentication for more secure application login, integrated source control using Git and GitHub, SAP HANA data integration, Chunked Responses for giving users progress reports for long-running server tasks, report optimizations that speed up generating reports, upgraded web security with support for TLS 1.3, and more. Alpha Anywhere developers who are also using Alpha TransForm can also leverage the new Alpha Anywhere onSubmit Genie to create reports, send emails, and import form data directly into any database from their TransForm accounts.</p>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere 4.6 also marks the initial release of Alpha Software's WkWebView plugin as a solution for rendering controls in PhoneGap applications. WkWebView serves as a replacement for iOS's UIWebView which has been deprecated and will be removed in a future release of iOS. Users are strongly encouraged to switch to the new WkWebView plugin prior to the next release of iOS in order to ensure their applications continue to run smoothly on future versions of iOS.</p>
                <p>*[link:Click here to learn more.@https://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index?search=aav4_6_0%20overview]*</p>
            </description> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Release Overviews</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:*Release-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Release Videos</title>
            <description>
                <p>Many releases of Alpha Anywhere include new videos. Click the link below for a list of videos released with the version of Alpha Anywhere listed.</p>
            </description>
            <note>Alpha Anywhere 1.0 was the successor to Alpha Five Version 11.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:*Videos-->
            <!--order:
Alpha Anywhere 4.6 Release
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4 Release
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.3 Release
Alpha Anywhere 4.6 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.5 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.4 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.3 Videos
Alpha Five Version 11 Videos
Alpha Five Version 10 Videos
Alpha Five Version 10 Desktop Videos
-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Technical Release Notes</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Release Notes describes updates and fixes made to Alpha Anywhere since its initial release. *[extlink:Click here@http://aadocuments.s3.amazonaws.com/ReleaseNotes/ReleaseNotes.Html]* to view the release notes.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Pre-Release Builds</title>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to the official updates that Alpha Software makes available from time to time (which are described in this document), we also make available our internal pre-release builds that allow you to see what features have been added and what bugs have been fixed since the last official update. The features and bug fixes in the pre-release build will be part of the next official update.</p>
                <p>*[extlink:Click here to view the Pre-Release Notes.@http://aadocuments.s3.amazonaws.com/ReleaseNotes/PreReleaseNotes.Html]*</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="a5v10 desktop videos">Alpha Five Version 10 Videos</link>
        <link link="a5v10 web app videos">Alpha Five Version 10 Desktop Videos</link>
        <link link="a5v11 videos">Alpha Five Version 11 Videos</link>
        <link link="Xbasic return">RETURN</link>
        <link link="Xbasic if then else">ENDIF</link>
        <link link="ux component listcolumnselector method">toggling visible columns</link>
        <link link="ux list fields client side properties word wrapping option">content behavior</link>
        <link link="server ref Web Project Settings#section2_Delete old backups">component backups</link>
        <link link="list columns showhide control">new pre-built control</link>
        <link link="server ref Web Project Settings#section2_Switch year">switch year for 2-digit dates</link>
        <link link=""></link>
    </links>
</page>