<page>
    <shortlink>Current and Pre Release Notes</shortlink>
    <topic>Release Notes</topic>
    <description>Follow the links below to read the release notes for the current release and pre-release versions of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4.8 Now Available!</title>
            <description>
                <p>Several features were added in Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4.8, including:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Upgraded to use OpenSSL version 1.0.2q.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>More fine-tuned control for List columns for setting visibility and content behavior as well as new complementary JavaScript methods for toggling column visibility.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>More pre-defined buttons for the ControlBar.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>New enhancements that let you easily create Javascript Actions from defined event handlers.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>New keywords added to the Xbasic language: *[xb:RETURN]* (defines a value to return from a function) and *[xb:ENDIF]* (identical to *[xb:END IF]*).</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Numerous IDE improvements including: specify default switch year for 2-digit dates, property grid enhancements including grid lines and active property highlighting, interface for deleting old component backups, and more.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Release Overviews</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:*Release-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Release Videos</title>
            <description>
                <p>Every release of Alpha Anywhere includes new videos. Click the link below for a list of videos released with the version of Alpha Anywhere listed.</p>
            </description>
            <note>Alpha Anywhere 1.0 was the successor to Alpha Five Version 11.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:*Videos-->
            <!--order:
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4 Release
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.3 Release
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.4 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.3 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.2 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.1 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.5.0 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.4 Videos
Alpha Anywhere 4.3 Videos
Alpha Five Version 11 Videos
Alpha Five Version 10 Videos
Alpha Five Version 10 Desktop Videos
-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Technical Release Notes</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Release Notes describes updates and fixes made to Alpha Anywhere since its initial release. *[extlink:Click here@http://aadocuments.s3.amazonaws.com/ReleaseNotes/ReleaseNotes.Html]* to view the release notes.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Pre-Release Builds</title>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to the official updates that Alpha Software makes available from time to time (which are described in this document), we also make available our internal pre-release builds that allow you to see what features have been added and what bugs have been fixed since the last official update. The features and bug fixes in the pre-release build will be part of the next official update.</p>
                <p>*[extlink:Click here to view the Pre-Release Notes.@http://aadocuments.s3.amazonaws.com/ReleaseNotes/PreReleaseNotes.Html]*</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="a5v10 desktop videos">Alpha Five Version 10 Videos</link>
        <link link="a5v10 web app videos">Alpha Five Version 10 Desktop Videos</link>
        <link link="a5v11 videos">Alpha Five Version 11 Videos</link>
    </links>
</page>