<page>
    <shortlink>grid conditional styles</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Client Side Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Conditional Styles">Conditional Styles</topic>
    <description>Conditional Styles contain conditions that are evaluated in a Browser using Javascript. </description>

    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>This makes it possible to dynamically style controls without having to make Ajax callbacks. For example, if a user enters an exceedingly large value into a Quantity field, the entry can immediately be displayed in red to show it is too big. In contrast to 'client-side' conditional styles, 'server-side' conditional styles use conditions that are expressed using Xbasic expressions. These conditions are then evaluated on the server. This [video] shows how client-side conditional styles can be used to display a different font and background color depending for different ranges of values.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Conditional styling for a Grid row, checked rows are red. Unchecked rows are black.</title>
                <link>images/clienside_onrowchecked.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example: Using a Javascript Function</title>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to the functions listed in *[ui:Insert Function...]*, you can write your own JavaScript functions to use in the conditional expression. To define your own JavaScript function, go to the *[ui:Javascript Functions]* pane and define the JavaScript function you'd like to use. This function can include arguments populated from fields in the conditional expression.</p>
                <p>For example, assume you have three fields in the Grid row that you'd like to use in your JavaScript function in an expression: 'field1', 'field2', and 'field3'. The expression could be written as:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[myCustomFunction(field1, field2, field3)]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>where *[js:myCustomFunction]* is the name of your JavaScript function defined in the *[ui:Javascript Functions]* pane.</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[function myCustomFunction(field1, field2, field3) {
    // Code that performs the evaluation and stores
    // the computation in a variable called result

    return result; // result is a variable with a true or false value
}]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>The JavaScript function must return a value. If the function is used to compute the whole expression, the JavaScript function must return a *[js:true]* or *[js:false]* value. Otherwise, the return value must be used in a conditional expression that evaluates to true or false.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Client-side conditional style</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In this video, we show how to dynamically style controls in the Grid. The video demonstrates how the Quantity field can be displayed in a different font and background color depending on where the field's value occurs within a range.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/802dc7</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="https://www.viddler.com/v/802dc7">video</link>
    </links>
</page>