<page>
   <topic>CURRENT Function</topic>
    <description>CURRENT() returns the value of a field or an expression based on field contents for the current record.</description>
 
    <description>Returns 'current' value at beginning of print.</description>
   <syntax>Current_Value as A = CURRENT([c expression])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>expression</name>
         <description>The name of a field or an expression based on field contents.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <discussion>CURRENT() is used in reports to filter records based on values from the active session's current record ( Current_Value ). The Expression parameter is evaluated once before the report is printed, and the result is available to filter records while the report runs. For example, if the current STATE field is "MA", the following report filter: </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
            
            <example><![CDATA[
STATE_PROV = CURRENT(STATE_PROV)

]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>will become:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
STATE_PROV = "MA"
]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>when the report is printed. Limitation: Desktop applications only.</description>
           
       </section>
       
       
   </sections>
   
   <sections>
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>To print only the current invoice, use the following detail filter expression in your report:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[INV_NO = CURRENT(INV_NO)]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>To print the current record, use the following detail filter expression:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[RECNO() = CURRENT(RECNO() )]]></example>
       </section>
       
       
   </sections>
   
   <sections>
       <section><title>Form Filter and Order Expressions</title>
            <description>CURRENT() is particularly valuable when used with filter and order expressions that are based on functions. Consider a form filter based on the date. Assume that on August 30 the filter is run.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[inv_date = date()]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>If the date changes to August 31 but the index is not updated (because the table has not changed), Alpha Five will think that the index created on August 30 is still valid. The result is that the filter will still return records for August 30. The way to solve this problem is with the CURRENT() function.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[inv_date = current(date() )]]></example>
       </section>
       
       
   </sections>
   
   
   <see>
      <ref href="/Guides/Report/Report Overview.xml">Report Overview</ref>
      <ref link="Form Properties">Form Properties</ref>
      <ref>Field Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
   <terms>reports,expressions,field,filter,filter records,forms,function,index,overview,record</terms>
</page>