<page>
    <topic>PhoneGap File System Actions - (File URI Based) Action Javascript</topic>
    <description>The PhoneGap File System Actions - (File URI Based) Action Javascript allows you to perform an action on a mobile device's file system in a PhoneGap application. The directory in which the file system action is performed is specified using a file URI.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>PhoneGap File System Actions - (File URI Based) is similar to [PhoneGap - File System Actions] in that both actions allow you to perform actions on the device's file system, such as read a file, write a file, create a directory, delete a directory, etc. The key difference is PhoneGap File System Actions - (File URI Based) gives you explicit control over where the operations are performed in the device's file system by specifying a file URI. [PhoneGap - File System Actions] only operates on files in a default location.</p>
        <p>You can perform the following actions using PhoneGap File System Actions - (File URI Based) Action Javascript:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/fileURIBased2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Action Name</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>File System Is Available</name>
                    <description>Returns true if PhoneGap is running an the local file system is available.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Get Base URI of Requested File System Part</name>
                    <description>Returns the file URI of the requested part of the file system. Your code can request the URI for the following abstract file system parts: 'temp', 'private', 'saved' or 'public'.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Read a File</name>
                    <description>Read the contents of a file. Optionally specify a starting and ending position in the file.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Write a File</name>
                    <description>Write a file. Optionally specify if the data should be appended to the end of the existing data if the file already exists.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Check if file exists</name>
                    <description>Check if a file exists. If the file does exist, the callback function is called with the properties of the file (such as size, date last updated, etc.).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Delete a file</name>
                    <description>Delete a file.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Copy a file</name>
                    <description>Copy a file.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Move a file</name>
                    <description>Move a file.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Remove a directory (recursively)</name>
                    <description>Deletes the specified directory and all of its contents, including other directories and their contents.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Create directories (recursively)</name>
                    <description>Ensures that a directory structure (specified by subdirpath) exists within the specified rootpath. If the directories do not exist, they are created.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List files in a directory (recursively)</name>
                    <description>List files in a directory and the sub-directories of the specified directory.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>List matching files in a directory</name>
                    <description>List files in a directory. If a filter (defined by a regular expression) is specified only matching files are listed.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Delete matching files</name>
                    <description>Delete files. If a filter (defined by a regular expression) is specified, only matching files are deleted. If a 'keep list' is specified files in the list are not deleted, even if they matched.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref>PhoneGap - File System Actions Action Javascript</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="PhoneGap File System Actions.xml">PhoneGap - File System Actions</link>
    </links>
    <terms>file upload,file download,local storage,disconnected application,offline application,mobile application,phonegap build</terms>
</page>