<page>
   <topic>ComponentGuid Function</topic>
   <syntax>C componentGUID()</syntax>
   <description>For use in Web applications only. Returns the GUID for the current component. Only for use in creating a filter to find records in the Repository that belong to the current component.</description>
   <discussion>
      ...put discussion here....
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
...put example code here....
]]></example>
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>put description here</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
      ...put example here....
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Web Application Repository V11</ref>
   </see>
   <original> ComponentGuid()SyntaxC Result =  componentGUID()


Argument Description
C ResultThe GUID of the current Web component

DescriptionFor use in Web applications only. Returns the GUID for the current component. Only for use in creating a filter to find records in the Repository that belong to the current component.

This is a special function that is intended for use in Web Applications to allow you to manage the records in the Repository that 'belong' to the current component.

For example, when you save search criteria from the Search Part of a Grid to the Repository, the search is saved with the GUID of the current component. This is important because when you load a saved search, you only want the user to see the saved searches that belong to the current component. If you want to manage the records in the Repository, (by creating a Grid that is based on the Repository table), you might want to filter the records in the Repository based on the Guid of a particular component.

Say you have a Grid called Customers and you want to put a button on this Grid to show the Repository entries that belong to this Grid. You can do this by setting the filter on the target Grid to

componentGuid = ComponentGuid()

Watch Video
LimitationsExamplesSee AlsoWeb Application Repository V11
</original>
</page>