<page build="4171">
   <shortlink>tabbed ui builder search properties</shortlink>
   <topic>Search Properties</topic>
   <description>If a TabbedUI component has a large number of items, it can be difficult for a user to find the item that they want. The search feature allow users to quickly find the items in the Tabbed UI interface. As the user types into the search box a filtered list of the matching items is displayed.</description>
   <!--order:
enablesearch.xml
label.xml
watermark.xml
searchpartclass.xml
searchresultsclass.xml
searchinputclass.xml
searchresultsbuttonclass.xml
noresultsfoundmessage.xml
-->   <!--list:.-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>In the image below the search feature has been turned on, but the user has not yet typed into the search box.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/tabbedUISearch.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>In this image the user has typed a string into the search box and all of the matching items are displayed.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/tabbedUIsearch2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To turn the search feature on, go to the TabbedUI Properties pane in the TabbedUI builder and check the *[ui:Enable search]* property.</p>
                <p>Once you have turned on the search feature, there are a number of other properties you can set.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/tabbedUIsearch3.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Adding a Search Feature to the TabbedUI</title>
                <description>
                    <p>It is not uncommon for developers to create TabbedUI components with a very large number of items. Users may then struggle to find a particular item in the list of available menu items. Adding a search feature to the TabbedUI component makes it very easy for users to find the menu item they want.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how the search feature is added to the TabbedUI component.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2017-02-24</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/PXpitZyADPfqporQ8CsjR8</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
