<page>
   <topic>OBJECT.SHOW_ALL Function</topic>
<description>When you use the .VIEWQUERIED() method to open a Form or Browse and apply a filter, you can specify if the filter that is applied to the target layout is a base filter, or a user filter. If the filter is a user-filter, the .SHOW_ALL() method can be used to remove the filter. However, if the filter is a base filter, the .SHOW_ALL() method cannot be used to remove the base filter.</description>
   <syntax>.Show_All()</syntax>
   <description>Turns off the current query and shows all records (subject to any base filter that was specified).</description>

   <sections>
         
         <section>
               <description><![CDATA[The <OBJECT>.SHOW_ALL() method applies to:]]></description>
<cases>
      <case>
            <description><![CDATA[Where <OBJECT>  is a pointer to an open Form or Browse layout..]]></description>
      </case>
       <case>
            <description><![CDATA[The <OBJECT>.SHOW_ALL() method turns off the current query and shows all records in the table (subject to any base filter that may have been specified).
]]></description>
      </case>
       <case>
            <description><![CDATA[In the case of Form layouts that have embedded browse objects, or sub-forms, that display records from one-to-many linked child tables, the .SHOW_ALL() method can also be used to show all of the records in a child table, after a filter has been applied to the child table. (See example below)]]></description>
      </case>
      
</cases>
         </section>
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>This script is attached to a button. It turns off the current query.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
Parent.show_all()
]]></example>
       </section>
       
        <section>
            <description>This script is attached to a button. It turns off the current query that was applied to the records in the embedded browse 'browse1'.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
topparent:browse1.show_all()
]]></example>
       </section>
       
        
       
   </sections>
   <limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Ref/Desktop_Api/Layout/Form/Form Functions and Methods.xml">Form Functions and  Methods</ref>
      <ref href="/Desktop/Reference/Design/View/Browse/Browse Functions and Methods.xml">Browse  Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
 <terms>object,filter,function,layout,query,script</terms>
</page>