<page>
   <topic>Report.SaveAs Function</topic>
   <description>The report.SAVEAS() method prints Layout_Name to file in PDF, HTML, RTF, or TXT formats. If no format is specified, the .PDF format is used.</description>
   <syntax>Report.SaveAs as c( Layout_Name as C [, Format as C [, Filter_Expression as C [, Order_Expression as C [, Output_Filename as C [, Open_Application as L [, PrintOptions as P [, Arguments as SQL::Arguments [, Options as P ]]]]]]]] )
</syntax>
   <arguments>
   <argument>
         <name>Layout_Name</name>
         <description>The name of a form, browse, label, letter, or report layout.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>Format</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "PDF". The options for Format are:

Format

File Type

"PDF"

Adobe Acrobat PDF Format.

 Note : The PDF Printer drivers used in Version 7 will not create valid PDF files if you have created layouts that use a "percentage" as the property for the Background Fill property an object. The work around is to only use the "Solid", "Translucent" or "Transparent" option for the Background, Fill property.

"HTML"

Dynamic HTML

"RTF"

Rich Text Format

"TXT"

Plain Text Format

V11

"XPS"

XPS (XML Paper Specification, an alternative to PDF) Format</description>
     </argument>
    <argument>
         <name>Filter_Expression</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = ".T." (All records).

A character filter expression that evaluates to a logical value and selects records from the table.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>Order_Expression</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = record order.

A character order expression that sorts selected records.</description>
     </argument>

<argument>
         <name>Output_Filename</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = Layout_Name in the same folder as the database. The path and name to give the saved file.</description>
     </argument>

<argument>
         <name>Open_Application</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .F. (FALSE).

.T. = After the layout is printed, Alpha Five opens the file with its associated applications. For example, if you saved as a Rich Text Format file, and WordPerfect is the associated application for .RTF files on your computer, Alpha Five will start WordPerfect and load the file.

.F. = Do not open associated application.</description>
     </argument>
<argument>
         <name>PrintOptions</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = NULL. You can override the default system settings on a permanent basis. When you override the system defaults, your settings are stored in a text file in the Alpha Five program folder. These files are named: 

AlphaFivePrinterDriver_htm.PrintOptions 
AlphaFivePrinterDriver_pdf.PrintOptions 
AlphaFivePrinterDriver_rtf.PrintOptions

For more information about print options.</description>
     </argument>

<argument>
         <name>Arguments</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = NULL_VALUE(). Arguments that retrieve value(s) from variable(s) or prompts for value(s) at runtime. Only applicable to SQL Reports. Refer to SQL::Arguments Object.</description>
     </argument>
<argument>
         <name>Options</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = NULL_VALUE(). Sets filter (WHERE) and order (ORDER BY) expressions for a query against a passive-linked table. A pointer dot variable with 2 elements. Refer to Using the Options Argument.

.filter = Adds to the WHERE clause in the underlying SQL expression.

.order = Replaces the ORDER BY clause in the underlying SQL expression.</description>
     </argument>
     </arguments>
     <discussion>
     <p>If you specify an optional Filter_Expression, the only records matching the filter are printed. (In addition to the filter specified here, the layout may have a filter defined within the layout definition).</p>
      <p>The layout is printed to Filename. If Filename is not specified, the layout is printed to a file with the same name as the Layout_Name in the same folder as the database.</p>
     </discussion>
</page>