<page build="4438">
    <shortlink>ux data controls more controls expandingmenu control</shortlink>
    <topic>ExpandingMenu</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Displays a list of menu items. Menus can have sub-menus. Sub-menus are animated into view when expanded.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Expanding Menu control displays a list of menu choices, some of which may have sub-choices (indicated by an icon at the right edge of the item). When a menu item is clicked, it can invoke Javascript code. If the menu has a sub-menu, the sub-menu is shown using animation.</p>
        <p>In the image below the Expanding Menu is shown in its full collapsed state and it a partially expanded state.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Expanding Menu control - collapsed</title>
                <link>images/expandingmenuclosed.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Expanding Menu control - expanded</title>
                <link>images/expandingmenuopen.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To add an Expanding Menu control to your UX component, select the [More...] item in the Data Controls category.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>The Expanding Menu control is in the Data Controls section, because, like all Data Controls, it has a {dialog.object}.setValue() and a {dialog.object}.getValue() method. The 'value' of the current selection in the Expanding menu is defined by the 'value' property for each node in the tree (see below).</p>
            </note>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu1.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Then select the ExpandingMenu option from the dialog.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To configure the Expanding Menu control, click the smart field for the Control properties property.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu3.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This will bring up a genie where you can define the choices shown in the Expanding Menu and also set other properties.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu4.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To define the choices and sub-choices shown in the menu click on the smart field for the Menu data genie property.</p>
                <p>This will bring up a dialog where you can type in your menu choices, using tab indents to indicate which menu choices are sub-choices.</p>
                <p>For example, in the image below, the top level menu choices are:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[item1
item2
item3
item4]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Item1 and item2 hav3 sub-choices.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu5.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When you close the Add Item dialog, the Tree Data Genie is shown (see image below). This dialog allows you to set properties for each menu item in menu tree.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/expandingmenu6.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Properties that you can set include:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Item</name>
                    <description>The HTML text show in the menu.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Icon</name>
                    <description>An optional icon shown to the left of the menu text.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Value</name>
                    <description>
                        <p>An optional value that indicates what the value of the Expanding Menu control will be if this menu item is selected.</p>
                        <p>If you want to use Data Control methods, such as {dialog.object}.setValue() and {dialog.object}.getValue(), or the Expanding Menu's [collapseMenu()] method, you must define a Value for the menu items in the control.</p>
                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Security groups</name>
                    <description>If using the Security Framework- the security groups that can see this menu item. If a menu item is hidden because it is not in the specified security group, the menu item and all of its children are hidden.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Server-side show/hide expression</name>
                    <description>An expression that is evaluated server-side to determine if the menu item should be shown. Server-side show/hide expressions typically involve session variables. Enter an expression that evaluates to .t. or .f.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Client-side show/hide Javascript</name>
                    <description>Javascript code that returns a true or false value. If the code returns false, the menu item (and all of its children) are now shown.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Expanding Menu Topics</title>
            <!--list:.-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Expanding Menu Control Methods</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Expanding Menu control is a ViewBox control. You can use all of the standard [ViewBox Methods] with the Expanding Menu's JavaScript object. You can get a pointer to the Expanding Menu control's JavaScript object using the [{dialog.object}.getControl()] method:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[var menuObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('EXPANDINGMENU_1');]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>In addition to the standard ViewBox methods, the following Expanding Menu object methods are available for working with the Expanding Menu control:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">collapseMenu()</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Collapses a branch in the Expanding Menu. In order to use this function, you must define a *[ui:value]* for the menu branches you want to collapse.</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var menuObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('EXPANDINGMENU_1');
if (menuObj) {
    var menuNode = 'Clients';
    menuObj.collapseMenu(menuNode);
}]]></example>
                        </p>
                        <p>See [Collapsing the Expanding Menu Selecting an Action] to learn more.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Additional Functions and Methods</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Client-side</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In addition to the [standard methods] for working with Data Controls, you can use JavaScript the methods below to manipulate the Expanding Menu control:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>[{dialog.object}.refreshExpandingMenuData()]</name>
                            <description>Refresh the menu options in the Expanding Menu control by making an Ajax Callback to the server to retrieve the menu.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>[{dialog.object}.populateExpandingMenuControl()]</name>
                            <description>Repopulates the Expanding Menu control with a new set of menu options passed to the method as a JSON object.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Server-side</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Xbasic functions for working with Expanding Menus.</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>[a5_sqlToJSONExpandingMenu()]</name>
                            <description>Generates JSON to populate an Expanding Menu control from a SQL query.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>[a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData()]</name>
                            <description>Generates the JSON to populate an Expanding Menu control from a 'friendly' menu definition.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <annotations>/Guides/Mobile and Web Components/UX/Controls/More/inserting.xml</annotations>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Collapsing Menu When Selecting an Action</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When you select the action on a leaf node in an Expanding Menu control, you might want to collapse the menu so that some or all of the expanded nodes are collapsed.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how an expanded node in an Expanding Menu control can be collapsed.</p>
                </description>
                <date></date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/839b0e50</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/collapseExpandingMenu.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Dynamically Populating an Expanding Menu with Ajax Callbacks</title>
                <description>
                    <p>This video shows how you can dynamically populate an Expanding Menu control with data computed in an Ajax callback.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2018-08-09</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/5cd9a216</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/expandingmenu.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section2_collapseMenu()">collapseMenu()</link>
        <link link="UX Controls Data Controls#section1_Working with Data Controls in Javascript">standard methods</link>
        <link link="the%20viewbox%20control#group_Methods">ViewBox Methods</link>
        <link link="ux%20component%20getcontrol%20method">{dialog.object}.getControl()</link>
        <link link="ux%20component%20refreshexpandingmenudata%20method">{dialog.object}.refreshExpandingMenuData()</link>
        <link link="ux%20component%20populateexpandingmenucontrol%20method">{dialog.object}.populateExpandingMenuControl()</link>
        <link link="api%20a5%20sqltojsonexpandingmenu%20function">a5_sqlToJSONExpandingMenu()</link>
        <link link="api%20a5wcb_convertfriendlymenutoexpandingmenujsondata%20function">a5wcb_convertFriendlyMenuToExpandingMenuJSONData()</link>
        <link link="uxexpanding menu auto collapse">Collapsing the Expanding Menu Selecting an Action</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux expandingmenu properties">ExpandingMenu Properties</ref>
    </see>
</page>