<page>
    <shortlink>css layout container properties properties</shortlink>
    <topic>FormView Layout Container Properties Properties</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring a Layout Container.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Add spacing after last control on each row</title>
            <description>
                <p>Should the control spacing be added after the last column in a row (the row must be explicitly ended by setting the control's Break property to 'After').</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Add spacing before first control on each row</title>
            <description>
                <p>Should the control spacing be added before the first column in a row.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Container class</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify one or more classes to apply to the Layout container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Container inline style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the in-line style for the Layout Container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Containing DIV class</title>
            <description>
                <p>Defines the class applied to the DIV that contains the Layout Container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Containing DIV inline style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Defines in-line styling that should be applied to the DIV control that contains the Layout Container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Control spacing</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the spacing at start and end of each line and between controls (if there is more than one control on a line).</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Freeform layout template</title>
            <description>
                <p>Defines the freeform layout template for the Layout Container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Id</title>
            <description>
                <p>The ID of the Layout Container.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Layout type</title>
            <description>
                <p>Defines the type of layout to use. Available container types include:</p>
            </description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Flow</name>
                    <description>Controls in the Layout Container "flow" from one line to the next based on the width of each control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Freeform</name>
                    <description>Control layout is explicitly defined using HTML.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Column</name>
                    <description>Controls are placed in one or more columns.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Show/hide expression</title>
            <description>
                <p>An expression that defines whether or not the Layout Container and the controls contained within it are visible.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Wrap each control in a containing div</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify whether or not each control in the freeform layout should be wrapped in a containing DIV element.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
