<page>
   <topic>EMAIL_CLIENT_EXTERNAL Function</topic>
   <syntax>Result as C = email_client_external([C send_to [,C subject [,C message [,C attachments [,C cc [,C bcc ]]]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>send_to</name>
         <description>Optional. One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>subject</name>
         <description>Optional. The subject of the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>message</name>
         <description>Optional. The contents of the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>attachments</name>
         <description>Optional. The name of one or more files to attach to the message. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>cc</name>
         <description>Optional. One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>bcc</name>
         <description>Optional. One or more comma delimited addresses. Character</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Display the default external e-mail client.  Maximum of 100 recipients.</description>
   
   <discussion>
EMAIL_CLIENT_EXTERNAL() opens the default email client and fills in any of the optional arguments that you specify. The default email client is typically Eudora, Netscape Mail, Outlook Express, etc.

   </discussion>
   
  <sections>
  <section>
  <title>Note:</title>
  <description>The email_client_external() function opens the the user's external email client (e.g. Outlook, Eudora, etc.). This function allows you to pass in a message to show in the client. The function uses Widows MAPI to open the external client. If the message you pass in uses HTML syntax, then the email client shows the HTML code, not the rendered HTML message as you would expect. This is, unfortunately, a limitation of MAPI. Build 4345-3709  (June-3-2011) introduces a way to work around this MAPI limitation so that if you pass in an HTML message, it is rendered as HTML. However, the work-around will only work as long as you do not pass in any attachments.
</description>
  </section>
  </sections>
  
  
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>You can only specify multiple attachment files. You can also use the ZIP_FILES()function to create a single zip file containing multiple attachments.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
attachments = <<%str% 
c:\foo.dbf 
c:\foo.ddd 
c:\foo.ddm 
c:\foo.cdx 
%str%

email_client_external("somebody@somewhere.com","foo", "Test", attachments)

]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
   <see>
      <ref>Email Functions and Methods</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/System/index.xml">EMAIL_CLIENT()</ref>
      <ref><![CDATA[<EMAIL> Pointer Properties]]></ref>
   </see>
<terms>email,arguments,defaults,display,file,function,html</terms>
</page>