<page>
    <topic>Create a static HTML page with an Application Cache</topic>
    <description>Specify if a static HTML page should be created for the UX Component. The page will define an application cache so that it can be loaded (after its initial load) even if there is no connection to the server.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Offline web pages can be created using the *[ui:Application Cache]*, a file that defines all resources that are need to run the web page offline. When the browser loads a page that specifies the name of an *[ui:Application Cache]* file, the browser will download and store all of the files listed in the *[ui:Application Cache]* on the user's machine.</p>
        <p>The next time the page is opened, it will be loaded from the browser's *[ui:Application Cache]*, unless there has been a change to the *[ui:Application Cache]*. Because the page is loaded locally instead of from a server, the page will load *[even if there is no Internet connection]*.</p>
        <p>If there *[has]* been a change to the *[ui:Application Cache]*, the browser will download the files listed in the *[ui:Application Cache]* from the server. The files stored in the *[ui:Application Cache]* will be updated to store the new files, and the browser will reload the new version of the page.</p>
        <p>The *[ui:Application Cache]* can be used to build offline mobile applications that do not require Cordova.</p>
        <p>Applications built using the *[ui:Application Cache]* can be downloaded on a mobile device by creating a shortcut on the device's home screen. When the user taps the icon to launch the app for the first time, the files listed in the *[ui:Application Cache]* will be cached on the device. Subsequent launches of the app will load the locally stored files from the *[ui:Application Cache]*, even if no Internet connection is available. Because the app is loaded from locally stored files, the app will start very quickly.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Enabling the Application Cache</title>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>In the UX Properties, locate the *[ui:Application Cache]* properties section. Click the [...] button to open the *[ui:Static HTML Page with an Application Cache]* dialog.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/appcache1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Check the *[ui:Create a static HTML page for this UX Component with an Application Cache?]* checkbox. This enables the Application Cache.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Static HTML Page with an Application Cache dialog</title>
                        <link>images/staticHTMLPage1.png</link>
                        <alt></alt>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Optionally specify the *[ui:Page name]* for the static HTML page or create default event handlers.</p>
                        <p>The *[ui:Create Default Event Handlers]* button will create default handlers for the following Application Cache events:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>AppCache Event</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>error</name>
                            <description>Fires when there is an error downloading files in the Application Cache</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>progress</name>
                            <description>Allows you to display progress to the user while files in the Application Cache are downloaded.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>updateready</name>
                            <description>Fires after a new version of the component has ben downloaded in the Application Cache. It is used to swap the old cached version of the component for the new version.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                    <note>The *[js:progress]* event is not supported in Firefox.</note>
                    <warning>When you click the *[ui:Create Default Event Handlers]* button, any existing code in the event handlers will be *[overwritten]*.</warning>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save your changes.</description>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Files needed for configuring the Application Cache are stored in the *[ui:staticHTMLFileset]* directory, located in the web project folder. This directory is created for you automatically when the Application Cache is enabled. The static HTML page for the UX Component and the Application Cache manifest can be found in the *[ui:staticHTMLFileset]* directory. The manifest includes a listing of files (eg, css, javascript, images, etc) that the UX Component requires to function offline.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="Static HTML page name.xml">Static HTML page name</ref>
        <ref href="Javascript - cacheError.xml">Application Cache error Event</ref>
        <ref href="Javascript - cacheProgress.xml">Application Cache progress Event</ref>
        <ref href="Javascript - updateReady.xml">Application Cache updateready Event</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>appcache,offline web app,static HTML page</terms>
</page>