<page>
    <topic>Data Series Editor</topic>
    <description>The Data Series Editor allows you to create Data Series before creating a control that uses the data in that 
        data series; for example a list control or a button list control.  
    </description>
  

<sections>
    <section>
        <figure><title>The Data Series Builder</title><link>images/dsb.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
        <title>Data Source Type</title>
        <description>The data source type menu determines what type of data the data series will be created from. 
            The options are:
        </description>
        <list>
            <item>
                <name>SQL</name>
                <description>Uses SQL data to create a data series that can be used inside a control. You 
                    will need to build a connection to the SQL data to be used.
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>SQL -CrossSection</name>
                <description>Uses SQL data to create a data series that used with different controls. "Cross sectional" 
                    means the data will be plotted from multiple fields in a single record. 
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>DBF</name>
                <description></description>
            </item>
             <item>
                <name>DBF -CrossSection</name>
                <description></description>
            </item>
            
            <item>
                <name>Static</name>
                <description>Create a list or table of static data by typing in the options to appear in the data series.</description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>Custom</name>
                <description></description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>Javascript</name>
                <description>Creates a data series based on Javascript, making the data accessible to Javascript functions in your component.</description>
            </item>
           
            
            
        </list>
        
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Using Cross Sectional SQL and DBF Types</title>
        <description>Cross sectional data types allow you to plot data from multiple fields in a single record, rather 
            than plotting data from a single field in multiple records. For more on this data type watch 
            [this video on cross-sectional data] 
           
        </description>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Using the Javascript Type</title>
        <description>For more on the Javascript Type watch this two part video: [Part 1], [Part 2].</description>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
       <title>Using the Data Series Editor to Create Static Data</title>
       
       <steps>
           <step>
               <description></description>
               
           </step>
           
           
       </steps>
       
       
       
    </section>
    
    
    
   
    
      <section>
        <title>Using a Defined Data Series Inside a Control.</title>
        
    </section>
    
    
    
</sections>


<links>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/Chart_CrossSectionalData.swf">this video on cross-sectional data</link>
<link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/charts_jsDataSeries_1.swf">Part 1</link>
<link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/charts_jsDataSeries_2.swf">Part 2</link>

</links>




</page>