<page build="6945">
    <shortlink>ux floating label settings</shortlink>
    <topic>Floating label settings</topic>
    <description>Defines the appearance and behavior of floating control labels.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A floating label is a dynamic label displayed as either a watermark or text above the control. The watermark is used when the control has no value (such as a blank text box.) When the user interacts with the control, or the control has a value, the label is placed above the control, i.e. the floating position. Animations are also used to transition from the watermark to the floating position.</p>
        <p>Edit controls (text boxes, text areas, and dropdowns) in a UX component support floating labels.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/labelfloatabove.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring Floating Label Settings</title>
            <figure>
                <link>images/floatingLabelSettings.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:Floating Label Settings]* affect the behavior of all floating labels in a component. These settings include:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Padding on left when label is in floated position</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Padding on right when label is in floated position</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Margin above label when label is in floated position</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The label's location relative to the control</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The label's font size when label is in floated position</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In the image below, the *[ui:insideControl]* option has been selected. Also note that the edit control sub-theme has been set to a custom sub-theme based on the *[ui:Primary]* sub-theme (which puts a border around the control). The custom sub-theme has set the border-radius to 10px.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/fkiatubglabels302.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To define settings, click the smart field for *[ui:Floating label settings]*</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Property</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Indent - left</name>
                            <description>The distance between the left edge of the control and the label. The left indentation is specified using CSS units. E.g. *[css:4px]*, *[css:0.5in]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Indent - right</name>
                            <description>The distance between the right edge of the control and the label. Right indentation only applies if the [Alignment] property for the control's label is set to Right. The right indentation is specified using CSS units. E.g. *[css:4px]*, *[css:0.5in]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Margin - above</name>
                            <description>The distance between the label when positioned above the control and the control, container, or object located above the label. The above margin is specified using CSS units. E.g. *[css:4px]*, *[css:0.5in]*. Defaults to *[css:20px]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Floated label location</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>The location where the label will be positioned relative to the control. Can be one of the following locations:</p>
                                <p>
                                    <list>
                                        <item>
                                            <name-title>Location</name-title>
                                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>aboveControl</name>
                                            <description>Label is positioned outside of the control.</description>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <name>insideControl</name>
                                            <description>Label is positioned inside the control.</description>
                                        </item>
                                    </list>
                                </p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Floated label font size</name>
                            <description>The label's font size when floated above the control. The font size is specified using CSS units. E.g. *[css:20px]*, *[css:12pt]*. Defaults to *[css:10px]*.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Floating Textbox Labels</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A popular design pattern displays the label for a textbox as a watermark in the field. When the user clicks in the field to begin typing, the watermark animates into position above the textbox.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how animated textbox labels can be specified.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2020-07-27</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EXklCdpJYr8</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="cssgrid floatabove">Configuring Float Above Labels in CSSGrid Containers</ref>
    </see>
</page>