<page>
    <shortlink>grid field lookup properties lookup type</shortlink>
    <topic parent="Lookup Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Lookup Type">Lookup Type</topic>
    <description>Lookup Type has a dropdown select list with these options: Grid Component, Auto-Suggest List, and Edit-Combo List. The Auto-Suggest list option creates Lookups that function much like a Google search toolbar.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p></p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>As you type in the textbox, a list of suggestions is supplied. With Grid Component Lookups, the suggestions can come from either a static list of values or, more commonly, from a table. Both the Auto-suggest and edit-combo controls allow you to enter multiple values in the field you are editing. For example, say you have a field called 'Send to' and you want to support a comma delimited list, such as 'Smith,Jones,King,Cohen' and you want the user to be able to select each entry in the list from the pick list. The edit-combo, or auto-suggest control can be used for this. For more info, check out the [videos below]. </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Lookup Grid Component Type</title>
                <link>images/01_lookup2.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>Lookup with Auto-Suggest List</title>
                <link>images/01_lookup3.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>Lookup using an Edit-Combo List</title>
                <link>images/01_lookup4.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Lookups</title>
                <description>A textbox can be configured to be a 'Lookup' field. A Lookup is a field that is populated by selecting from a list of choices. A Grid Component can be used to generate the list. In this video, we demonstrate how to create a Lookup field, including how to open the lookup in another window and applying dynamic filtering to the list of choices.</description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/D9wfCS8wVtPfC1sEcGatA7</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
            <videos>
                <title>Auto-suggest Fields</title>
                <description>Auto-suggest fields works similarly to the Google Search toolbar. As you start typing in the textbox, a list of suggestions is supplied. The suggestions in the list can be statically defined or dynamically populated from a database or server-side variable. The list of choices can also be filtered on the value in other fields. For example, a 'City' field could be filtered to only display the cities for the selected 'State'.</description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/dAS11VcXggVtddgf786arY</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
            <videos>
                <title>Edit-Combo box fields</title>
                <description>Standard HTML does not support an edit-combo box control. This video shows how you can include edit-combo boxes in your Grid components. You can use the edit-combo boxes in the Search, Grid, and Detail View parts.</description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/HAvk7k31fNq4Tby1vkCuPe</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="#section1_Videos">videos below</link>
    </links>
</page>