<page>
    <shortlink>ux components data binding</shortlink>
    <topic>Data Binding</topic>
    <description>Create new tables with fields that match the controls on your UX Component, or bind the controls in your UX Component to fields in existing tables. 
        The Data Binding page lets you bind an entire UX component to new or existing SQL or DBF tables in a database and then 
        assign controls to fields in those table accordingly. 
    </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dataBinding.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:.-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You can also do data-binding when you create a Detail View from an SQL database inside a List Control. 
                When you define the Detail view specified data controls are bound to selected fields from the SQL table that the list is linked to. 
                Once you do this, you should be able to see the data bound list appear on the Data Binding page's 'Summary' section, as 
                demonstrated by the image below.  
            </description>
            <figure><title>A summary showing a List Detail-View with data binding</title><link>images/datalist.png</link></figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>One advantage of using the detail view of a list for databinding is that you are can do CRUD operations 
                against two independent a unlinked tables from the same UX component. This as opposed to having one table or group 
                of tables linked directly to the component itself. The difference between these two models of data-binding is explained in these two videos:
                 [Part 1], [Part 2].
            </description>
             <figure><title>A summary showing a component with data-binding</title><link>images/datacomp.png</link></figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <!--order:
Create Tables to Match Controls
Bind Controls to Existing Tables
Specify Primary Keys and Sequences
Permissions and Security
Refresh Table Information
Remove all Data Binding Settings
-->


<links>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_crud_1.swf">Part 1</link>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_crud_2.swf">Part 2</link>
    
</links>
</page>