<page>
   <topic>AudioRecorderAndPlayer Control</topic>
    <description>The AudioRecorderAndPlayer control allows you to add a control to the UX component to play audio files and to record audio files in PhoneGap applications. Rich Data Capture.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <note>A separate [AudioPlayer control] is also available. The AudioPlayer control and can be used in web and mobile applications.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To add a new AudioRecorderAndPlayer control to the UX, select the [More...] entry in the controls toolbox (in the 'Data Controls' section) and then select the 'AudioRecorderAndPlayer' control.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/selectaudioplayerfrommore.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The AudioRecorderAndPlayer controls is a dual purpose control. It can be used to play audio files (or streams) and it can also be used to record audio files.</p>
                <p>You can only record audio files if you are using PhoneGap.</p>
                <p>When you build your PhoneGap application you must must ensure that the Media plugin has *[not been]* selected:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pgMedia.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>and that the Media With Compression plugin has been selected.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pgMediawithCompression.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In addition, you are likely to need to upload the captured audio files to a server so the following PhoneGap plugins should also be loaded: *[ui:Device]*, *[ui:File]*, *[ui:File transfer]*.</p>
                <p>When you add an AudioRecorderAndPlayer control to your UX you customize the control properties by clickin the smart field for the *[ui:Control properties]*.</p>
                <p>The customization genie allows you to set customize text and also set the maximum recording duration (in seconds).</p>
                <p>When the component is run, the AudioRecorderAndPlayer control will look like this (if not audio file has been loaded for playback):</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/audiorecorderplayer1.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The red circle button will put the control into record mode. When the control is in record mode, it will appear as follows:</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/audiorecorderplayer2.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Done button (text on this button is customizable -- you can use language, or text dictionary tags for International applications- <![CDATA[<a5:r> or <a5:t>]]>) becomes enabled. This button indicates that you want to end the recording. The record button changes to a Pause button. You can use this button to pause the recording.</p>
                <p>The horizontal line at the top of the control indicates the recording level. The color of the line will be orange, green or red to indicate if the recording level is too low, ok or too high.</p>
                <p>The number on the right indicates the duration of the recording.</p>
                <p>If you set the value of the control to an audio stream or an audio file ( using the *[js:{dialog.object}.setValue()]* method ),  the control's appearance will change as shown below.</p>
                <p>The control is now in 'Player' mode. The play button in the center of the control will start playback. The small record button at the left of the control will allow you to switch the control from 'Player' mode to 'Record' mode.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/audiorecordplayerinplaymode.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="AudioPlayer Control.xml">AudioPlayer control</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/Guides/UX Components/Rich Data Capture/AudioPlayer Control.xml">AudioPlayer Control</ref>
    </see>
    <limitations>PhoneGap Applications Only</limitations>
    <terms>audioplayer,audio capture,audio recording,mobile app,phonegap</terms>
</page>