<page>
	<shortlink>grid checkbox properties</shortlink>
	<topic>CheckBox Properties</topic>
	<description>Check boxes are appropriate when you want to set a True/False value into a logical field. The most important property for a check box control is the definition of its choices.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Choices</title>
			<description>Click [...] to define the true and false choices set by the check box. Refer to Defining Choices for Check Boxes, Radio Buttons, and Drop Down Lists for details.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Orientation</title>
			<description>The orientation of the label. The choices are:  </description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Horizontal" </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Vertical"  </description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Column flow</title>
			<description>Specify how the choices are organized. LRTB - left-to-right, then top-to-bottom. TBLR - top-to-bottom, then left-to-right Choices include.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Column count</title>
			<description>Specify how many columns should be used to display the CheckBox choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Row count</title>
			<description>Specify how many rows should be used to display the CheckBox choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Maximum choices</title>
			<description>Specify the maximum number of choices to show. Set to 0 to show all choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>In-line style</title>
			<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click [...] to define the inline style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Not in list rule</title>
			<description></description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"First Entry" - use the first entry in the list  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Null" - set the field to NULL  </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Do Nothing" - accept the user input  </description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Style control if error</title>
			<obsolete>This property is obsolete and no longer available in Alpha Anywhere.</obsolete>
			<description>Specifies whether to apply a second style to the field if a validation error occurs.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>In-line style for errors</title>
			<obsolete>This property is obsolete and no longer available in Alpha Anywhere.</obsolete>
			<description>Specifies style attributes that are used when a validation error occurs. Click to define the inline style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<links>
		<link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
	</links>
</page>