<page>
<topic>Hidden Properties </topic>	
	<sections>
<section>
	<description>The Hidden control type displays a grid column (or row), but does not display any data. This is different from the Hide property, that hides a grid column (or row). 
In this example we would like to achieve three goals:  
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Set the value of a field with a script in the CanInsertRecordevent </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Display the value of said field. </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Prevent the user from editing the field. </description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Updating Hidden Grid Fields using dbf:  </title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Open the Grid Builder and go to the Design tab. Go to the Component Type page and select Grid is: Updateable . On the Data Source page select .dbf .  </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>On the Query(DBF) page connect to the table that you will extract data from. This example uses the AlphaSports Customerstable.  
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you are using Query(DBF) click the Calculated fields button. The Calculated Values dialog will open. Create a calculated field definition similar to the one below and click OK .  </description>
		<example><![CDATA[cust_id = customer_id]]></example>
		<note>This calculated field definition takes the customer_idfield in the Alpha Sports customers table and creates a new identical field named cust_id. This copy can be displayed but be placed in a non-editable label control.</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Open to the grid Fields page. Take the two fields that appeared in your calculated field definition and move them from the Available fields: list to the Selected: fields list.  </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Add two additional fields to the Selected: fields list from the Available fields list. Position these fields in the middle of the Selected: fields list using the up and down arrows.  </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Go to Live Preview . Your table should look something like this.</description>
			<figure><link>images/01_hide.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the Selected: fields list, click on the control of the field you copied in your calculated field definition; this example uses Customer_id.  
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Go to the Field Properties list for this field control. Find the Display Settings section and under it the Control type property. Change Control type to ' Hidden </description>
			<figure><link>images/01_hide3.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Scroll down the Field Properties list to the Column Properties section. Check the Hide column property checkbox.

</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the Selected: fields list, select the second field, in this case the firstnamefield.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In the Field Properties list go to the Column Properties section again.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Find the Column heading property and change it, in this case to 'First Name'. Also change the Heading in-line style property to ' text-align: left '.
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_hide4.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Check the Freeform layout property checkbox. The Freeform template property will appear. Click the button next to it to open the Freeform Column Layout dialog.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In  the Freeform Column Layout dialog enter a field definition similar to the one below and click OK.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[{Customer_Id}{Firstname}]]></example>
			<note>This step is important. This step places the editable field that you copied, in this example "customer_ID",  on the grid. This allows the event script to modify it. However, since, the "customer_ID" control is hidden, only the "firstname" field shows.  </note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click on the third field in your Selected: fields list, in this case the "lastname" field.  </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>In Column Properties change the Column heading property, in this case to "Last Name", and set Heading in-line style to "text-align: left;"  
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_hide5.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Finally, click on your calculated field in the Selected: fields list. Go back to the Column Properties section of the Field Properties list.  
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Change the Column heading property. In this example our calculated field is cust_id so the heading will be "Customer ID". Also change the Heading in-line style property to "text-align: left;"  </description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Scroll up to the Display Setting section of the Field Properties list. Change the Control type to ' Label '. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_hide6.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>From the Design menu, open then Properties page. Find the Layout Options section and under it the Rows of data property. Set Rows of data to 5.  
</description>
<figure><link>images/01_hide7.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Now click on the Update Settings page. Find the Permissions section of the page and in it the Number of new record rows property , set this to 1.  
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Save the grid and go to Live Preview .</description>
			<figure>
				<title>Placing scripts in the CanInsertRecordevent will  now update the Customer_IDfield.</title>
				<link>images/01_hide2.png</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Custom Control Properties</description>
	<example><![CDATA[with tmpl.field_info[N]            
.CustomControlXbasic as C ]]></example>
</section>
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Suppressing Blank Fields in an Address</ref>
		<ref>Creating a Grid that Looks Like a Dialog</ref>
	</see>
</page>