<page>
	<shortlink>gridfieldprops radiobutton properties</shortlink>
	<topic>RadioButton Properties</topic>
	<description>RadioButton controls are appropriate when you want to select between a small number of choices. </description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title></title>
			<description>The most important property for a check box control is the definition of its choices. When you allow the user to select multiple values, the control returns an array. To convert an array to a character value, you need to use an expression like the following:</description>
			<example code="xb">
				<![CDATA[TargetVariable=crlf_to_comma(ControlName.dump()]]>
			</example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>In-line style</title>
			<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Orientation</title>
			<description>The orientation of the label. The choices are: "Horizontal" and "Vertical"</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Column flow</title>
			<description>Specify how the choices are organized. LRTB - left-to-right, then top-to-bottom. TBLR - top-to-bottom, then left-to-right Choices include.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Column count</title>
			<description>Specify how many columns should be used to display the radiobutton choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Row count</title>
			<description>Specify how many rows should be used to display the radiobutton choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Maximum choices</title>
			<description>Specify the maximum number of choices to show. Set to 0 to show all choices.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Not in list rule</title>
			<description>Specifies the value to display if the list contains a value not coded in the page. The options are:</description>
			<list>
				<item>
					<name>Add to list</name>
					<description>Display the value</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Do Nothing</name>
					<description>Show the first value in the list</description>
				</item>
			</list>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>