<page>
	<topic>[Tab Control]</topic>
	<description>A tab control allows you to selectively hide and display different groups of fields. Refer to Setting Grid Tab Properties.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Properties</title>
			<list>
				<item>
					<name>Use modern tab style</name>
					<description>If you uncheck this box, then the Grid will use legacy tab styles. The older tab styles are included for backward compatibility. You are strongly encouraged to switch to the modern tab styles.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Tab properties</name>
					<description>Specify the properties for the Tab Control. You can select a 'classic' tab style, banded style, or Genie style.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Tab ID</name>
					<description>Specify a unique ID to identify the tab control. At run-time, the actual ID will automatically include the component alias and convert to uppercase. e.g. 'CUSTOMERGRID.TAB.1'.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Tab type</name>
					<description>Specify the tab control style. The control can be formatted as a Tab or Accordion control.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Tab label position</name>
					<description>Specify the location of the tab labels.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Accordion style</name>
					<description>Specify if only one accordion band at a time can be open, or if the user can open multiple bands</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Initial tab pane</name>
					<description>Specify which tab pane should be initially selected. Use a numeric index. e.g. '3' for the third tab pane.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Initial opened panes</name>
					<description>Specify which accordion panes (if any) are initially opened. Enter a comma delimited list. E.g. 1,3  - indicates that the first and third accordion pane are initially open. If the accordion style is set to 'Single', then enter a single value. Leave blank if no panes are initially opened.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Pane Width</name>
					<description>Optional. Width of the tab panes. If left blank, tab panes will automatically resize based on tab contents.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Pane Height</name>
					<description>Optional. Height of the tab pane. If left blank, tab panes will automatically resize based on tab contents.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Animation</name>
					<description>Specify if the tab/accordion panes should be animated when they are selected. See "Animating the Tab Control" below.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Show animation style</name>
					<description>Select the animation method to use when the pane is shown. 'Suggested' is 'Slide' for an Accordion and 'Fade' for a Tab control. Choices include *[ui:Slide]*, *[ui:Fade]*, *[ui:Suggested]*, *[ui:None]*.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Show animation speed</name>
					<description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Hide animation style</name>
					<description>Select the animation method to use when the pane is shown. 'Suggested' is 'Slide' for an Accordion and 'None' for a Tab control. Choices include *[ui:Slide]*, *[ui:Fade]*, *[ui:Suggested]*, *[ui:None]*.</description>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>Hide animation speed</name>
					<description>Specify the animation speed. You can select a pre-defined option (slow = 600 milliseconds, fast = 200 milliseconds), or you can enter an explicit value in milliseconds.</description>
				</item>
			</list>
		</section>
		<section>
			<videos>
				<title>Animating Tab and Accordion Objects in the Grid</title>
				<description>You can control the animation method to hide and show panes. The animation methods are 'slide' and 'fade'. You can use one method to show the pane, and another method to hide the pane. For example, you might choose to 'slide' the pane into view, but 'fade' it out of view.</description>
				<video>
					<name>Watch Video</name>
					<link>https://www.viddler.com/v/8c634926</link>
				</video>
			</videos>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>