<page>
	  <topic>TextArea Properties</topic>
<description>The most important properties of a TextArea control are the Rows and Columns properties, which define its size.  
</description>
 
	<sections>
		<section>
<title>HTML editor </title>
<description>If you are creating an Updateable grid you can check the HTML editor property checkbox and add an HTML editor to your grid. This will allow users to easily add HTML to their records. If you want to add this property to a number of fields then you will need to go to Display Settings in the Field Properties list and  change the Control Type for each field to TextArea . After creating a second TextArea control, simply check the HTML property again for that control, or use the eyedroppertool.  
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>The HTML editor comes with a number of additional properties. HTML editor width defines the width between columns that the unopened editor fills. Similarly HTML editor height specifies the row height of the unopened editor. These properties are for the default editor, where a user clicks on a given TextArea control to open the HTML editor for that record. However, you can also define a Popup mode by checking the HTML editor is popup property checkbox. When you add a popup HTML editor to the Grid, to edit HTML fields, the data in the Grid is not saved when the user closes the popup HTML editor. The data is only saved when the user clicks the Submit button. The Save grid data when closing popup editor property allows you to automatically submit the data in the Grid as soon as the popup HTML editor is closed. 
</description>
		
	</case>
	<case>
		<figure>
			<title>Unopened HTML editor width </title>
			<link>images/01_htmled2.png</link>
		</figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<figure>
			<title>An Open HTML editor </title>
			<link>images/01_htmled.png</link>
		</figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<figure>
	
			<link>images/SaveHTMLOnClosePopup.gif</link>
		</figure>
	</case>
	
</cases>


		</section>
<section>
	<title>Rows</title>
	<description>Sets the height of the control by specifying the number of rows.  </description>
</section>		
		
<section>
	<title>Columns</title>
	<description>Set the width of the control by specifying the number of columns.  </description>
</section>		

<section>
	<title>In-line Style </title>
	<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  
</description>
</section>		

<section>
	<title>Watermark </title>
	<description>Sometimes, the size of screen matters when a user is accessing an application you've created. So how do you build an effective application to be used when screen real estate is limited, such as an Ajax Web app that will run on an iPhone? 
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>That's why "liquid" forms are an increasingly popular platform for running Web applications today. Liquid forms automatically reconfigure themselves based on the screen size. That's necessary for something like a smart phone,ine- color: initial; "  This first video  we put together will show how the grid makes it easy to design liquid forms.  Watermark fields     are also an effective tool for dealing with small screen sizes. Watermark fields let you put the field label inside the field itself. This is a great way to save space when you don't have space to spare.  
</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
</section>
<section>
	<description>code reference:</description>
	<example><![CDATA['Rows  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]        .TextArea.Rows as N 
'Columns  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]        .TextArea.Cols as N 
'In-line style  
tmpl.Field_Info[N]        .TextArea.InLineStyle as C 
]]></example>
</section>

		
	</sections>
</page>