<page>
	<topic>TextBox Properties</topic>
	<description>The most important properties of a TextBox control are the Size and MaxLength properties. 	The MaxLength should match the field definition in your table. The size can be large</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>HTML5 type</title>
			<description>Specify an optional value for the textbox 'type' attribute. Leave blank to use 'text'.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Size</title>
			<description>Sets the width of the field in characters.</description>
			<important>If the 'Lookup' property is checked, set the control size using the 'In-line style' property. E.g. width: 3in;</important>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>MaxLength </title>
			<description>Sets the maximum length of the user's input in characters. Set to -1 for no limit.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>In-line style </title>
			<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details.  </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Container in-line style </title>
			<description>(Only applies to controls that have a smart field button - e.g. Lookups, Date/Time pickers) Specify style attributes for the container for the control.  The container encloses both the input control and the smart field button.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Is a password field </title>
			<description>If this is a password field, the characters will be replaced with bullets.  </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Watermark</title>
			<description>Specify if the field has a watermark. The watermark text appears in the textbox when there is no value in the textbox.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark text</title>
			<description>Specify the watermark text. Set to &lt;FieldLabel&gt; to use the field label as the watermark text.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark class name</title>
			<description>Specify the class name for the watermark text. Leave blank to use default class. This class is applied on top of any existing classes.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark style</title>
			<description>Specify the style for the watermark text.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Custom attributes </title>
			<description>Additional custom HTML attributes to add to the generated HTML for the control.</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>