<page>
	<shortlink>gridfieldprops textarea properties</shortlink>
	<topic>TextArea Properties</topic>
	<description>The most important properties of a TextArea control are the Rows and Columns properties, which define its size. </description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>HTML editor </title>
			<description>If you are creating an Updatable grid you can check the HTML editor property checkbox and add an HTML editor to your grid. This will allow users to easily add HTML to their records. If you want to add this property to a number of fields then you will need to go to Display Settings in the Field Properties list and change the Control Type for each field to TextArea . After creating a second TextArea control, simply check the HTML property again for that control, or use the *[Paste Property Value]* tool.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>The HTML editor comes with a number of additional properties. HTML editor width defines the width between columns that the unopened editor fills. Similarly HTML editor height specifies the row height of the unopened editor. These properties are for the default editor, where a user clicks on a given TextArea control to open the HTML editor for that record. However, you can also define a Popup mode by checking the HTML editor is popup property checkbox. When you add a popup HTML editor to the Grid, to edit HTML fields, the data in the Grid is not saved when the user closes the popup HTML editor. The data is only saved when the user clicks the Submit button. The Save grid data when closing popup editor property allows you to automatically submit the data in the Grid as soon as the popup HTML editor is closed. </description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<figure>
						<title>Unopened HTML editor width </title>
						<link>images/01_htmled2.png</link>
					</figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<figure>
						<title>An Open HTML editor </title>
						<link>images/01_htmled.png</link>
					</figure>
				</case>
				<case>
					<figure>
						<link>images/SaveHTMLOnClosePopup.gif</link>
					</figure>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor width</title>
			<description>Specify the editor width. Use CSS style syntax. For example: '6in', '100px' etc.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor height</title>
			<description>Specify the editor height. Use CSS style syntax. For example: '6in', '100px' etc.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Popup editor width</title>
			<description>Specify the width for the popup editor. If width is blank uses same size as the initial display. Use CSS style syntax. For example: '6in', '100px' etc.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Popup editor height</title>
			<description>Specify the height for the popup editor. If height is blank uses same size as the initial display. Use CSS style syntax. For example: '6in', '100px' etc.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Save Grid data when closing popup editor</title>
			<description>Specify if the data in the Grid should be saved when the popup editor is closed. Normally the Grid data is not saved when the popup editor is closed.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor style</title>
			<description>Inline styles to apply to the HTML editor.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor linked CSS</title>
			<description>Specify a single CSS file to be used in the editor.  The HTML content normally only uses in-line styles to set fonts and colors and other styles.  A CSS file can be specified to add additional styles, such a styles for specific tags such as header styles.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor toolbar icons</title>
			<description>Customize the icons used in the HTML editor toolbar.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">HTML editor toolbar customization</title>
			<description>You can customize the toolbar for the HTML editor. You can select which controls appear on the toolbar, and the order in which they appear.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Has 'Click to edit' button</title>
			<description>If the HTML editor is a popup editor, by default, clicking on the control causes the editor to pop up. However, if you have enabled 'File upload' then you will want to be able to download linked files by clicking on them. If you check this property, an 'Edit' hyperlink will be shown. Clicking on the HTML editor will not cause it to pop-up, but instead will allow  you to download linked files. You will need to click on the Edit hyperlink to edit the HTML.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Edit hyperlink text</title>
			<description>Specify the text for the edit hyperlink. When you click this hyperlink the HTML editor pops up so that you can edit the text in the field.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Allow image upload</title>
			<description>Specify if the user can upload images to the server when editing this field. The uploaded images are inserted into the body of the memo.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="3">Upload folder</title>
			<description>Specify the folder where the uploaded images are stored. Enter a relative folder name. The folder is in the webroot. For example if you enter 'images' here, and the webroot is c:\a5webroot\project1, the physical folder where the images will be stored is c:\a5webroot\project1\images.</description>
			<important>If you have the Security Framework turned on, be sure to set the appropriate permissions for this upload folder and the files that it contains.</important>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="3">Image upload dialog customization</title>
			<description>Specify how the Image Upload dialog should be customized.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Allow file upload</title>
			<description>Specify if the user can upload files to the server when editing this field. The uploaded files are inserted into the body of the memo as hyperlinks.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="3">Upload folder</title>
			<description>Specify the folder where the uploaded files are stored. Enter a relative folder name. The folder is in the webroot. For example if you enter 'uploadedFiles' here, and the webroot is c:\a5webroot\project1, the physical folder where the files will be stored is c:\a5webroot\project1\uploadedFiles.</description>
			<important>If you have the Security Framework turned on, be sure to set the appropriate permissions for this upload folder and the files that it contains.</important>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="3">File upload dialog customization</title>
			<description>Specify how the File Upload dialog should be customized.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Rows</title>
			<description>Sets the height of the control by specifying the number of rows. </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Columns</title>
			<description>Set the width of the control by specifying the number of columns. </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>In-line Style </title>
			<description>Specifies style attributes that override the settings inherited from the style sheet. Click to define the In-line style. Refer to the Style Editor for details. </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Watermark </title>
			<description>Specify if the field has a watermark. The watermark text appears in the textarea when there is no value in the textarea.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark text</title>
			<description>Specify the watermark text. Set to &lt;FieldLabel&gt; to use the field label as the watermark text.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark class name</title>
			<description>Specify the class name for the watermark text. Leave blank to use default class. This class is applied on top of any existing classes.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title nested="2">Watermark style</title>
			<description>Specify the style for the watermark text.</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>