<page>
	<topic>Auto-Load Compiled Library</topic>
	<description>Here is an example of how you might use the Auto-Load Compiled Library:
Say that you have developed an application called MyApp (the database is called MyApp.adb ). You are now ready to distribute your application to your customers, but you want to make sure that they cannot see any of the source code of your application.
</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<description>Make a backup of your application. There are several ways in which you can do this. You can use the Tools > Backup Database command or the Tools > Zip Database command from the Control Panel. Alternatively, you can right click on the white background of the Code tab on the Control Panel and select the Export... command. This will create a text file of all of your scripts and functions.
</description>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>Right click on the white background of the Code tab on the Control Panel and select the Compile Scripts and Functions into an .AEX file command.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Name the .AEX file "MyApp.AEX", and make sure that MyApp.AEX is in the same folder as MyApp.adb.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Delete all of the scripts and functions shown in the Code tab on the Control Panel.</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Close MyApp database, and then re-open it.</description>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>When Alpha Anywhere re-opens MyApp.adb, it will auto-load MyApp.AEX, and all of the scripts and functions in your compiled library will be available. However, your customers will not see any scripts and functions in the Control Panel.</description>
		<note>When you compile a script library, you are only compiling the global scripts and functions (i.e. those that are listed in the Code tab of the Control Panel ). You are not compiling the scripts and functions that are in form and field rule events.</note>
	</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Using Compiled Script Libraries">Using Compiled Script Libraries</ref>
	</see>
	
	
	
	
</page>