<page>
	<topic>Web Applications - Xbasic Function Libraries</topic>
<description>When you build a web component that does Ajax callbacks, you typically define the Xbasic function that handles the Ajax callback in the component itself (in the Xbasic Function Declarations section of the component). Alternatively you can create a .AEX file that creates a library of global Xbasic functions that your component can call.</description>	
<sections>
<section>
	<description>Now a new method is now available. The Web Projects Control Panel now has a new category called Xbasic Function Library.
</description>
<figure><link>images/xbasicfunctionlibrary.jpg</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>An Xbasic Function Library is a text file with a .a5xbfl extension that is stored in your Web Project. This file contains definitions for one or more Xbasic functions.
</description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<description>Watch Video</description>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/xbasic_function_libraries.swf</link>
		</video>
	</videos>
</section>
<section>
	<description>To use an Xbasic Function Library in a component you must link the file by specify the Xbasic Linked files property in the component. You can link as many Xbasic Function Library files as you want.
</description>
<figure><link>images/linking an xbasic file.gif</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The benefit of using Xbasic Function Library files over defining the Xbasic function directly in the component is that you can share function definitions across multiple components. Xbasic Function Library files are text files, which makes them easy to manage in a source control system (such as Git), and they are easier to work with than .aex files (which provide an alternative method for sharing Xbasic function definitions across multiple components).
</description>
<note>If an Xbasic function is defined in both the Xbasic Function Declarations section within a component and also in a linked Xbasic Function Library file, the locally defined function is used.</note>
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</page>