<page build="0">
    <shortlink>ux controls control properties container begin properties container height</shortlink>
    <topic>Container height</topic>
    <description>Specify the container height. Use CSS syntax. Example: 3in, 100px, 33%, etc.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Height]* property defines the height of the container. The height is specified using CSS syntax. For example:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example><![CDATA[3in]]></example>
        </section>
        <section build="5244">
            <title>screen.height</title>
            <description>
                <p>In addition to values supported by CSS, you can also use the *[ui:screen.height]* variable to set the container's height:</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[screen.height]]></example>
            <important>You cannot use *[ui:screen.height]* when defining the in-line style for the container. You can only use screen.height in the container's *[ui:Height]* property.</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>*[ui:screen.height]* will adjust the height of the container to fill the vertical space of the screen. It can also be used with a simple expression to set the height of the container to a portion of the total screen height. For example, the following expression sets the height of the container to 50% of the screen height:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[screen.height/2]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title nested="2">Using screen.height in Alignment Containers</title>
            <description>If you use an Alignment container and you set the Container vertical alignment property to *[ui:Middle]* and you do NOT set the container height property, Alpha Anywhere will automatically set the container height property to *[ui:screen.height]*.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Understanding the screen.height Property</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When setting the height of a container you cannot use percentages. However, you use the special screen.height variable to represent 100% of the available height.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how a container's height can be set using the screen.height property.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2018-08-03</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/4ca6b084</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux containers container implementing a panel overlay">Implementing a PanelOverlay</ref>
    </see>
</page>