<page>
   <topic>UI_GET_DATE_CALENDAR Function</topic>
   <syntax>Result_String as C = ui_get_date_calendar(C title ,C default_date [,C style ])</syntax>
   <arguments>
   <argument>
         <name>Result_String</name>
         <description>Selecting a date returns that date and closes the dialog. Clicking Cancel returns a NULL string. Closing the dialog with  returns the current date.
</description>
     </argument>
     
     <argument>
         <name>title</name>
         <description>The title of the dialog box.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>default_date</name>
         <description>A default value to display in the date field.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>style</name>
         <description>Optional. The CSS style sheet to use. Use A5_CSS_LIST()to retrieve a list of style sheets provided with Alpha Anywhere. The value "" displays the version 5 style calendar.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Prompts for a date by displaying a popup-calendar.</description>
   <discussion><![CDATA[
UI_GET_DATE_CALENDAR() creates and displays a dialog box containing a calendar. This function is useful for obtaining a valid date. When the user clicks on a date value, the calendar is closed and Result_String contains the date value that the user selected.
You can then convert the Result_String into a date value using the CTOD()function. You specify the title of the dialog box with the Title parameter.
If you call UI_GET_DATE_CALENDAR() without a Style parameter and the View > Settings > Preferences > Calendar popup style is set to "", you will get the Xdialog style pop-up calendar.
The Xdialog style calendar has OK and Cancel buttons. The HtML style calendar does not. 
]]>   </discussion>
   <sections>
   
     <section>
           <figure><link>images/UI_Get_Date_Calendar.gif</link></figure>
       </section>
       <section>
           <figure><link>images/UI_Get_Date_Calendar2.gif</link></figure>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>Note : If you have changed the Xdialog system font setting from its default value, you should use HTML style display. To enable HTML style display, select View > Settings > System > Preferences > Calendar Popup. Select Style and a cascading style sheet from the Value list. 

If you use the Xdialog style, you should have your Xdialog system font setting at its default value (Tahoma 8 point). To restore the default font setting select View > Settings > System > System Fonts > Restore Default.
These settings also affect POPUP.CALENDAR()and A5_GETDATEHTML().
Limitations
Desktop applications only.
</description>
            
       </section>
   </sections>
   <sections>
       <section><title>Example</title>
            <description>This script computes the day on which you were born.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
dim birthday as D
date_string = ui_get_date_calendar("When is your birthday? ", "11/11/68")
birthday = ctod(date_string)
ui_msg_box("Happy Birthday!","You were born on a " + cdow(birthday))
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>((User Interaction _UI_ Functions|User Interaction  (UI) Functions))</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Data Type/Date and Time Functions/index.xml">Date  and Time Functions</ref>
   </see>
 </page>