<page>
	<topic>Columns from a Table or View</topic>
	<description>This approach to defining a SQL SELECT statement requires less knowledge of SQL.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Select the Columns from a table or view radio button.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>By default the Tables/Views list displays only standard tables and views.</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>1. Optionally, click Filter List to display the Filter Table/View List dialog.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>2. Place checks next to the types of data sources that you would like to view. These include:</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Views</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Linked Tables</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Synonyms</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Aliases</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>System Tables</description>
								</case>
							</cases>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>3. Click OK to continue.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select a table or view from the Tables/Views list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Place checks next to the columns you would like to include in your report. </description>
					<figure>
						<link>images/SQR_Specify_SQL_Select_Statement.gif</link>
					</figure>
					<note>At any time you can switch to defining the SQL directly by clicking the Custom SQL Select statement or stored procedure radio button.</note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you would like to use an argument in a WHERE or ORDER BY clause of the SELECT statement, click Define Arguments to display the Define/Edit Arguments dialog box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Where to filter the records that you will retrieve with a WHERE clause in the SQL SELECT statement. Refer to Creating a WHERE Clause.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Order By to sequence the records that you will retrieve with an ORDER BY clause in the SQL SELECT statement. Refer to Creating an ORDER BY Clause.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Preview Data to see the data that the SELECT statement will retrieve.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Advanced Options to define how the imported data will be mapped into fields in an Alpha Anywhere table. This dialog allows you to change data types and field lengths.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish to begin to display the Design Time Properties dialog box.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>	
		</section>	
	</sections>
	<limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Getting Started with Enterprise Reporting">Enterprise Reporting</ref>
	</see>		
</page>