<page>
	<topic>Custom SQL Select Statement or Stored Procedure
</topic>
<description>Procedural steps for customizing SQL statements and stored procedures.</description>
<sections>
<section>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>The first step is to define the type of SQL that you want to use. There are 3 options:
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>"Portable" - This Portable SQL, a generic and database independent version of SQL. Statements created with Portable SQL can be run against any SQL database. This option allows you to use the SQL Genie.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Native" - This is the specific SQL dialect of your database. You may be able to do things with a native SQL dialect that is not normally supported by other SQL databases. This option is incompatible with the SQL Genie.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>"Stored procedure" - This calls a stored SQL procedure on your database. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/SQR_Custom_SQL_Select_Statement.gif</link></figure>
				</case>
				
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you selected "Native" or "Stored procedure" in step 1,
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>1. Enter a SQL statement into the SQL Select Statement text area.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>2. Click Finish.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you selected "Portable" in step 1:
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>1. If you would like to use an argument in a WHERE or ORDER BY clause of the SELECT statement, click Define to display the Define/Edit Arguments dialog box.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>2. Click Query Builder... to display the SQL Genie.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Preview Data to see the data that the SELECT statement will retrieve.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Advanced Options to define how the imported data will be mapped into fields in an Alpha Anywhere table. This dialog allows you to change data types and field lengths.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you would like to save the data source definition that you have created as a Named DataSource, when you finish using the SQL Genie,
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>1. In the Specify DataSource dialog click Save as Named DataSource.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>2. Enter a name in the Save DataSource dialog and click OK.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	<note>At any time you can switch to defining the SQL directly by clicking the Custom SQL Select statement or stored procedure radio button.</note>
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Enterprise Reporting</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>