<page>
	<topic>Execute SELECT Query on a SQL Database</topic>
	<description>The Execute SELECT Query on a SQL Database action allows you to execute a SQL SELECT statement (a query) on a remote SQL database (or Excel spreadsheet) to retrieve one or more record(s). Alpha Anywhere will use AlphaDAO (Alpha Data Access Objects) to connect to the remote database.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<note>It is not necessary to use the Connect to SQL Database action before using this action.</note>
		</section>	
		<section>
			<description>Once you have executed the query, you can:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>preview the data in a window</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>generate sample code to show how to loop through the rows of returned data</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>save the result to a variable in the form of a CR-LF delimited list</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>perform other actions</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>	
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the required connection string into the Options > Connection string property. If you do not have a ready-made connection string, you may click   to display the Connection String dialog.</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>1. Optionally, select a named connection string from the drop-down list.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>2. Optionally, select Specify a connection string and click Build to display the  Create SQL Connection String dialog.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>3. Click OK to return to the Script Genie.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection from the Options > SQL Statement type list. The options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>" Portable " - the generic, multi-database version of SQL that allows use of the SQL Genie.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Native SQL Syntax" - appropriate for the database you selected</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Stored Procedure" - the name of a stored SQL procedure to run</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Portable" or "Native SQL Syntax" in step 2, click '...' in the Options > SQL Statement property to display the SQL Genie. Otherwise, enter the name of the SQL stored procedure to run.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click '...' in the Options > Arguments property to display the Define/Edit Arguments dialog. Arguments provide values to use in filter and order expressions. Argument values may come from variables or from user selections at run time.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click  in the Options > Arguments property to display the Define/Edit Arguments dialog. Arguments provide values to use in filter and order expressions. Argument values may come from variables or from user selections at run time.</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Open Window to Preview Result"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Generate code to loop over rows"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Dump results to a variable"</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click Preview Records. Note that this function does not use any defined arguments.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, enter a comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Generate code to loop over rows" in step 5, right click on the action and select View Xbasic.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>	
		</section>
	</sections>	
	<limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Connect to a SQL Database">Connect to SQL Database</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Using the SQL Genie">Using the SQL Genie</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=SQL Genie">SQL Genie</ref>
	</see>	
	
</page>