<page>
	<topic>Execute INSERT Query on a SQL Database</topic>
	<description>The Execute INSERT Query on a SQL Database action allows you to insert one or more records into a remote SQL database. Alpha Anywhere will use AlphaDAO (Alpha Data Access Objects) to connect to the remote database.</description>

<sections>
<section>
	<note>It is not necessary to use the Connect to SQL Database action before using this action.</note>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Procedure</title>
<steps>
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter the required connection string into the Options > Connection string property. If you do not have a ready-made connection string, you may click   to display the Connection String dialog.</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, select a named connection string from the drop-down list.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, select Specify a connection string and click Build to display the  Create SQL Connection String dialog.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Click OK to return to the Script Genie.</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Options > Table to delete record(s) from property click the '...' button to display the Select Table dialog.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Select a table or view from the list of entries.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Select an entry and click OK</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Options > Columns to update property click the '...' button to display the Select Columns dialog.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select the fields you wish to update and click OK.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Options > Set column values property click the '...' button in the Options > Arguments property to display the Column Mapping dialog.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter a comment that describes the action.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Finish.</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>If you ran this action to generate sample Xbasic code, right click on the action and select View Xbasic.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.</description>
</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Connect to a SQL Database">Connect to SQL Database</ref>		
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Using the SQL Genie">Using the SQL Genie</ref>		
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=SQL Genie">SQL Genie</ref>		
	</see>
	
</page>