<page>
	<topic>Execute DELETE Query on a SQL Database</topic>
	<description>The Execute DELETE Query on a SQL Database action allows you to delete one or more records from a remote SQL database. Alpha Anywhere will use AlphaDAO (Alpha Data Access Objects) to connect to the remote database.</description>

<sections>
<section>
	<note>It is not necessary to use the Connect to SQL Database action before using this action.</note>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Procedure</title>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the required connection string into the Options > Connection string property. If you do not have a ready-made connection string, you may click   to display the Connection String dialog.</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Optionally, select a named connection string from the drop-down list.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Optionally, select Specify a connection string and click Build to display the  Create SQL Connection String dialog.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Click OK to return to the Script Genie.</description>
			</case>
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Options > Table to delete record(s) from property click the '...' button to display the Select Table dialog.</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Select any combination of check boxes to filter the list of entries.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Select an entry and click OK</description>
			</case>
		
		</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>In the Options > WHERE clause property click the '...' button to display the WHERE Clause dialog.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, if you want to confirm record deletions, select the Options > Prompt for confirmation property.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click the '...' button in the Options > Arguments property to display the Define/Edit Arguments dialog. Arguments provide values to use in filter and order expressions. Argument values may come from variables or from user selections at run time.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Next >.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter a comment that describes the action.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Finish.</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>If you ran this action to generate sample Xbasic code, right click on the action and select View Xbasic.
</description>
</section>
	
</sections>	
<limitations>Desktop applications only.</limitations>
<see>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Connect to a SQL Database">Connect to SQL Database</ref>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Using the SQL Genie">Using the SQL Genie</ref>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=SQL Genie">SQL Genie</ref>
</see>	
</page>