
<page>
	<topic>Overview - Client/Server Applications</topic>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere's Enterprise software gives you the ability to read and write to back-end database products in a manner similar to the way you would read and write to an Alpha Anywhere table. The term "back-end database" refers to the following ODBC compatible database products which support the SQL query language.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<figure>
				<link>images/ctable.png</link>
			</figure>	
		</section>	
		<section>
			<description>
				<p>Alpha Anywhere continues to add support for other products, so if your favorite back-end database is not on the list, check with Alpha Software. In addition, the generic ODBC driver will support many database products that are not listed.</p>
				<p>Alpha Anywhere implements the back-end database connectivity with genie dialogs and an extensive tool kit of objects named AlphaDAO. AlphaDAO provides Action Scripting and Xbasic compatible functions that will let you:</p>
			</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>open a connection to a back-end database</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>select records from a table or view</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>browse through those records</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>retrieve them to your PC</description>
				</case>	
			</cases>	
		</section>	
		<section>
			<description>In addition, you can access a back-end database to:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>add records</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>delete records</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>edit records</description>
				</case>
			</cases>	
		</section>	
		<section>
			<description>The advanced user will also find tools that allow him or her to:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>manage back-end databases</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>manage tables and views</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>manage user security</description>
				</case>
			</cases>	
		</section>	
		<section>
			<description>Naturally, the standard access and security features of your back-end database still apply, and ultimately control any actions that you can take.</description>
		</section>
	</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Working with SQL Databases">Working with SQL Databases</ref>
	</see>
	<limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
</page>

