<page>
	<topic>SQL Genie Filter Tab</topic>
	<description>The Filter tab of the SQL Genie defines the expressions that limit the records that your SQL SELECT statement will return. 
</description>
<sections>
<section>
<figure><link>images/SQR_SQL_Genie_Filter_tab.gif</link></figure>	
	
</section>	
	<section>
		
	<description>Any time that the Execute Query button ('lightning' icon) is enabled, you may click it to see a sample of the records that the query will return. At any time you may click the  History button to see a list of SQL statements previously created in this session in the SQL History Dialog.</description>	
		
	</section>
<section>
	<title>Selecting the Records to Appear in the Report
</title>
<description><![CDATA[The WHERE clause of a SQL SELECT statement filters the records that will be returned. as the illustration above shows, a WHERE clause may have multiple parts, each of which evaluates to a logical value, separated by AND or OR keywords. In the example above, only records where Customers.Country <> 'USA' and Orders.OrderDate < {1998-01-01} will be returned.
There are 2 methods of generating a WHERE clause.]]>
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Directly enter it into the SQL text box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Use the genie controls at the top of the dialog to construct it
</description>
	</case>
</cases>	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Using the Genie Controls
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>To the right of the Field\Expression column click the 'up arrow' to display the Select Column or Expression dialog.
</description>
<figure><link>images/SQL_Expression_Button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create an expression that references one or more columns and click OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select an entry from the Operator list.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Depending on the operator you selected, To the right of the Value\Expression column click the 'up arrow' to display the Specify a Value or Expression dialog.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, place matching parentheses to the left and right sides of the expression.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, select the Not checkbox to invert the logic of the expression.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click the '+' to add another part to the WHERE clause.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select "And" or "Or" from the list box at the left side of the second and subsequent parts of a multi-part expression.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click '-' to remove a part of the WHERE clause.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
	
</section>
	
</sections>	
	
<see>
	<ref>Enterprise Reporting</ref>
</see>	
</page>