<page>
    <shortlink>transform api quickstartreference</shortlink>
    <topic>Full Quickstart Text Help</topic>
    <description>
        <p> Quickstart Text is a quick and easy method for adding form fields and explanatory text to a form type definition.</p>
    </description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>See the help section on "[What to do after entering Quickstart Text]" at the end of this Help for information about the steps to take to make use of the new form type as well as how to modify it later and add more capabilities. </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lines of text define form elements</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>To use Quickstart Text you enter lines of text into the text box in the middle of the screen. Each line specifies a new field or heading to be added to the form type. </p>
                        <p>Just typing one or more words as a line will specify a form field with that text as a title. As you type each line, the panel on the far left will display how the lines of text are being interpreted, such as showing the representation of a form field. </p>
                        <p>For example, entering: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[Name
Badge Number ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>will define two fields. The Preview on the right will show a representation of those fields. (*[Clicking on the Preview]* will select the corresponding text in the text box.) </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Prefixes and Options</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Certain *[punctuation marks]* included in the line can *[change]* how the line is interpreted. For example, a line that starts with the "#" character as a prefix defines explanatory text to be displayed in the form as a "Group Header"</p>
                        <p>The line: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[#Work Apron Request Form ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>will define a large heading displaying that text: </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> Text following a ":" character specifies *[Options]* that define additional properties. </p>
                        <p> For example, the ":photo" options in: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[Photo of the damage:photo ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> specifies that the field will be a photo field. The preview will appear as: </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> The double ":" followed by a comma-separated list of button names in: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[Performance test::Pass,Fail ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> will appear in the preview as: </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description> specifying a field whose value is set using a button-list. </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>How to enter Text</title>
                    <description>
                        <p> There are a variety of buttons embedded in this Help text as well as places you can click on the other two panels that facilitate entering Quickstart Text. </p>
                        <p> Clicking an *[Add]* button in this Help text will append a line to the end of the Quickstart Text similar to an example shown in the Help text. The Title text of that line will be selected so that you can replace the sample text with text of your own just by typing. </p>
                        <p> Clicking a *[Set]* button in this Help text will modify one or more existing lines of Text selected in the Quickstart Text to be similar to an example shown in the Help text. When this happens, an existing prefix and/or set of options may be changed or removed. The Title text of that line will be selected so that you can replace the sample text with text of your own just by typing. </p>
                        <p> Clicking the *[bold:#Prefix]*, *[bold:Title]* text, or *[bold::Options]* buttons above the Quickstart Text will select just the corresponding part of the line of Quickstart Text that contains the insertion cursor. This lets you, for example, quickly select just the Options text of a line and replace it with new text just by typing. Note: You need to include the ":" if you are adding or replacing options. </p>
                        <p> If more than one line of Quickstart Text is selected when the *[bold::Options]* button is clicked, a text box will be displayed showing the Options text of the first line. That text may be edited. When the *[Set Options]* button next to the text box is clicked, all of the lines in the selection will be given the contents of the text box as options. (Lines with a prefix will not be changed.) This lets you set multiple lines to have the same options very quickly. </p>
                        <p> Clicking on form elements displayed in the *[Preview]* will select the Title text of the corresponding line in the Quickstart Text. </p>
                        <p> There may be situations where changes are made to the Quickstart Text and they are not reflected immediately in the Preview, for example when using the mouse right-click menu to cut or paste. In such cases, you may use the *[Refresh]* button above the Preview to perform a manual update. </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Defining the Form Elements </title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> The following is a detailed explanation of each of the types of form elements that may be defined using Quickstart Text. </p>
                        <p> This is an example of several different form elements defined using Quickstart Text: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[#Work Apron Request Form
Name
Badge Number:number
###Correspond to sweatshirt sizes
Size::Small, Medium, Large]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> The Preview will show this representation of those fields: </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Form field</title>
                    <description>
                        <p> This type of Quickstart Text line starts with plain text, with an optional second part separated by a ":" character (the Options). Lines like this define data fields in the form. The first (or only) part of the line specifies the Title text to appear for the field. </p>
                        <p> For example: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[Name
Badge Number:number]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> In the first line, the word "Name" will appear as the Title text for the data field. In the second line, the words "Badge Number" will appear as the Title text for the data field. </p>
                        <p> The second part of the second line, with just the word "number", specifies the type of field if it is not a plain text field. The word "number" indicates the type and way that the field data will be entered, in this case a number represented in text and entered with a keypad. </p>
                        <p> The field types are: </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Option</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>(No options)</name>
                            <description>If no options are present (i.e., just plain Title text) the field will be treated as a plain text field. Input may be done in the Form Filler using a single-line input box. (A property may be set when doing Commands List Editing after completing Quickstart Text input to specify that a multi-line input box should be used.)</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:number</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9 and ".".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:phone</name>
                            <description>This is a field with digits that may include any number of optional "-" characters, entered with a keypad. It can be used for values like phone numbers, Social Security Numbers, serial numbers, and similar values.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:signed</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9 and ".". There is also a "+/-" button for toggling the value between positive and negative.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:integer</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9. On the main form screen there will also be buttons for "-10", "-1", "+1", and "+10" to facilitate quick input.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:currency</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using a keypad with the digits 0 through 9 and "00". There is an implied decimal point before the last two digits. That is, if you enter just "2", you get "0.02", and "1.00" would be entered with either "100" or "1" followed by "00".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:date</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using spinners for Month, Day, and Year. There is also a "Today" button. The value will be stored as text such as "2017-09-15".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:datetime</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered using spinners for Month, Day, Year, Hour, and Minute. There is also a "Now" button. The value will be stored as text such as "2017-09-15 14:04".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:timenow</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will get the current Month, Day, Year, Hour, Minute, and Second when a button is tapped. The value will be stored as text such as "2017-09-15 14:04:35".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:stopwatch</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will get an elapsed time in seconds. The stopwatch timer is started when the field is first tapped and then stopped when tapped again. The value will be stored as text such as "38.9".</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:photo</name>
                            <description>This is a field for capturing photos. It will display "Tap to capture image" or a preview of the captured image. The image may be obtained either with the device camera or from stored images.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:scanner</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will be entered by using the device's camera to "scan" a barcode. The value will be stored as the decoded text.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:audio</name>
                            <description>This is a field for recording audio, such as the user making a comment. It will display either "Tap to record" or "Tap to play" on the form. When tapped, large Record/Pause/Stop/Play buttons will be shown, as appropriate.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:signature</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will display a "Tap to sign" button that will allow the user to write on the screen to capture a signature. The value will be stored as text specifying the "ink" using the SVG data format usable by browsers. A preview will be displayed once the writing is completed.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>:location</name>
                            <description>This is a field that will display a "Get Location" button that will use the device's GPS capability to obtain a "latitude,longitude" value such as "42.480137,-71.203598".</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Form field choosing from a list</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If the Options part of the line consists of two or more pieces of text separated by commas, then that specifies that the field data will be entered using a *[list]* consisting of those pieces of text as choices: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example code="">
                        <![CDATA[Apron Color:Red,Orange,Yellow,Green,Blue 
Priority:First choice,Second choice,Last choice 
Size::Small, Medium, Large]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>(The spaces between the choices are optional and are ignored.) </p>
                        <p>If the two parts are separated by two ":" characters, as shown in the second line of the example above, then instead of needing to tap on the field and then choose from a list on a separate screen, the choices will be individual buttons in the form display itself. This is known as a "button-list" data field. </p>
                        <p>Here are some sample button-lists: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[Button-list Field::Yes,No 
Button-list Field::Pass,Fail ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p> For both a list (e.g., title:first,second,third) and a button list (title::1st,2nd,3rd), the pieces of text may optionally themselves have two parts, separated by a "|" character. The text after the "|" will be the value that will be assigned to the field if the choice is selected. If there is no "|" for a choice, then the value will be the same as the displayed choice. For example, if the line of Quickstart Text was "Married?:Yes|y, No|n", choosing the first choice would set the field to "y" and the second to "n". </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>#Heading</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>This is how you specify a static text, such as that used for a heading. Use one, two, or three "#" characters, followed by an optional space, then the text you wish to appear. </p>
                        <p>The three variations correspond to Group Headings, Section Headings, and Instructions Headings as the type of heading. They are interpreted as shown here: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[#Work Apron Request Form
##Delivery Info
###Correspond to sweatshirt sizes ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>#Heading with a Data Group</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Alpha TransForm system uses what it calls "Data Groups" to specify parent-child, one-to-many relationships. Data Groups can be used, for example, to let the user of the Form Filler capture multiple photos without needing to include in advance separate fields for each possible photo. Technically, in JSON terminology, a Data Group is an attribute value that is an array of objects. </p>
                        <p> When using Quickstart Text, the start of a Data Group is indicated by a Group or Section Heading with options ":dataGroup". All fields following that Heading, up to but not including the next Heading of the same type, will be part of the Data Group. </p>
                        <p> For example: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[#Family Info
Family Name
#Children:dataGroup
Name
Age:number
#Phone Phone number:phone ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>will be interpreted as:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs7.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Note how the Data Group is displayed indented, with a button below it for adding new "children". </p>
                        <p>Data Groups may be started with either a Group Heading or a Section Heading with ":dataGroup" options. </p>
                        <p>If, following a Group Heading Data Group, there is a plain Group Heading, that will end the Data Group. If following it is a Group Heading with a ":dataGroup", then that will end the first Data Group and start a new, separate one. If following it is a plain Section Heading, then that Section Heading will appear within the Data Group. If following it is a Section Heading with a ":dataGroup", then that Section Heading will start a new, "grandchild" Data Group within the main "child" DataGroup. </p>
                        <p>If, following a Section Heading Data Group, there is a plain Section or Group Heading, that will end the Data Group. If following it is a Group or Section Heading with a ":dataGroup", then that will end the first Data Group and start a new, separate one. </p>
                        <p>To *[end a Data Group without displaying a Heading]*, use the appropriate heading ("#" or "##") with no Title text: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[#Photos:dataGroup
Photo:photo
Description
#
Location:location ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>will be interpreted as: </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>&gt;Submit Form</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The "&gt;" prefix specifies that a button should be included on the form for submitting the data back to the server. This uses what is known in the Alpha TransForm system as the "Change Status" command. When the button is tapped when using the Form Filler, the status will be changed to a new, specified value and then the app will initiate the uploading of the form to the server to save the data. </p>
                        <p>The Title text specifies what should be displayed on the button. The default is "Submit Form". If the form already has the desired status, then "Upload Form" will be displayed. </p>
                        <p>The options let you specify the status to change to (which must be one of the statuses available for this account). The default is "submitted". The format for specifying status is: "*[emphasis::status|new status name]*". </p>
                        <p>Here are three examples: </p>
                    </description>
                    <example>
                        <![CDATA[>Form Finished
>
>Form Finished:status|closed ]]>
                    </example>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <figure>
                        <link>/images/qs9.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>What to do after entering Quickstart Text</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>When you are done entering the Quickstart Text click the *[Save button]* above the Quickstart Text. This will switch to the full TransForm Form Designer where you can upload or continue designing your form. </p>
                        <p>In order to use a form type in the rest of the TransForm system, its current definition must be uploaded to the TransForm server. To upload changes, use the "*[Click to save changes]*" button above the Form Types list after you finish and save the Quickstart Text. </p>
                        <p>Most of the definition of a form type consists of a list of commands that tell apps what to display, how to receive input, and how to store the data received in a particular instance of a form. Quickstart Text may be used to initially populate that list using multiple, simple lines of text. The other way to enter commands, to edit them, and to adjust a wide variety of properties that affect their behavior, is to use Commands List Editing. </p>
                        <p>Once Quickstart Text has been saved to start defining a form type, only Commands List Editing may be done to make additions or changes. Commands List Editing is started by clicking the "Edit Form Commands" button above the Form Types list, or by double-clicking on a row in the list. </p>
                        <p>For more information, see the Help provided on the TransForm Form Designer Preview Screen once Quickstart Text has been saved or canceled. </p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="#group_What to do after entering Quickstart Text">What to do after entering Quickstart Text</link>
    </links>
</page>