<page>
	<shortlink>grid component update settings customizations</shortlink>
	<topic>Customization</topic>
	<description>Customize update settings.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Submit button label</title>
			<description>Specifies the label of the submit button.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Submit button in-line style</title>
			<description>Specify the in-line style for the Submit button.</description>
			<tip>To hide the button, set the style to *[css:display:none;]*.</tip>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Delete record control</title>
			<description>Defines the control used to delete records. The delete record control can be a checkbox or an icon. The control is added to each row in the Grid. If 'None' is chosen, you must put a Delete Record control in the freeform edit region of one of the cells in the Grid using this syntax:</description>
			<example><![CDATA[{controlDef.system.Delete}]]></example>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Delete check box label</title>
			<description>Specifies the label of the delete check box. </description>
		</section>
		<section build="4438">
			<title>Allow 'delete-all' checkbox</title>
			<description>If checked, a checkbox will be displayed next to the Delete checkbox label in the Grid header. The checkbox can be used to select or unselect the delete checkbox in every row on the current page of the Grid.</description>
			<figure>
				<link>images/deleteallcheckbox.jpg</link>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Has 'Cancel' button</title>
			<description>Specifies whether the grid has a cancel button. </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Cancel button label</title>
			<description>Appears if Has Cancel button is selected. Specifies the label of the cancel button.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Cancel button in-line style</title>
			<description>Specify the in-line style for the Cancel button.</description>
			<tip>To hide the button, set the style to *[css:display:none;]*.</tip>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Confirm before submit</title>
			<description>Specifies whether the user must confirm changes before they are submitted.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Confirm message</title>
			<description>The message displayed in the confirm message box. </description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Target page</title>
			<description>The next page to display if the update is successful. Clicking the button next to the Target page  property will display the Specify Target Page  dialog. The Target page can be a specified full URL, return to 'this' page, or a .A5W or .HTML page from your project. Make a selection and click OK. The target page will appear if the update is successful.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Auto-increment field label</title>
			<description>The value shown for auto-increment fields when entering new records. The default is "Auto".</description>
		</section>
	</sections>
</page>