<page>
    <shortlink>ux controls containers free form layout container</shortlink>
    <topic>Free-form Layout</topic>
    <description>Wraps a selected set of controls in a free-form layout defined using HTML.</description>
    <!--add .list here later-->
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Free-form Layout]* can be used to position controls on a UX Component using HTML. To embed a control in a Free-form Layout on the UX, the control must be hidden. A control can be hidden by checking its *[ui:Hide]* property.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/freeformHide.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When a control is embedded in a Free-form Layout control, the HTML that is generated for that control is embedded into the layout. Controls that can be placed in the [Free-form layout] will be shown in the toolbox in the Freeform Edit Region dialog. Double-clicking an item inserts it into the layout. Any HTML can be used to define the layout. EG:</p>
            </description>
            <example code="html"><![CDATA[<table>
    <tr><td>{firstname}</td><td></td><td>{lastname}</td></tr>
    <tr><td>{city}</td><td>{state}</td><td>{zip}</td></tr>
    <tr><td></td><td>{phone}</td><td>{email}</td></tr>
</table>]]></example>
            <figure>
                <title>Hidden fields are shown in a list on the left in the builder.</title>
                <link>images/freeformLayout.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The rendered result of the Free-form layout definition defined in the image above.</title>
                <link>images/freeformLayoutPreview.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If the data you want to show in a free-form layout is from a List control, a free-form layout can be defined in the List control's definition or created using a [FormView] or [ViewBox] control. The ViewBox control is also a powerful tool for creating templates to display data in a UX Component.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="formviewcontrol">FormView</link>
        <link link="the%20viewbox%20control">ViewBox</link>
    </links>
</page>