<page>
   <topic>IIF Function</topic>
    <description>Tests an expression and returns one of two expressions.</description>
   <syntax>Value as A = IIF(L condition,A result_true,A result_false)</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>condition</name>
         <description>Logical. An expression that evaluates to .T. (TRUE) or .F. (FALSE).</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>result_true</name>
         <description>A value.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>result_false</name>
         <description>A value of the same type as  True_Value  (i.e. character, date, logical, memo, or numeric).</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
  
   <discussion>
IIF() evaluates the Logical_Expression. If  the expression evaluates to TRUE, the True_Value is returned, otherwise the False_Value is  returned. For example:   IIF(.T., "ABCDEF",  "XYZ") ?ABCDEF".
Note : Use IIF() instead  of IF() when using the expression in an Xbasic script.
   </discussion>
   
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>If STATE contains "MA"</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
? iif(STATE = "MA", .05, 0)
= .05
]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>If PAID (a logical field) is TRUE</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
? iif(PAID, "Paid", "Outstanding")
= "Paid",
]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
            <description>Suppose that your company offers a discount based on the total amount  of goods purchased. Customers buying over $1,000 worth of merchandise  receive a 10% discount. The amount of the order before the discount is  kept in a field called SUBTOTAL. You can make DISCOUNT a calculated field,  using the following expression:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
iif(SUBTOTAL > 1000, .1, 0)
]]></example>
       </section>
       <section>If the value of SUBTOTAL is greater than 1000, then the value of DISCOUNT  is .1 (10%). If the value of SUBTOTAL is not greater than 1000, then the  value of DISCOUNT is 0.
       </section>
   </sections>
   
   <sections>
   <section>
   <title>Nested if Statements</title>
   <description>You can nest IIF() statements to create more complex tests. For example,  assume that you use codes to save data entry time when entering college  students into a table.
The field CLASS contains 1 for "Freshman", 2 for "Sophomore",  3 for "Junior", and 4 for "Senior".
To print a report that contains the year of school a student is in,  rather than the code, define and place a calculated field called GRADE,  which uses the following expression:
</description>
   <example>iif(class=4, "Senior", iif(class=3, "Junior",  iif(class=2, "Sophomore", "Freshman")))</example>
   </section>
   
   <section>
   <description>If the CLASS is 4, then the TRUE action is taken and the expression  returns "Senior." If the first test is FALSE, then the false  action is taken. The false action in this case is another IIF() statement.
The second IIF() tests CLASS to see if it is 3. If TRUE, then the expression  returns "Junior." However, if the second test also fails, then  the third IIF() is evaluated.
The third IIF() tests to see if class=2. If so, the expression returns  "Sophomore." If the third test fails the false action is taken.  At this point, you have already tested for the other possibilities, so  no further test is necessary. The student must be a "freshman."
</description>
   </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Data Type/Character Functions/Formatting Functions/index.xml">Expression  Evaluation Functions</ref>
   </see>
<terms>expressions,calculated field,case,contains,field,function,logical,reports,save,time,xbasic</terms>
</page>