<page>   
    <topic>Formatting Functions</topic>
    <description>Functions to format strings.</description>
    <!--list:.-->
    
    <sections>
        <section><title>Related Functions</title>
            <description>*TREE_FROM_OUTLINE() - Converts an indented list into data formatted for display in a tree control.
</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>*TREE_TO_OUTLINE() - Converts data formatted for a tree control into an indented list.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>ALLTRIM() - Removes leading and trailing blanks from a Input_String.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>FORMAT_DATA() - Formats a character, date, numeric, or logical value.</description>
        </section>
         <section>
            <description>LEFT() - Returns a character string containing the specified Number_Of_Characters starting from the left-most character of the Input_String.
</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>LTRIM() - Removes any specified leading characters in the Input_String.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>OEM_TO_ANSI() - Converts characters from the OEM (DOS) character set to the ANSI (Windows) character set.</description>
        </section>
         <section>
            <description>QUOTE() - Inserts quotes around Input_String.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>REGEX_ESCAPE() - Formats data for processing by REGEX functions.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>REMSPECIAL() - Strips all non-alphabetic and non-numeric characters, including spaces, from a string.
</description>
        </section>
            <section>
            <description>RTRIM() - Removes any specified trailing characters in the Input_String.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>S_QUOTE() - Quotes and formats data for use in expressions.
</description>
        </section>
            <section>
            <description>STR() - Converts a Number to a right-justified character string.</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>STUFF() - Alters Input_String by replacing the specified Number_Of_Characters, beginning at the specified Starting_Position, with the Insert_String.</description>
        </section>
            <section>
            <description>TAGGED_PATTERN() - Parses the Input_String (into "tags", or "fields") using the format specified by the Input_Format string and creates a formatted character string based on the format specified by Output_Format.
</description>
        </section>
           <section>
            <description>UNQUOTE2() - Removes one level of quotation marks, but never removes the last level, which is necessary for character string data.</description>
        </section>
         <section>
            <description>UT() - Converts all the text to uppercase, and removes trailing blanks from a Input_String.</description>
        </section>
         <section>
            <description>WORD_TAGGED_PATTERN() - Parses each "word" (or "record") in the input string (into "tags", or "fields") using the format specified by the Input_String string and creates an output result string based on the format specified by Output_Format.
</description>
        </section>
         <section>
            <description>ZBLANK() - Converts a Number to a formatted right justified character string.
</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    
    
    
</page>
