<page>
	<topic>Custom Components</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<description>In Version 11, Alpha Five has added two types of reusable web components that can be created by any developer with a good knowledge of Xbasic, HTML, and JavaScript. One type is the Custom Component, discussed in this article and those following. The other is the User-defined Component, which is both more flexible and harder to develop. We recommend starting by creating a Custom Component even if your ultimate goal is to develop a User-defined Component.
</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Uses and Benefits of a Custom Component
</title>
	<description>In Alpha Five Version 10, you can open a Grid Component in a window, a DIV, or a Tabbed UI Pane, in a linked content section of another Grid, and in a row expander of another Grid. In Alpha Five Version 11, you can do all of those things with a Custom Component and a User-defined Component. For example, here are the possible Action JavaScript actions from one V11 installation:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/v11_action_javascript_actions_open_custom_component.png</link></figure>
</section>		
<section>

	<description>When you pick the action to Open a Custom Component, you see a builder that lets you select the component and set its parameters:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/open_a_custom_component.png</link></figure>
</section>		
<section>
	
	<description>A key benefit is that you can bind arguments in the Custom Component to the current row of a grid. In this case, we are binding a custom map component to a grid that has airport data including latitude and longitude:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/open_custom_component_genie_arguments.png</link></figure>
</section>			
<section>
	
	<description>At runtime, this lets us bring up a map for each airport:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/logan_airport_map.png</link></figure>
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Custom Component Videos</title>
	<description>The Custom Component is for developers who want to generate the component using their own Xbasic code. These videos give a basic overview of the Custom Component. The explain what a custom component is, and show how the component can define arguments whose value can be passed in from the calling program.
The videos show how a custom component can be called from a Grid component and how the values of the arguments defined in the custom component can be passed in from data in the current Grid row.
Next the videos demonstrate a more realistic example where the Custom Component is used to define a pie chart displaying the breakdown of items on an order.
</description>
<videos>
	<video>
		<name>Watch Video 1
</name>
		<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/IntroductionToCustomComponents_1.swf</link>
	</video>
	<video>
		<name>Watch Video 2
</name>
		<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/IntroductionToCustomComponents_2.swf</link>
	</video>
	<video>
		<name>Watch Video 3
</name>
		<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/IntroductionToCustomComponents_3.swf</link>
	</video>
	
	
</videos>
</section>		
<section>
	<title>For More:</title>
	<description>The articles that follow explain the JavaScript helpers for Custom components, how to create a Custom component, the function of the various parts of the Custom component builder, and how a Custom component can be shared and reused.
</description>
	<figure><link></link></figure>
</section>		

</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Using the Custom Component JavaScript Class </ref>
		<ref>Creating a Custom Component </ref>
		<ref>Custom Component Sections and Events </ref>
		<ref>Sharing and Using a Custom Component </ref>
		
		
	</see>
	
	
</page>