<page>
	<topic>Dialog Component - Managing Data in the Security Framework</topic>
<description>Create an Account for a new user, store personal information in a related table, modifying the account of an existing user, and using the page permissions genie. Video links included.</description>	
	
<sections>
	
<section>
	<title>Dialog Component - Security Framework - Create an Account for a New User</title>
	<description>Managing data in the Web Security Framework tables at run-time is a common requirement. These videos show how this is easily done using Dialog components.
This video shows how a Dialog Component can be used to create an account for a new user. The Dialog Component prompts for account information (such as username and password), and enters the data in the tables used by the Web Security Framework.
</description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch Video
(Requires build 3829 or above).
</name>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/SavingSecurityDatawithADialog_Video1.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Video Number:</title>
			<description>D_SF_1</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
<section>
	<title>Dialog Component - Security Framework - Create an Account for a New User and also Store Personal Information in a Related Table</title>
	<description>This video builds on the concepts of video D_SF_1. It shows how you can also add data to a related table at the same time that you create a new user account. The account credentials are stored in the Web Security Framework tables, and the additional information (which could include any data that you choose to collect) are stored in a related table.

All of the coding in the Dialog Component is automated through the use of Server-side Action scripting.
</description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch Video
(Requires build 3829 or above).</name>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/SavingSecurityDatawithADialog_Video2.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Video Number:</title>
			<description>D_SF_2</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
<section>
	<title>Dialog Component - Security Framework - Modifying the Account of an Existing User</title>
	<description>This video builds on the concepts of video D_SF_2. It shows how you can use the Dialog Component to retrieve the account information for an existing user into the Dialog component, and then edit that data. For example, you might want to change the Group (i.e. role) to which the user is assigned.</description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch Video
(Requires build 3829 or above).
</name>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/SavingSecurityDatawithADialog_Video3.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Video Number:</title>
			<description>D_SF_3</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>Modifying the Security Account of an Existing User and Update Personal Information in a Related Table using a Grid. </title>
	<description>This video builds on the concepts shown in video D_SF_2. It shows how you can use a Grid based on a table related to the Web Security settings to find and edit a record in the related table using a Grid, and then open a Dialog to edit the security information. The Dialog is opened in a dropdown window from the Grid. 

All of the coding in the Dialog Component is automated through the use of Server-side Action scripting. 
</description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch Video </name>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/SavingSecurityDatafromGridUsingADialog.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Video Number:</title>
			<description>D_SF_4</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	
	
<section>
	<title>Setting Security on Pages and Components - Using the Page Permissions Genie </title>
	<description>When you turn the Security Framework on, you can then set permissions on individual pages (.a5w pages) and Components in your project. This video gives a quick overview of the Page Permissions Genie. </description>
	<videos>
		<video>
			<name>Watch Video</name>
			<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/UsingThePagePermissionsGenie_in_WebSecurity.swf</link>
		</video>
		
		
	</videos>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Video Number:</title>
			<description>D_SF_5</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	

	
	
</sections>	
	
	
	
</page>