<page>
	<topic>Types of Web Components</topic>
<description>There are seven types of web components, that you can embed in HTML pages to give them the ability to interact with your Alpha Anywhere application.
</description>	
<sections>
<section>
	<title>Grid</title>
	<description>The Grid component displays multiple fields from multiple records in a table format. The data can come from one or multiple tables (as long as the tables are linked one-to-one). The Grid component can be either read only or editable. When the Grid component is read only, there is an option to have an additional Detail View form that allows you to edit the fields of any selected record.</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Grid Linker</title>
	<description>The GridLinker component contains and displays multiple Grid Components, allowing you to display data from tables linked one-to-many (or parent-child) relationships.</description>
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Dialog</title>
	<description>The Dialog component is a form that allows you to read and write variable data and execute Xbasic scripts. It is not intended for supporting read and write transactions with tables.</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Navigation System</title>
	<description>The Navigation System component allows you to create horizontal toolbars with drop-down menus, or vertical menus with fly-out menus. The menus can control navigation to the various pages of your web site.</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Tabbed GridLinker </title>
	<description>The Tabbed GridLinker component organizes its grids in a tabbed structure that displays only one grid per level, but allows you to switch to any other grid in any level with a click of the mouse.</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Login</title>
	<description>The login component provides user ID and password security for web applications.</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Maintenance</title>
	<description>The Maintenance component will pack and re-index Alpha Five tables and sets.</description>
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
<limitations>Web publishing applications only until Version 10.
</limitations>	


	
</page>