<page api="js">
    <shortlink>grid component runAction method</shortlink>
    <topic parent="{grid.object}" parentType="object" elementName="runAction Method">{grid.object}.runAction Method</topic>
    <description>Runs a Javascript Action for the Grid Component that was defined using the Action Script builder.</description>
    <prototype>{grid.object}.runAction(actionName [, ele]);</prototype>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>actionName</name>
            <type>string</type>
            <description>The action to run.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument optional="true">
            <name>ele</name>
            <type>object</type>
            <description>A pointer to a DOM element. This is only required if the action performs a task that is relative to other controls in the component, such as opening a window in a dropdown or positioned relative to another object.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <discussion>
        <p>Runs an action that was defined using the Action javascript builder. You can optionally pass in a pointer to the object that invokes the action.</p>
        <p>Passing in a pointer to the element that invokes the action is necessary when the action you are running opens a 'dropdown' window or a window positioned relative to an object.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Running an Action</title>
            <description>To run an action, simply call *[js:{grid.object}.runAction]* with the name of the action to execute.</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{grid.object}.runAction('report1');]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Passing in a Pointer to an Element</title>
            <description>Some actions, such as opening a window in a dropdown or a window that is positioned relative to another control, require additional information provided by passing an element to the *[js:{grid.object}.runAction]* method. You can pass the *[js:this]* pointer to the method to accomplish the task:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[{grid.object}.runAction('showWindow',this);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You can also pass in a different element in your component. For example, suppose you wanted the popup window to appear relative to a button when the action is invoked:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[//Get a pointer to BUTTON1 in Row 2
var ele = $('{grid.componentName}.V.R2.BUTTON1');

{grid.object}.runAction('showWindow', ele);]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="grid%20components">Grid Component</ref>
    </see>
</page> 