<page>
    <topic>Has On/Off Value</topic>
    <description>This only applies when the field displayed on a form layout is using a switch control.
         Checking the Has On/Off Value property will prompt for an on value and off value, as well as a data type.
    </description>
 
<sections>
    <section>
       
         <figure><title>The "Has On/Off Value" property</title><link>images/has2.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    
      <section>
        <description>Below is a list control that has been set as the data source for a form view. 
            The Processed and Delivered fields have had their 'Has On/Off Value' box checked on the Field pane of the Form View Builder.
            On the Form Layout pane these fields have had their control type changed to be 'Switch'.
            Finally, in order to make the switches active a predefined save a cancel button have been added to an editor inside and editor set.
            This last step means that the list itself can be updated when the list is changed. To see a visual example of how this was done watch [this video].
        </description>
        
        <figure><link>images/has.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Creating a Switch Control in a Form Layout.</title>
        <description>This example will use a List Control as the Data Source for the Form View Control. A switch will then be added to the form view control that will 
            update field values in the list control when saved.
        </description>
        
        <steps>
            <step>
                <description>Open the UX Builder's UX Controls page. In the Data Controls menu click [List] to add a list control to the component.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>In the control properties list, in the List Properties section, click the [...] button next to the 
                    'List properties' property to open the List Builder.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch2.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>In the List Builder's Data Source pane set the Data Source Type to be 'Static'. </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch3.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Click the [...] button next to the 'Static data' property to open the 'Static Choices' dialog.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch4.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Create a simple table of static choices like this one. Here three fields are defined. The Processed and Delivered 
                    fields will be updated using a switch in the form view control.
                </description>
                <example><![CDATA[Item|Processed|Delivered
143|No|No
163|No|No
231|No|No
543|No|No
790|No|No]]></example>
                <figure><link>images/switch5.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>On the List Layout pane move the three fields from the Available Fields list to 
                    the Columns in List area using the blue > arrow. Click OK to close the List Builder
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch6.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>On the UX Controls page open the 'Other Controls' menu. Click on [Form View] to add a 
                    form view control to the component.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch7.png</link></figure>
            </step>
           
               <step>
                <description>Highlight the Form View Control. Click on the Form properties property to open the Form View Builder.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch10.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Open the Data Source pane. Set the Datasource type property to 'List' and the List name 
                    property to the name of the list control you just added, in this case 'list1'. 
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch11.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Open the Fields pane. Highlight the 'Processed' Field. Click the [...] next to the 'Other Settings' property. 
                    
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch13.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Check the 'Has On/Off Value' property and click OK.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch12.png</link></figure>
            </step>
         
           
               <step>
                <description>Highlight the 'Delivered' field and check the 'Has On/Off Value'.</description>
                  <figure><link>images/switch15.png</link></figure>
            </step>

               <step>
                <description>Open the Form Layout pane. Click the Add Item button</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch16.png</link></figure>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>In the Category menu select Data Controls, then highlight the data fields in the list on the right, 
                    highlight [Label] in the Control menu, and click OK.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch17.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Back on the Form Layout highlight the 'Processed' field. In the properties list on the right under 
                    Data Bound Field Properties, change the Control Type to 'Switch'.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch18.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Change the 'Delivered' field's Control Type to switch as well.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch19.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Click on the 'Add Item' button again.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch20.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Under 'Category' select Pre-defined Controls. Then in the 'Control' menu select [Save Form Edits/Cancel Edits Button] and click OK. Close the Form View Builder.</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch21.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Open the Component in Live Preview and Click on a row in the List. The Form View Control should appear</description>
                <figure><link>images/switch22.png</link></figure>
            </step>
              <step>
                <description>Change the switch for that field and click the 'Save' button underneath the switch. You should see the highlighted list row for that 
                    field update.
                </description>
                <figure><link>images/switch23.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            
        </steps>
        
    </section>
    
</sections>
<links>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_formview_immediate_editors_switch.swf">this video</link>
    
</links>
</page>