<page api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 d date relative templates namespace</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.d.date.relative" parentType="namespace" elementName="templates Namespace" >A5.d.date.relative.templates Namespace</topic>
	<description> The namespace for templates used in relative dates. See *[link:Date.toRelative]*.</description>
	<properties>
		<property>
			<name>before</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when the date is before the current date. The relative date is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "{data} ago".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>same</name>
			<type>object</type>
			<description>The templates to use when the date is the same as the current date given the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
			<properties>
				<property>
					<name>year</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same year as the current date, and the year is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>month</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same month as the current date, and the month is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>week</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same week as the current date, and the week is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>day</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same day as the current date, and the day is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>hour</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same hour as the current date, and the hour is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>minute</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same minute as the current date, and the minute is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
				<property>
					<name>second</name>
					<type>string</type>
					<description>The template to use when the date is the same second as the current date, and the second is the smallest unit of comparison.</description>
				</property>
			</properties>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>after</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>The template to use when the date is after the current date. The relative date is included by inserting "{data}" into the template. The default template is "in {data}".</description>
		</property>
	</properties>
	<note> Any properties in this namespace can be replaced in order to support other languages or formats.</note>
	<!--list:.-->
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/d_namespace/date_namespace/relative_namespace/templates_namespace/index.xml</annotations>
</page>
