<page build="7534">
    <shortlink>embedded detail view container</shortlink>
    <topic parent="List Builder Detail View Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Detail view container for Detail View positioned in List">Detail view container for Detail View positioned in List</topic>
    <description>
        <p>The container with the content to embed in the List row.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Detail view container for Detail View positioned in List]* is the container that contains the content to embed in the list. The container must be a *[ui:Container]* control with a *[ui:Sub-type]* of 'None'.</p>
        <p>The container can contain any controls to embed in the List. You are not limited to just controls for editing the List row (i.e. Detail View controls).</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Embedding Child Lists in the Top-most Parent List</title>
                <description>
                    <p>It is quite common to build UX components with a series of related lists. For example, you might have lists for Customers, Orders and OrderDetails. When you select a row in the Custom list, the Orders list is repopulated showing he orders for the selected Customer, and so on. You might want to embed these child lists inside the top-most parent list (i.e. the Customer list in this example). so that the child Lists are only shown when the user taps on a row in the parent list.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how this can be done.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-03-06</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/ux_nested_lists.mp4</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>https://alphamediacapture.s3.amazonaws.com/videos/ux_nestedLists.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <videos>
                <title>Webinar: Embedded Detail View in a List Control</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In this Alpha Anywhere Demo and Q&amp;A session, we demonstrate the new Embedded Detail View in a List Control feature in Alpha Anywhere 4.6.2.7 release.</p>
                    <p>Did you miss the webinar? *[extlink:Register for the weekly Wednesday webinars@https://www.alphasoftware.com/weekly-alpha-anywhere-overview-webinar]* and join us for the next broadcast.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2021-03-17</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Webinar</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lfusT7lrmlU</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="embedded%20list%20detail%20view">Embedding Detail Views and Child Lists into a List</ref>
        <ref link="list detail view position">Detail view position</ref>
        <ref link="list embedded detail view properties">Embedded detail view properties</ref>
    </see>
</page>