<page build="0">
    <shortlink>linked freeform layout controls</shortlink>
    <topic parent="List Builder Detail View Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Detail view field map">Detail view field map</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Defines a mapping between fields in the List to controls in the component.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Detail view field map]* property specifies which controls should be populated with data from the List. Controls do not need to have the same name as the List field mapped to the control.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Specifying the Field map</title>
            <description>
                <p>Fields can be mapped to existing controls, or new controls can be created for the List Control's fields. Only one field can be mapped to each control. To map a field to an existing control, click *[ui:Map Field]* and select the control from the list of available controls. Select the control to use from the list of available controls. You can specify that a new control should be created by selecting the *[ui:&lt;Create New UX Control&gt;]* option at the top of the Target Control list.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Map Field dialog</title>
                <alt>The Map Field dialog</alt>
                <link>images/fieldMap1.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can use the *[ui:Create new UX controls for all un-mapped fields]* link to quickly map all unmapped controls to a new UX control. Alpha Anywhere will generate controls for all unmapped fields and insert them into the UX.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Fields mapped to new UX Controls</title>
                <alt>Fields mapped to new UX Controls</alt>
                <link>images/fieldMap2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You will be asked where the new controls should be created when you click *[ui:Ok]* to save your changes.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Prompt asking where new controls should be inserted</title>
                <alt>Prompt asking where new controls should be inserted</alt>
                <link>images/fieldMap3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If you've already created controls for the fields, you can use the *[ui:Auto-map Fields]* link. Auto-mapping will assign fields to controls in the UX that have the same name. If no control exists with the same name as the field, the field will not be mapped.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Auto-map Fields link</title>
                <alt>The Auto-map Fields link</alt>
                <link>images/fieldMap4.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To remove a mapping to an existing control or a new control, select the field and click *[ui:UnMap Field]*. All unmapped fields will not be assigned controls. You can select multiple fields by holding the ctrl key while selecting controls</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Selecting multiple fields</title>
                <alt>Selecting multiple fields</alt>
                <link>images/fieldMap5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>