<page build="7534">
    <shortlink>list detail view position</shortlink>
    <topic parent="List Builder Detail View Properties" parentType="guide" elementName="Detail view position">Detail view position</topic>
    <description>Defines where the detail view for editing records in a List is located: within the List or externally located, such as on another panel. This property can also be used to embed other content -- Lists, Maps, etc -- in the List row.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The *[ui:Detail view position]* specifies whether or not content, such as the Detail View, is embedded in a List or resides external to the list, such as in another Panel or container. The position can be one of the following:</p>
        <p>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Position</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>OnPage</name>
                    <description>The Detail View and/or related content exists externally to the List, such as on another panel or in a Container next to the List. The List contains no embedded content.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>InsideList-BeneathListRow</name>
                    <description>The List contains embedded content. The content to embed must be placed inside a Container. The content can be the List's Detail View or any other controls you wish to embed within the List row.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>If the *[ui:Detail view position]* is set to *[InsideList-BeneathListRow]*, addition settings are exposed to select the container that contains the content to embed and additional settings to configure how the embedded content is shown, including animation duration, icon used to display the open/closed state, and custom JavaScript to execute when the content is shown. See [Detail view container] and [Embedded detail view properties] for more information.</p>
    </discussion>
    <links>
        <link link="detail view container">Detail view container</link>
        <link link="list embedded detail view properties">Embedded detail view properties</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="embedded%20list%20detail%20view">Embedding Detail Views and Child Lists into a List</ref>
        <ref link="detail view container">Detail view container</ref>
        <ref link="list embedded detail view properties">Embedded detail view properties</ref>
    </see>
</page>