<page build="0">
    <shortlink>howto close parent xdialog window from component</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Close the Window in which the Component is Shown</topic>
    <description>A UX or Grid component opened in a window in a Desktop application can close the window when the component is submitted or a button is clicked.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>If you use a Grid or UX component in a Desktop Application and you open an Xdialog window that hosts a component, a common use case is to automatically close the host Xdialog window when data in the Grid is submitted or when a button is pressed in a UX.</p>
        <p>Here is how you can do this:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <warning>
                <p>This will only work in a desktop application. If the component can be used in both a desktop and web application, you will need to add additional checks to ensure that the JavaScript is not executed in a web environment.</p>
            </warning>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Close the Window on Submit</title>
            <description>
                <p>First, add this code to the Javascript Functions section in the component:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[function closeXdialog() {
    var xb = [];
    xb.push('dim dlgtitle as c');
    xb.push('dlg_title = ui_dlg_query("dialog")');
    xb.push('dlg_title = filter_string(dlg_title,"GridComponentInXdialog_",crlf())');
    xb.push('ui_modeless_dlg_close(dlg_title)');
    xb = xb.join(';');
    genericXbasicUIFromWorkingPreview(xb);
}]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>Then, for a Grid component, add this code to the [afterGridSubmit] and [afterRowSubmit] Client-side events:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[if(e.hasErrors == false) {
    closeXdialog();
}]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>If wanting to close a UX component after data is submitted, add this to the JavaScript returned by the [afterDialogValidate] event:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="xb"><![CDATA[e.javascript = e.javascript + "closeXdialog();"]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Close the Window when a Button is Clicked</title>
            <description>
                <p>Add the *[js:closeXdialog()]* javascript function from the example above to the Javascript Functions of the component.</p>
                <p>Then, add this code to a button in the component:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[closeXdialog();]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>This method will work for buttons placed in both UX and Grid components.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20events%20afterdialogvalidate">afterDialogValidate</link>
        <link link="grid%20component%20client%20side%20aftergridsubmit%20event">afterGridSubmit</link>
        <link link="grid%20component%20client%20side%20afterrowsubmit%20event">afterRowSubmit</link>
    </links>
</page>