<page>
    <shortlink>grid detail images conflict checking check for write conflicts property</shortlink>
    <topic>Check for write conflicts</topic>
    <description>If checked, the record will be checked for existing edits on the server before saving changes.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>*[ui:Check for write conflicts]* will compare the original values of the edited record against the current values stored in the data source before any changes are submitted to the server. If the record has been modified on the server before local changes were saved, a conflict occurs. If *[ui:Check for write conflicts]* is enabled, a message will be shown in the Grid component, alerting the user to the issue. If *[ui:Check for write conflicts]* is not checked, the data will be saved to the server, overwriting the record without checking for write conflicts.</p>
        <p>The write conflict message can be customized using the [OnWriteConflict] sever-side event.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Multi-user Editing</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The Grid component uses 'optimistic record locking' to trap write conflicts which result from multiple users editing the same record. To minimize the changes of write conflicts, the Grid component can be configured to automatically refresh row data when a user starts editing a record and conflicts can be trapped when the record is saved. Watch the video to learn how.</p>
                </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/yAxnVF5vh6isfHC7kuEQGt</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="grid onwriteconflict event">OnWriteConflict</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="grid onwriteconflict event">OnWriteConflict Event</ref>
    </see>
</page>
