<page>
    <shortlink>howto install the nightly build</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Install the Nightly Build for Alpha Anywhere</topic>
    <description>The Universal Installer can be used to install the nightly build of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Nightly build is a daily build of Alpha Anywhere that contains the most recent changes added by the Alpha Software development team. This build is made available to users who want to try out new features as they're being developed.</p>
        <p>Because this build is a development build, we strongly discourage using the Nightly build in a production environment.</p>
        <p>The steps below describe how to install the Nightly Build in a separate directory from your main install of Alpha Anywhere. These instructions apply to the Community Edition, Development Edition, Application Server for IIS, Application Server, and Runtime products. Images in this guide use the Alpha Anywhere Universal Installer which includes all products. If you are using the Community Edition Installer, you will only see one product listed on the Available tab.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <warning>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere workspaces are not forwards compatible. Always make a backup and test your app thoroughly before migrating your application to a new version of Alpha Anywhere. Workspaces created or modified in newer builds do not work in older builds of Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </warning>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[extlink:Download@https://download.alphasoftware.com/Installer/InstallAlphaAnywhere.exe]* and run the Installer.</p>
                    </description>
                    <important>
                        <p>If you have already downloaded the Installer, you do not need to download it again.</p>
                    </important>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the *[ui:Available]* tab, locate the product you want to install the Nightly build for.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, click *[ui:More...]* &gt; *[ui:Options...]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the installation location. This can be an existing location (use the *[ui:...]* button to select a location) or a new location, such as *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\Alpha Anywhere Nightly Build]*.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Use the *[ui:...]* button to select a different installation location</title>
                        <link>images/install14.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Configure the *[ui:Include Oracle Instant Client]* as needed.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install11.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select *[Nightly build]* from the *[ui:Type of build to install]* dropdown.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install12.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the version to install from the *[ui:Version to install]* dropdown. We recommend installing the most recent release of the Nightly Build.</p>
                        <p>The available versions for the selected build type are listed in chronological order with the newest build at the top of the list. The newest release for the build type is selected by default.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Available versions are listed in chronological order with the newest at the top.</title>
                        <link>images/install13.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the installation options.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the *[ui:Install]* button to install the product.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install15.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you are installing to an existing location, you may be prompted to confirm overwriting the directory. Click *[ui:Overwrite]* to continue the installation.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install16.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If prompted to reboot, reboot your computer and rerun the installer. You may see this prompt if you have pending Windows Updates or have installed another product that requires a reboot. A pending reboot may prevent the Alpha Anywhere installation from completing.</p>
                        <p>You can optionally click *[ui:Continue]*, however it is strongly recommended that you reboot your system before continuing with the installation.</p>
                        <p>If you reboot, you may need to reconfigure your Installation Options as described above.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>After the installation completes, the Nightly build of the selected product will be available on the *[ui:Installed]* tab where you can *[ui:Launch]* the product as well as manage future updates.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/install17.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>