<page build="8500">
    <shortlink>howto run installer unattended</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Run the Installer Unattended</topic>
    <description>The Universal Installer can be run without a UI when an automated installation is needed.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Universal Installer can be run in unattended mode with a JSON configuration file containing the options that would normally be set in the Universal Installer UI.</p>
		<p>This can be useful if an automated process is used to deploy a new server or update one or more servers.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Create a text file for the unattended JSON configuration.</title>
            <description>
				<p>The Universal Installer will use the options in the JSON configuration file in place of the prompts in the UI when running 
				in unattended mode. The content of the file is as follows:</p>
				<p>
					<example caption="Example unattended JSON configuration" code="json"><![CDATA[{
	"mode": "install",
	"productName": "Developer Edition",
	"installationFolder": "c:\\TestDE_8485",
	"buildType": "nightly",
	"version": "8485",
	"shutdownRestartRunningProcesses": false,
	"killProcessesNotRespondingToShutdown": false,
	"retryCountOnFileDownloadError": 5,
	"overwrite": true
}]]></example>
				</p>
				<p>The possible values for each option are:</p>
				<table>
					<tr>
						<th>Option</th>
						<th>Description</th>
						<th>Values</th>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[mode]*</td>
						<td>The operation the Universal Installer is to perform.</td>
						<td>
							<ul>
								<li>install</li>
								<li>update</li>
								<li>reinstall</li>
								<li>uninstall</li>
							</ul>

						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[productName]*</td>
						<td>The name of the product on which the Universal Installer operation is to be performed.</td>
						<td>
							<ul>
								<li>Developer Edition</li>
								<li>Application Server for IIS</li>
								<li>Application Server</li>
								<li>Runtime</li>
							</ul>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[installationFolder]*</td>
						<td>The location for or of the product on which the Universal Installer operation is to be performed.</td>
						<td></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[buildType]*</td>
						<td>The type of build for the product on which the Universal Installer operation is to be performed.</td>
						<td>
							<ul>
								<li>nightly</li>
								<li>preview</li>
								<li>stable</li>
							</ul>
						</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[version]*</td>
						<td>The version/build number of the product on which the Universal Installer operation is to be performed.</td>
						<td></td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[shutdownRestartRunningProcesses]*</td>
						<td>The Universal Installer checks if there are any running processes from the <code>installationFolder</code>. 
						If any processes are found to be running from the installationFolder, the Universal Installer will ask to stop and restart
						them. This option is the answer to whether processes are stopped and restarted.</td>
						<td>*[true]* or *[false]*. Default is *[false]*.</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[killProcessesNotRespondingToShutdown]*</td>
						<td>When a process is being shutdown due to having been found running from the installationFolder, it may not respond to the shutdown request. 
						In that case, the process can be killed if this option is set to true. The process will be restarted as part of the normal operation of the 
						shutdownRestartRunningProcesses option.</td>
						<td>*[true]* or *[false]*. Default is *[false]*.</td>
					</tr>
					<tr>
						<td>*[retryCountOnFileDownloadError]*</td>
						<td>If an error occurs during a file download, the Universal Installer can retry downloading the file. The Universal Installer will wait 5 seconds between each retry.</td>
						<td>A value between 0 and 60 inclusive. The default value is 5 if this option is not included in the JSON configuration file.</td>
					</tr>						
					<tr>
						<td>*[overwrite]*</td>
						<td>If the mode option is set to &quot;install&quot; and the Universal Installer list of installed products already 
						includes a product installed in installationFolder, this option set to true will allow the &quot;install&quot; to 
						overwrite the existing install.
						</td>
						<td>*[true]* or *[false]*. Defaults to *[false]*.</td>
					</tr>
				</table>				
            </description>
        </section>
		<section>
            <title>How to run the Universal Installer in unattended mode.</title>
            <description>
				<p>
				The Universal Installer can be run in unattended mode by using the *[xb:/unattended]* command line switch specifying an unattended configuration file.
				<syntax>/unattended="C:\temp\unattended.json"</syntax>
				</p>
			</description>
		</section>
    </sections>
</page>