<page>
    <shortlink>flying start genie select tables tab</shortlink>
    <topic>2:&#160;Select&#160;Tables</topic>
    <description>After the connection has been configured, the next step in the Flying Start Genie is to select the tables and views to include. On the Select Tables tab, you can also customize the Grid Component for each table, overwriting the settings defined in Global Properties.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <title>Overview</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/selectTablesOverview.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>The second step in the Flying Start Genie is to select the tables and views to include the web application as Grid Components. One Grid will be generated for each selected table and view. Tables can be selected by double-clicking the table name in the *[ui:Available Tables and Views]* list or by clicking the select and unselect arrow buttons. Selected tables and views will be shown in the *[ui:Selected Tables and Views]* list box in the order they were selected.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/selectTables.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You can preview a table using the *[ui:Show records in table]* link for a selected table in the *[ui:Available Tables and Views]* list.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/previewData.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You can filter the objects listed in the *[ui:Available Tables and Views]* list using the *[ui:Filter available object types]* link. The types of objects that can be selected include:</description>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Views</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Linked Tables</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Synonyms</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Aliases</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>System Tables</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/filterList.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>Not all object types may be available for your database. Consult your database documentation for information of what types of objects are supported.</note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>When the Flying Start Genie generates the Grid Components for the selected tables and views, it creates the components based on the Global Properties. The Global Properties can be overridden on an individual table and view basis by unchecking the *[ui:Use default settings for this Grid component?]* box below the table list. This allows you to generate some tables as read-only or define what fields should be shown for a particular view.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/customizeGrid.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Available Customization</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Grid Properties</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Grid Properties can be used to define the Grid Parts that should be generated (Search, Detail View) as well as the fields to include, the Grid Component's filename, and whether or not data in the Grid Component is editable.</p>
                        <p>Some settings can be specified for all tables. For example, when you click the [...] smart field button for the *[ui:Editable]* property, you can set the property to *[ui:Use Global Setting]*, *[ui:Yes]*, or *[ui:No]*. If you would like to set *[ui:Editable]* for all selected tables and views to "No", this can be done by selecting *[ui:Set All to 'No']* from the list of options.</p>
                        <p>For properties that can be configured for all selected tables and views, the [...] button will display a menu with the following options:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/setOptions.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>The following properties are available for customizing the Grid Component for the selected table or view:</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Grid component name</name>
                            <description>Specify the name of the Grid component. You can specify an explicit name or automatically generate a name based on the source table name and the global prefix you specified on the [Global Properties] tab. Use the placeholder &lt;Auto-Generated from Source Table Name&gt; to use the default component name.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Editable</name>
                            <description>Specify if the Grid is editable. You can specify an explicit setting, or use a default setting that you set on the Global Properties pane. If the Grid is editable, then the Detail View is automatically turned on (since the edits are made in the Detail View part). *[ui:Editable]* can be set to *[ui:Use Global Default]*, *[ui:Yes]*, or *[ui:No]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Grid part fields</name>
                            <description>You can choose the fields you want to see in the Grid part or accept the default.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Has Search part</name>
                            <description>If checked, a Search Part will be created for the Grid Component for this table. *[ui:Has Search part]* can be set to *[ui:Use Global Default]*, *[ui:Yes]*, or *[ui:No]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Search part fields</name>
                            <description>Specify the fields to show in the Search Part.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Has Detail View part</name>
                            <description>Specify if the Grid component should have a Detail View part. If the Grid is editable, the Detail View will be automatically turned on since Grid edits are done in the Detail View. *[ui:Has Detail View part]* can be set to *[ui:Use Global Default]*, *[ui:Yes]*, or *[ui:No]*.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Detail View part fields</name>
                            <description>Specify the field to show in the Detail View part.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Tabbed UI Properties</title>
                    <description>The Tabbed UI Properties can be used to customize the button and pane labels that open the Grid Component generated for the selected table.</description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>Button label</name>
                            <description>Specify the label for the button in the Tabbed UI object that will open this Grid. By default, the button label is the same as the table name. Use the placeholder &lt;Table Name&gt; to use the table name in the label.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Pane label</name>
                            <description>Specify the label for tab pane in the Tabbed UI object. By default, the pane label is the same as the table name. Use the placeholder &lt;Table Name&gt; to use the table name in the label.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link link="flying start genie global properties tab">Global Properties</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="flying start genie connect to database tab">1: Connect to Database</ref>
        <ref link="flying start genie global properties tab">3: Global Properties</ref>
    </see>
</page>