<page>
    <shortlink>The Alpha Developer IDE</shortlink>
    <topic>The Alpha Anywhere IDE</topic>
    <description>The Alpha Anywhere integrated development environment (IDE) is used to build web and mobile applications. It includes code editors, automation tools for writing and organizing your applications, preview windows, and a debugging tools. The main parts of the IDE are listed below.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Web Projects Control Panel</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Web Projects Control Panel is the primary interface for working with the files and settings of your application. From this control panel you can launch editors to create or modify your application. You can add resources for your application, including images, fonts, stylesheets, and third-party JavaScript libraries. You can also create Web Services, Reports, and publish your application to Alpha Cloud.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Projects Control Panel</title>
                <alt>The Web Projects Control Panel</alt>
                <link>images/webprojectscontrolpanel.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Workspaces can contain multiple projects. Each project is a separate application. Additional projects can be created and managed in your Alpha Anywhere workspace using the Web Projects Control Panel. Each project's files and publishing settings are managed independently of other projects. Some settings, such as connection strings, are shared among all projects. You can change the active project using the Project selector on the left-hand side of the Web Projects Control Panel. New Projects are created using the *[ui:New Project]* button.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Component Editors</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere applications are built with components. The main components used to build web and mobile applications are the Grid, Tabbed UI, and the UX, the most versatile component and the primary building block for mobile applications.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Left: Selecting the type of file to create. Right: Selecting the type of component to create.</title>
                <alt>Left: Selecting the type of file to create. Right: Selecting the type of component to create.</alt>
                <link>images/componentsFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Each component type has its own builder. Builders have several screens where you can add controls, customize server- or client-side events, define component properties, add user-defined functions, or specify a data source that contains the information to show in your application.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The UX Builder</title>
                <alt>The UX Builder</alt>
                <link>images/uxcomponentFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Code Editors</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere includes several code editors, including an HTML editor, an Xbasic editor, a JavaScript Editor. In addition, Alpha Anywhere offers Action Scripting and Action Javascript to automatically generate tested code. The generated code can be used as is, or it can be further refined in the Xbasic and JavaScript editors.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Theme Builder includes a code editor for CSS and SASS</title>
                <alt>The CSS and SASS editor in the Web Theme Builder</alt>
                <link>images/sassEditor.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>The Action Javascript action selector</title>
                <alt>The Action Javascript action selector</alt>
                <link>images/actionjavascriptFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Xbasic Genies, found in the right-click context menu, are available to generate scripts for common tasks, such as calling web services or querying a database.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Genies to generate Xbasic are found in the context menu.</title>
                <alt>The Xbasic editor context menu displaying a list of available genies.</alt>
                <link>images/xbasicGenies.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere also has Interactive Windows. An Interactive Window runs code immediately, printing the output on the screen. The [Interactive Window] is great for exploring the [Xbasic Language library] or testing scripts.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Xbasic Interactive Window</title>
                <alt>The Xbasic Interactive Window</alt>
                <link>images/xbasicInteractiveWindow.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Previews</title>
            <description>
                <p>While building your app in the component builder, you can [Preview] your application with the Previews tabs. Previews can include mobile simulators, allowing you to see how your application appears on different mobile devices. The Working Preview can also be detached and displayed alongside the component builder while you create your app.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Previewing an application on an iPhone 5</title>
                <alt>Preview of an application on a vertically oriented iPhone 5</alt>
                <link>images/previewFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Debugger</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere includes a [debugger] that lets you step through and examine your server-side Xbasic code.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Xbasic Debugger paused in the middle of script execution</title>
                <alt>The Xbasic Debugger paused in the middle of script execution</alt>
                <link>images/debuggerFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The [Chrome Debugger] can be accessed directly in the preview window to help diagnose layout and JavaScript issues in your application.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Chrome Debugger running in Live Preview</title>
                <alt>The Chrome Debugger running in Live Preview</alt>
                <link>images/javascriptDebugger.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Report Editor</title>
            <description>In addition to components, Alpha Anywhere has a built-in report editor for designing reports. The [Layout Table Report Editor], which is a robust, multi-banded report builder, can be used to create PDFs, HTML reports, and format Excel files. Reports can be emailed, downloaded, or opened in a mobile device's [native app] for viewing.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>A Layout Table report design in the Report Editor</title>
                <alt>A Layout Table report design in the Report Editor</alt>
                <link>images/reportFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Video Library</title>
            <description>The [Video Finder] can be used from within Alpha Anywhere to search our vast library of videos on a variety of topics ranging from detailed multi-part tutorials to short how-tos.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Video Finder</title>
                <alt>The Video Finder</alt>
                <link>images/videoFinderIDE.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can also find recordings of our *[link:Alpha Anywhere Webinars@https://www.alphasoftware.com/weekly-alpha-anywhere-overview-webinar]* on *[link:Alpha Software's YouTube Channel@https://www.youtube.com/user/AlphaSoftwareInc]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="web%20projects%20control%20panel%20topics">Web Projects Control Panel Documentation</link>
        <link link="layout table reports">Layout Table Report Editor</link>
        <link link="dt form Settings">Settings dialog box</link>
        <link link="server video finder">Video Finder</link>
        <link link="Server API References">Xbasic Language library</link>
        <link link="server%20debugger%20features">debugger</link>
        <link link="testing%20and%20debugging">Chrome Debugger</link>
        <link link="previewing%20components">Preview</link>
        <link link="phonegap%20open%20file%20with%20native%20application">native app</link>
        <link link="using%20the%20interactive%20window">Interactive Window</link>
    </links>
</page>