<page>
    <shortlink>The Alpha Developer IDE</shortlink>
    <topic>The Alpha Developer IDE</topic>
    <description>The Alpha Developer is the integrated development environment (IDE), in which you build your application. It includes code editors, automation tools for writing and organizing your applications, preview screens, and a debugger. The main parts of the IDE are listed below.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Web Projects Control Panel</title>
            <description>The Web Projects Control Panel is the primary interface for working with the files and settings of your application. From this control panel you can launch editors to create or modify your application. You can preview your application, and you can publish it for deployment to Alpha Cloud. See [Web Projects Control Panel Documentation] for details.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Projects Control Panel</title>
                <alt>The Web Projects Control Panel</alt>
                <link>images/webprojectscontrolpanel.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Component Editors</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere applications are built out components. Some components are general purpose, like the UX Component, a primary building block for mobile applications. Some are more specific, like the Google Map component. Each component type has its own component builder.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>Left: Selecting the type of file to create. Right: Selecting the type of component to create.</title>
                <alt>Left: Selecting the type of file to create. Right: Selecting the type of component to create.</alt>
                <link>images/componentsFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>The UX Builder</title>
                <alt>The UX Builder</alt>
                <link>images/uxcomponentFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Report Editor</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere includes two types of a report builders/editors. The first is called The Report Builder, and is not optimized for web/mobile use. It is included for backwards compatibility to applications built with Alpha Five Version 11 and prior. The second is called the Layout Table Report Editor, which is a robust, multi-banded report builder, which can be used to create PDFs, HTML reports, and formatter Excel files. For details see the [Layout Table Reports documentation].</description>
            <figure>
                <title>A Layout Table report design in the Report Editor</title>
                <alt>A Layout Table report design in the Report Editor</alt>
                <link>images/reportFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Code Editors</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere includes several code editors, including an HTML editor, an Xbasic editor, a JavaScript Editor. In addition is offers Action Scripting and Action Javascript to automatically generate tested code. The generated code can be used as is, ot it can be further refined in the Xbasic and JavaScript editors.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Web Theme Builder includes a code editor for CSS and SASS</title>
                <alt>The CSS and SASS editor in the Web Theme Builder</alt>
                <link>images/sassEditor.png</link>
            </figure>
            <figure>
                <title>The Action Javascript action selector</title>
                <alt>The Action Javascript action selector</alt>
                <link>images/actionjavascriptFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Previews</title>
            <figure>
                <title>Previewing an application on an iPhone 5</title>
                <alt>Preview of an application on a vertically oriented iPhone 5</alt>
                <link>images/previewFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Preview your application with the Previews tabs. Previews can also include mobile simulators - allowing you to see how your application appears on different mobile devices.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Debugger</title>
            <description>Alpha Anywhere includes a debugger that lets you step through and examine your server-side Xbasic code.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Xbasic Debugger paused in the middle of script execution</title>
                <alt>The Xbasic Debugger paused in the middle of script execution</alt>
                <link>images/debuggerFullsize.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Chrome Debugger can also be accessed directly in the preview window to help diagnose layout and JavaScript issues in your application.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Chrome Debugger running in Live Preview</title>
                <alt>The Chrome Debugger running in Live Preview</alt>
                <link>images/javascriptDebugger.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Video Library</title>
            <description>The [Video Finder] can be used from within Alpha Anywhere to search our vast library of videos on a variety of topics ranging from detailed multi-part tutorials to short How Tos.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>The Video Library</title>
                <alt>The Video Library</alt>
                <link>images/videoFinderIDE.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can also find recordings of our *[link:Alpha Anywhere Webinars@https://www.alphasoftware.com/weekly-alpha-anywhere-overview-webinar]* on *[link:Alpha Software's YouTube Channel@https://www.youtube.com/user/AlphaSoftwareInc]*.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="web%20projects%20control%20panel%20topics">Web Projects Control Panel Documentation</link>
        <link link="layout table reports">Layout Table Reports documentation</link>
        <link link="dt form Settings">Settings dialog box</link>
        <link link="server video finder">Video Finder</link>
    </links>
</page>