<page>
	<topic>About Forms and Browses 
</topic>
<description>Much of the ease of use and simplicity of Alpha Anywhere comes from the fact that forms and browses are bound to tables or sets. A form allows you to view a single record from a table. A browse displays multiple records. Schematically, they are illustrated below. 
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<figure><link>images/Browse Illustration.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>You can switch back and forth between the form and browse views of your table by clicking F8.
When creating a form or browse, you can select to display:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>all or a subset of the available fields 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>values (calculated fields) that appear to be fields but are in fact the result of an calculation based on real field values 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>a selected subset of the table's records (based on the form's filter expression) 
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>the selected records in a new order (based on the form's order expression) 
</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
</section>		
<section>
	<description>When you are developing an application with Xbasic, the close association with a table or set means that:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>in Design mode you can click View > Dragdrop list and see a list of fields that can be displayed 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>you can dynamically change the form's or browse's filter and order expressions 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>you can dynamically add additional filter and order expressions 
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>you can read from and write to any field in any record 
</description>
		</case>
	</cases>
</section>	
<section>
	<description>For more information about forms and browses:</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>How to refer to form and browse objects</title>
			<description>Referring to Form and Browse Objects
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>How to open a form or browse</title>
			<description>Opening the Default Form or Browse
Xbasic Methods for Opening Forms and Browses
Summary of Methods for Opening Forms and Browses
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Test to see if a form or browse is open</title>
			<description>Testing if a Form or Browse is Already Open</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Synchronizing a form and embedded browse</title>
			<description>Synchronizing Form and Embedded Browse Record Navigation</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Performing dynamic queries and sorts on the data that is displayed in a form's embedded browse.</title>
			<description>Querying and Sorting Child Tables on a Form
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Creating and using stylesheets</title>
			<description>Creating and Using Stylesheets</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Getting a pointer to the underlying table</title>
			<description>Form or Browse Table Pointer</description>
		</case><case>
			<title>Form and browse functions and methods</title>
			<description>Form Functions and Methods
Browse Functions and Methods
New Methods V10
Window Functions and Methods
User Interaction UI Functions
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Rich text fields</title>
			<description>Rich Text Overview
Working with Rich Text Fields
Working with Conditional Rich Text Fields
Working with RTF Data
RTF Functions and Methods
</description>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Help text and bubble help</title>
			<description>Creating Alpha Five Help Text
Bubble Help
Help Functions
</description>
		</case><case>
			<title>Form and browse security</title>
			<description>Object Level Security</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
		
		
</section>




		
</sections>	
	
</page>