<page>
   <topic>Modal and Modeless Data Entry
</topic> 
   <sections>
    <section>
        <description>Alpha Anywhere gives you three choices for data entry on Forms and Browses: modal, modeless, and parent-modal.
</description>
       <cases>
           <case>
               <title>Modal</title>
               <description>Prevents users from making edits, unless specific actions are taken.</description>
           </case>
             <case>
               <title>Modeless</title>
               <description>Users can edit any fields or records without taking prior actions.</description>
           </case>
             <case>
               <title>Parent-modal</title>
               <description>Similar to modal; useful when you are editing a Form that is based on a Set with one-to-many links.</description>
           </case>
       </cases> 
        
    </section>   
       <section>
          <description>To set the system data entry mode:
</description> 
        <steps>
            <step>
                <description>Select View > Settings.
</description>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>The Settings dialog box displays the data entry style dialog.
</description>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Expand the System menu, and select Data Entry. The default system data entry style is modeless.
</description>
            </step>
               <step>
                <description>Change the data entry style by selecting Modal.
</description>
            </step>
            
        </steps>   
           
       </section>
    
 <section>
     <title>Modal Data Entry Mode</title>
    <description>In Modal data entry mode:
</description> 
    <cases>
        <case>
            <description>To edit a record, you must first select the Change Record button on the toolbar, press F3, or press ALT+C.
</description>
        </case>
          <case>
            <description>To start a new record, you must first select the Enter New Record button on the toolbar, or press CTRL+E. 
</description>
        </case>
          <case>
            <description>Pressing Enter or Tab in the last data field does not open a new record.
</description>
        </case>
          <case>
            <description>After saving the record, edits are disallowed.
</description>
        </case>
          <case>
            <description>After making changes to a child record in a set, edits are disallowed.
</description>
        </case>
    </cases> 
     
 </section>   
 <section>
     <title>Parent-Modal
</title>
    <cases>
        <case>
            <description>User presses F3 to allow editing in the top level table of a set.
</description>
        </case>
           <case>
            <description>Form now remains editable regardless of what table in the set the user is editing.
</description>
        </case>
           <case>
            <description>Form will only revert to Modal when the user navigates to a different parent record.
</description>
        </case>
    </cases> 
     
 </section>
   <section>
       <title>Modeless Data Entry Mode
</title>
      <description>In Modeless data entry mode:
</description> 
       <cases>
           <case>
               <description>You can edit any fields or records without first selecting Change Record or Enter New Record mode. While modeless data entry is convenient, it allows accidental field editing.
</description>
           </case>
       </cases>
   </section>
   <section>
       <title>Changing the Setting of a Layout
</title>
      <steps>
          <step>
              <description>To change the data entry setting for a browse or form in Design Mode, press F12.
</description>
          </step>
           <step>
              <description>The Properties dialog box appears.
</description>
          </step>
           <step>
              <description>Select the Data entry tab, and select Modeless. Your selection specifies the data entry mode for a specific form or browse.
</description>
          </step>
           <step>
              <description>Selecting System Default applies the View > Settings > System > Data Entry settings.
</description>
          </step>
          
          
      </steps> 
       <note>Parent-modal data entry was added in Version 10.</note>
   </section>
    
    
       
   </sections> 
    
    
</page>