<page>
	
	<topic>Placing Bitmaps on a Form</topic>
<description>You can place images directly on a Form, Report, Letter, or Label layout. For example, you can insert your company logo on a Letter layout to give the Letter a more professional look.
To place an image on a form:
</description>

<sections>
<section>
	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select the Bitmap tool  from the Toolbox.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Bitmap_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click and drag over the area where you want to place the image. When you release the mouse button the object is created.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>To set the source of a bitmap, right-click on the bitmap object and select Properties... > Setup.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, change the Object Name of the image.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the source of the image. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Embedded :</title>
		<description>Loads and embeds the selected image into the layout. When you embed an image, the original Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) file is no longer needed; the embedded copy is stored in the database's data dictionary. If you plan to distribute a database, you can embed so that you do not have to supply separate image files.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>File :</title>
		<description>Displays the Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) file you select.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Library :</title>
		<description>Displays an image of type .BML from the Alpha Anywhere Bitmap Library (if installed).</description>
	</case>
</cases>


	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected "Embedded" in step 5:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click Change embedded bitmap.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Navigate to and select the Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) image file.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click Open.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected "Embedded" in step 5:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click open.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Folder_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Navigate to and select the Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) image file.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Click Open.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you selected "File" in step 5:
</description>
		<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Click 'up' to display the Insert Image dialog box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Select the image and click Insert.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select one of the display mode options.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>"Absolute"</title>
		<description>does not stretch the image. This option may cause the image to appear as a different size when printed.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>"Stretch"</title>
		<description>stretches the image both horizontally and vertically to cover the form's background. This option may distort the image.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>"Tile"</title>
		<description>tiles the image across the form. This option may cause the image to appear as a different size when printed.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>"Best fit"</title>
		<description>scales the image to the maximum size that will fit on the form background without clipping the image.</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Defining Bitmap Properties
</title>
<description>To display the Properties dialog for a bitmap, right click on it and select Properties... .
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>To adjust the dimensions of a bitmap, display its Dimensions tab, and set its Left and Top coordinates, and its Width and Height. You may change the units of measure on the Settings dialog.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>To adjust the border or fill styles of a bitmap, display the Border tab.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>To adjust the border properties of the bitmap, refer to Defining Border Style and Color.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>To adjust the shadow properties of the bitmap, refer to Defining Shadows.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>To adjust the fill properties of the bitmap, refer to Defining Fill Style and Color.
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
</steps>	
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Using the Toolbox Panel">Using the Toolbox</ref>
		<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Bitmap Properties">Bitmap Properties</ref>
	</see>
</page>