<page>
	<topic>Placing Lines and Frames
</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<description>Lines and frames can make layouts more visually appealing and easier to read. Tools for creating these objects can be found on the Toolbox , discussed earlier in this chapter. For more information on using these tools, refer to the following subsections.
</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Placing Frames
</title>
	<description>Frames let you enhance the appearance of forms, reports, letters, and labels. Frames can be used to place a border around several objects. In cases where you want a border around just one object, you can use the object's border properties.
To place a frame on a form:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the Frame tool from the Toolbox.
</description>
			<figure><link>images/Frame_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click and drag over the area on which you want to place the object. When you release the mouse button, the object is inserted.
A sample frame created in Alpha Anywhere:</description>
			<figure><link>images/UG_Frame_Options_v8.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Defining Frame Properties
</title>
	<description>To display the Properties dialog for a frame, right click on it and select Properties... .
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>To define the text of the frame caption, display its Setup tab and:
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Optionally, enter the caption into the Frame text control.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Optionally, click Xdialog Frame Text to define content that may contain text, images, and buttons.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To define the style of the frame caption, display its Font tab, and select the caption's font, point size, attributes, and color.
</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To adjust the dimensions of a frame, display its Dimensions tab, and set its Left and Top coordinates, and its Width and Height. You may change the units of measure on the Settings dialog.
</description>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To adjust the border or fill styles of a frame, display the Border tab.
</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>To adjust the border properties of the frame, refer to Defining Border Style and Color.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>To adjust the shadow properties of the frame, refer to Defining Shadows.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>To adjust the fill properties of the frame, refer to Defining Fill Style and Color.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To adjust the border or fill styles of a frame's caption, display the Border tab and click Frame Formatting.
</description>
				<cases>
				<case>
					<description>If you want a different fill style for the frame caption, check Enable separate formatting for Frame Heading. Clear this check box if you wish to remove the caption's fill style.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>To adjust the fill properties of the caption, refer to Defining Fill Style and Color.
</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Click OK to continue.
</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
</section>	
<section>
	
	<title>Placing Lines
</title>
<description>Lines can also enhance the appearance of layouts. To place a line on a form:
To place a line on a form:
</description>	
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the Line tool from the Toolbox.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Line_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click and drag over the area on which you want to place the object. When you release the mouse button, the object is inserted.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select whether you want a Thin Line, Medium Line, or Thick Line and click OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To adjust the color, thickness, or style of a line, right click on it and select Properties... > Setup from the right-click menu.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>To adjust the dimensions of a line, right click on it and select Properties... > Dimensions from the right-click menu.
</description>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
</section>
		
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Using the Toolbox</ref>
		<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
		<ref>Line Properties</ref>
		<ref>Frame Properties</ref>
	</see>
	
	
</page>