<page>
	<topic>Setting Form Restrictions
</topic>
<sections>
	
<section>
	<title>Types of Restrictions</title>
	<description>It is possible for you to prevent your user from using any of the following functions when viewing a table through a form.
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Enter Record</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from entering a new record.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		
		<case>
			<title>Change Record</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from saving a changed record.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Delete Record</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from deleting a record.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Find Commands</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from using the Find by Key function (Control K).</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Query Commands</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from using the Query by Form (Control B), Quick Filter, and Query Genie (Control Q) functions.
</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Select Index</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from using the Select Index/Query function (Control I).</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Select Range</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from selecting the Records/Advanced/Apply Range command to order and/or filter the current selection of records.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Navigate</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from navigating from the current record to any other record.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Open/Edit Layouts</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from using the Design function.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Continuous Enters</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from automatically beginning a new record when pressing Enter or Tab when in the last field of a new record.</description>
			
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<title>Browse Mode</title>
			<description>Prevents the user from switching the form to browse view (F8).
</description>
			
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The following procedure assumes that the developer has opened the form in the Form Editor. Follow these instructions to set form restrictions similar to those of CustQueryReport :</description>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Right click on the form's background (avoiding all placed objects).
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select Properties....
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>In the Restrictions list of the Form tab place checkmarks next to the "Enter Record" and "Delete Record" items. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/AL_form_custqueryreport_form_restrictions.gif</link></figure>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click the OK button to return to the Form Editor.
</description>
	</step>
</steps>	
	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
	
</page>