<page>
	<topic>Using the New Form Genie
</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>When you create a new form for a table or set, the New Form Genie lets you create customized form layouts in a fraction of the time that it would take to manually layout out a new form.
The New Form Genie lets you:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Select which fields from the table or set to include on the form
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Create forms with tabbed objects and select which fields go on each tab page
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Layout the fields on the form in multiple columns
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Create forms with embedded browse objects
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Assign a stylesheet to the form 
</description>
<figure><link>images/New_Form_Genie.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Select Table or Set
</title>
	<description>To create a form with the New Form Genie :
</description>
<steps>
	<step>
		
		<description>Display the Forms tab of the Control Panel.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
	
		<description>Click New.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
	
		<description>In the Data Source list select the table or set that will provide the data.
</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
	
		<description>Click Next >.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<title>Select a Design Approach
</title>
		<description>Select how to start the form design. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Blank Form</title>
		<description>you can then drag fields from the Drag Drop List and controls from the Toolbox and place them on the form.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Default Form</title>
		<description>you can then rearrange, delete or modify the fields on the form. This is often a good starting point for forms based on sets.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Custom Form</title>
		<description>allows you to select the fields that appear on the form</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Click Next >.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<title>Select a Layout Style
</title>
		<description>If you selected "Custom Form" in step 5, the Selected Fields tab appears. Otherwise, continue with step 12.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Select the Layout Style. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Default (Single Column)"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Multi-Column"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Tabbed"
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>If you selected "Multi-Column" in step 8:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Enter a value in the Number of Columns field.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Select a column number from the Fields in Column drop-down list.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Select each field that you want to display on the column in the Available Fields list and click the '>' icon to add it to the Fields in Column list. Click the '>>' button to add all fields to the form.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>4. Select each field that you want to remove from the column in the Fields in Column list and click the '<' icon. Click the '<<' icon to remove all fields from the column.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>5. Use the following buttons to reorganize the fields within a column.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Move_First_button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Up_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Down_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Last_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>6. Select each of the remaining column numbers from the Fields in Column drop-down list and repeat steps 9c and 9e.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		
		<description>If you selected "Tabbed" in step 8:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>The default design includes two tabs, plus regions above and below the tabs. To change the number of tabs display the Tabs tab.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>To change a tab name, select it in the Tabs list, enter a new name in the Tab Name field, and click Change.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>To delete a tab, select it in the Tabs list and click Delete.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>To add a tab, select "Tabs list, enter its name in the Tab Name field, and click Add.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>The default design has one column per tab. To change the number of columns on a tab, select the tab page in the Fields on Tab drop-down list, and change the value in Number of Columns.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select each field that you wish to display from the Available Fields list, select a location from the Fields in Column drop-down list, and click the '>' icon to add it to the Fields on Tab list. Click the '>>' button to add all fields to the selected destination.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Select each field that you want to remove from an area on the form and click the '<' icon. Click the '<<' button to remove all fields from this area.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Use the following buttons to reorganize the fields within an area on the form.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Move_First_button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Up_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Down_Button.gif</link></figure>
<figure><link>images/Move_Last_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Click Next >.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<title>Select a Stylesheet
</title>
		<description>Select a design for the form from the Stylesheet list. Refer to Overview of Stylesheets to learn more about stylesheets.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Click Next >.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<title>Finish Design
</title>
		<description>Optionally, change the Horizontal and Vertical Spacing Between Fields.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Optionally, click Show Xbasic to see the code that will create the form.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		
		<description>Click Finish.
</description>
	</step>
</steps>	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>If you select to create a new form, starting with the Default Form (containing all of the fields in the table or set), the New Form Genie will create a form with as many tabs as Needed to display all of the fields in the underlying table or set.
</description>
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
	<ref>Using the Drag and Drop List</ref>
	<ref>Setting the Tab Order</ref>
</see>
	
</page>