<page>
	<topic>Using the Form Editor</topic>
	<description>Form design overview and using the form editor.</description>
<sections>
	
	<section>
		<title>Form Design Overview
</title>
		<description>Forms provide a detailed, one-record-at-a-time view of data in a table or set, and are most commonly used for data entry and editing. Forms also make it easy to enter and modify data stored across multiple tables in a database.
</description>
		<note>A form can display data only from a single table or a single set.</note>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<description>For example, you can use a form to create invoices. A Form for an Invoice:

</description>
		<figure><link>images/Sample_Invoice_Form.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>The form above is based on a set. It displays one invoice at a time and contains data from the parent and child tables used to create invoices.
</description>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Using the Form Editor
</title>
	<description>After you create a new form, the Form Editor appears. It contains three windows:
</description>	
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>the new form (the illustration below shows a blank form, although a default or custom form would already contain fields and other objects).
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>the Drag and Drop List (the floating toolbar with the white background, which lists variables, system fields, and table fields that you can place on the form).
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>the Toolbox (docked at the right side of the screen, listing the various objects that you can place on the form).
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Form_Editor.gif</link></figure>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>	
	</section>
<section>
	<description>Note how the title of the new form identifies its table and the form's name, which at this point is untitled. The Window Bar at the bottom of the screen indicates the there are two windows open. You are currently using the Form Editor  to edit "Untitled".
</description>
	<figure><link>images/Form_View_Button.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The  button at the top of the screen hides and displays the Toolbox. </description>
	<figure><link>images/Toolbox_button.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>The button at the top of the screen hides and displays the Drag and Drop list.
From this point you can:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/Drag_and_Drop_List_button.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
	<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Place table fields on the form, all or a selected subset of the table's or set's fields
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Place summary fields, calculated fields, and system fields on the form
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Customize field properties, changing color, font, borders, and backgrounds
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Insert an embedded browse, which lets you view multiple records at a time
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Insert a subform, which can display different fields from the table or set
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Place buttons that run scripts that perform calculations, print reports, or open other forms
</description>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<description>Add color, text, lines, and graphics to the form
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Rearrange, align, and group objects on the form
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Modify the form's dimensions
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Modify fields so they move or resize with the form
</description>
		</case>
		
		<case>
			<description>Set the tab order of fields
</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Create and apply a different or modified stylesheet
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Create and assign toolbars to appear with the form.
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Create and assign menus to appear with the form.
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Preview your form design
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Add help text to the form or bubble help to fields
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Restrict access to options like entering, changing, and deleting records
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Set the record-order and record-selection criteria for the form
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Add security to the form
</description>
		</case>
			<case>
			<description>Define local, session or global, variables.
</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>	
		
		
	</section>		
	
	
</sections>	
	
	
</page>