<page>
	  <topic>Query by-Example Row</topic>

   <description>Query-by-Example Row is a search feature that lets you search individual columns. </description>
	   
	   <!--list:.-->
	   <!--order:
Query-by-Example row 
Query-by-Example menus internationalization
Query-by-Example row initial display 
Query-by-Example hyperlink text 
Search rules 
-->		   
	   
<sections>
<section>
	<description>Query-by-Example Row is a search feature that lets you search individual columns. It effectively opens up a single row of text control boxes above your grid, allowing users to search individual fields. After entering text in the control the user then clicks on an icon to the right of the textbox and a list of possible search criteria opens. The user can clear all filters on all columns, remove the filter on the current column with 'No filter'., or select specific criteria for the current row. The query runs as soon as the criteria is clicked. Additional queries can be run on other rows to further filter the data. A show or hide a query row button on your grid's record navigation bar can be used to turn Query-by-Example on and off. You can also decide whether you want the initial display of the Query-by-Example row to be shown or hidden using the Query-by-Example Row initial display property. In addition to Query-by-Example row, the Quick Search property also lets you create search features inside of your grid. You read more on Quick Search properties [here]. 
</description>
	
	
</section>	
	
	<section>
		
		<description>Grid with Query by-Example feature 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/1_queryby.png</link></figure>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>Search Criteria available to user from grid 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/1_queryby3.png</link></figure>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>Grid Filtered on 2 columns using the ' Starts with (x..)' filter 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/1_queryby4.png</link></figure>
	</section>	
	
	
</sections>
<links>
	<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/pages/Guides/Web%20Components/Grid%20Components/Grid%20Properties/Quick%20Search/index.xml">here</link>
</links>
	
</page>