<page>
    <shortlink>UX Properties Wait Messages on Ajax Callbacks</shortlink>
    <topic>Wait Messages on Ajax Callbacks</topic>
    <description>Settings for adding a wait message to the UX Component that is shown when a callback to the server is made.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p> In mobile applications, where network connections are often slow, it becomes important to let the user know that there will be a delay while an Ajax callback completes. This is easily done with a global setting in the UX Component.</p>
        <p>To turn on automatic wait messages, go to the Properties pane in the UX Component and check the *[ui:Show wait messages on Ajax callbacks]* property.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Show wait messages on Ajax callbacks</title>
            <description>Specify if a wait dialog should be shown when an Ajax callback is made. When the callback completes, the wait message will be hidden.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Use CSS3 Animation</title>
            <description>The wait window can display a wait icon. This icon can be an image (such as an animated .gif) or a CSS3 animation. Specify if the wait window should use a CSS3 animation by checking this property</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Animation size</title>
            <description>Specify the animation size in pixels. This option is only available if *[ui:Use CSS3 Animation]* is enabled.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Wait message text</title>
            <description>Specify the text to show in the message. You can leave this blank if you only want to show the spinner. You can use language or text dictionary tags here (e.g. &lt;a5:r&gt; or &lt;a5:t&gt;) This option is only available if *[ui:Use CSS3 Animation]* is disabled.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Wait image</title>
            <description>Specify the wait icon. Typically an animated .gif image is used. This option is only available if *[ui:Use CSS3 Animation]* is disabled.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Message class name</title>
            <description>This property can be used to assign a CSS class to the wait message. The CSS class can be used to style the message. Leave this property blank to use the default class name for the wait message.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Lock screen class name</title>
            <description>This property can be used to assign a CSS class to the lock screen. The CSS class can be used to style the lock screen. The lock screen is used to prevent the user from using the app until the operation completes. Leave this property blank to use the default class name for the lock screen.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Automatically Displaying a 'Wait' Message on an Ajax Callback</title>
                <description>In mobile applications, where network connections are often slow, it becomes important to let the user know that there will be a delay while an Ajax callback completes. This is easily done with a global setting in the UX Component. </description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/MwSfNfgkLSEagKi5cwbWrd?</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="howto display wait message on load">How to Display a Wait Message While a Large App is Loading</ref>
        <ref link="display a 'wait...' message">Display a Wait Message Action Javascript</ref>
        <ref link="hide a 'wait...' message">Hide a Wait Message Action Javascript</ref>
        <ref link="ux component showwaitmessage method">{dialog.object}.showWaitMessage Method</ref>
        <ref link="ux component hidewaitmessage method">{dialog.object}.hideWaitMessage Method</ref>
    </see>
</page>