<page>
    <shortlink>form layout other properties properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Other Properties</topic>
    <description>Other settings for configuring controls in the FormView layout. These settings can be used to customize the style of controls in the layout.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Item class name</title>
            <description>
                <p>One or more class names assigned to the wrapper element for the control. This property overrides the classes specified in the [Item class name] property on the *[ui:Form Properties]* tab.</p>
                <p>To prevent any classes from being applied, specify *[ui:&lt;None&gt;]*.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Styling Switches</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Switch controls in the FormView layout can be customized using the *[ui:Item class name]* property. The class name assigned using the *[ui:Item class name]* property can be used in a CSS selector rule to modify the look and feel of a Switch. Switches in the FormView layout are assigned the default class names for the Switch control's Base sub-theme from the selected web theme. For the system Alpha theme, this means the Switch will be assigned the following class names:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Class name</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switch</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned to the switch control</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchOn</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned when the switch is in the on state</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchDisabled</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned when the switch is disabled</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchInner</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned to the inner part of the switch</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchLeft</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned to the left part of the switch</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchRight</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned to the right part of the switch</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>switchButton</name>
                                    <description>Class name assigned to the button part of the switch</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>Using a class assigned to the container for the FormView switch control via the *[ui:Item class name]* property, you can add *[extlink:CSS descendant combinator@https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Descendant_combinator]* rules to restyle the switches. For example, the CSS below changes the background and border colors for a switch control in a FormView when the class name "orange" is set in the *[ui:Item class name]* property.</p>
                        <p>
                            <example code="sass"><![CDATA[.orange .switch {
    background: gray;
    border: gray;
}
.orange .switchOn {
    background: orange;
    border: orange;
}]]></example>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Left: FormView Switch styled to appear orange. Right: Default FormView Switch style using the Alpha web theme.</title>
                        <link>images/stylingFormViewSwitch.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
