<page>
    <shortlink>ux properties apply security and server side show hide expressions client side</shortlink>
    <topic>Apply security and server-side show/hide expressions client-side</topic>
    <description>If you select this option, the component is not re-rendered at run-time to apply security and server-side show/hide expressions. Client-side JavaScript is used to hide controls that should not be visible to the user. This is less secure than applying these calculations server-side because the controls are still included in the component's HTML.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>When this property is turned on, the UX is not recomputed at run-time (as is normally the case when a UX which uses security and/or server-side show/hide expressions). Instead, at run-time, data are sent to the UX with information about what security groups the user is in, and which controls need to be hidden or shown as a result of evaluating server-side show/hide expressions. A client-side function will then hide the controls that should not be visible.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <figure>
            <link>images/uxclientsidesecurity.jpg</link>
        </figure>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>It is important to understand that when you turn on the option to apply security and server-side show/hide expressions client-side, the result is not as secure as applying security and server-side show/hide expressions on the server. That's because when security and server-side show/hide expressions are applied server-side, the HTML and data that are sent to the client does not physically include anything that should not be visible to the user.</p>
                <p>But when apply these settings client-side, the HTML may contain sensitive information that the user could see by viewing the page source (even though this information is hidden on the page itself).</p>
                <p>A side benefit of turning this option on is that any controls whose visibility is controlled by a server-side show/hide expression will be shown or hidden if any ajax callback sets the value of a session variable that is used in a server/side show expression.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>