<page>
    <shortlink>ux the ux controls page</shortlink>
    <topic>UX Controls Page</topic>
    <description>Welcome to the UX Controls Page! The UX component contains a large number of different types of controls. 
        Each of these controls comes with its own advantages as well as its own sets of properties. 
        Some of these properties are shared across controls while others are specific to a given control type. 
        This page contains links to the different groups of controls available in Alpha Anywhere 
        as well as a link the Control Properties pages. If you are looking for guides on how to assemble working controls, 
        populate controls with data, or see what a given property in a control's Properties list then this is a good place to start.
    </description>
    
    
    <sections>
        <section>
            
            <figure><title>The UX Controls page</title><link>images/controls.png</link></figure>
            
            
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The lower left-hand corner of the UX Controls page contains the menus for the 
Data Controls, Panels, Containers, Other Controls, and Defined Controls. The links shown below, 
will open guides relating to the controls contained in each of these menus. 
The toolbar in the UX Controls page also contains a menu known as the 
"Additional options menu". The link to this menu contains pages describing how each of the options in the 
additional options menu can be used. The "Control Properties" links displays the groups of property settings for 
all of the available controls and containers on the Controls page. 'Control Properties' are the properties that are displayed 
on the left-side of the Controls page whenever an added control is highlighted in the controls tree.</description>
            
            
        </section>
        
        <section>
            
             <!--list:.-->
<!--order:Data Controls
Panels
Containers
Other Controls
Defined Controls
-->
            
        </section>
        
        
        
    </sections>
   


</page>