<page>
   <topic>RECNO Function</topic>
   
     <description>Returns the record number of the current record.</description>
     
     
   <syntax>Record_Number as N = RECNO([C tablename])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>tablename</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = current or primary table. The name of a table.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
 
   <discussion>
RECNO() returns the record number of the current record in the specified table.
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Examples</title>
            <description>A common requirement when you print reports is to print each record's physical record number in one of the columns. You can do this by defining a calculated field called NUMBER with the expression:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
recno()
]]></example>
       </section>

</sections>
<sections>
       
       <section>
       <title>How to initially assign unique record numbers</title>
            <description>To initially assign unique numbers to each record in a table, starting with any number (say, 1000), use the Update operation with the following update expression:
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
recno() + 1000
]]></example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
       <description>This expression creates a unique identification code for each composite record of a set:</description>
       <example>"R" + ltrim( str( recno("Product") ) ) + ltrim( str( recno("Vendor") ) )</example>
       </section>
       
       <section>
       <description>Note : Using the record number to create a unique record ID is not a good idea. The value returned by RECNO() is only a physical position in a table. It can change if you delete a record and then pack the table.
</description>
</section>
</sections>
       
       <sections>
       <section>
       <title>How to display the current record number</title>
       
       <list>
       
       <item>
       <name>1</name>
       <description>While your form is in design mode, click  to create a calculated field.</description>
       </item>
       
       <item>
       <name>2</name>
       <description>Give the field a unique name.</description>
       </item>
       
       <item>
       <name>3</name>
       <description>In the Expression field enter RECNO().</description>
       </item>
       
       <item>
       <name>4</name>
       <description>Click OK to save.</description>
       </item>
       
       <item>
       <name>5</name>
       <description>Drag the new field from the Drag and Drop List onto your form. </description>
       </item>
       
       </list>
       
       </section>
       
       </sections>
       
       
       
  
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Document Types/index.xml">Record Functions</ref>
   </see>
<terms>expressions,calculated field,click,defaults,delete,display,drag and drop,field,forms,function,list,number,operation,record,reports</terms>
</page>