<page>
    <shortlink>dt xb Creating Your First Action Script</shortlink>
    <topic>Creating Your First Action Script</topic>
    <description>To follow the examples in this tutorial, open the Learning Action Scripting workspace stored in the "Learning Action Scripting" folder in the main folder where you installed Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The "Learning Action Scripting" workspace is used by many of the tutorials in the [Introduction to Action Scripting (Desktop)] guide. In order to follow along with the examples, the "Learning Action Scripting" workspace needs to be copied from the installation folder to a folder in your documents directory.</p>
        <p>The steps below explain how this is done.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Navigate to the folder where Alpha Anywhere is installed. The default installation directory is typically *[C:\Program Files (x86)\a5V12]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Locate the *[Learning Action Scripting]* folder. Select the folder and copy it.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/copyWorkspace.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, open your user *[Documents]* folder. Paste the copied "Learning Action Scripting" folder here.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/pasteWorkspace.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>After the folder has been copied, navigate inside the "Learning Action Scripting" directory that you created and double-click on the *[Learn Action Scripting.adb]* file to open the workspace. Alpha Anywhere should launch and open the project.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/openWorkspace.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>After a workspace is opened in Alpha Anywhere, it will be availalbe in the *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog, which is shown on startup or when the *[ui:Recent Workspaces]* dialog is opened from the Alpha Anywhere toolbar (all opened workspaces must be closed before the Recent Workspaces button is availabe on the Alpha Anywhere toolbar.)</p>
                <p>To see the list of recent workspaces, select the *[ui:Open an existing Workspace]* option in the Select Workspace dialog. If your workspace is not listed, you can use the *[ui:More Workspaces...]* option to navigate to where you copied the "Learning Action Scripting" workspace.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/selectWorkspace.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
    <links>
        <link link="dt actionscripting tutorial">Introduction to Action Scripting (Desktop)</link>
    </links>
</page>