<page>
   <topic>A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_BROWSE Function</topic>
   <syntax>P a5_open_default_browse(C table_set_name [,C filter [,C order [,C description [,C options [,L enable_show_all [,* arguments ]]]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>table_set_name</name>
         <description>The name of the table or set to display. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>filter</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = .T. (all records). A character filter expressionthat evaluates to a logical value. Selects records from the table.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>order</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = record order. A character order expressionthat sorts selected records.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>description</name>
         <description>The description that you assign to the query that Alpha Anywhere creates when the browse is opened.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>options</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = Record order, ascending, not unique. Controls whether Alpha Anywhere uses an index, a new query list, or an existing query list to satisfy a query. This string can contain one or more of the following codes:</description>
     
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>Code</name>
     		<description>Description</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>N</name>
     		<description>Builds a query list even if an index matches the query definition.</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>D</name>
     		<description>The descending order option puts the records in descending alphabetical order or, for a numeric field, from highest to lowest value.
</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>T</name>
     		<description>Temporary query. Alpha Anywhere will automatically delete this query if necessary if building a new query would cause it to run out of query slots. there are a maximum of 16 query slots.
</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>U</name>
     		<description>The unique option includes only unique records in the query list.</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>M</name>
     		<description>Builds a new query list even though a) an existing query list exists, and b) an existing Index exists (both of which, Alpha Anywhere could have used rather than running a new query).
</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>X</name>
     		<description>Use an index even if an existing query exists (which Alpha Anywhere would otherwise have used in preference to the index).
</description>
     	</item>
     </list>
     <list>
     	<item>
     		<name>I</name>
     		<description>The I flag is obsolete. It was used by Alpha Five V1 to indicate that the index should be case-insensitive. However since V2, Alpha Five automatically builds all indexes as Case-insensitive. It is documented because in some situations, the Script Recorder will show Xbasic code that includes the "I" flag.
</description>
     	</item>
     </list>

     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>enable_show_all</name>
         <description>Logical. Optional. Default = .F. Specifies whether the Show All icon that appears on the toolbar is enabled.
.T. = Icon enabled, .F. = Icon not enabled. 
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>arguments</name>
         <description>*</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Opens the default Browse for a table or set.</description>
   <discussion>
The A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_BROWSE() function displays the default browse for the selected table or set. If you specify an optional filter and order, you can give the query a description (which shows up when you press Control I to display the index selector).
options are the standard options that apply the to .query_create() method.
If you do not want the user to remove the filter/order that you specified for the default browse, you would want Show_Allicon to be disabled. otherwise the user could press the icon and remove the filter that you specified.
Limitations: Desktop applications only.
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
       <title>Example</title>
            <description>The following displays all the entries from the Customer table where the lastnamefield starts with the letter M or greater. The entries are also ordered by lastname.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
a5_open_default_browse("customer", "lastname > " + quote("M"), "lastname")
]]></example>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Desktop/Reference/Design/View/Browse/Browse Functions and Methods.html">Browse Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
<terms>browse,a5,arguments,contains,control,defaults,delete,filter,function,icons,index,letter,list,logical,query,record,script,string,toolbar,users,xbasic</terms>
</page>