<page>
	<topic>Lookups</topic>
		<description>When entering values in a Character, Numeric, or Date field, it is useful to choose a value from a list. For example, in a table of invoice items, you can use a Lookup to display a list of products from which to choose. 
</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<figure><link>images/UG_Field_Rules_Lookups_tab.gif</link></figure>
		
	</section>
<section>
	<description>You can use a Lookup to display and insert values from either a pre-defined list (that you create in the Field Rules Editor ) or from a lookup table. The user selects a value to enter in the lookup field. 
</description>
	<figure><link>images/UG_Simple_Lookup.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>By choosing entries from a list, instead of typing them manually, data entry is expedited and accuracy is ensured.
A selection from a lookup list can fill multiple fields in the current record.
</description>
	<note>Field Rule lookups are not supported by grid or dialog components. In these applications, you must define a DropDownBox control and set its Choices properties.</note>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Creating a Lookup</title>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select your table in the Table/Sets tab of the Control Panel.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select Design > Field Rules.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the field from the drop-down list at the top left corner of the dialog.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Display the Lookups tab. Field types that support choices include the following:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Combo Box</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>List Box</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Multi-state button</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Tree Control
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Drop Down Tree
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Record List-List Box
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Two-state Button
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Check Box
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Field Select
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>File Select
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Filter Builder
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Order Builder
</description>
	</case>
	
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<title>Selecting the Type of Lookup</title>
		<description>Select one of the five types of Lookup styles. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Simple list </title>
		<description>Use when you have a static list of options, such as gender.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Cascading list</title>
		<description>Use for a limited set of values that can be presented in a menu hierarchy</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Table lookup</title>
		<description>Use for dynamic, high transaction volume applications where you need to associate records in the current table with a changing list of values in the lookup table.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Conditional table lookup</title>
		<description>Use for situations where you need a two-stage lookup. The first value selects the table. The second value generates the selection list.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Previous values</title>
		<description>Allows you to build a lookup list as you go. A good solution when you cannot anticipate the values that will go into the list.</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>
	
</sections>	
	
	<see>
		
<ref>Completing Several Fields</ref>
<ref>Displaying Selected Lookup Table Records (Filtered Lookups)</ref>
<ref>Creating a Simple Lookup List, Creating a Cascading Lookup List</ref>
<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Creating a Table Lookup">Creating a Table Lookup</ref>
<ref>Creating Conditional Table Lookups, Creating a Previous Values Lookup</ref>
		
		
		
		
	</see>
</page>