<page>
	<topic>Setting Choices for Record Lists</topic>
<description>A data field displayed as a record list-list box or record list-combo box accepts only new or changed values that are already in the list. The difference between the two control types is only in the display of the data. A data field displayed as a record list-edit combo box accepts both values in the list and new values entered by the user.</description>
<sections>
<section>
		
	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select the control, choose Object > Properties and display the Setup tab.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select "Record List-List Box", "Record List-Combo Box", or "Record List-Edit Combo Box" in the Field-Type list.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Display the Choices tab.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select a table in the From Table list.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Specify the value you want to place into the field in the local table in the Return value field.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>1. Optionally, click the 'down arrow' button and select a field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>2. Optionally, click and select "" to open the Expression Builder to help you construct an expression.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>A filter expression selects values from a lookup table based on one or more values in the current table. Optionally, check Enable Filter Expression and click Edit Filter Expression to display the Filter Expression dialog.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Click Add New Column to Record List to display the Add New Record List Field dialog.
</description>
		<cases>
		<case>
			<description>1. Select the field you want to display from the Field list.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>2. Optionally, change the column label in the Header field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>3. Optionally, change the number of characters to display in the Width field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>4. Click OK to continue.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>5. Repeat steps 7a through 7d for each additional field that you would like to display in the list.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, select any item in the Columns in Record List and click Edit Selected Item to display the Edit Existing Record List Field dialog.</description>
		<cases>
		<case>
			<description>1. Optionally, select a different field to display from the Field list.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>2. Optionally, change the column label in the Header field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>3. Optionally, change the number of characters to display in the Width field.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>4. Click OK to continue.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>5. Optionally, select any item in the Columns in Record List and use the 'up triangle' (move left) and the 'down triangle' (move right) buttons to change its column position.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear Include column headings to suppress the display of column labels.</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Display only unique keys to prevent duplicate entries from appearing in the list.</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Setting Choices for List and Combo Boxes</ref>
	
</see>	
	
</page>