<page>
   <topic>REGION_FROM_AREACODE Function</topic>
    <description>Returns the region for the specified telephone area code as defined by the North American Numbering Plan Administration (http://www.nanpa.com/).</description>

   <prototypes><prototype>C region_from_areacode(* areacode )</prototype>
   <prototype>Region as C = REGION_FROM_AREACODE( Area_Code as C )</prototype>
   <prototype>Region as C = REGION_FROM_AREACODE( Area_Code as N )</prototype>
  
   </prototypes>
   <arguments>
       <argument>
         <name>Region</name>
         <description>The region for the specified telephone area code as defined by the North American Numbering Plan Administration.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>areacode</name>
         <description>A 3 digit number or character string.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
     <discussion>
The REGION_FROM_AREACODE() function returns the region for the specified telephone area code as defined by the North American Numbering Plan Administration. The area code may be passed in as either a character or numeric value.
If the specified area code is in use and assigned to a specific region, the result will be the 2 letter abbreviation for the North American region served by the specified area code (US state, Canadian province or ISO country code). If the area code is not in use or is not specific to a geographic region (such as 800, 888, 900, etc), an empty string is returned.
There are a few exceptions to 2 letter code convention:
   </discussion>
  
   <sections>
       <section>
            <list>
            <item>
            <name>345 </name>
            <description>Returns "Cayman Islands". The ISO country code is "KY" which could be confused with the state of Kentucky so the full name is returned.
</description>
            </item>
            
            <item>
            <name>600 </name>
            <description>Returns "Canada" as it is used throughout the country and not in one specific province. The country code CA could be confused with California so the full name is returned.
</description>
            </item>
            
            <item>
            <name>664 </name>
            <description>Returns "Montserrat". The ISO country code is "MS" which could be confused with the state of Mississippi so the full name is returned.
</description>
            </item>
            
            <item>
            <name>667</name>
            <description>Returns"YT, NT, NU" as it is shared by these 3 Canadian provinces. </description>
            </item>
            
            
            
           </list>
       </section>
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Data Type/Character Functions/List Processing Functions/index.xml">List Processing Functions</ref>
   </see>
   
 

<terms>list processing,function,letter,list,number,string</terms>
  
  
  
  
 
</page>