<page>
    <shortlink>form layout image properties properties</shortlink>
    <topic>FormView Image Properties Properties</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring a data-bound Image in the FormView layout.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Base64 prefix</title>
            <description>
                <p>The prefix (if required) to add to the base64 encoded image data. This is required if the image is base64 encoded and does not include a prefix.</p>
                <p>If the base64 data in the field already has a prefix in the base64 encoded data (e.g. 'data:image/jpg;base64,' ) then you will not need to add a prefix. If the data in the field is raw base64 encoded data, you will need to add the appropriate prefix.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image class name</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify one or more classes to apply to the image control.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image display dimension</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify if the 'Image display height/width' property is a 'width' or 'height' property.</p>
                <p>You cannot specify both properties (because it would distort the image by changing its aspect ratio).</p>
            </description>
            <note>You can only specify the 'Image display height/width' if Annotation is turned on.</note>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name>Width</name>
                    <description>Use the image width.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Height</name>
                    <description>Use the image height.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image display height/width</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the display width or height of the image. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 300px) - but not percentages (e.g. you cannot use '50%').</p>
                <p>The *[ui:Image display height/width]* property is only used if the image has the 'Allow image annotation' property turned on. This property overrides any height or width setting in the image inline style or class.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Image inline style</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify an in-line style to be applied to the image.</p>
            </description>
            <important>If Annotation is turned on, height and width settings in the inline-style are ignored</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Item class name</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify a class name for the 'control wrapper'. If this value is blank, the value specified in the 'Form Properties' tab for the 'Item class name' will be used. If you do not want to use any value you can specify &lt;None&gt;.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Missing image HTML</title>
            <description>
                <p>Specify the HTML to display if there is no image for this field in the current record.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
