<page>
	<topic>Creating Scripts attached to Forms and Form Objects</topic>
	
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Example</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>To create a new script:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>From the menu bar, select Scripts > New Script, and choose Use Action Script Editor or Use Xbasic Code Editor.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>If you are going to create a script:</description>
						<cases>
							<case>
								<description>Select either the Script Genie or Xbasic radio buttons.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<description>Enter the name of the script in the Script Name field.</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<description>Optionally, check Put script on Favorites list. This will make the script appear in the Scripts menu for the form or browse.
</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<description>Optionally, enter a comment in the Script Description field. Your Favorites list will show the description in place of the script name.
</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<description>Optionally, check Associate image with script to display the Image Name field.
</description>
							</case>
							<case>
								<description>Click the 'palette' icon to the Insert Image dialog box to select an image.
</description>
							</case>
							
						</cases>
					
					
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>If you are going to create a function:</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>Display the Functions tab.</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Enter the Function Name.</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Select the Return Type.</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Optionally, if you know what arguments the function will take, check Specify optional arguments.</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>Enter the names and types of the arguments.</description>
								</case>
								
							</cases>
				
				
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>Click OK to continue or Cancel to discard your inputs.</description>
							<cases>
								<case>
									<description>If you selected Script Genie in step 2a, the Action Script Editor opens.
</description>
								</case>
								<case>
									<description>If you selected Xbasic in step 2a or decided to create a function, the Code Editor opens.
</description>
								</case>
							</cases>
						
						
						</case>
						
					</cases>
				</step>
				
				
				
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>When you are done, save the script and it will appear in the Scripts menu for the form or browse.</description>
		</section>
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Show Favorites Toolbar</title>
			<description>Selecting Scripts > Show Favorites Toolbar displays a toolbar with buttons for each of your favorite scripts.
</description>
			<figure><link>images/Script_Favorites.gif</link></figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>The toolbar remains open while you work, giving you quick access to your favorite scripts.</description>
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</page>