<page>
	<topic>Open a Form as a Dialog Box</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Open a Form as a Dialog Box action provides a alternative approach to displaying a dialog. Rather than creating an Xdialog or message box, you select a predefined form to open as a modal dialog box.
The form you select to open as a dialog must contain buttons. Using the Script Genie, you define actions to take place according which buttons are selected by the user.
</description>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Select the form you will be using from the Form Name list.</description>
				</step>
					
				<step>
					<description>Enter a name for the dialog box in the Dialog Box Name field. The name should be unique so that when referenced, Alpha Anywhere will not confuse it with any other objects.</description>
				</step>	
					
				<step>
					<description>Select each button in the If the user clicks on list and make a selection in the Then... field to specify what happens when you press the button. You can attach a previously defined script, or have it do nothing.</description>
					<cases>
						
						<case>
							<description>"Play a Script". Use this option to attach a script to a button. When you select this option, you'll be prompted to select the script you wish to attach. A drop-down box appears, listing available scripts. Pressing the button runs the script. </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Do Nothing - just set a Flag Variable to .T.". Use this option if you do not want the button to play a script. When the button is selected, the message box will close, and set a Flag Variable. </description>
						</case>
					</cases>
		
		<note>In both cases, Alpha Anywhere automatically creates and names Flag Variables. In this case: "QuickCustomer_BUTTON2_button", "QuickCustomer_BUTTON2_button", etc.</note>
		
				</step>	
					
				
				
				
				
			</steps>
			<step>
					<description>Select a Default Action if the user closes the form by clicking the 'x' close icon.</description>
				</step>	
			<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
			</step>	
			<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
			</step>	
			<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
			</step>	
			
		</section>
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>FORM.DIALOG()</ref>
		
	</see>
	
</page>