<page>
	<topic>Open Default Form or Browse</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Open Default Form or Browse action opens the default form or browse window for a table or set. You can use this to display records to a user or allow them to edit information. The action also returns a pointer to the window that you can use to manipulate the contents of that window.</description>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Open Default Form or Browse Layout? field. The choices are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Form"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Browse"</description>
						</case>
					
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the For which Table/Set? field select one of the listed forms or browses.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click the Advanced tab. as the tab explains, you should not make any changes here unless you have a specific reason for doing so. The pointer required to write Xbasic code that reads or writes form or browse values or properties.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, change the pointer name in the Pointer field.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, change the scope of the pointer variable. Scope controls what other scripts can use this pointer.</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Session" means that all the other scripts on the window you opened will have access to the variable.</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Global" will allow any script running, even from another form, to access this pointer.</description>
					</case>
					
					
				</cases>
		
		
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, specify the record selection criteria to apply in addition to those defined in the layout.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_BROWSE()</ref>
		<ref>A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_FORM()</ref>
		
		
	</see>
	
</page>