<page>
    <shortlink>AlphaDAO OData</shortlink>
    <topic>Consuming Data from OData Sources</topic>
    <description>AlphaDAO connections can be created for performing CRUD (create, read, update, delete) actions against an OData source.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>Standard AlphaDAO methods can be used to access data exposed by OData data sources. The ideos below show how to create an AlphaDAO connection string for an OData source. The OData connection string is then used to create a Grid Component. Part 3 demonstrates how the same AlphaDAO OData connection string is used to populate a List control in a UX Component.</description>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Using OData Data Sources Part 1</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/odata_1.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Using OData Data Sources Part 2</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/odata_2.swf</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Using OData Data Sources Part 3</name>
                    <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/odata_3.swf</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>OData is a very popular standard for accessing data using REST calls. Alpha Anywhere can connect to OData services and execute [standard portable SQL statements] against the OData source. The SQL is limited to functionality supported by the OData service. For example, JOIN commands are not supported by OData.</p>
                <p>To use OData data, create a named AlphaDAO connection string and select OData as the connection type.</p>
                <p>The AlphaDAO Connection String dialog will prompt for the Base URL of the OData service. When the named connection string is created, you can continue to build Grid and UX components in the same way that you would for any SQL database.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/odata_connection.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=supported portable sql syntax">Supported Portable SQL Syntax</ref>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search=json_from_xml_odata()">json_from_xml_odata Function</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=supported portable sql syntax">standard portable SQL statements</link>
    </links>
    <terms>odata,data integration,alphadao</terms>
</page>