<page>
	<topic>Placing Type-In Controls
</topic>
	<sections>
<section>
	<description>Type-In controls allow you to input and edit the values of data fields and variables. You can place a type-in control in two ways.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Select the Type-In Tool on the Toolbox panel, and draw a field on the layout, and then assign a character, memo, or RTF memo field or a variable to it.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Typein_Tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Drag a character, memo, or RTF memo field or a variable from the Table Fields section of the Fields panel onto the layout.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<description>To create a Type-In control using the Type-In Tool.
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select the Type-In Tool  on the Toolbox panel.
</description>
<figure><link>images/Typein_Tool_button.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click and drag over the area on which you want to place the object. When you release the mouse button, the Field Select dialog appears.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Select a category from the Table list. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>the current table name
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Var" - variables
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Calc" - calculated fields
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"System" - system fields
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you selected the current table name in step 3, select a field from the Available Fields list, and click OK.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>If you selected "Var" in step 3:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>1. Optionally, select an existing variable for the Available Fields list, and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>2. Optionally, click Add Variable to display the Add Variable dialog box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>3. Select the Scope of the variable.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>4. Select the Data Type of the variable.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>5. Enter a Name.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>6. Click OK and OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>7. If you selected "Calc" in step 3, select a calculated field from the Available Fields list, and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>8. If you selected "System" in step 3, select a system field from the Available Fields list, and click OK.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>9. Alternatively, you can create a text object by choosing Object > New. When the New Object dialog box appears, choose "Field" from the Object Type list box.
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Continue with Setting Field Properties.
</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>Using the Toolbox</ref>
		<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
		<ref>Field Properties</ref>
	</see>
	
	
</page>