<page>
	<topic>Setting Choices for Check boxes
</topic>
<description>A data field displayed as a check box sets only two predefined values.
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Select the control, choose Object > Properties and display the Setup tab.
</description>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Select "Check Box" in the Field-Type list.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Display the Choices tab.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, change the Check box text that appears next to the check box.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Select the Display style. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap followed by text"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap only"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Bitmap over text"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Text followed by bitmap"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Text only"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Text over bitmap"
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, make a selection from the Radio style list. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Checkmarked"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Default Style"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Indented Checkmarked"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Indented Diamonds"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Indented Style"
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter the Check box true value. This is the value that is stored in your field when the check is visible.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>Enter the Check box false value. This is the value that is stored in your field when the check is not visible.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	<step>
		<description>If the selection in step 5 included bitmaps:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Click Define bitmaps... to display the Define Bitmaps dialog box. Otherwise, click OK to save your choices definition.
</description>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<description>In the Define Bitmaps dialog box select each entry in turn and click Define Bitmap to display the Define Picture dialog box.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>In the Define Picture dialog box optionally check Button displays a different picture when a button is pressed. This causes the Pressed tab to appear.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, on the Default tab click Embedded and Select Embedded Bitmap. Navigate to the image, select it, and click Open.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, on the Default tab click File and the 'up arrow' icon. Navigate to the image, select it, and click Open.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Optionally, on the Default tab click Internal and the 'up arrow' icon. Select the image from the Insert Image dialog box, and click Insert.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>If the Pressed tab is visible, display it, and select another image in the same manner as described by steps 9b through 9f.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Click OK, OK and OK to save your choices definition.
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	
	
	
</steps>	
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Specifying User Defined Choices
</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>