<page>
	<topic>Using the Toolbox Panel
</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>The Toolbox panel contains a collection of layout tools. Each tool is used either to create new objects, such as the Bitmap Tool which lets you insert pictures, or move objects, such as the Horizontal Shift Tool which lets you move multiple objects left or right.
You can place a data field on a form by selecting one of the field data controls on the Toolbox panel and sketching its outline on the form.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Selection Tool</title>
		<description>Selects an object on the form so you can modify, move, resize, delete it.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Selection_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Horizontal Shift</title>
		<description>Selects all objects to its right so you can move them as a group.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Horizontal_Shift_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Vertical Shift</title>
		<description>Selects all objects below it so you can move them as  a group.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Vertical_Shift_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Text Object</title>
		<description>Label text can has the following properties: font, point size, style, color, border style, border color, fill color. You can also word wrap the text to multiple lines.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Text_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Browse Object</title>
		<description>An embedded browse is good for showing details of child records associated with the parent record on the form.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Browse_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Subform Object</title>
		<description>An embedded form is a technique for placing more data on a form without overcrowding.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Sub_form_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Bitmap Object</title>
		<description>The bitmap tool places a picture on the form.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/Bitmap_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>OLE Object</title>
		<description>OLE objects can add new functionality to an Alpha Anywhere application.</description>
		<figure><link>images/OLE_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Frame Object</title>
		<description>Places a frame on the form. A frame is good for naming and associating a group of controls.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Frame_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Line Object</title>
		<description>Places a line on the form. Lines can have thickness and color.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Line_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Page Break Object</title>
		<description>The page break indicates where a form should break when it is printed.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/Page_break_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Conditional Object</title>
		<description>A conditional object is a container for other controls and dynamically displays those controls based on the values of variables.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Conditional_tool_v6_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Tabbed Object</title>
		<description>A tabbed object has multiple pages and is a container for other controls. A tabbed control is a familiar technique for placing more controls on a form without crowding them.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/Tabbed_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Hot Spot Object</title>
		<description>A hot spot is an invisible area that responds to mouse clicks. It is typically used to run scripts or set the values of variables.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Hotspot_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>User Object</title>
		<description>User objects can add new functionality to an Alpha Anywhere application.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/User_object_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>ActiveX Object</title>
		<description>ActiveX objects can add new functionality to an Alpha Anywhere application.</description>
		<figure><link>images/ActiveX_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Rich Text Object</title>
		<description>You can specify the font, point size, style, and color of rich text. You can word wrap the text to multiple lines. Rich text can dynamically change based on the value of variables.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Rich_Text_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	<case>
		<title>Button Object</title>
		<description>Places a button on the form. Buttons can have text and/or pictures as Labels, as well as Color and shape. Buttons typically are used to run scripts or set the values of variables.</description>
		<figure><link>images/Button_tool_button.gif</link></figure>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>	
	
</section>	
	
	
	
</sections>	
<see>
	<ref>Placing a Field on a Form</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>