<page>
	<topic>Send a Table or Set</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Send a Table or Set action lets you select tables or sets to zip up and send by email. You can specify a specific table or set name in the genie, or prompt the user for the name at run-time.</description>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Click the Set or Table radio button to specify what type of file you are sending.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select a table or set from the resulting Set Name or Table Name list.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you want the user to make the decisions in steps 4, 5, and 6, check the Display the Table/Set Send Options dialog box check box and skip to step 7. Otherwise, continue with step 4.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check Compress the table or set before sending. If you choose this option, Alpha Anywhere will compress the table or set before sending the email. Compression reduces the size of the attached files.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check Include the table or set's data dictionary. The Data Dictionary stores any component object created by the table or set such as forms, browses, reports, query definitions, and scripts: the data dictionary for a table also stores the field rules. Specify whether or not to transmit this information with the table or set.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check Include indexes if you want to include the table or set's indexes in the email.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the email address of the recipient. You can use multiple addresses as long they are separated by commas.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Send using list select either:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client" </description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Default email client (e.g. Eudora, Outlook, etc.)" </description>
						</case>
					</cases>
					<note>If you select "Built-in Alpha Anywhere email client", the user has the opportunity to make edits before sending the. Otherwise, the email is sent automatically without further user interaction.</note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
					
				</step>
				
				
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>TABLE.SEND()</ref>
		<ref>Email Client</ref>
		
		
	</see>
	
</page>