<page>
	<topic>Set Variable(s) to Field Statistics (External Table)</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Set Variable(s) to Field Statistics (External Table) action retrieves statistical information (such as the count, minimum, maximum, average, and variance) about an external table's field or expression.</description>
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Select a table or set from the Table Name list.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, enter a filter that selects records into the Filter field. Optionally, click the 'funnel' icon to display the Filter Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter a field name or an expression into the Expression field. Optionally, click x-y icon to display the Expression Builder.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the name you would like to use for the variable in the Variable Name field.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Select Existing Variable to select from a list of existing variables. The actual variables created will be listed at the bottom of the genie. If a statistic does not apply to that field type, such as minimum for a Logical field, it will not be created.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select each object in the list and select the variable's scope from the Scope list. There are two options:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>"Shared" - means that the variable can be used only by other scripts on the window </description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>"Global" - means that all scripts can access the variable </description>
					</case>
				</cases>
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
				
				
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref><![CDATA[<TBL>.FIELD_STATISTICS()]]></ref>
		<ref>Categorized List of Actions</ref>
		
		
	</see>
	
</page>