<page>
    <topic>Placing a Map Control on a UX Component</topic>
    <description>Place a simple map control on a UX Component and set basic properties of the map object.</description>
  
<sections>
    <section>
        <description>Map control placement is also covered in [this video].</description>
    </section>
    <section>
       <description>Place a Map on a UX</description>
       <steps>
           <step>
               <description>In the UX Builder open the UX Control page.</description>
           
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>On the left side of the page scroll down through the Data Controls menu and click on the Map Control.</description>
               <figure><link>images/map5.png</link></figure>
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>The New Control dialog will open. Give the map a name and click OK.</description>
               
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>The Map control should now appear in the UX component. If you run the component in Live Preview you should see a simple Google Map.</description>
               <figure><link>images/map1.png</link></figure>
           </step>
          
       </steps>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>You can modify a Map control using the Map Properties section of the Control properties list. This list appears
            on the right side of the UX Controls page whenever a control on the page is highlighted.
        </description>
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <title>Adjusting the Size of a Map</title>
<steps>
    <step>
        <description>Highlight the Map control that has been placed on the UX component. In the properties list find the Map width and Map height properties.
        </description>
          <figure><link>images/map6.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Change the Map width and Map height properties by typing in new dimensions</description>
               <figure><link>images/map8.png</link></figure>
    </step>
     <step>
        <description>Run the modified map</description>
        <figure><link>images/map7.png</link></figure>
    </step>
    
</steps>
    
     
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Center Map on a specific location</title>
       <steps>
           <step>
               <description>In the Map Properties section of the Control Properties list Check the Center map on location property. The Center latitude and Center longitude properties will appear.</description>
               <figure><link>images/map.png</link></figure>
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>The Map Initial Position dialog will open. In the Address textbox type the address of the place where the map should be centered.</description>
                <figure><link>images/map2.png</link></figure>
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>Click the Geocode Address button. This will fill in the longitude and latitude for the typed address automatically.</description>
                <figure><link>images/map3.png</link></figure>
           </step>
           <step>
               <description>Click OK and view the map in either Live or Working Preview.</description>
                <figure><title>A map centered on the given address</title><link>images/map4.png</link></figure>
           </step>
       </steps>
        
        
    </section>
   
   <section>
       <description>For more on modifying a map control, including adding overviews and walkaround features, visit the [Map properties] section of the documentation.</description>
       
   </section>
   
</sections>
<links>
    <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/dialog_component_placingAMapOnTheDialog_BasicIntrol1.swf">this video</link>
<link href="http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/documentation/pages/Guides/Web%20Components/UX%20Components/UX%20Controls/Control%20Properties/Data%20Control%20Properties/Map%20Properties/index.xml">Map properties</link>
</links>

</page>