<page>
	<topic>Check the port</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Network services use TCP ports to "listen" for incoming requests from remote clients and service them. The combination of IP address and TCP port is what provides the unique address for your service, so only one process can use a given port at a time. When you attempt to start the Application Server, it will warn you if there is already some other program using the port it is configured to use and it will then abort starting. If this happens, you can either use a different port for the Application Server, or you can determine what other program is using the port and stop it.

Changing the port used by the Application Server is the easiest solution - simply change the port number designation in the Application Server Control Panel and start the server. However it is also typically less desirable, because it means that clients must now modify the URL they use to access your server. If you specify a port other than 80 (or 443 in the case of an SSL-enabled server), the client must then know the port number you are using, and include it as part of the URL that they access, e.g. http://www.server.com:8080(external link)

The Application Server cannot determine what other process is using a port on your computer for you, but the procedure to determine this is included in the Alpha Anywhere documentation. Once you know the other process involved, you can determine whether it is providing a critical service, in which case you will possibly want to change the port used by the Application Server, or if it is safe to disable.

Another remediation option is the ability for the Application Server to bind to a specific IP address, it is possible to have multiple processes on the same computer use the same port number as long as they use different IP addresses. Consult with your network administrator regarding using multiple IP addresses for your computer.
</description>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
</page>