<page>
   <topic>CHRTRAN Function</topic>
   <syntax>Output_String as C = CHRTRAN(C string_1,C string_2,C string_3)</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>string_1</name>
         <description>Input String. A character string to translate.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>string_2</name>
         <description>Search Pattern. A character string as the same length as input string containing characters likely and unlikely to match Input_String.
</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>string_3</name>
         <description>Replace Pattern. A character string as the same length as  Input_String containing the characters to substitute when a character in Search_Pattern matches a character in Input_String.
</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Replaces a portion of one string with another.</description>
   <discussion>
CHRTRAN() returns a character string where characters in Input_String that match those in Search_Pattern have been replaced with characters in the same position in Replace_Pattern. Case sensitive.
Common uses include changing character values within either a global update or an append operation. CHRTRAN() is especially useful for blanking specific positions in fields and for changing formatting characters used within a character code.
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
chrtran( "(617)229-2924" , "(XXX)XXX-XXXX" , " XXX XXX-XXXX" ) -> " 617 229-2924"
chrtran( "AaBbCcDd" , "XXBXXXXX" , "XXbXXXXX" ) -> "AabbCcDd"
]]></example>
   <sections>
       <section>
            <description>Assume the HOMEPHONE field contains values such as "(102)345-6789" and "(304)567-8901".
In the following expression, since only the parentheses specified in Search_Pattern match any values in HOMEPHONE, CHRTRAN() forms values using all the other characters from a HOMEPHONE value, plus the spaces included in the first and fifth position from Replace_Pattern.
</description>
            <example><![CDATA[
chrtran(HOMEPHONE, "(AAA)AAA-AAAA", " AAA AAA-AAAA")
]]></example>
       </section>
       <section>
       <description>For the records containing the values listed above, CHRTRAN() returns " 102 345-6789" and " 304 567-8901".
</description>
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   <see>
      <ref>Character Replacement Functions</ref>
   </see>
</page>