<page>
	<topic><![CDATA[<ARRAY>.setDynamic()]]></topic>
<description>Turn on/off the dynamic sizing property of an array.</description>
		
	
	
	<syntax><![CDATA[<ARRAY>.setDynamic(Boolean Flag)]]></syntax>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name></name>
			<description></description>
		</argument>
		
	</arguments>
	
	
	<discussion><![CDATA[The <array>.set_dynamic(flag) method can be used to turn on/off the dynamic sizing property of an array. The <array>.get_dynamic() method can be used to determine the state of an array's dynamic sizing property.
 If you dim an array with a size of 0 and then populate the array using the [ ] syntax, the dynamic sizing property is automatically assumed to be set to True. Otherwise, the dynamic sizing property defaults to False.]]></discussion>
	
	<sections>
	<section>
	<title>Example</title>
	<description>When you delete entries from an array, the array size does not change. With dynamic array sizing turned on, deleting an entry from an array will resize the array. The following Interactive window session demonstrates:
</description>
	
	
	<example><![CDATA[dim array[3] as c
array[1] = "alpha"
array[2] = "beta"
array[3] = "gamma"
?array.size[]
=3
array.delete[2,1]
?array.dump[]
= alpha
gamma
?array.size[]
=3 ]]></example>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
	<description>Now, repeating this exercise, but turning on the array's 'dynamic' property:
</description>
	
	
	<example><![CDATA[dim array[3] as c
array.set_dynamic[.t.]
array[1] = "alpha"
array[2] = "beta"
array[3] = "gamma"
?array.size[]
=3
array.delete[2,1]
?array.dump[]
= alpha
gamma
?array.size[]
=2 ]]></example>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
	<description>As mentioned above, if you dim an array with a size of 0 and then populate the array using the [] syntax, the dynamic sizing property is automatically assumed to be set to True. For example:
</description>
	
	
	<example><![CDATA[dim array[0] as p
array[] = "alpha"
array[] = "beta"
?array.size[]
=2
array.delete[2,1]
?array.size[]
=1   ]]></example>
	
	</section>
	
	<section>
	
	<description>This shows that an array dimmed with an initial size of 0 defaults to dynamic properties on, whereas an array dimmed with non-zero size defaults to dynamic properties off.
</description>
	
	
	<example><![CDATA[dim arr1[0] as p
dim arr2[1] as p
? arr1.get_dynamic[]
= .T.
? arr2.get_dynamic[]
= .F.
   ]]></example>
	
	</section>
	
	
	</sections>
	
	
	
	
	<see>
		<ref>Arrays </ref>
		<ref href="/Api/Functions/Data Type/Array Functions/Array Functions and Methods.html">Array Functions and Methods</ref>
		<ref>Miscellaneous Xbasic Array Improvements </ref>
	</see>
	
</page>