<page>
    <topic>Dock</topic>
    <description>Specify the initial dock state for this panel. If set to none, the panel will be visible.</description>

<sections>
    <section>
        <figure><link>images/dock.png</link></figure>
    </section>
<section>
    <description>The 'Dock' property includes the following options. Each of them vary depending on the 'Layout flow direction' 
        specified for the Panel Layout that contains the docked Panel. The options for the Panel Layout flow direction are:
        Left-to-right (LTR), Top-to-bottom (TTB), Right-to-left (RTL), Bottom-to-top (BTT).
        </description>
  <cases>
      <case>
            <name>none</name>
            <description></description>
        </case>
         <case>
            <name>collapse-before</name>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <description>LTR - If the Layout flow direction is Left-to-right (LTR) then this setting will cause the docked panel to appear 
                from the left side of the screen and move right.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>TTB - For Top-to-bottom (TTB) the docked panel will appear from the 
                top of the screen and move downwards.</description>
                    
                </case>
                       <case>
                    <description>RTL - Setting the Layout flow direction to Right-to-left (RTL) will cause the 
                Panel to appear on the right side of the screen and move left.</description>
                    
                </case>
                       <case>
                    <description>BTT - Setting the Layout flow direction to 
                Bottom-to-top (BTT) will cause the docked panel to appear from the bottom of the screen and move up.</description>
                    
                </case>
                    
            </cases>
    </case>
         <case>
            <name>collapse-after</name>
            <description>Collapse-after is like collapse-before but reversed. Here setting the Layout flow direction to 
                LTR causes the docked panel to appear from the right side of the screen and move left. TTB makes the 
                docked panel appear from the bottom of the screen and move upwards. RTL causes the 
            </description>
      </case>
         <case>
            <name>auto-collapse-before</name>
            <description></description>
    </case>
         <case>
            <name>auto-collapse-after</name>
            <description></description>
      </case>
         <case>
            <name>portrait-collapse-before</name>
            <description></description>
       </case>
         <case>
            <name>portrait-collapse-after</name>
            <description></description>
        </case>
         <case>
            <name>landscape-collapse-before</name>
            <description></description>
  </case>
         <case>
            <name>landscape-collapse-after</name>
            <description></description>
      </case>
         <case>
            <name>self-portrait-collapse-before</name>
            <description></description>
        </case>
         <case>
            <name>self-portrait-collapse-after</name>
            <description></description>
      </case>
         <case>
            <name>self-landscape-collapse-before</name>
            <description></description>
        </case>
         <case>
            <name>self-landscape-collapse-after</name>
            <description></description>
     </case>
        </cases>
        
        
    </list>
    
</section>    
    
    
    
</sections>


</page>