<page>
	<topic>Tables</topic>
	<description>A single database can contain many tables. From a client program, you do not see the individual files. You simply refer to the table by name. Each database user can be granted permission to create tables. The tables the user creates can be referenced by simply connecting to the database as the same user who created the table and using name as created.
</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		<description>
Example:
</description>
		<example><![CDATA[CREATE TABLE CustomerOrder ...
SELECT ... FROM CustomerOrder]]></example>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>In larger systems with many users, tables are created by a specific user, but they are then made available to other users to share. If you need to access a table created (and owned) by another user, you have two options (depending on the database).</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Use a fully qualified table name in the form .
. For example, a table created by the user OrderAdmin and named CustomerOrder would be referenced as  OrderAdmin.CustomerOrder.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[SELECT ... FROM OrderAdmin.CustomerOrder
 ]]></example>
			
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Create an alias, or synonym (not supported by all databases) that all users can see. For example, in the Oracle database you can create the synonym CustOrder to act as shorthand for OrderAdmin.CustomerOrder. This provides a lot of flexibility for the administrator and makes it simpler to create queries.</description>
			<example><![CDATA[SELECT ... FROM CustOrder
 ]]></example>
			<note>Each database uses a slightly different syntax to format the name of a table. Access and SQL Server, for example use square brackets to delimit a name with spaces, while Oracle uses single and double quotes. Wherever possible, those differences are hidden in Alpha Anywhere.</note>
		</step>
	</steps>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>For example:

The table name dbo.My Table is allowed for Access and SQL Server, but system."My Table" is allowed for Oracle.

Limitations

Desktop applications only.
</description>
		
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	
</page>