<page>
	<topic>What is SQL?</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>SQL stands for Structured Query Language. Known best for the SELECT statement, the language actually contains a number of statements grouped into Data Definition Language (DDL) and Data Manipulation Language (DML).

SQL databases are relational databases, but use DML to manipulate sets of data rather than addressing a physical row, as is the case with dBase files. Statements may retrieve or update one or more rows in a single command. Record numbers are not used in the database itself. Instead, each table is usually defined with a primary key (a set of columns) which uniquely defines the row in the table.

The four commands that make up the DML language are:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>SELECT</title>
			<description>Retrieves data based on some selection criteria</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>INSERT</title>
			<description>Inserts a new row of data or copies one or more rows</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>UPDATE</title>
			<description>Updates one or more rows of data</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DELETE</title>
			<description>Deletes one or more rows of data</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>DDL statements vary somewhat by database, but generally include:</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>CREATE USER</title>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DROP USER</title>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>CREATE TABLE</title>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>DROP TABLE</title>
			
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>CREATE INDEX</title>
			
		</case>
			<case>
			<title>DROP INDEX</title>
			
		</case>
	</cases>
	
</section>	
	<section>
		<description>The more advanced databases support user groups, user defined types, rules (called constraints and triggers and foreign keys), stored procedures and functions (reusable SQL statements and some form of scripting language) and have DDL statements to maintain those database definitions as well.</description>
	</section>
</sections>	
	
</page>