<page>
    <shortlink>ux properties date picker month names</shortlink>
    <topic>Date picker - month names</topic>
    <description>Specify the month names to be shown when the pop-up data picker is used. Enter a comma 
        separated list. TIP: You can also set the month names in this special session variable:
        session._protected_datePickerMonthNames.
    </description>
 
 
 
 
<sections>
    <section>
        <title>Changing Month Names</title>
        <description>Changing the month names is easy, just write the new month names in place of the old names, 
            making sure to delimite months using a comma. For example, you might replace this...
        </description>
         <figure><link>images/dpm.png</link></figure>
        
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>with a set of months in French, like this...</description>
         <figure><link>images/dpm2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>For any calendar control used in the component the month names should change automatically.</description>
        <figure><link>images/dpm3.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>This approach presents an easy fix if you want to quickly change how the months are spelled. However, 
            if you want to use more complex characters or switch out multiple languages in you application, you migh want to consider 
            using text dictionary tags, as described below.
        </description>
    </section>
    <section>
        
        <title>Creating Month Names in Multiple Languages</title>
        
        <description>The 'Date picker - month names' property can be tagged with [Text dictionary tags]. 
            Each month can then be written in multiple languages and displayed in the calendar whenever 
            a given language is active. When using this approach, each month is tagged separately... 
             
        </description>
        <example><![CDATA[<a5:t>January</a5:t>,<a5:t>February</a5:t>,<a5:t>March</a5:t>,<a5:t>April</a5:t>,
<a5:t>May</a5:t>,<a5:t>June</a5:t>,<a5:t>July</a5:t>,<a5:t>August</a5:t>,<a5:t>September</a5:t>,
<a5:t>October</a5:t>,<a5:t>November</a5:t>,<a5:t>December</a5:t>]]></example>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Perhaps the fastest way to assign these tags to individual months is to make use of the 
            [Internationalization Helper Utilities] on the UX Controls page, in the Additonal Options Menu. 
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/dpm5.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>In the Internationalization Helper Utilities dialog you can click the 'Select All' button to 
            define text dictionary tags for all the text that can be tagged inside the component. Then click the 'Execute Code' 
            button to add the tags.
        </description>
        <figure><link>images/dpm6.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>If you open the UX Properties page again the text will be tagged...</description>
        <figure><link>images/dpm7.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
        <description>After being tagged, multiple language definitions can be added for each month using the 
            Text dictionary tags property in the 'Other' properties section of the UX Properties page. This is assuming 
            that an SQL table has been created to store this information. For a detailed explanation on how to do this 
            see the page on [Text dictionary tags].
        </description>
         <figure><link>images/dpm4.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    <section>
       
        <figure><title>A calendar control using text dictionary tags</title><link>images/dpm8.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
</sections> 
 
 
 
 <links>
     <link link="ux properties text dictionary tags">Text dictionary tags</link>
     <link link="internationalization helper utilities">Internationalization Helper Utilities</link>
 </links>
 
</page>