<page>
    <shortlink>UX Properties Text dictionary tags</shortlink>
    <topic>Text dictionary tags</topic>
    <description><![CDATA[Show and define the Text Dictionary tags (<a5:t>...</a5:t>) used in this component]]></description>
 
 <sections>
     <section>
         <figure><title>A textbox control that has been tagged. The tag has five assigned languages with data for each language.</title><link>images/dict.png</link></figure>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>Text dictionary tags are a very convenient way to add internationalization to a component. 
             The text dictionary tags function very much like language tags. However, unlike language tags, the data 
             used in text dictionary tags is stored in an SQL table. This table can be easily created in the Project Properties 
             section of Alpha Anywhere. The generated table has three fields: a key field, a language field, and a data field. 
             The rows of generated tables can be filled in here, using the 'Text dictionary tags' property, provided that there are controls 
             in the component that have recieved text dictionary tags.. 
              
         </description>
         <figure><title>The 'Create New Text Dictionary Entry' hyperlink makes it easy to add new language definitions to controls</title><link>images/dict2.png</link></figure>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description><![CDATA[In cases where you wish to assign <a5:t>..</a5:t> tags to many controls in one go, it can be very helpful to use 
             the [Internationalization Helper Utilities] option, which is accesible theough the [Additional Options Menu] on the UX Controls page. 
             Once a number of tags have been defined you can set the language that you want to display in the component using the 
             '[Active language]' property.
         ]]></description>
         
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>In addition to the guides found on this page and linked pages, there are also several videos that explain 
             the use of text dictionary tags. This two part video: [Part 1], [Part 2], explains how to create and define 
             text dictionary tags. There is also a video [here] that explains how to edit existing tags. Finally, there is also 
             a video that explains how to use the [internationalization genie], i.e. the internationalization helper utilities.
         </description>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <title>Using Text Dictionary Tags</title>
         
         
         
         
         
     </section>
     
     
     <links>
         <link link="internationalization helper utilities">Internationalization Helper Utilities</link>
         <link link="additional options menu">Additional Options Menu</link>
         <link link="ux properties active language">Active language</link>
         <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/textDictionary_1.swf">Part 1</link>
         <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/textDictionary_2.swf">Part 2</link>
         <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/text_dic_editing.swf">here</link>
         <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_internationalizationGenie.swf">internationalization genie</link>
     </links>
     
     
 </sections>
 
 
 
 
</page>