<page>
    <shortlink>ux properties xbasic aex files</shortlink>
    <topic>Xbasic .aex files</topic>
    <description><![CDATA[Specify a comma delimited list of .aex files. These files contain compiled 
        Xbasic functions that can be used in any of the server-side event handlers.
    ]]>
    </description>
 
 
 <sections>
     <section>
         <note>You do not have to list .aex files here if you have specified the .aex files in the Project Properties 
             dialog. Concerning the 'Aex files property', if you specify .aex files here they will be automatically 
             added to the 'Aex files' property in the Project Properties. The Project Properties dialog is opened 
             from the toolbar of the Web Projects Control Panel.
         </note>
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>An .aex file is a library of functions. It lets you take all of the global functions that you have defined in a project 
             and put them into a single file, with the file extension .aex. 
             This enables you to use these functions in the Xbasic handlers of your components. These files are useful 
             if you have code that exists outside a component that you want to include in that component after the component is published. 
             
             
             
         </description>
         
         
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>Before 'projects' or the 'Web Project Control Panel' existed in Alpha Anywhere, aex libraries were 
             usually loaded by hand, by using a load function. This worked ok, but there were some problems, particularly 
             with caching issues that happened at run time.
             The ability to automatically to include aex libraries using a property setting was added to Alpha Anywhere
             after the idea of 'projects' and the 'Web Project Control Panel' were fully implemented. 
             You can add aex files at either the component or project level. 
         </description>
         
         
     </section>
     
     
     
     
     
     first define a function in the interactive window
     
     
     
     
     
     
     <section>
         <steps>
             
             <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
                 <example><![CDATA[function showDateTime as c ()
showDateTime = "<b>Current</b> date and time is: " + now()
end function]]></example>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link></link></figure>
             </step>
             
             
             
         </steps>
         
         
         
     </section>
     
     
     
 </sections>
</page>