<page>
	<topic>Defining Property Overrides</topic>
	<sections>
<section>
	<description>Web publishing applications only. Web components have many properties, which you set in the grid, dialog, and other component builders. After you place a component on an A5W page, you will find a property override section for it in the source of the page.
The code below shows a piece of an A5W page which contains a grid component named Invoices.
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[<html>
<head>
<%a5
Delete tmpl_Invoices
DIM tmpl_Invoices as P
tmpl_Invoices = a5w_load_component("Invoices")
'Following code allows you to override settings in the saved component, and specify the component alias (componentName property).
'Tip: Keep the componentName property short because this name is used in page URLs, and it will help keep the URLs short.
'Each component on a page must have a unique alias (componentName property).
with tmpl_Invoices
    componentName = "Invoices"
end with
... ]]></example>
</section>		
<section>
	<description>The piece that is interesting is.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[...
with tmpl_Invoices
    componentName = "Invoices"
end with
... ]]></example>
</section>	
<section>
	<description>Between the with ... end with statements, you may redefine any of the Invoices grid component properties. For example.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[...
with tmpl_Invoices
    componentName = "Invoices"
    DBF.filter = "userID = " + quote(session.protectedUserID)
    SearchField_Info[1].CheckBox.Filter = "userID = " + quote(session.protectedUserID)
    field_info[7].DropDownBox.Filter = "userID = " + quote(session.protectedUserID)
    QuickSearch.Radiobutton.Filter = "userID = " + quote(session.protectedUserID)
end with
...]]></example>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>There are two important prerequisites.</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>You must know the exact property name and data type. See Setting Grid Properties, Setting Grid Control Properties, Setting Dialog Properties, Setting Dialog Control Properties, and Setting Update Properties.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>When defining expressions that filter records, list boxes, radio buttons, and check boxes, you must remember that all page variables (controls) are type character. See Filtering a Grid with a Session Variable and Filtering an ADO Grid with a Session Variable.</description>
		</step>
	</steps>
</section>	
		
	</sections>
<see>
	<ref>Setting Default Property Values</ref>
</see>
</page>