<page>
    <topic>Getting and Setting the Value of a Slider Control</topic>
    <description>The value for a Slider Control can be set using javascript.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Setting the Value for a Slider Control</title>
            <description>The Slider Control is a Data Control. The value can be set for all Data Controls using the *[js:{dialog.object}.setValue]* method. For single value sliders, setting the value is straightforward. For a two value slider, you must pass in an array that defines the start and end value for the slider. See examples below:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[//Set the value for a one value slider:
{dialog.object}.setValue('S1',12);

//Set the value for a two value slider:
{dialog.object}.setValue('S2',[10,20]);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Getting the Value for a Slider Control</title>
            <description>As with setting the value, you can use *[js:{dialog.object}.getValue]* to get the value from a Slider Control. getValue will return the value for a single value slider as expected:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[var value = {dialog.object}.getValue('S1');
alert("Slider value is: " + value);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For a two value slider, *[js:{dialog.object}.getValue]* will return a string with the format "start..end". If you wanted to set the value in a two value slider with the current value in another two value slider, you would need to convert the string to an array:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[var value = {dialog.object}.getValue('S2');
value = value.split("..");

{dialog.object}.setValue('S3',value);]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Example Component</title>
            <description>[Click here] to download an example component (shown in the image below) that demonstrates getting and setting the value of one and two value Slider Controls.</description>
            <figure>
                <title>A UX component with three slider controls that demonstrates getting and setting Slider Control values.</title>
                <link>images/slidersExample.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="components/sliderDemo1.zip">Click here</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search={dialog.object}.getvalue method">{dialog.object}.getValue Method</ref>
        <ref href="/documentation/index?search={dialog.object}.setvalue method">{dialog.object}.setValue Method</ref>
    </see>
</page>