<page>
	<topic>Additional Record Selection Criteria
</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>When you are printing the data in a form or browse, the Print Layout Genie, Print Genie , Query Genie , and Query by Expressio n give you the ability to further refine the records that you will select.
These sub-selections are particularly useful for mailing list applications in which you want to send a mailing to a subset of your list. The ability to select records randomly is also very useful in statistical sampling applications.
</description>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Criteria</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>No additional selection criteria</title>
		<description>Print the records already selected by the form or browse filter. To see the current filter, right click on the layout in Design Mode, select Properties..., and display the Filter/Order tab.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Current record only</title>
		<description>The record that you are viewing in a form or the current line in a browse.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Currently selected records</title>
		<description>-</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Sub-Selection from currently selected records</title>
		<description>If you have applied an index or query to the layout, you can choose a sub-selection option:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<title>Top N Selected Records</title>
				<description>Enter the number of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Bottom N Selected Records</title>
				<description>Enter the number of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>N Records Selected at Random</title>
				<description>Enter the number of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Top N% Selected Records
</title>
				<description>Enter the percentage of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Bottom N% Selected Records</title>
				<description>Enter the percentage of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>N% of Records Selected at Random</title>
				<description>Enter the percentage of records to select.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<title>Every Nth Selected Record</title>
				<description>Enter the interval between records.
</description>
			</case>
			
			
		</cases>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Order criteria, no additional Filter criteria</title>
		<description>Enter an Order Expression. Click the 'A..Z' icon to display the Order Builder.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Records selected by a Filter Expression</title>
		<description>Add an additional Filter Expression. Click to display the Filter Builder.
Optionally, enter an Order Expression. Click the 'A..Z' icon to display the Order Builder.
Optionally, pick a Sub-select option.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Records selected by a saved Query definition</title>
		<description>Select a Query Name. Click the 'up' icon to see a list of saved queries. Optionally, pick a Sub-select option. Check Save filter/order expression if you want Alpha Anywhere to remember the filter expression, and NOT the name of the saved Query Operation.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Marked/Un-Marked Records</title>
		<description>Select either the Marked Records or Un-Marked Records radio buttons. Optionally, clear Search in only if you want to work with the entire table. Optionally, enter an Order Expression. Click the 'A..Z' button to display the Order Builder.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Range of Record Numbers</title>
		<description>Enter the First record number and Last record number.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Range of Key Values</title>
		<description>Click Key to select either an Index, a Query, or a Field to use as a key. Click the 'up' icon to see a list of key values for the First ke y and Last key fields. Click First or Last to have Alpha Five automatically use the first and last key values.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Selected Record Numbers</title>
		<description>Enter a comma delimited list of record numbers. Place a hyphen between pairs of numbers to indicate a range.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Selected Key Values</title>
		<description>Click Key to select either an Index, a Query, or a Field to use as a key. Click  to see a list of key values. Enter a delimited list of key values. Optionally, select a different delimiter than "," from the Delimiter list.</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
	
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref>Print Layout Genie</ref>
		<ref>Print Genie</ref>
		
	</see>
	
	
</page>