<page api="xb">
    <shortlink>api week iso function</shortlink>
    <topic>WEEK_ISO Function</topic>
    <description>Get the ISO calendar week number for a date where Monday is the first day of the week.</description>
    <prototype>Week_Number as N = week_iso(date as D)</prototype>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>date</name>
            <type>D</type>
            <description>The date to be analyzed.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <returns>
        <return>
            <name>Week_Number</name>
            <type>N</type>
            <description>Returns the ISO week number of the year where Monday is the first day of the week. Dates at the beginning or end of a calendar year may be included in the week for the previous or next year, respectively.</description>
        </return>
    </returns>
    <discussion>
        <p>The WEEK_ISO() function returns the ISO 8601 week number of the year where Monday is the first day of the week. Week numbers are 1 to 52 or 53. Part of week 1 may include dates from the previous calendar year. Part of week 52 or 53 may include dates from the next calendar year.</p>
        <p>The first week of the year is calculated as the week containing the first Thursday of the calendar year. This implies the following:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>The first week is mostly within the calendar year.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The first week contains January 4th.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The first week starts with the Monday nearest January 1st.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The last week of the year is the week containing the last Thursday of the calendar year. The following statements are also true of the last week of the year:</description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>The last week of the year is mostly within the calendar year.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The last week contains December 28th.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>The last week ends with the Sunday nearest to December 31st.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <example>
                <![CDATA[dim start as D = {1/1/2005}
? cdow(start)
= "Saturday"

? week_iso(start)
= 53

? week_iso(start+1)
= 53

? week_iso(start+2)
= 1

? cdow(start+2)
= "Monday"]]>
            </example>
        </section>
    </sections>

    <see>
        <ref link="date and time functions">Date and Time Functions</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>time,function,number</terms>

</page>