<page>
  <topic>UX Component - List Control - Hyperlink - Telephone</topic>
  
  <description>You can now configure a hyperlink control in a List to dial a telephone number. This is particularly useful in mobile applications that are run on a phone.</description>
  
  <sections>
    
    <section>
     <videos>
       <video>
         <description>Watch Video</description>
         <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/ux_list_dialPhone.swf</link>
       </video>
       
     </videos>
    </section>
    <section>
      <description>Assume you have a List control with this data:
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[name|phoneDisplay|phoneDial
John Smith (home)|(555) 555-5555|+15555555555
John Smith (mobile)|(555) 555-5556|+15555555556]]></example>
      
    </section>
       <section>
      <description>The List data contains both the phone number to display in the List and the phone number to actually dial. Notice that the phone number that should be dialed includes the +1 prefix to indicate that this is a U.S. phone number. The phone number to be dialed must start with + and then the country code (1 in the case of the U.S.). 
The phone number to be dialed can also include special directives. For example you can insert 'p' in the number to indicate a one-second pause and 'w' to indicate 'wait for dial tone'.
Using the sample data shown above, to configure the hyperlink to dial the telephone number in the 'phoneDial' field, but display the number shown in the 'phoneDisplay' field, you would set the 'Action type' property to 'Telephone', the 'Phone number' field to '{phoneDial}' (note that the placeholder is case-sensitive) and the 'Hyperlink text' property to '{phoneDisplay}', as shown in the image below.
It is permissible for the value passed in as the phone number to dial to include spaces and parentheses. For example, +1(555) 555-5555 is a valid number to dial.
</description>
   <figure><link>images/hyperlink-telephone.gif</link></figure>
    </section>
     <section>
      <description>If, for example, your List data had separate fields for the phone number (called 'phone' for example) and country code (called 'code' - without the leading + in the data), you could set the 'Phone number' field to:
</description>
      <example><![CDATA[+{code} {phone}
]]></example>
      
    </section>
  </sections>
</page>