<page>
    <topic>Window height</topic>
    <description>Specifies the height of the on-page window where the object will be shown.
        Leave blank to auto-size based on the object's height. Use CSS syntax (e.g. 5in, 200px)
    </description>



<sections>
    <section>
        <title>Adjusting Window Height</title>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <description>In the UX Builder, open the UX Controls page. Go to the Other Controls Menu and scroll down to [Embedded Object].</description>
                <figure><link>images/height.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Click on [Embedded Object] to add an existing object to a control. A list of your predefined objects to choose from will appear.
                    Select an object.
                </description>
                 <figure><link>images/height2.png</link></figure>
                 <note>Use whatever predefined component you have. In this case I am using a component that is a simple ButtonList control titled 'entomology'.</note>
            </step>
          
            <step>
                <description>View the component in Live View to see how the object looks inside the new component. 
                </description>
             
                     
                       <figure><title>A simple UX component in Live View</title><link>images/height3.png</link></figure>
                  
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Go back to the UX Controls page. On the right hand side of the page in the control properties menu there should be an On-page Window Properties 
                    section.
                </description>
                   <figure><link>images/height4.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Find the Window height property in this section and change the height to something smaller that your embedded object. Use CSS
                    syntax to define the height (e.g. 3in)
                </description>
                 <figure><link>images/height6.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            <step>
                <description>Run the component in Live View. The component should now appear inside a borderless window set to the height you specified. To add styling and a border to this window see 
                    the "Window style" property.
                </description>
                   <figure><link>images/height5.png</link></figure>
            </step>
            
            
        </steps>
        
        
    
    </section>
    
    
</sections>

</page>