<page>
	<topic>How to download Visual Studio 2010 builds of Alpha Anywhere</topic>
	<description>Internal development on Alpha Anywhere is now being done using Visual Studio Version 2010 (VS10) . However, the official Alpha Anywhere release is still compiled using a much older version of Microsoft Visual Studio. The version of Alpha Anywhere that is compiled using Visual Studio 2010 has some significant benefits over the official release - it is faster, and more importantly, will allow integration of functionality from the .NET Framework. 
</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>
 You can choose which version you want to use. You can continue to use the 'official' release, (built with the older version of Microsoft Visual Studio), or you can switch to the version built with the latest version of Microsoft Visual Studio. Our intention is to release updates built for both versions of the Microsoft tools for the next few updates, and then switch the official release to the version built with Visual Studio 2010.

 To download the Visual Studio 2010 builds, click on the appropriate link: Full Version Patch(external link), Runtime Patch(external link), Application Server Patch(external link).
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Full Version Patch</title>
		<description>"http://dl.filekicker.com/send/file/232433-JUEG/a5v10_full_patchVS10.exe" rel="external nofollow"</description>
		
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Runtime Patch</title>
		<description>"http://dl.filekicker.com/send/file/232425-2T11/a5V10_Runtime_PatchVS10.exe"</description>
		
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Application Server Patch</title>
		<description>"http://dl.filekicker.com/send/file/232440-Z3UW/a5v10_AppServer_patchVS10.exe"</description>
		
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
</section>
<section>
<description>
 IMPORTANT: If you get an error after starting the VS10 build about a5controls.dll or a5contexteval.dll, it means that the installer was not able to register these controls. To solve the problem, open a command window (you need to run the command window as an Administrator), navigate to the folder where Alpha Anywhere is installed, and enter these two commands:
</description>
			<example><![CDATA[
 regsvr32.exe a5controls.dll
 regsvr32.exe a5contexteval.dll]]></example>
			
		</section>
		
		
	</sections>
	
</page>