<page>
    <shortlink>list builder properties search part</shortlink>
    <topic>Search Part</topic>
    <description>You can add a Search part to a List Control in the List Properties pane of the List Builder. The         Search Part Pane contains properties that allow you to further define the Search Part.    </description>
    <!--list:.-->
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The Search Part Pane</title>
                <link>images/search.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search Properties Properties</title>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Search part style</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Defines the search interface style. The Search style can be one of the following:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Search Style</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>IndividualControls</name>
                            <description>Individual controls are placed in the UX component and map to each field in the List Control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>SingleKeywordControl</name>
                            <description>A single control is used to search one or more fields in the List. A record matches if one or more fields in a record contain the search criteria.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>QueryByForm</name>
                            <description>If the List has a Detail View, the Detail View is used as a search form.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Keyword search fields</title>
                    <description>Defines the fields in the data source that will be searched when the Search Part is configured to use a single keyword control.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if the *[ui:Search Part style]* is set to "SingleKeywordControl".</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Keyword search control</title>
                    <description>Defines the control where the user will enter the search value for a keyword search.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if the *[ui:Search Part style]* is set to "SingleKeywordControl".</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Search part field map</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Search part field maps]* defines the mapping between controls in the UX component and fields in the List. The value in the controls will be used to search the corresponding field in the List's data source when a search is executed.</p>
                        <p>If no control exists in the UX Component to map to the List control's field, a new control can be created by choosing *[ui:&lt;Create New UX Control&gt;]* from the Target Control list when mapping fields to controls.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if the *[ui:Search Part style]* is set to "IndividualControls".</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Combine multiple search conditions using</title>
                    <description>The value for each control can be combined using either "AND" or "OR" criteria. If "AND" criteria is used, a record matches the search terms if the record contains all of the search terms for the corresponding fields. If "OR" criteria is used, a record matches the search terms if at least one of the fields contains the search terms.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if the *[ui:Search Part style]* is set to "IndividualControls".</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Search field properties</title>
                    <description>Specify search settings for each search field.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Delay populate List till active search</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>*[ui:Delay populate List till active search]* is primarily used in mobile applications or in applications where the data source for the List control contains a large number of records. If enabled, the List control will not be populated until a search is performed.</p>
                        <p>If a search is performed and no search criteria is provided (i.e. the filter is blank), the List is not populated with any records.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Set search maximum result size properties</title>
                    <description>You can specify a maximum number of records, or maximum size of the payload that can be returned to the client after a search completes. In a mobile application you might want to make sure that user enters a sufficiently restrictive search definition so as not to return too much data to the client.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Maximum search size properties</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In a mobile application that is designed for disconnected use, the data in List control represents the 'disconnected' data (i.e. the subset of the master database that the user will have available to them on the mobile device. The typical design pattern is to specify that the List should not be populated with any records until the user has performed a search to retrieve the sub-set of records that they want to use when they are disconnected.</p>
                        <p>The *[ui:Maximum search size properties]* can be to set to guard against the situation where the user performs a search that returns a subset of the data source that is too large. You would want to prevent this from happening because downloading a large data set can take an excessively long time to download to the mobile device as well as exceed the amount of storage space available on the device.</p>
                        <p>You can specify the maximum search result in two ways:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name>number of rows</name>
                            <description>The maximum number of rows that a search can return. (In the case of hierarchical data - i.e. a List that has child, grandchild, great-grandchild Lists, etc. the row count refers to rows in the top-most parent List).</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>payload size</name>
                            <description>The maximum size in bytes of the data in the search result. This is the data that would be sent to the browser to populate the List. This is typically the more important setting as a large number of rows that have a very short record length would not result in a large payload and might not result in excessive download times or memory usage.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                    <important>Even if the user performs a search that satisfies the rules specified here, there is still a chance that the data will fail to load successfully into the List after it has been downloaded. This can happen if you have specified List data should be persisted to *[ui:Local Storage]* and there is not enough free space in *[ui:Local Storage]* to store the data. In this case the client-side [onSearchResultTooLargeForLocalStorage] event will fire allowing you to instruct the user to enter a more restrictive search, or to try to free space in *[ui:Local Storage]*.</important>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if *[ui:Set search maximum result size properties]* has been enabled.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Debugging info</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If enabled, Alpha Anywhere will display the generated filter expression in a placeholder control on the UX Component. This is useful during development to diagnose issues or learn how queries are generated to search the List control's data source.</p>
                        <p>Debugging info should be turned off in a production environment.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Placeholder for debugging info</title>
                    <description>Specify the placeholder where the debugging info should be shown. Placeholders can be added to the UX Component by adding a [Placeholder control] to the layout.</description>
                    <note>
                        <p>This property is only available if *[ui:Debugging info]* has been enabled.</p>
                    </note>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20controls%20other%20controls%20placeholder">Placeholder control</link>
        <link link="ux%20list%20clientside%20event%20onsearchresulttoolargeforlocalstorage">onSearchResultTooLargeForLocalStorage</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux data controls list control">List Control</ref>
        <ref link="list control ux api">List Control JavaScript Methods</ref>
    </see>
</page>