<page build="3522">
    <shortlink>Stylesheet Builder</shortlink>
    <topic>Stylesheet Builder</topic>
    <description>A new Style Builder is available for Alpha Anywhere V3 Styles - Alpha Anywhere styles that were released in older versions of Alpha Five (e.g. MobBlue, MobGreen, GrBlue, etc) are tagged internally as 'version 2' styles. Newer styles (e.g. iOS, iOS7, AndroidLight, AndroidDark) are tagged internally as 'version 3' styles.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>A new Style Builder is available for 'version 3' styles. Previously it was not possible to edit a 'version 3' style in the 'version 2' style builder.</p>
        <p>Now, when you try to edit a style, Alpha Anywhere automatically selects the appropriate style builder.</p>
        <p>There are several ways to get to the style builder. The easiest is to open the UX or Grid component and click the smart field button for 'Edit style in Style Builder'  property (which is just below the Style Name property).</p>
        <p>You can also select the Edit, Open Web Style Builder command from the menu when the Web Control Panel has focus.</p>
        <p>Alpha Anywhere web styles can be stored in one of three places:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Location</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>system</name>
                    <description>styles are stored in the CSS folder in the executable folder -- these styles cannot be directly edited. If you want to edit a 'system' style, you must first make a 'local' or 'global' copy of the style. You will edit the copy of the style.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>local </name>
                    <description>styles are stored in the CSS folder in the Web Project folder</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>global </name>
                    <description>styles are stored in a special folder that is visible to all web projects in your Workspace.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When you select a style to edit, if you selected a 'system' style, you will get a dialog asking you to make a 'local' or 'global' copy of the style.</p>
                <p>When you make a copy of the style you can keep the same name as the source ('system') style, or you can give the style a new name. Since the local or global style is stored in a different folder than the system style, it is perfectly OK to use the same name as the source ('system') style.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/copysystemstyle.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you selected a version 3 style the new style builder will be displayed:</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/stylebuilderV3.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Style Builder has two distinct modes:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Mode </name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Code</name>
                    <description>where you can directly adjust the CSS for the style and create new 'sub-themes' for different control types.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Adjust</name>
                    <description>where you can adjust the SASS variables used in the style.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Alpha Anywhere styles sheets are defined using SASS syntax. To learn more about SASS visit *[extlink:http://sass-lang.com/@http://sass-lang.com/]*</p>
                <p>One huge advantage of SASS syntax is the ability to define variables for many of the setting in the stylesheet, especially colors.</p>
                <p>The Adjust mode allows you to easily adjust the SASS variables in your stylesheet. For example if you use the built-in iOS7 stylesheet you will see that the predominant color in the style is blue. By changing a single SASS variable in Adjust mode you can change the entire</p>
                <p>The tabs at the bottom on the screen allow you to switch between Adjust mode and Code mode.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Color Mode</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In Code mode the left side of the screen has a preview of the style in the top and the actually CSS in the bottom.</p>
                        <p>The property grid on the right shows all of the "object" types defined in the stylesheet. Examples of "objects" include Textbox, Button, Accordion.</p>
                        <p>For each object type one or more named sub-types can be defined. The sub-types are called 'sub-themes'. Generally every "object" has at least one 'sub-theme' called 'base'. For some object types only 'base' sub-theme is defined. You can add an arbitrary number of sub-themes for any object type.</p>
                        <p>A sub-theme defined all of the CSS classnames used to style the object.</p>
                        <p>At the top of the code window when you are in Code mode you will all of the SASS variables defined in the stylesheet. </p>
                        <p>You can adjust the variable values directly in the Code window or you can switch to Adjust mode to change the SASS variables.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Opening the Style Builder from a Component</title>
            <description>You can open the Style Builder directly from the UX and Grid component. A new property 'Edit style in Style Builder' appears directly below the 'Style name' property.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/editstyleinstylebuilder.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To learn more, watch the video below:</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Style Builder</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In Alpha Anywhere V4 the Style Builder has been rewritten. You can now easily adjust the entire appearance of a style by simply adjusting the SASS variables that control the style colors and you can also easily add new sub-themes for different control types.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how you create a new style for buttons and we also show how the entire style can be c hanged from a 'blue' color to a 'green' color.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2016-03-26</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://www.viddler.com/v/a59a15fc</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>