<page build="0">
    <shortlink>ux properties date picker month names</shortlink>
    <topic>Date picker - month names</topic>
    <description>Specify the month names to be shown when the pop-up date picker is used. Enter a comma separated list.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p> TIP: You can also set the month names in this special session variable:
        session.__protected_datePickerMonthNames.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Changing Month Names</title>
            <description>Changing the month names is easy, just write the new month names in place of the old names, making sure to delimited months using a comma. For example, you may replace the following</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>with a set of months in French</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>For any calendar control used in the component the month names should change automatically.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm3.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>This approach presents an easy fix if you want to quickly change how the months are spelled. However, if you want to use more complex characters or switch out multiple languages in you application, you may want to consider using &lt;cultureMonthNames&gt; or text dictionary tags.</description>
        </section>
        <section build="5738">
            <title>Automatically Setting Month Names Based on the User's Locale</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can specify that the month names should be dynamically computed based on the user's locale by setting the *[ui:Date picker - month names]* property to &lt;cultureDayNames&gt;. This makes it easier to build applications that seamlessly adapt based on the user's locale setting.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/cultureMonthNames.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating Month Names in Multiple Languages Using Text Dictionary Tags</title>
            <description>The *[ui:Date picker - month names]* property can be tagged with [Text dictionary tags]. Each month can then be written in multiple languages and displayed in the calendar whenever a given language is active. When using this approach, each month is tagged separately.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[<a5:t>January</a5:t>,<a5:t>February</a5:t>,<a5:t>March</a5:t>,<a5:t>April</a5:t>,
<a5:t>May</a5:t>,<a5:t>June</a5:t>,<a5:t>July</a5:t>,<a5:t>August</a5:t>,<a5:t>September</a5:t>,
<a5:t>October</a5:t>,<a5:t>November</a5:t>,<a5:t>December</a5:t>]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The quickest way to insert text dictionary tags is using the [Internationalization Helper Utilities].</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm5.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>The Internationalization Helper Utilities dialog can be used to quickly add text dictionary tags (or language tags) to all text in the UX component. Click the *[ui:Select All]* button to generate a script to add text dictionary tags for all the text within the component. Then click the *[ui:Execute Code]* button to add the tags.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm6.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>When you open the UX Properties page, the text will be tagged</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm7.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>After being tagged, multiple language definitions can be added for each month using the *[ui:Text dictionary tags]* property.</description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/dpm4.png</link>
            </figure>
            <note>
                <p>In order to use Text Dictionary tags, you must first configure a SQL table where the translations can be stored. For a detailed explanation on how to do this see the page on [Text dictionary tags].</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>A calendar control using text dictionary tags</title>
                <link>images/dpm8.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux properties text dictionary tags">Text dictionary tags</link>
        <link link="internationalization helper utilities">Internationalization Helper Utilities</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="language culture">Supporting Device Culture Codes</ref>
        <ref link="date culture">Setting the Date Format Based on the User's Locale</ref>
    </see>
</page>