<page>
    <shortlink>Populating a Repeating Section from a Table</shortlink>
    <topic>Populating a Repeating Section from a Table</topic>
    <description>You can use Alpha Anywhere's Data Binding features to automatically 
      populate a repeating section with data from an external table.
    </description>
  
 <sections>
   <section>
     <description>
       [Data Binding]
     </description>
     
   </section>
   <section>
       <description>For more on this subject watch this two part video: [Part 1], [Part 2], or 
         follow the guides below.
       </description>
   </section>
   <section>
     <title>About Populating Repeating Sections</title>
     
     <description>Repeating Sections require slightly more complex data binding than, for example, 
       a simple textbox control that is bound to a given field in a SQL table. Instead of 
       being bound to a given field, repeating sections are tied to a table that is linked to a 
       parent table using a OneToMany 'Link type'. The repeating section can then be used to display 
       data in a child table of the table that the repeating section is bound to. 
</description>
     
   </section>
   <section>
     <description>Repeating sections are frequently used to create an invoice or detail form based on a larger table.
     For example, say you have a table that defines a list of orders from different customers.
      A second table might display the details of the customers orders
       and a third table the details of the products that were ordered. A repeating section could 
      be used to display product information about all of the products that were ordered by a given 
      customer.</description>
       </section>
   <section>
     <description>It is necessary to define a primary key in order to link two tables.
        A primary key references the name of a field that is present in both tables. 
       For example, the 'order' table and 'order detail' table might share a field named 'OrderID'. 
       This field could then be defined as the primary key linking the two tables.
        You can use a different primary key to link the 'order detail' and 'product' tables, 
        like 'ProductID'. 
        
       
     </description>
     <figure><link>images/dbi.png</link></figure>
     
   </section>
   
   
   
   <section>
     <title>Define a Repeating Section to Populate</title>
     <description></description>
     <steps>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
       
       
     </steps>
     
   </section>
   
   
   
    <section>
     <title>Bind the Component to Data in Tables</title>
     <description></description>
      <steps>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
   </section>
   
   
   
     <section>
     <title></title>
      <steps>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
     
   </section>
   
   
     <section>
     <title></title>
      <steps>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
       <step>
         <description></description>
         
       </step>
     
   </section>
    
   
   
 </sections>
  
    <links>
<link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/PopulatingADialogwithData_part1.swf">Part 1</link>
 <link href="http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/PopulatingADialogwithData_part2.swf">Part 2</link>
 <link link="ux components data binding">Data Binding</link>
 
    </links>
    
    
    
    <terms>container,repeating section</terms>
</page>