<page>
     <shortlink>grid component action javascript in the grid</shortlink>
	  <topic>Action Javascript in the Grid</topic>

   <description>Action Javascript adds functionality to your app by defining behaviors using property sheets. The code required to perform the actions is generated for you. These articles cover a wide variety of Action Javascripts available in the Grid Component..</description>
 
 
 <sections>
	 <section>
		 <list>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition]</name>
				 <description>Export data to Excel, Word, HTML or Ascii using a Report Definition.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Ajax Callback]</name>
				 <description>Define a user-defined ajax callback. The callback can be handled by an Xbasic function that is defined in the component, by a separate .a5w page, or by another page (.e.g., .php, .asp, etc.).</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[City, State Lookup from Zip Code]</name>
				 <description>For a given zip code, lookup the city and state on the USPS web site and fill in the city and state in the current record.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Export to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format]</name>
				 <description>Export data to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format. The Custom format option allows you to define an Xbasic function that creates the file.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Fade Out Message]</name>
				 <description>The Fade Out Message action displays a message on the screen for a short period of time. The message fades away after a specified duration.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[File Download]</name>
				 <description>Download a file from the server to the user's machine.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[File Upload]</name>
				 <description>Upload a file to the server and store a reference to the file in a Grid field, or embed the file in a Drid field.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[File Upload - User Defined]</name>
				 <description>Upload one or more files to the server. A server-side event then gets called to allow you to process the uploaded files.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Geocode an address]</name>
				 <description>Makes an Ajax callback to a web service to geocode an address. Fill in the latitude and longitude fields in the current record with the information.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Geolocation Functions]</name>
				 <description>Get geolocation information from the browser and store information in the current Grid/UX component object (e.g. if you are in a Grid, the data is stored in the {grid.object}.geoLocation object). (Requires an HTML5 browser).</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Global Search and Replace]</name>
				 <description>Search and replace values in a field in all currently visible rows in the Grid.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Global Update]</name>
				 <description>Set the value in a field in all currently visible rows in the Grid.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Google Map Method]</name>
				 <description>The Google map method action calls a method to perform some action on a Google Map. </description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Image Upload]</name>
				 <description>Upload an image file to the server.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Import Data from Excel or Ascii file]</name>
				 <description>Upload an Excel or Ascii file and import data into the current Grid or an external table.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Inline-Javascript]</name>
				 <description>Allows developer to enter javascript code. Unlike most other actions there are no properties to check for the Inline-Javascript action, just the code you want to fire.
</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Lock/unlock a container, DIV or entire page (by showing an overlay over it)]</name>
				 <description>Lock a container, DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it so that the user can't click on the controls under the overlay, or unlock the element.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Lookup and Fill-in Fields]</name>
				 <description>Lookup values in a table and fill-in fields in the current row from fields in the Lookup Table.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Menus]</name>
				 <description>Display a dropdown menu.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Message box]</name>
				 <description>Displays a Javascript alert box on the screen.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a AppLauncher component]</name>
				 <description>Open a AppLauncher component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Calendar component]</name>
				 <description>Open a Calendar component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Custom component]</name>
				 <description>Open a Custom component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Google Map component]</name>
				 <description>Open a Google Map component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Grid component]</name>
				 <description>Opens a grid component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page. This requires first defining a grid component.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Help Window]</name>
				 <description>Open a window to display a help topic from the Help Table.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a ImageGallery component]</name>
				 <description>Open a ImageGallery component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Page Layout component]</name>
				 <description>Open a Page Layout component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay]</name>
				 <description>Open a generic, pop-up window (often called an overlay). The window can be modal, or modeless, and can be populated by making an Ajax callback.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a Report, Label or Letter layout]</name>
				 <description>Displays a report, label or letter layout as a PDF file using the Acrobat PDF reader. The report is displayed in either a pop-up window or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record]</name>
				 <description>Open a UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page, to edit the record currently being edited in the Grid or UX component.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a UX component]</name>
				 <description>Opens an UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page. (Only new Ajax components can be opened. Old dialogs built in V10 and earlier are not supported.</description>
			 </item>
			 <item>
				 <name>[Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record]</name>
				 <description>Open an UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page, to edit the current row in a Grid component or to enter a new record. (Only new Ajax Components can be opened. Old Dialogs in V10 and earlier are not supported.)</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Open a Video Player component]</name>
				 <description>Open a Video Player component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV]</name>
				 <description>Open a document (including .a5w pages, static .html pages, any other web page, e.g. www.google.com, or PDF document) in a modal, or modeless pop-up window, or in a DIV on the page.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Run Action]</name>
				 <description>The Run Action runs an action that was defined using Javascript.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Send email]</name>
				 <description>This javascript action sends an email.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Set Page Content]</name>
				 <description>Set the content in one or more page elements (i.e. 'divs', 'spans', form fields, etc.) to values obtained from fields in a Lookup Table.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation]</name>
				 <description>Adds toggle animation to a DIV or container. When the action is run the dive or container will be shown or hidden using a specified animation such as 'slide' or 'puff'. </description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Web-sockets Server Actions]</name>
				 <description>Performs an action on the web-socket server, such as 'Send a message to the web-sockets server'. The message will be received by all UX and Grid components that are listening for web-socket messages and the 'webSocketOnMessage client-side event in all listening components will fire.</description>
			 </item>
			  <item>
				 <name>[Zip Code Lookup from Address]</name>
				 <description>For a given address, lookup the Zip code on the USPS web site and fill in the current record.</description>
			 </item>
		 </list>
	 </section>
	 
	 
	 
 </sections>
 
 <links>
	 	
	 <link link="Zip Code Lookup from Address">Zip Code Lookup from Address</link>
	 <link link="Web-sockets Server Actions">Web-sockets Server Actions</link>

	 <link link="Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation">Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation</link>
	<link link="Set Page Content">Set Page Content</link>
	<link link="Send email">Send email</link>
	<link link="Run Action">Run Action</link>
	<link link="Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV">Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV</link>
	<link link="Open a Video Player component">Open a Video Player component</link>
	<link link="Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record">Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record</link>
	<link link="Open a UX component">Open a UX component</link>
	<link link="Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record">Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record</link>
	<link link="Open a Report Label or Letter layout">Open a Report, Label or Letter layout</link>
	<link link="Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay">Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay</link>
	<link link="Open a Page Layout component">Open a Page Layout component</link>
	<link link="Open a ImageGallery component">Open a ImageGallery component</link>
	<link link="Open a Help Window">Open a Help Window</link>
	 <link link="Open a Grid component">Open a Grid component</link>
	 <link link="Open a Google Map component">Open a Google Map component</link>
	 <link link="Open a Custom component">Open a Custom component</link>
	 <link link="Open a Calendar component">Open a Calendar component</link>
	 <link link="Open a AppLauncher component">Open a AppLauncher component</link>
	 <link link="Message box">Message box</link>
	 <link link="Menus">Menus</link>
	 <link link="Lookup and Fill-in Fields">Lookup and Fill-in Fields</link>
	 <link link="Lock unlock a container DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it">Lock/unlock a container, DIV or entire page (by showing an overlay over it)</link>
	 <link link="Inline-Javascript">Inline-Javascript</link>
	 <link link="Import Data from Excel or Ascii file">Import Data from Excel or Ascii file</link>
	 <link link="Image Upload">Image Upload</link>
	 
	 <link link="Google Map Method">Google Map Method</link>
	 <link link="Global Update">Global Update</link>
	 <link link="Global Search and Replace">Global Search and Replace</link>
	 <link link="Geolocation Functions">Geolocation Functions</link>
	 <link link="Geocode an address">Geocode an address</link>
	 
	 <link link="File Upload - User Defined">File Upload - User Defined</link>
	 <link link="File Upload">File Upload</link>
	 <link link="File Download">File Download</link>
	 <link link="Fade Out Message">Fade Out Message</link>
	 <link link="Export to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format">Export to Excel or Ascii or Custom Format</link>
	 <link link="City, State Lookup from Zip Code">City, State Lookup from Zip Code</link>
	 <link link="Ajax Callback">Ajax Callback</link>
	 <link link="Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition">Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition</link>
	 
	 
 </links>
 
	
</page>