<page>
	<topic>Legacy Documentation Viewer</topic>
	
	<description>Alpha Anywhere has a documentation viewer built into it. 
Settings under the View drop down menu make it easy to open the legacy documentation viewer.
Key features of the Documentation Viewer include:</description>
<sections>
	<section>
		
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Read documentation from within the Alpha Anywhere environment </description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Disconnected viewing - don't need an Internet connection 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Find topics quickly - filtering and full text searching 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Save and restore open tabs 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Save tab list of exit 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Two window styles - MDI and Modeless - Modeless is ideal for users with two monitors - keep the documentation open at all times on the second monitor 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Real-time help in code editors - As soon as you type a function or method name in a code editor, the documentation synchronized on that function or method 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Print topics to PDF 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Browser like experience - Back and Next buttons to see previously viewed topics 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Add notes to any topic 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Add user defined topics 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Mark individual topics as 'favorites' so you can quickly find them again. 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Every topic in the Documentation Viewer has a button at the end of the topic that allows you to send feedback on the topic. 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>Table of Contents is displayed in a tree view 
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>'Breadcrumbs' - When a topic is displayed, a series of hyperlink breadcrumbs is shown that indicate where this topic fits in the overall structure of the documentation. The placement of the breadcrumbs is controlled in the Preferences dialog. The breadcrumbs can be above, below or above and below the help text. 
</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Opening the Legacy Documentation Viewer</title>
		<steps>
			<step>
				<description>In the View drop down select the 'Settings...' option</description>
				<figure><link>images/viewer.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>When the Settings tab opens select the Preferences option from the System Setting tree menu.</description>
				<figure><link>images/viewer2.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>From the Miscellaneous Preferences Menu click on Documentation</description>
				<figure><link>images/viewer3.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>With Preferences and Documentation selected click on the Value dropdown at the bottom of the Settings Dialog.
					Select the UseLegacy option. Click OK to close the Settings dialog.
				</description>
				<figure><link>images/viewer4.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>In Alpha Anywhere go to the Help menu and select 'Open Documentation'.</description>
				<figure><link>images/viewer5.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>The Legacy Documentation Viewer should now open.</description>
				<figure>
			<title>The Legacy Documentation Viewer</title>
			<link>images/local_help_viewer.png</link></figure>
			</step>
			
			
		</steps>
		
	</section>
	
	
	
	
	<section>
<description>The following videos demonstrate the features of the documentation viewer:
</description>		
		<videos>
			<video>
				<name>Watch video - part 1</name>
				<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/documentationViewer_1.swf</link>
			</video>
			<video>
				<name>Watch video - part 2</name>
				<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/documentationViewer_2.swf</link>
			</video>
			<video>
				<name>Watch video - part 3</name>
				<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/documentationViewer_3.swf</link>
			</video>
			<video>
				<name>Watch video - part 4</name>
				<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/documentationViewer_4.swf</link>
			</video>
			
			
		</videos>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Note about images in the documentation.</title>
		<description>When you first view a particular topic in the Documentation Viewer, the images in the topic are displayed from the Alpha Wiki website. This means that in order to see the images you would need to have an internet connection. However, as the images are retrieved from the wiki, they are cached locally so that the next time you visit that particular topic, the images will be read from the local cache. That means that if you are viewing the documentation and you do not have an internet connection, topics that were previously viewed when a connection was available will show images, but if you have not previously viewed the topic, the images will not be visible.</description>
		
	</section>
</sections>	
	
	
</page>