<page>
    <shortlink>Layout type</shortlink>
    <topic>Layout type</topic>
<description>Specify the way in which the HTML is generated</description>  
  
<sections>
    <section>
        <description>The UX component supports two layout modes:</description>
        <list  bullet="true">
            <item>
                <name>Control Width</name>
            </item>
            <item>
                <name>Container width (recommended because the precise layout of the UX Component is much easier.</name>
            </item>
            
        </list>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Control Width</title>
        <description>In this mode, the width dimension that you specify for a control is applied to the control itself. 
            If the control label position is set to the Left or Right of the control, the total width taken up by the 
            container 'div' that contains the control is the label width plus the control width.
        </description>
        
        
        
        
        
    </section>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <section>
        <title>Container Width</title>
        <description>In this mode, the width dimension that you specify for a control is actually 
            applied to the container 'div' that contains the control. If the control label position 
            is set to the Left or Right of the control, the actual width of the control is reduced 
            by the width of the label (because the width property is applied to the container, and not the actual 
            control).
        </description>
        
      
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>When using Container Width mode it is easy to make the total width of all controls on a single 
            line to exactly match the total width of the controls 
            on other lines. This makes it very easy to right align controls on multiple lines. 
            You can easily lay out your dialog using percentage widths for controls.
        </description>
        
        
        <note>The term 'container' on this page refers to the <![CDATA[<div>...</div>]]> html tags that encompass 
            every control  in Alpha Anywhere, and that is generated automatically when a component is run. This has no relation to the [Container] controls 
            that are used to wrap existing controls.</note>
        
      
        
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>How Does Layout Type Impact Design?</title>
        
        <description>By default all controls have 4 pixels of padding around them that is defined using CSS. 
            This padding can be adjusted using the [A5CWLayout class padding] property, which can be found 
            on the UX Properties page in the CSS/SVG section. Because the 'Control Width' setting sets 
            a specific width for the control, the final container width for a control using this setting will be the specified 
            width of the control plus two times the width of the padding. So, if Layout type is set to 'Control Width' 
            the control is 100px wide, and the padding is set to its default of 4px; the final width of the container will be 108 pixels.</description>
        
        
        <figure><title>Using 'Control Width', a control of 100px will result in a total container width of 108px.</title><link>images/lt.png</link></figure>
        
 
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>With the 'Container Width' setting, the defined width of the control includes everything inside the automatically 
            generated <![CDATA[<div>...</div>]]> tags that contain that control. Because the CSS padding is included
            in this div tag, the control and the padding combined must equal the specified container width. In this case if we set the 
            control to be 100 pixels the total container width will be 100 pixels. The control itself will be 92 pixels wide and still have 8 pixels of padding.</description>
        
     
     
     <figure><title>Using 'Container Width', a control setting of 100px will result in a container width of 100px and a control width of 92px.</title><link>images/lt2.png</link></figure>
     
     
     
     
     
     
     
       
        
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>While the difference between these settings might appear trivial 
            when dealing with a small number of pixels, the impacts on design grow more stark when 
            a larger number of pixels or percentages are used in a control's width definition. For instance, 
            say you have two controls that are set to '50%', meaning they will each take up fifty percent of the 
            available screen space...
            </description>
        
     
        
    <figure><link></link></figure>
        
        
            
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>If the 'Layout type' property is set to 'Container Width' then each of the controls will appear side by side 
            when the component is run. Because the control's width setting includes the padding as well as the defined control, 
            the whole container will only take up half the screen. 
        </description>
        
        <figure><link></link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>Should the 'Layout type' property be set to 'Control Width' for the component, these two 
            controls can no longer have padding between them and still be side by side. One control must be above or below the other. This is because 
            the '50%' defined as the control width only includes the width of the control itself. The extra 8 pixels of CSS padding 
            will mean that the 'div' container, which the control is automatically placed in when the component is run, will take 
            up more than half the screen. 
        </description>
        <figure><link></link></figure>
    </section>
    <section>
        <description>This is why 'Container Width' is the recommended setting, while 'Control Width' is included more as 
            a legacy setting.
        </description>
        <note> It is possible to set the padding between controls to zero.</note>
    </section>
    
    
    
</sections>
  <links>
      <link link="ux property a5cwlayout class padding">A5CWLayout class padding</link>
      
      
      
  </links>
  
</page>