<page>
    <shortlink>UX Properties Style name</shortlink>
    <topic>Style name</topic>
<description>Click the button to select a new style, or edit the existing style. You can also use 
    <![CDATA[<ProjectStyle> or <Session:varname>]]>
</description>  
  
<sections>
    <section>
        <figure><link>images/sn.png</link></figure>
        
    </section>
    
    
    <section>
        <description>The 'Style name' property in the UX Builder is the same as the [Grid Component's 'Style name' property]. 
Existing styles are mostly defined using CSS. The 'Alpha' style is built using SASS, a scripting
 language that outputs code which looks like CSS and that is parsed as such. In the top right corner of the 
 Select Style dialog the Location menu lets you set where the CSS styles for your UX components are stored.


        </description>
         <figure><link>images/sn2.png</link></figure>
    </section>
    
<section>
<description>'Local' styles are stored in the same folder as a web project and can only be seen by components
in that project. In contrast, 'Global' files are stored in a folder that contains all of the web
 projects in the current open Alpha Anywhere Workspace (.abd file).
  Components in any web project inside the current workspace can see global styles. The Select Style dialog
</description>
        
    </section>
    
    <section>
        <description>With the 'System' option, the styles are stored in a CSS folder contained in the
             executable folder. During publishing 
this CSS file is sent from the executable folder to a root folder that outputs the stylized controls. 
Every web project you create has access to System styles. You can edit some, though not all, of the system files 
using the '[Customize style colors and fonts]' property on the UX Properties page. This makes it easy 
to change the colors and fonts used with a given style. If you make any alterations to a style using this property 
then those changes will be implemented across all of the components in a project that also make use of that style.</description>
        
    </section>
  <section>
      <description>In addition to tweaking a style using the 'Customize style colors and fonts' 
          property, you can also customize a style using the [Style Builder]. You can access the Style Builder through the 
          [Edit style in Style Builder] property on the UX Properties page. The style builder operates by making a 
          copy of a particular style. This copy can be either 'Local' or 'Global' in scope, and can be assigned 
          to a component from the 'Style name' property's 'Local' or 'Global' menu. Because these custom styles are
           based on a copy of a System style, if the system style changes then the copy will not. Therefore, if new CSS 
           classes for new controls are added to a 'System' style, then the styling for these controls will not be available in 
            a customized style designed before the classes were created. The CSS classes would need to be added to the new 
            style by hand (Tip: see [Local sub-theme definitions - Javascript]).</description>
      
      
  </section>
  
  <section>
      <title>Project Styles</title>
      <description><![CDATA[The "Use <ProjectStyle>" setting defers to a default project style for all of the components in a 
          project. The default style can be set using the '[Project style]' property in the Project Properties page off the Web Projects Control Panel. ]]></description>
      
     
      
      <steps>
          <step>
              <description>The define a default style open the Project Properties from the Web Projects Control Panel</description>
               <figure><link>images/sn3.png</link></figure>
          </step>
           <step>
              <description>Click on the button next to the 'Project style' property. </description>
               <figure><link>images/sn4.png</link></figure>
          </step>
          <step>
              <description>Assign a style. The project style dialog looks exactly like the 'Project name' dialog</description>
               <figure><link>images/sn5.png</link></figure>
          </step>
          
      </steps>
  </section>
  
  
  
  
  
  
    <section>
        <title>Sub-themes</title>
      <description>Once you have selected a style you can assign [sub-themes] based on that style to individual controls. 
          This can be done by setting the sub-theme property in a highlighted control's properties list on the UX Controls page. 
          You can also define custom sub-themes by taking the javascript that calls the CSS classes for 
          the sub-theme for a given control and creating a new sub-theme name and new CSS class names. This can 
          be done using the [Local sub-theme definitions - Javascript] and the [Local sub-theme definitions - CSS] 
          properties. 
          
      </description>
       <figure><title>Sub-themes can be set on the UX Controls page in a control's properties list.</title><link>images/sn6.png</link></figure>
  </section>
  
  
  
</sections>
  <links>
      <link link="style name">Grid Component's 'Style name' property</link>
      <link link="subthemes in alpha">sub-themes</link>
      <link link="ux properties local subtheme definitions javascript">Local sub-theme definitions - Javascript</link>
      <link link="ux properties local subtheme definitions css">Local sub-theme definitions - CSS</link>
      <link link="customize style colors and fonts">Customize style colors and fonts</link>
      <link link="css style builder">Style Builder</link>
      <link link="edit style in style builder">Edit style in Style Builder</link>
      <link link="project style - web project properties">Project style</link>
  </links>
  
</page>