<page>
   <topic>Web Socket Server</topic>
<description>The Web Socket Server allows you to build 'connected' application (like a message board) where all of the clients are permanently connected to the Web Socker Server. To enable the Web Socker Server you must turn it on in the Project Properties dialog (accessible from the Web Applications Control Panel).
You must also enable Web Socket support in any UX or Grid component that will communicate with the Web Sockets server.
</description>


   <discussion>When Web Socket Support is enabled, Web Applications are capable of broadcasting JSON packets between
the active users in an application, which means that in addition to implementing features like message boards,
applications that once required polling to check for updates can be notified when a change occurs. This can
reduce traffic to the application server. </discussion>
   <sections>
      <section>
      <description>
      The Web Socket Implementation supports the concept of Message Queues - this is important for applications like
      message boards, where a new user joining a discussion needs to receive the most recent postings to the message board.
      </description>
      </section>
      <section>
      <title>Simple Web Socket Server</title>
      <description>
      The simplest supported Web Socket Server implementation (when using the stand-alone Application server -- not the IIS plugin) uses a single Node.js process to handle broadcast of messages between all open connections.
      All the memory of queue contents, and all the broadcasting of messages is handled by a single instance of Node.js.
      </description>
      <figure><link>images/simple_node_websocket_server.svg</link></figure>
      </section>
      <section>
      <title>Scalable Web Socket Server (Redis Implementation)</title>
      <description>
      When Redis is used for the the Web Socket Server implementation (with the stand-alone Application Server), the broadcasting of messages, as well as queue memory, are offloaded to Redis.
      The Node.js process only manages the connections for the instance of Alpha Anywhere, which allows for multiple instances backed by a single Redis instance.
      </description>
      <figure><link>images/redis_node_websocket_server.svg</link></figure>
      </section>
      <section>
      <title>Picking an implementation</title>
      <description>If less overhead is required, and requirements are met by a single instance of the Alpha Anywhere server, the Simple Web Socket Server Implemention is adequate.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
      <description>If it is important that queues retain state when the server is restarted,  or a load balancer is being used, which requires multiple instances of the Alpha Anywhere Application Web Server, the Redis implementation provides the ability to scale, and provides persistence of state information.</description>
      </section>
   </sections>
</page>