<page>
    <shortlink>transform app addform</shortlink>
    <topic>Add Form</topic>
    <description>The list of the types of forms you may add.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>About the Add Form list</title>
            <description><p>
        The Add Form screen displays a list of the types of forms that may be added and then filled out.
      </p>
      <p>
        The list is in alphabetic order, showing the display name of each type of form, along with the associated icon and background
        color. The Form ID of each type of form is also displayed. (Form IDs are unique within each account, while the display
        names, colors, and icons need not be unique.)
      </p>
      <p>
        One type of form may be shown with a blue left border to make it easier to find in a long list of form types. This is usually
        the type of form that is currently selected on the Existing Forms screen.
      </p>
      <p>To go back to viewing existing forms and not create a new form instance, tap the *[&lt;Forms]* button on the left side of the control bar at the top of the screen. </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a form</title>
            <description><p>
        Tapping the row for a particular form will create a new instance of that type of form and open it for editing. See the
        [Form Details Screen] help for more information about editing a form.
      </p></description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Searching and Filtering the list </title>
            <description>
                <p>There are buttons to control searching and filtering the list of forms. See [Search, Sort, Filter] for more information about these functions.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="transform app formdetails">Form Details Screen</link>
        <link link="transform%20app%20search">Search, Sort, Filter</link>
    </links>
</page>