<page>
    <shortlink>transform app formlist</shortlink>
    <topic>Forms List</topic>
    <description>The list of form instances to edit or view.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>About the Forms List</title>
            <description>
                <p>
        The Forms List screen displays instances of forms. These are forms that are ready to be filled out, partially filled out,
        or completed but still available for viewing and perhaps modification.
                </p>
                <p>
        The Forms List is, by default, listed in chronological order of creation. That is, the oldest forms will be displayed last.
        The list may optionally be sorted and filtered by form
        *[status]* and/or form
        *[type]*.
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The form rows</title>
            <description>
                <p>
        Each row in the list represents one instance of a particular type of form. The display name of that type of form is shown
        in large bold type. The icon associated with the form type will be shown on the left and the associated color background
        will be used for the row. The date/time when the form instance was first created will be shown above the display
        name. If there are any issues with the form (such as missing required fields or detected validation errors) a red [redStar] star will be displayed after the date/time. (Information about any issues is available when viewing the form details through
        a menu item.) A blue [blueDot] dot indicates that the form was changed in a recent Refresh from the server. The current status of the form (for example,
        "Open") will be displayed on the upper-right of the row.
                </p>
                <p>
        Some types of forms display additional information below the display name, such as the value of certain form fields.
                </p>
                <p>
        The left edge of the colored part of the row may optionally have a different color:
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <content><![CDATA[
<ul style="font-size:16px;list-style-type:none;">
<li style="margin-bottom:10px;">
<span style="color:#00F;font-weight:bold;border-left:3px solid #00F;padding-left:3px;">Blue</span> indicates a new form that has not been uploaded to the server.</li>
<li style="margin-bottom:10px;">
<span style="color:#FFA500;font-weight:bold;border-left:3px solid #FFA500;padding-left:3px;">Orange</span> indicates a form with edit modifications that have not been uploaded to the server.</li>
<li style="margin-bottom:10px;">
<span style="color:#F00;font-weight:bold;border-left:3px solid #F00;padding-left:3px;">Red</span> indicates a form which encountered errors when attempting synchronization with the server. Information
          about the errors is available when viewing the form details through a menu item.</li>
<li style="margin-bottom:10px;">
<span style="color:#000;font-weight:bold;border-left:3px solid #000;padding-left:3px;">Black</span> indicates a form has been deleted on the device but has not been deleted from the server.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>            </content>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Selecting a form</title>
            <description>
                <p>Tapping the row for a particular form will select it for viewing, editing, or deletion, and then switch to the Form Details Screen. After returning to the Forms List screen from viewing or editing a form, that form will remain selected in the list. Selection is shown with a darker drop-shadow on the row. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Viewing and editing a Form</title>
            <description>
                <p>To view and optionally edit the contents of a form *[Tap]* the form row to both select and open for edit. </p>
                <p>See the [Form Details Screen] help for more information about viewing and editing a form.
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Top of the screen</title>
            <description>
                <p>
        There is a control bar at the top of the screen. It includes a [menu] 
        Menu button and information described in the
        [Main Control Bar] help.
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Searching, Sorting, and Filtering the list </title>
            <description>
                <p>There are buttons to control searching, sorting, and filtering the list of forms. See [Search, Sort, Filter] for more information about these functions. </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Deleting a form</title>
            <description>
                <p>
        To delete the selected form and all of its data, tap the [menu] Menu button and then tap the *[Delete Form]* menu item. Deleting a form requires confirmation. There is no "undelete".  There is also a "Delete Form" Form Action menu item on the Form Details Screen Menu.</p>
                <p>See the [Main Control Bar] help for more information about deleting a form.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding a new form</title>
            <description>
                <p>Above the list there is an *[Add Form]* button to switch the display from the list of existing form instances to list of the types of forms available for creating new form instances.</p>
                <p>
        For information about adding form instances, see the
        [Add Form Help].
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Refreshing and Uploading</title>
            <description>
                <p>
        Above the list is information and buttons related to downloading and uploading form data from and to the server. For more
        information see the
        [Downloading, Refreshing, and Uploading].
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="transform app formdetails">Form Details Screen</link>
        <link link="transform app maincontrolbar">Main Control Bar</link>
        <link link="transform app addform">Add Form Help</link>
        <link link="transform%20app%20search">Search, Sort, Filter</link>
        <link link="transform app refreshing">Downloading, Refreshing, and Uploading</link>
        <link href="/images/redStar.svg">redStar</link>
        <link href="/images/blueDot.svg">blueDot</link>
        <link href="/images/menu.svg">menu</link>
        <link href="/images/sort.svg">sort</link>
        <link href="/images/delete.svg">delete</link>
    </links>
</page>