<page>
    <shortlink>transform app</shortlink>
    <topic>Alpha TransForm Form Filler</topic>
    <description>The Alpha TransForm form filler is an application used to fill out forms created using TransForm Central. The form filler is available as both a mobile application and web app.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The Alpha TransForm Filler app lets you create, fill out, and upload forms for Alpha TransForm. You must have an Alpha TransForm login and be a member of an active TransForm account in order to use the filler application.</p>
                <p>The mobile form filler application can be downloaded from the *[extlink:Google Play]* or Apple *[extlink:App Store]* for free. The web filler can be accessed at *[extlink:https://transform.alphasoftware.com/transformFiller.a5w@https://transform.alphasoftware.com/transformFiller.a5w]*. To access the Web Filler, you need to create a new [Permission Role] called "browseruser" and [add the role] to users in the TransForm account you would like to give access to the Web Filler.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
    <!--list:.-->
    <!--order:
loginScreen
formsList
formTypes
refreshing
mainControlBar
search
details
editors
formTOC
detailsMenu
info
systemMessage
screen
language
tools
versions
-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Web Filler Limitations</title>
            <description>
                <p>Some features are unavailable or may not behave as expected in v1 of the Web Filler. This includes:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Access to On-device Data: on-device data cannot be downloaded to the browser and is unavailable. You can access images, however, if hosted on an external server. See [Adding a cloudpath Policy to display assets in the Web Filler] to learn more.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Audio and Video Recording: recording audio and video is not available.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Barcode Scanning: barcode scanning is not available. Barcode values must be entered manually.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>GPS functions: values returned by the browser depend on the computer's IP address, which may not return the user's actual location.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>ajaxGET() function: calls using this function may fail in the browser filler. Use ajaxSendRequest() or ajaxSendRequestFromServer(). See [Calling Web Services in TransForm Forms from the Web Filler] for more information about using ajaxSendRequestFromServer().</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>On-device Data TPL Functions are unavailable: this includes phoneGapTFExecuteSQL(), inappbrowser(), and fileviewer().</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>phonecall() TPL function: calls may only be made from the web filler in browsers that have been configured to use a specific application to make phone calls and support opening an app to make the call.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>These features and more will be added in future versions of the Web Filler.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Mobile or Web? Determining which filler app is in use using TPL</title>
            <description>
                <p>The *[tpl:$environment]* system variable contains properties you can use to determine which filler app is running. If your forms use TPL code to access on-device data, you'll want to take advantage of these variables to adapt your forms for use in the web filler:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>TPL Variable</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[tpl:$environment.browser]*</name>
                            <description>Has a value of 1 when running in the web filler.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[tpl:$environment.browserurl]*</name>
                            <description>If running in the web filler, the portion of the URL after the domain name.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[tpl:$enviornment.nativemobile]*</name>
                            <description>Has a value of 1 when running in the mobile filler.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/help.svg">help</link>
        <link link="ondevice%20assets%20policy#section2_Adding%20a%20cloudpath%20Policy%20to%20display%20assets%20in%20the%20Web%20Filler">Adding a cloudpath Policy to display assets in the Web Filler</link>
        <link link="otheraccountsettings">Calling Web Services in TransForm Forms from the Web Filler</link>
        <link link="transform central permissions roles">Permission Role</link>
        <link link="transform%20central%20home#section1_Manage%20User%20Roles">add the role</link>
    </links>
</page>
