<page>
    <shortlink>transform app maincontrolbar</shortlink>
    <topic>Main Control Bar</topic>
    <description>Confirm login, logout, Help, and more.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>There is a control bar at the top of the screen. It includes a [menu] Menu button, the user name, and a button on the right to control communications with the TransForm server. Tapping the Menu button brings up a set of menu choices.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Menu Choice: Help</title>
            <description>
<p>
  The [help] Help menu choice brings up the Help screen displaying help about what is currently on the screen.
  On the Help screen the *[Show TOC]* button may be used to display the Table of Contents
  to navigate to any other part of Help.
  After navigating to another part of Help, the *[Back]* button may be used to traverse back to 
  the previously displayed parts of Help.
 </p>
 <p>
  If you *[press and hold]* the [help] Help menu choice, the help will go directly to the Table of Contents.
</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
          <title>Menu Choice: Duplicate Form</title>
            <description>
              <p>To create a copy of the selected form (including copies of its associated media files), tap the [menu] Menu button and then tap the *[Duplicate Form]* menu item. Duplicating a form requires confirmation. The new form will have the current date/time as its creation date/time. </p>
              <p>Forms that have Upload Errors that prevent them from being uploaded can usually be duplicated to create a new form that is more likely able to be uploaded. See "Errors during uploading" in the [Downloading, Refreshing, and Uploading] help.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Menu Choice: Delete form</title>
            <description><p>
        To delete the selected form and all of its data, tap the [menu] Menu button and then tap the
        *[Delete Form]* menu item. Deleting a form requires confirmation. There is no "undelete".
      </p>
      <p>
        Forms that have not yet been uploaded will be deleted immediately. Forms that already have been uploaded to the server will
        be deleted on the server the next time uploading is performed. Such "waiting to delete" forms will be marked with
        a black left border in the Forms List. However, logging out without performing an upload operation will not delete
        the form on the server and it will be re-downloaded on the next login.
      </p></description>
            <warning>There is no undo for this action.</warning>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Menu Choice: Other Actions</title>
            <description>
            <p>
            The *[Other Actions]* menu choice brings up another menu with commands to update or delete 
            On-Device Data.
            </p>
            <p>
            Information about these commands is specific to each account and is not provided in this help.
            </p>
            <p>
            There is also an On-Device Data Info command that displays statistics relating to the On-Device Data.
            </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Menu Choice: Confirm login</title>
            <description><p>
        To confirm login credentials, tap the [menu] Menu button and then tap the
        *[Confirm login]* menu item. This is used when a user has been logged in more than a specific amount of time (for
        example, two days) and the system requires re-confirmation before allowing uploading or downloading of data. A user
        who is already logged in can still create new forms and do editing but may not save that data back to the server
        until confirmation is done successfully. The app will display a prompt when confirmation is needed.
      </p>
      <p>
        Confirmation of login requires the device to be online since it communicates with the server.
      </p></description>
        <note>Logging out and then logging in again will lose any data that has not been uploaded. Use confirmation instead, which maintains the same login and does not erase the data.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Menu Choice: Logout</title>
            <description><p>
        To logout the current user, tap the [menu] Menu button and then tap the
        *[Logout]* menu item. The user will then be prompted to login again, optionally with a different User ID and/or account.
      </p></description>
      <note>Logging out will lose any data that has not been uploaded (a warning will be displayed). To prevent the loss of data, but confirm login credentials, use the Confirm Login menu item instead, which maintains the same login and does not erase
        the data.</note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Upload / Refresh / Offline</title>
            <description>
            <p>
  The Alpha TransForm app performs almost all of its operations using only the device's hardware and data resident on the device. 
  It only communicates with the TransForm server using WiFi or cellular data when you direct it to. 
  Buttons in the upper-right of the Menu Control Bar are used to initiate this communication.
 </p>
 <p>
  For more information, see the <a a5-item="show:Refreshing" href="#help-Refreshing">Downloading, Refreshing, and Uploading</a> help.
</p></description>
        </section>

    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/menu.svg">menu</link>
        <link href="/images/expand.svg">expand</link>
        <link href="/images/collapse.svg">collapse</link>
        <link href="/images/help.svg">help</link>
        <link link="transform%20app%20refreshing">Downloading, Refreshing, and Uploading</link>
    </links>
</page>