<page>
    <shortlink>server component Video Player Component</shortlink>
    <topic>Video Player Component</topic>
    <description>The Video Player component is a Custom component that can be used to display and play HTML5 video, Flash video, or embed a hybrid HTML5/Flash video and player from YouTube in a web application.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Video Player component is used to play videos referenced in a parent container, such as Grid Component or UX Component, in a web application. This makes it easy to build a data driven multimedia application which includes promotional, reference or training video assets.</p>
        <p>The Video Player component includes the ability to:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>Add a hybrid HTML5 and Flash video player for hosted streaming video.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Embed any video from YouTube in a hybrid HTML5/Flash video player.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <!--list:.-->
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Referencing the Video Player Object in JavaScript</title>
            <description>The Video Player component can be used in JavaScript scripts by referencing the *[js:{component.object}]* object. For example:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var vPlayer = {component.object};
vPlayer.clearVideo();]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Video Player JavaScript Methods</title>
            <description>The Video Player object has the following JavaScript methods:</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">clearVideo()</title>
                    <description>Clears the div containing the HTML5 or Flash video player. Typically called in the onHide event of a pop-up window.</description>
                    <example code="js"><![CDATA[{grid.childObject}.clearVideo();]]></example>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Video Player</title>
                <description>The Video Player Component allows you to easily display video content in a web application. The videos below show how to get started with the Video Player Component.</description>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/YZJmH2LenTNgK4uK1fSXRV</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/vaBpdZcKfJHxQfEyWYtbFM</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 3</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/mngVW62VRvQruh8KwGHxjh</link>
                </video>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video - Part 4</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/W3Y1Gf9KxMewMcKSShHox5</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>