<page>
    <shortlink>ux control properties field label</shortlink>
    <topic>Field Label</topic>
    <description>Settings for configuring label for a data control.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Label</title>
            <description>
                <p>The text shown in the label.</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Aligning Controls with a Blank Label</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>When a label is placed above a control, it makes the entire control container taller. When placed inline with other controls that do not have a label, the controls will align to the top of the label. Turning the label on but leaving the *[ui:Label]* text blank will align controls as expected.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Left: Dropdown box label *[ui:Position]* is set to "None". Right: Dropdown box label *[ui:Position]* is set to "Above" and the *[ui:Label]* text is blank.</title>
                        <link>images/blankLabelText.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Bubble help</title>
            <description>
                <p>Optional help text shown when the user hovers the mouse over the label. *[ui:Bubble help]* can be used to add tips for how to enter information into a control. See also [Has help] for adding a help icon to a control.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Bubble help</title>
                <link>images/field.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Class</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Class property allows you to add one or more classes to the label for the control, including classes from the component's selected Web Theme. Use the [...] smart field button to open the CSS class name selector to choose classes defined in the component's style, locally defined classes, or create new classes to apply to the label.</p>
                <p>The images below show a label that has been styled using classes from the iOS7 theme.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Label styled using the *[css:iOS7GroupLabel]* class from the iOS7 web theme</title>
                <link>images/class.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Label styled using the *[css:iOS7ButtonDenyPressed]* class from the iOS7 web theme</title>
                <link>images/class2.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Style</title>
            <description>
                <p>The Style property adds optional inline style attributes to the label. Use the [...] smart field button to open the Style Editor. The Style Editor provides a UI for specifying the style properties to add to the label. It also contains a *[ui:Code]* tab for directly adding CSS styles.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Position</title>
            <description>
                <p>Sets the position of the label relative to the control:</p>
                <p>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Position</name-title>
                            <description-title>Description</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Above</name>
                            <description>The label is shown above the control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Left</name>
                            <description>The label is shown to the left of the control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Below</name>
                            <description>The label is shown below the control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Right</name>
                            <description>The label is shown to the right of the control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>None</name>
                            <description>No label is shown.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item build="">
                            <name>Float above</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>If the control has no value, the label is shown in the control. When the user clicks on the control, the label animates to a position above the control. If the control contains a value, the label is positioned above the control.</p>
                                <p>You can customize floating labels using the UX component's [Floating label settings].</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
                <p>If the Position is Left or Right, the *[ui:Width]* determines the width of the label.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Width</title>
            <description>
                <p>The width of the control's label. The width is specified using CSS syntax (e.g. *[css:5in]*, *[css:250px]*.) The *[css:{Global.LabelWidth}]* placeholder can also be used to specify the label width. If set to *[css:{Global.LabelWidth}]*, the label width will be the width specified in the UX component's [Label width] property.</p>
                <p>If width is blank, the width is automatically determined from the contents of the label.</p>
                <p>This property is only shown if the *[ui:Position]* is set to Right or Left.</p>
            </description>
            <important>
                <p>The *[ui:Layout type]* for the UX Component affects how the label and control are sized. If set to *[ui:ContainerWidth]*, increasing the label width reduces the width of the control. See [Layout type] to learn more.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Alignment</title>
            <description>
                <p>The position of the text within the label.l Text can be Left, Right, or Center aligned. Only applies if the label's *[ui:Position]* has been set to Left or Right.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>If the width of the label is the same width as the text in the label, you may need to make the label wider to see the alignment change.</p>
            </note>
            <figure>
                <link>images/labelAlignment.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Floating Textbox Labels</title>
                <description>
                    <p>A popular design pattern displays the label for a textbox as a watermark in the field. When the user clicks in the field to begin typing, the watermark animates into position above the textbox.</p>
                    <p>In this video, we show how animated textbox labels can be specified.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2020-07-27</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EXklCdpJYr8</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link link="ux%20control%20field%20properties%20has%20help">Has help</link>
        <link link="ux%20properties%20label%20width">Label width</link>
        <link link="ux floating label settings">Floating label settings</link>
        <link link="ux%20properties%20layout%20type">Layout type</link>
    </links>
</page>