<page>
    <shortlink>howto add a webfont</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Add a Web Font to Your Project</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Learn how to include web fonts in your web and mobile applications using the @font-face CSS rule in Alpha Anywhere.</p>
    </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Web fonts can be distributed with web and mobile applications. In order to use a web font, the web font must be either included and published with your project or hosted somewhere that the font can be accessed and downloaded via the web.</p>
                <p>The CSS @font-face rule can be used to add a web font to your application. @font-face defines where the font can be downloaded. The @font-face rule is specified in the stylesheet used by the application. The URL for the web font files can be an absolute URL or a relative URL. For example, the Alpha style can be extended to include a web font that is included in the Web Project and stored in the same folder as the Alpha theme as follows:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="css" caption="The CSS required to include a web font is often distributed with the font when you download the font from a site such as Font Squirrel."><![CDATA[@font-face{ 
 font-family: 'MyWebFont';
 src: url('css/fonts/WebFont.eot'); /* IE9 Compat Modes */
 src: url('css/fonts/WebFont.eot?iefix') format('embedded-opentype'), /* IE6-IE8 */
 url('css/fonts/WebFont.woff') format('woff'), /* Modern Browsers */
 url('css/fonts/WebFont.ttf') format('truetype'), /* Safari, Android, iOS */
 url('css/fonts/WebFont.svg#webfont') format('svg'); /* Legacy iOS */
}]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>The font-family property defines the name of the font that will be assigned when the font is loaded from the URL defined in the src property.</p>
                <p>Alternatively, you can store the @font-face directive for your font in its own css file and use the @import directive to include the font in your web theme (the imported file location is relative to the file it's declared in or an absolute URL):</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="css"><![CDATA[@import url("fonts/myWebFont.css"); /* Local Web Font */
@import url('https://fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Roboto&display=swap'); /* Web Font Hosted on a 3rd party site */]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>After defining the location of the font files, the font can be referenced by the font-family property throughout an application or added to a SASS variable (such as $fontFamily variable defined in the Alpha style) as follows:</p>
                <p>
                    <example code="css"><![CDATA[$fontFamily: 'MyWebFont', Arial, san-serif; // *AA:Font|Family|fontFamily|The font family to use.]]></example>
                </p>
                <p>Web Fonts can be referenced anywhere in your application, including in locally defined CSS (such as in the in-line style property for a control) in your components and controls.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <title>Web Fonts can be added to any Version 4 style by Adjusting the theme's font variable(s).</title>
                <link>images/settingFontAdjust.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Where to Find Web Fonts</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can find web fonts at the following sites. These are just a few resources. It is neither a definitive list nor endorsed by Alpha Software.</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Google Fonts@https://fonts.google.com/]*</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Font Squirrel@https://www.fontsquirrel.com/]*</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Fontspring@https://www.fontspring.com]*</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Adobe Fonts@https://fonts.adobe.com/]*</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>