<page>
    <shortlink>howto createsubtheme</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Create and Add a Sub-theme</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Sub-themes are reusable style definitions for controls.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Sub-themes allow you to create one or more reusable 'looks' for controls - such as buttons or Lists. In a sub-theme definition, basic styling as well as behaviors (hover, visited, active, focus, etc) can be defined for a control.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <tip>
                <p>For a great guide to pseudo-elements and pseudo-classes, check out *[extlink:https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2016/05/an-ultimate-guide-to-css-pseudo-classes-and-pseudo-elements/]*.</p>
            </tip>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The sub-theme is applied to a control using its *[ui:Sub-theme]* property. Multiple sub-themes can be created for the same control type, however only one sub-theme can be assigned to a control at design time. </p>
                <p>To create a sub-theme, use the Sub-theme Builder. Sub-themes can be created in several locations:</p>
            </description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>In the Sub-theme Builder accessed via a control's *[ui:Sub-theme]* property</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>In the component settings when defining Style Tweaks</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>In the Web Theme Builder</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>While sub-themes can be defined directly using a source editor (JavaScript and CSS), it's easiest to start by copying an existing sub-theme and then making your own modifications. In the Sub-theme Builder, you can optionally select a sub-theme to copy when creating a new sub-theme. All items that support sub-themes have at least one sub-theme, "base", defined in the styles that ship with Alpha Anywhere. Some controls, such as List controls (listbox) and button controls (button) have multiple sub-themes defined in the styles that ship with Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Creating a Sub-theme</title>
            <description>
                <p>To create a sub-theme, it's easiest to start by copying an existing sub-theme definition and then adding your own class definitions.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>The following steps show you how to create a sub-theme using the Web Style Builder. Sub-themes can also be created from within the UX Builder using the [Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'].</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open the Web Style Builder from the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select one of the style sheets that support sub-themes. Styles that support sub-themes include "Alpha", "iOS7", "AndroidDark", and "AndroidLight".</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>
                        <p>You can create your own style that supports sub-themes as well by copying an existing style sheet and editing it using the Web Style Builder.</p>
                    </note>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the Code tab in the Web Style Builder, locate the *[ui:Select part...]* menu.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the part for which you would like to create a new sub-theme. Every part in the list can have a sub-theme. The list below explains what each listed part corresponds to in the UX Component (this is not a comprehensive list):</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Part</name-title>
                            <description-title>Supported Controls</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Panel Card</name>
                            <description>The Panel Card control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Panel Navigator</name>
                            <description>The Panel Navigator control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Panel Layout</name>
                            <description>The Panel Layout control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Control Bar</name>
                            <description>The ControlBar control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Accordion</name>
                            <description>Tab Control rendered as an accordion</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Tab</name>
                            <description>The Tab control - styles the tab pane</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Tab Band</name>
                            <description>The Tab control - styles the tabs</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Menu</name>
                            <description>The Menu control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Menu Bar</name>
                            <description>The Menu control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Window</name>
                            <description>The Window container control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>List</name>
                            <description>The List control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Spin List</name>
                            <description>The Spin List control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Tree</name>
                            <description>The Tree control</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Date Picker</name>
                            <description>The Date Picker for a Text Box control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Time Picker</name>
                            <description>The Time Picker for a Text Box control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit</name>
                            <description>Text Box, Textarea, and Dropdown Box controls.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Edit Button Group</name>
                            <description>The in-control buttons shown in a Text Box control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Button</name>
                            <description>A Button control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Button Dropdown</name>
                            <description>A Button control with [Has dropdown icon] enabled.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Button Split</name>
                            <description>A Button control  with [Has dropdown icon] and [Display as split button] enabled.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Button List</name>
                            <description>The Button List control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Slider</name>
                            <description>The Slider control.</description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Switch</name>
                            <description>The Switch control.</description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>After you select a Part, you can optionally select a *[ui:Sub-theme]* to copy. Every Part has at least one sub-theme - "base". In the image below, the base sub-theme will be copied to a new sub-theme called "orangeButtons".</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click *[ui:Create]* to create the sub-theme. This will take you back to the Code tab in the Web Theme Builder with the new sub-theme selected. Both CSS and Sass can be used to define the style for the sub-theme. Several tools exist to make it easier to add colors and variables to your style. To insert a color, select *[ui:Insert Color]* from the *[ui:Add Variable]* menu.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Color Picker]* includes multiple tools for selecting colors, including Fan Decks and the ability to select colors from an existing image. The *[ui:Palettes]* tab is where you can create and save color collections.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme7.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Once you have finished defining your new sub-theme, it's ready to be used. Click the *[ui:Save]* icon in the toolbar to save your changes.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/subtheme8.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Assigning a Sub-theme</title>
            <description>
                <p>Sub-themes are assigned to controls using the Sub-theme property. Let's assign the sub-theme created in the previous section to a button in a UX Component.</p>
            </description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open the UX Builder and go to the Controls pane.</p>
                    </description>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select a control to the UX that you built the sub-theme for. Then, click the [...] smart field for the *[ui:Sub-theme]* property for the control.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/applySubtheme1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Select the new sub-theme from the *[ui:Select Sub-theme]* dialog and click OK to assign the sub-theme. Open the component in Live or Working Preview to preview your change.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A button in a UX with the "orangeButtons" sub-theme applied.</title>
                        <link>images/applySubtheme2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20properties%20style%20subtheme%20and%20tweaks">Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'</link>
        <link link="">Has dropdown icon</link>
        <link link="">Display as split button</link>
        <link href="/images/tools/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux%20properties%20style%20subtheme%20and%20tweaks">UX Component - Properties - Style sub-theme and CSS 'tweaks'</ref>
        <ref link="stylesheet%20builder">Web Theme Builder</ref>
    </see>
</page>