<page build="5229">
    <shortlink>howto set height to screen height</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Set the Height of a Container to the Screen Height</topic>
    <description>Learn how to set the height of a container to the full height of the screen.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>If you try the set the height of a Container in a UX Component to 100% of the screen using *[css:height: 100%;]*, it won't work. This is because percentage (%) is a relative unit, so the resulting height of the Container will be relative to the object that contains it. This is often another container (e.g. a Panel Card) or &lt;div&gt; Alpha Anywhere creates for the UX Component itself.</p>
        <p>While you could manually set the height to 100% for all of the Container's parent container elements (Panels, frames, other containers, the UX Component, etc), this is tedious and is not guaranteed to work in all cases.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>The container height is limited to the height of it's parent object. In this image, the parent object is the UX Component.</title>
                <link>images/height100.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Instead of trying to ensure that all parent containing elements are set to full height, you can use Alpha Anywhere's built-in *[ui:screen.height]* variable to set the height of the container to the full height of the screen. The *[ui:screen.height]* variable will size the height of the container to the height of the screen.</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[screen.height]]></example>
            <important>You cannot use *[ui:screen.height]* when defining the in-line style for the container. You can only use screen.height in the [Height property].</important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>You can also use an expression with the *[ui:screen.height]* to specify the height of the container. For example, the following expression sets the height of the container to half of the screen height:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[screen.height/2]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>To learn more, watch the video below:</description>
            <videos>
                <title>Understanding the screen.height Property</title>
                <description>
                    <p>When setting the height of a container you cannot use percentages. However, you use the special screen.height variable to represent 100% of the available height.</p>
                    <p>In this video we show how a container's height can be set using the screen.height property.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2018-08-03</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/q2VQjVubacSvxEFEc5Fj2Q</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>UX Container Objects Only</limitations>
    <links>
        <link link="ux%20controls%20control%20properties%20container%20begin%20properties%20container%20height">Height property</link>
    </links>
</page>