<page>
	<topic>IMPORT_SCRIPTS_UDF()</topic>
	
<description>The IMPORT_SCRIPTS_UDF() function imports scripts and user defined functions from a text file.</description>	
	
	<syntax>IMPORT_SCRIPTS_UDF( [ Filename as C [, Silent as L [, Automatic_Overwrite as L ]]] )</syntax>
	<arguments>
		<argument>
			<name>Filename</name>
			<description>Optional. The name of a text file created with the EXPORT_SCRIPTS_AND_UDF()function. If no filename is specified, then the function prompts for filename.
</description>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>Silent</name>
			<description>Optional. Default = .F.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>.F. = Alpha Anywhere displays a dialog box showing the scripts and UDFs in the text file that you are importing. You can select which scripts and UDFs to import.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>.T. = This dialog is suppressed, and Alpha Anywhere imports all scripts and UDFs.</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</argument>
		<argument>
			<name>Automatic_Overwrite</name>
			<description>Optional. Default = .F.</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>.F. = Alpha Anywhere does prompts before overwriting any script or UDF with the same name.</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>.T. = Alpha Anywhere does not prompt before overwriting any script or UDF with the same name.</description>
			</case>
		</cases>
		</argument>
		
		
	</arguments>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<note>The IMPORT_SCRIPTS_UDF() function is called when you use the Import command on the right click menu from the Code tab on the Control Panel. It allows you to import scripts and UDFs into a database that were previously exported using the Export command (also on the right click menu from the Code tab on the Control Panel ). Using this function, it is possible to write code that allows you to update your customer's applications by sending them enhanced scripts and UDFs.</note>
		</section>
	</sections>
	
	
<example><![CDATA[export_scripts_udfs("c:\myfunctions.txt")
import_scripts_udfs("c:\myfunctions.txt")]]></example>	
	
	
<see>
	<ref href="/Ref/Api/Functions/Xbasic/Script Functions/index.xml">Script Functions</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>