<page>
	<topic>Define an Access Query</topic>
	<description>This procedure is part of the Web Component Builder procedure for building a component.</description>
			
	<sections>

<section>
	<title>Establishing the Connection</title>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Select Grid > Query (ADO).</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>In the Connection type list select "Access Database".</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>Click 'open folder' icon to navigate to and select the Microsoft Access (.MDB) database file.</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>Click Connect. If Alpha Anywhere was able to open the database, additional fields will appear on the dialog box.</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>Continue with Retrieving Your Data From a Table or View.</description>
		</step>
			<step>
			<description>Select how to retrieve data. The options are:</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>Table or View</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>SQL Select Statement</description>
			</case>
			
		</cases>
		
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>
		<section>
			<title>Retrieve Your Data from a Table</title>
	<description>If you selected "Table or View" in step 6:</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Click the 'down' icon to select a table or view from the Table/View list.</description>
			<note>A table alias can make your grid portable, by separating it from direct reference to a table name. as long as a table has the same structure and the same alias, it can use a grid originally built for another table.</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, enter an alias for the table into the Table/View alias field. If you do not enter an alias, it will default to the name of the table.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, click Define Arguments to display the Define Arguments dialog. You use arguments to provide run-time values for filter and order expressions.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, specify a filter expression in the Filter field that selects records from the table. Click the '...' icon to display the Specify Filter dialog. Refer to Specifying a Filter Expression.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, specify a ordering expression in the Order by field that sequences selected records. Click the '...' icon to display the Specify Order dialog. Refer to Specifying an Order Expression.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Optionally, check Read only to prevent user updates. If you are in the process of creating a grid, continue with Selecting the Fields to Display.</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click Select Primary Key(s) to display the Specify Primary Keys dialog. Select the field(s) that uniquely identify each record and click OK.</description>
		</step>
		
	</steps>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>Retrieving Your Data with a SQL Statement</title>
			<description>If you selected to retrieve your data with a "SQL Select Statement":</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Select SQL Select Statement.</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Click Edit SQL to display the SQL Builder to define the table(s) and fields that you want to work with. Continue with SQL Builder.</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
	</sections>
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.</limitations>
	<see>
		<ref>Selecting the Fields to Display</ref>
	</see>
	
	
	
</page>