<page>
	<topic>Using Xbasic to Read and Write to a Table</topic>
	<description>The new Alpha Anywhere developer eventually comes to the point where he or she would like to write a script that directly reads from and writes to a table. This topic provides a couple of simple examples that you can elaborate upon. The are based on the Customer table in the AlphaSports sample database.</description>
	<sections>
<section>
	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Script or Function?</title>
		<description>Perhaps the first question you will ask is: "Should this be a script or a function?". There is little difference in the Xbasic coding between the two alternatives. The determining issue is whether you want to return a value. Functions can return values. Scripts cannot return values, except by setting the value(s) of global variable(s), and this is often considered a sloppy and potentially troublesome programming practice.</description>
	
	
</section>

	</sections>
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>How Do I Call a Script or Function?</title>
		<description>Calling a function is as easy as naming it and catching the return value, if any. This example returns a value from the find_last_name() function:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[dim return_value as C
... some code
return_value = find_last_name()
... some code ]]></example>
	</section>	

	<section>
		
		<description>Or, if the find_last_name() function required a parameter, you might write something like this:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[dim return_value as C
... some code
return_value = find_last_name("Michael")
... some code]]></example>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>If the find_last_name() function did not return a value, the syntax would simply be:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[... some code
find_last_name()
... some code ]]></example>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>Calling a script named find_first_name is just as easy:</description>
	<example><![CDATA[... some code
script_play("find_first_name")
... some code]]></example>


<note>Function names always have parentheses in their names. Scripts do not.</note>
	</section>	
	
	
</sections>
	
	
	
	
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Sequencing Through the Records of a Table</title>
		<description>The following is the beginning of a script that reads and writes to the customer table. This script does not require that the customer table be open in a layout. First, create a table object named tbl (any variable name that is not a reserved word will do).</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
tbl = table.open("customer")]]></example>
	</section>	

	<section>
		
		<description>Now read the first record.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[tbl.fetch_first()
while .not. table.fetch_eof()
    ' ... do something
    tbl.fetch_next()
end while
tbl.close()]]></example>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>Keep reading until you reach the end of the file.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[tbl.fetch_first()
while .not. table.fetch_eof()
    ' ... do something
    tbl.fetch_next()
end while]]></example>
	</section>	
	<section>
	
		<description>Now, close the table.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[tbl.close()]]></example>
	</section>	
	
	
</sections>

<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Reading a Field Value</title>
		<description>Reading a field value is as simple as referencing table_object.field_name. In the following script the variable ln always contains the value of the lastname field in the current record:</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
dim ln as C
tbl = table.open("customer")
tbl.fetch_first()
while .not. table.fetch_eof()
    ln = tbl.lastname
    tbl.fetch_next()
end while
tbl.close() ]]></example>
	</section>
	
</sections>




<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Writing a Field Value</title>
		<description>Writing a changed field value in a record requires two more statements. Suppose you wanted to make sure that the lastname field had an initial capital letter.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
dim ln as C
tbl = table.open("customer")
tbl.fetch_first()
while .not. table.fetch_eof()]]></example>
	</section>	

	<section>
		
		<description>The tbl.change_begin(.t.) statement says that you are changing an existing field and that you want to honor any existing field rules.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[ tbl.change_begin(.t.)
    tbl.lastname = f_upper(tbl.lastname) ]]></example>
	</section>	
	<section>
		
		<description>The tbl.change_end(.t.) statement says that you are finished changing an existing field and want to save the changes.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[ tbl.change_end(.t.)
    tbl.fetch_next()
end while
tbl.close() ]]></example>
	</section>	
	
	
	
	
	
	
	
</sections>
	
<sections>
	
	<section>
	<title>Deleting a Record</title>
	<description>The process of deleting a record is similar to changing a record. First, you need to use one of many techniques for finding the record you are going to delete.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
dim ln as C
tbl = table.open("customer")
tbl.fetch_first()
while .not. table.fetch_eof()]]></example>
	</section>	
	
	<section>

	<description>This script tests the values of the firstname and lastname fields, and only deletes specific records.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[  if (tbl.lastname = "Smith") .and. (tbl.firstname = "John") then
        tbl.change_begin(.t.)
        tbl.delete() ]]></example>
	</section>	
	
	<section>

	<description>The tbl.change_end(.t.) statement says that you are want to delete the record.</description>
	<example><![CDATA[tbl.change_end(.t.)
    end if
    tbl.fetch_next()
end while
tbl.close() ]]></example>
	</section>	
</sections>

<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Adding a Record</title>
		<description>Adding a record is simple. You bracket your field updates with the tbl.enter_begin() and tbl.enter_end() statements.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
tbl = table.open("customer")
tbl.enter_begin()]]></example>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>The tbl.enter_begin(.t.) statement says that you are adding a existing field to the end of the table and that you want to honor any existing field rules.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[tbl.firstname = "George"
tbl.lastname = "Washington"]]></example>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>The tbl.enter_end(.t.) statement says that you are finished adding a record and want to save the changes.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[tbl.enter_end(.t.)
tbl.close()]]></example>
		
	</section>
</sections>

<sections>
	<section>
		<title>Selecting a Subset of Records with a Query</title>
		<description>In each of the examples above, the code opened the customer table and sequenced through all of its records. Suppose you wanted only to sequence through the records when the bill_state_region field contained the value "MA". Instead of writing this code at the beginning of the script:</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
tbl = table.open("customer")]]></example>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>you would write:</description>
		<example><![CDATA[dim tbl as P
dim qry as P
tbl = table.open("customer")
query.filter = "bill_state_region = 'MA'"
qry = tbl.query_create()
... add, change, or delete ...]]></example>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		
		<description>Finish the script or function by detaching the query and closing the table.</description>
		<example><![CDATA[tbl.query_detach()
tbl.close()]]></example>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>Now, you will sequence through only those customers in the state of Massachusetts.</description>
	</section>
</sections>
<see>
	<ref>Table Functions and Methods</ref>
	<ref>Overview: Functions and Expressions</ref>
</see>
</page>