<page>
	
	<topic>Changing Browse Columns and Rows
</topic>

	<description>While viewing records in a browse, you can resize rows and columns, re-arrange columns, split the browse to view as many as four different areas in the same window, and show only parent records from a set.
</description>
<sections>
	
<section>
	<note>Appearance modifications remain in the browse only as long as the browse is open; once you close the browse or change to form view, the settings are reset to their default values.</note>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Resizing Columns and Rows</title>
	<description>You resize rows and columns in a browse by dragging the horizontal or vertical sizing handles. The sizing handles appear when the mouse hovers over the top or left border of the browse. When the pointer becomes a horizontal or vertical sizing handle, you can drag the column or row border to a desired size. Vertical Sizing Handle:

</description>
	<figure><link>images/UG_Vertical_Sizing_Handle.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	

<section>
	
	<description>Horizontal Sizing Handle</description>
	<figure><link>images/UG_Horizontal_Sizing_Handle.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	

<section>

	<description>If you want to resize a column that fills the entire window, click the column's title and press CTRL LEFT. Move left or right until the column divider is in the desired position.</description>

</section>	

<section>
	<title>Rearranging Columns
</title>
	<description>To rearrange browse columns:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Click the title of the column you want to move, which selects the entire column.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Click and hold in the title of the column again and the Column Reordering Bar appears.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Drag the column to a new position, and release. The Column Reordering Bar:
</description>
			<figure><link>images/UG_Browse_Column_Reordering.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Splitting a Browse</title>
	<description>Splitting a browse lets you view the multiple copies of the same browse in the same window, side-by-side. This can be helpful when a browse is wider than the screen, or when you want to work in different areas of the browse simultaneously. You can split a browse up to three times for a total of four sections. Browse Splitting Handle:
</description>
	<figure><link>images/UG_Browse_splitting_handle.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	

<section>

	<description>To split a Browse:
</description>
	<steps>
		<step>
			<description>Move the mouse over the left edge of the browse window.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>When the Browse Splitting Handle appears, click and drag the splitting bar to the right, to where you want to divide the Browse.
</description>
		</step>
		<step>
			<description>Repeat the process to split the browse up to three times. A Split Browse:
</description>
<figure><link>images/Split_Browse.gif</link></figure>
		</step>
		
		
	</steps>
	
</section>	


	
</sections>
<see>
	<ref>Using the Browse Editor</ref>
</see>

	
</page>