<page>
	<topic>Open Form or Browse Layout</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<title>Overview</title>
			<description>The Open Form or Browse Layout action opens a form or browse.</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Procedure</title>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Open Form or Browse Layout? field. The choices are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Form"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Browse"</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, check the Only show Layouts for current Table/Set to filter the list of layouts.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>In the Layout Name list:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>1. Optionally, select one of the listed forms or browses.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>2. Optionally, select "" if you would like the user to select the form or browse to open.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "", select a value in the When prompting, show layouts from field. The options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Another Table/Set"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Current Table/Set"</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Another Table/Set", pick a table or set from the Select Table/Set Name list.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Display the Options tab.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select a window style from the Window Style list. The options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Normal-(form opens as a standard Modeless window)". This opens the layout just as you would from the Control Panel. It can be moved to the background.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Dialog-(form opens as a Modal window)". This opens the layout modally, the user must close the form before doing something else.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Hidden,Normal-(form is hidden until a subsequent command activates it)".</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Hidden,Dialog-(form is hidden until a subsequent command activates it as modal)". Actions after this one will continue to execute until you issue a Show Window action to display the hidden dialog. At that point, the script will pause until the dialog is closed.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If this form or browse has previously been opened, choose whether to:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Switch to the previously opened Form or Browse window"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Open a new instance of the Form or Browse"</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Make a selection in the Position field. Options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Default - use position defined in the Layout"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Override - use position defined here"</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Override", set values in the X (horizontal) and Y (vertical) fields. The options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>X (horizontal) : "Left", "Center", "Right", "Fill", pixel coordinate</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>Y (vertical) : "Top", "Center", "Bottom", "Fill", pixel coordinate</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, display the Advanced tab. as the tab explains, you should not make any changes here unless you have a specific reason for doing so. The pointer required to write Xbasic code that reads or writes form or browse values or properties.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, change the pointer name in the Pointer field.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, change the scope of the pointer variable. Scope controls what other scripts can use this pointer.</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Session" means that all the other scripts on the window you opened will have access to the variable.</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Global" will allow any script running, even from another form, to access this pointer.</description>
						</case>
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, specify the record selection criteria to apply in addition to those defined in the layout. Note that you can specify to enter a new record.</description>
					<note>The pixel coordinate option and the Enter new record option are available in Alpha Five version 6 and above.</note>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally modify the comment that describes the action.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Finish.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<see>
		<ref>FORM.VIEW()</ref>
		<ref>BROWSE.VIEW()</ref>
	</see>
</page>