<page>
	<topic>Placing Dynamic Content into Browse Columns</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>You may place dynamic (computed) content into any column of a browse. The column may contain any combination of the following content:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>static text
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>images
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>dynamic text (computed from data in the current row)
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>To create dynamic content for a browse column:
</description>
<steps>
	<step>
		
		<description>Open a browse in design mode.
</description>
	</step>
		<step>
		
		<description>Select Column > Properties.
</description>
	</step>
		<step>
		
		<description>Display the Other tab of the Column Properties dialog.
</description>
	</step>
		<step>
		
		<description>Click Edit Display Expression to display the Conditional Expression Builder.
</description>
	</step>
		<step>
		
		<description>Click OK to save your edits and exit from the Column Properties dialog.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Each column of the browse has a .displayequation property. This property defines the button format. Here are three examples.
Alpha Anywhere allows you to embed buttons (and their attached Action or Xbasic scripts). This picture shows a browse with two buttons with constant text. You may place one or more buttons into any column of a browse. The button style may contain any combination of:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>static text
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>graphic
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>dynamic text (computed from data in the current row)
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>	
</section>
<section>
	<description>Each column of the browse has a .displayequation property. This property defines the button format. Here are three examples.
</description>
</section>
<section>
	<title>Dynamic Text</title>
<description>If the company field is not blank, the button text displays "Edit " plus company name. It the company name is blank, no button appears. Note the custom images in the upper left corner and used for the row picker. 
</description>	
<figure><link>images/MK_Browse_with_Button_and_Images.gif</link></figure>	
</section>

<section>
	<title>Static and Dynamic Text
</title>
<description>This example shows a combination of static and dynamic text. It displays the company name if it is not blank. 
</description>	
<figure><link>images/MK_Browse_with_Button_and_Dynamic_Text.gif</link></figure>	
</section>	

<section>
	<title>Text and Graphic
</title>
<description>This example shows a combination of static text and icon graphics. 
</description>	
<figure><link>images/MK_Browse_with_Button_and_Images2.gif</link></figure>	
</section>
<section>
	<description>The icons and buttons have a OnFlyOver style is used for the buttons. They do not look like buttons until you put your mouse over them.
</description>
</section>
	
</sections>	
	<limitations>Desktop applications only.
</limitations>
	
</page>