<page>
   <topic>GET_INDEX_DEFINITIONS Function</topic>
    <description>Gets the definitions of all index tags in a table's index file. Format is: tagname|OrderExpn|FilterExpn|Flags. Returns a CRLF delimited string. Use create_indexes() to rebuild indexes using this definition string.</description>

   <syntax>Definitions as C = Get_Index_Definitions(C tablename )</syntax>
   <arguments>
    <argument>
         <name>Definitions</name>
         <description>A CR-LF delimited list of index definitions. The format of each definition is:
 Tag_Name | Index_Expr | Filter_Expr | Index_Type</description>
 <list>
 <item>
 <name-title>Argument</name-title>
 <description-title>Description</description-title>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>Tag_Name</name>
 <description>Any character string, up to 32 characters long, used to identify the index. Spaces are not permitted in the tag name.</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>Index_Expr</name>
 <description>A character expression indicating the field or combination of fields used to order the index.</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>Filter_Expr</name>
 <description>Optional. Default = all records. A logical expression that indicates the field value(s) that must be satisfied in order for a record to be included in the index.</description>
 </item>
 
 <item>
 <name>Index_Type</name>
 <description>Optional. A string of character flags that can specify a descending sort order ('D'), or include only records with unique key values ('U'). By default, an index is ascending and includes duplicate key values.</description>
 </item>
 
 </list>
     </argument>
     
     
      <argument>
         <name>tablename</name>
         <description>The name of the table whose indexes you are examining.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
     <discussion>
The GET_INDEX_DEFINITIONS() function returns a CR-LF delimited string of the definitions of all indexes (i.e. index tags) for a table. This function is useful for taking a snapshot of the indexes in a particular table. You can then have code in your application that checks the current indexes in the table and compares them with the saved snapshot. If there is a mismatch, the missing index tags can be recreated with CREATE_INDEXES().
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
? Get_Index_Definitions("index_entries")
= Entry|PADR(LEFT(ENTRY,40),40," ") + PADR(LEFT(SUBENTRY,40),40," ") + PADR(LEFT(TOPIC,40),40, " ")||
Index_Id|INDEX_ID||U

]]></example>
   
   <see>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Document Types/DBF/Index Functions/Index Functions and Methods.html">Index Functions and Methods</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Document Types/DBF/Index Functions/CREATE_INDEXES Function.xml">CREATE_INDEXES()</ref>
      <ref href="/Api/Functions/Document Types/DBF/Index Functions/INDEXES_MATCH_DEFSTRING Function.xml">INDEXES_MATCH_DEFSTRING()</ref>
   </see>
<terms>index,arguments,defaults,expressions,field,function,list,logical,record,string</terms>
 
</page>