<page>
        <topic>UX Component - Action JavaScript - Stripe Checkout</topic>
       <description>There is an Action JavaScript in the UX component that allows you to easily use Stripe Checkout. </description> 
 <sections>
     <section>
         <description>
Stripe Checkout, and the Stripe API, allow you to process credit card payments from within your desktop web or mobile app. 
You will need to obtain your unique test and live authentication/api keys from Stripe prior to working with Stripe Checkout within your app. See the [Stripe Website] to setup your account.
</description>
         <figure><link>images/stripe_website.png</link></figure>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>A typical use case is to assign the action to a button click event, once the total of all items to be purchased has been computed. 
</description>
     </section>
     <section>
         <videos>
             <video>
                 <description>Watch Video</description>
                 <link>https://www.youtube.com/embed/aRie5a4XzQQ?feature=player_detailpage</link>
             </video>
                <video>
                 <description>Download Component</description>
                 <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/RocketMotors.a5wcmp</link>
             </video>
             
         </videos>
         
     </section>
  <section>
      <title>Specifying your Stripe API Keys:</title>
      <description>Stripe will issue you a total of four authentication/api keys. One set is for testing and one set is for a live app. The keys can be entered in explicitly within the Action Javascript builder or you may specify the keys within your project properties (click the Project Properties button when the Web Control Panel has focus). </description>
      <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs1.png</link></figure>
  </section>   
     
    <section>
       <title>Entering the Stripe Checkout keys in the Project Properties
</title> 
       <description>Entering the Stripe Checkout Keys in the Project Properties allows you to easily use Stripe Checkout within multiple components. Be careful to enter the test keys (typically prefixed with sk_test and pk_test) and the live keys (typically prefixed with sk_live and pk_live) in the appropriate fields. 

The secret key is used server side when the server is communicating to the Stripe API with the token supplied by Stripe Checkout. The secret key is never revealed client side. 
</description> 
        <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs1a.png</link></figure>
    </section>
     
     <section>
       <title>Stripe App Type:</title> 
       <description>The app type can be Test or Live. Use Test for all of your testing and when you are ready to go live you must switch this property to Live and republish the app. If you are building a PhoneGap app, make sure to rebuild the PhoneGap app and upload to PhoneGap Build. </description> 
       
    </section>    
       <section>
       <title>Icon Image: </title> 
       <description>The icon image is displayed at the top of the Stripe Checkout component. The recommended minimum size is 128 x 128 px. Supported image types include .gif, .jpeg and .png. </description> 
        <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs3.png</link></figure>
    </section>  
     <section>
         <title>Currency type: </title>
         <description>This specifies the currency of the amount being charged. The code entered here is the 3 letter ISO country code. Stripe offers support for a worldwide range of currencies. You can accept payments in your supported currencies from almost any credit card and debit card no matter where the customer lives. Customers in other countries may be charged additional fees by their bank. </description>
     </section>
       <section>
         <title>Charge description:</title>
         <description>A general description of the product or service being purchased. The JavaScript you enter here can simply return a string (like the example below), return the value contained within a control or return the result of a JavaScript function, defined within the UX component's JavaScript Functions property. </description>
         <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs4.png</link></figure>
     </section>
     <section>
         <title>Charge amount: </title>
         <description>The amount (in cents) that is being charged. The JavaScript you enter here may simply return a number (example: return 1235; for a $12.35 charge), may read the value of a control (make sure you convert to cents!) or may return the result of a JavaScript function, defined within the UX component's JavaScript Functions property. </description>
         <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs5.png</link></figure>
     </section>
     <section>
         <title>OnStripeCheckoutComplete: </title>
         <description>This event fires after Stripe has attempted to process the payment with the token supplied by Stripe Checkout. The JavaScript you enter here can examine the results returned from Stripe by calling the {dialog.object}.getStripeResults() method (see the sample code below). The {dialog.object}.getStripeResults method returns either a Stripe charge object with a wide range of properties or an error. </description>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <description>See [Stripe Charges Doc] for more information. </description>
         <figure><link>images/stripe_ajs6.png</link></figure>
     </section>
       <section>
         <title>HTTPS For Your Site</title>
         <description>All submissions of payment info using Stripe Checkout are made via a secure HTTPS connection. However, in order to protect yourself from certain forms of man-in-the-middle attacks, it is suggested that you serve the page containing the payment form with HTTPS as well. </description>
        
     </section>
     
     
 </sections>   
 <links>
     <link href="https://stripe.com">Stripe Website</link>
     
 </links>
        
</page>