<page>
    <shortlink>data binding existing tables</shortlink>
    <topic>Bind the controls on your UX to fields in one or more existing tables. </topic>
    <description>This page contains two main parts. The first allows you to bind and existing table or tables in a database to the UX component. 
        The second part lets you maps, or "bind", the controls in the UX component to fields in the existing table(s).</description>
   
 <sections>
     
     
     
     
     <section>
         
          <figure><link>images/cs.png</link></figure>
         
     </section>
     <section>
         
         <description>Use this command once you have designed your UX and added controls to it. This command allows you to bind the controls in your UX to fields in one or more tables. The binding information that you specify using this command can then be used in the 'afterDialogValidate' event to save the data that the user submitted to the tables.</description>
     </section>
     
     
     
     <section>
         <title>Specify Tables</title>
         
         
         
     </section>
     <section>
         <title>Bind the Component to an Existing SQL Table</title>
         <steps>
               <step>
                 <description>In the UX Builder open the Data Binding page from the main menu.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs10.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>On the Data Binding page click on the 'Bind the controls on your UX to fields in one or more existing tables'.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs.png</link></figure>
             </step>
             
             <step>
                 <description>Click the 'Specify Tables' button.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs2.png</link></figure>
             </step>
              <step>
                 <description>In the lower left of the 'Select Table(s)' dialog click the 'Table type' dropdown and 
                     select 'SQL'.
                 </description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs3.png</link></figure>
             </step>
             <step>
                 <description>At the bottom of the 'Select Table(s)' dialog click the 'Select' button next to the 
                     SQL connection string textbox control.
                 </description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs4.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>Create a connection string to the Northwind database and click OK.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs5.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>Click the 'Add table' button.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs6.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>Click the 'Select' button.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs7.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>Select a Table from the Northwind database, like the 'Customers' table, and click OK.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs8.png</link></figure>
             </step>
               <step>
                 <description>Add an Alias for the table and click OK.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/cs9.png</link></figure>
             </step>
            
               <step>
                 <description></description>
                 <figure><link>images/cos.png</link></figure>
             </step>
             
         </steps>
          
         
         
     </section>
     
     
     <section>
         <title>Bind UX Controls to the Specified Data Bound Table</title>
         <description>Once a link to an existing data bound table has been defined you can click the button shown below to match controls to fields in that table.</description>
         
         
         <steps>
             <step>
             <description>Continuing from the Specify Tables section. open the UX Controls page.</description>
                 
             </step>

             
             <step>
                 <description>Click the 'Bind UX Component Controls to Table Fields' button.</description>
                 <figure><link>images/controls2.png</link></figure>
             </step>
             
             
         </steps>
         
     </section>
     
     
     
     
 </sections>   
    
    
    
</page>