<page>
    <shortlink>Build a Web App</shortlink>
    <topic>Getting Started With Alpha Anywhere - Build Your First Web App</topic>
    <description>A step-by-step guide to building your first web application using Alpha Anywhere's Flying Start Genie.</description>
    <groups>
        <group background="true">
            <title>Overview</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>In this guide, Building Your First Web Application, you will build a web application with data integration that can be deployed to a website or internal intranet. Staring with a blank Alpha Anywhere workspace, your will use the Flying Start Genie to create an application that can perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on every table in the Northwind database. The application will be composed of a Tabbed UI component and several Grid components. The Tabbed UI component provides the user interface through which you can open the Grid components that are used to view and edit data in the Northwind database.</p>
                        <p>In addition, you will learn how to configure the Development Server and publish web applications to the local webroot.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <alt>The completed web application</alt>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>First Things First - Set Up Your Workspace</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>Before you can start building your web application, you must first setup a new Alpha Anywhere workspace. Your web application will need an AlphaDAO connection that talks with the Northwind database. You will also need to setup the Development Server and a publishing profile so you can publish and test your web application in the local webroot.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 1: Create a new Web Project</title>
                    <description>
                        To create a new web application with Alpha Anywhere, you must create a new workspace. A workspace contains all the files that your application needs, including files such as Grid and Tabbed UI components, javascript libraries, images, HTML pages, .a5w pages, and css style sheets. Let's create a new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>Launch Alpha Anywhere. Under the *[ui:File]* menu, select *[ui:New Workspace...]* to create a new Alpha Anywhere project.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Create a New Workspace from the File menu.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Create a new directory called "HelloAlpha". This directory is where you will save your project.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Create a new directory where your workspace will be saved.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Navigate inside the "HelloAlpha" directory. Type "HelloAlpha" into the *[ui:File name:]* text box. Click the *[ui:Save]* button to create your new workspace.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Naming your workspace.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>When the *[ui:Startup Control Panel]* appears, check the box for *[ui:Open the Web Control Panel when this Workspace is opened.]* You will be creating a web application. The Web Control Panel is where all the resources for a web or mobile application are listed. Click *[ui:OK]* to finish creating your new workspace.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Specifying the Web Control Panel should be opened when the Workspace is opened.</title>
                                <link>images/newWorkspace4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>You can also access the Web Projects Control Panel by clicking on the Web Projects button your Alpha Anywhere workspace.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Web Projects button</title>
                                <link>images/webprojects.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>You have created a new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace. You can now start building your web application.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>A new, blank Alpha Anywhere workspace.</title>
                        <link>images/newWorkspace5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The web application you will be creating will interact with the Northwind database. Alpha Anywhere can communicate with databases using an AlphaDAO connection string. AlphaDAO stands for "Alpha Anywhere Data Access Object". AlphaDAO is an interface through which you access data stored in SQL, noSQL, DBaaS, SaaS, and other data sources, including static JSON and OData (Open Data Protocol) APIs. (See *[extlink:AlphaDAO Overview@http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index/AlphaDAO Overview]* and *[extlink:AlphaDAO Objects@http://documentation.alphasoftware.com/index/AlphaDAO Objects]* for information on using AlphaDAO with xbasic.)</p>
                        <p>You will create an AlphaDAO connection string to communicate with the Northwind database. The Northwind database is a Microsoft Access database that ships with Alpha Anywhere. If desired, the Northwind database can be imported into SQL Server or MySQL. Choose the type of database connection string you wish to create from the list below, and click the link to get started.</p>
                    </description>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <description>[Build an Access Connection String]</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>[Build a SQL Server Connection String]</description>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <description>[Build a MySQL Connection String]</description>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <cases>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build an Access Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guides you through the process of setting up an Access AlphaDAO connection string to the Northwind database. In order to perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the Access Northwind database that ships with Alpha Anywhere, it must be copied from the installation directory to a directory where you have read/write access.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Locate the *[Northwind.mdb]* Access database. It can be found in the installation directory for Alpha Anywhere inside the MDBFiles directory. EG, *[bold:C:\Program Files (x86)\a5v12\MDBFiles\]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The MDBFiles folder in the Alpha Anywhere installation directory is where you can find the Northwind Access database</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring0.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Select the *[Northwind.mdb]* file and copy it to your Users directory. Your Users directory is typically found in *[bold:C:\Users\Your_Windows_UserName]*.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, build a connection string to the Northwind database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel in Alpha Anywhere, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                        <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" in the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to build the connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind Access database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>The Connection Type for your new connection string is "Access". The *[ui:Connection Type]* should be set to "Access" when the Create SQL Connection String dialog opens. If it is not, click the [...] button and select Access from the list of options.</p>
                                    </description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>Click the browse button for the *[ui:File Name]* option and navigate to where you copied the Northwind database. Select the Northwind.mdb file in your Users directory and click *[ui:Open]*.</p>
                                    </description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Select the Northwind database you copied to the Users directory.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind database is correct by clicking the "Test Connection" button. If everything is configured properly, it will display the "Succeeded" message.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The connection string works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <note>On some systems where Office 365 is installed, you may receive a *[Can't Load ODBCJI32.dll Error]* message. To fix this error, you will need to install the Microsoft Access Database Engine. You can download the Microsoft Access Database Engine Installer *[extlink:here@https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=13255]*. If the Microsoft Access Database Engine is already installed, running a 'Repair' on the engine should fix the issue. If this does not solve the issue, follow the instructions for [Build a SQL Server Connection String] or [Build a MySQL Connection String] to create a SQL Server or MySQL version of the Northwind database and connection string.</note>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the Access connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The connection string dialog listing the Northwind connection</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the Northwind connection string and return to the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title></title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring8.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created an Access AlphaDAO connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your web application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing].</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for Access.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring9.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build a SQL Server Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guides you through the process of creating a SQL Server version of the Northwind database and setting up a SQL Server Alpha DAO connection string to communicate with the SQL Server Northwind database.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Follow the tutorial, *[extlink:Importing the Northwind Access Database into SQL Server@http://www.alphasoftware.com/documentation/pages/GettingStarted/GettingStartedTutorials/Basic Tutorials/Northwind/northwindSQLServer.xml]*, to create a Northwind SQL Server database. When you are finished, return to this guide and proceed to the next step.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind SQL Server database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                        <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to build the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind SQL Server database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[SQLServer]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Set the Connection Type to SQLServer.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>
                                        <p>Enter the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]* name, *[ui:Port]*, and *[ui:Credentials]* information for your SQL Server instance.</p>
                                        <p>Server names should be in the form *[server\instanceName]*. If you omit the instance name, the default instance is assumed.</p>
                                        <p>You can click the *[ui:How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?]* link to open the help pop-up (shown below) to find more information on the server name.</p>
                                    </description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Configuration options for SQL Server.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Help popup for "How do I format server names for SQL Server instances?"</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Test the connection by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. You should see a success message. If you receive an error message, verify the *[ui:Version]*, *[ui:Server]*, *[ui:Port]* and *[ui:Credentials]* are correct.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The SQL Server connection works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:Refresh]* button to populate the *[ui:Database]* dropdown box. Select the Northwind SQL Server database you created from the list of options. Click *[ui:OK]* to create the SQL Server connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Configuring SQL Server connection string. This is image shows a configuration for connecting to a SQL Server Express instance. The Northwind database in this SQL Server instance is named "northwindSQLServer".</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created a SQL Server AlphaDAO connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your web application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing].</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for SQL Server.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringSQLServer5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                        <case>
                            <title nested="2">Build a MySQL Connection String</title>
                            <description>This section guides you through creating a MySQL version of the Northwind database and setting up a MySQL AlphaDAO connection string to communicate with the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                            <steps>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Download *[extlink:northwindmysql.zip@http://downloads.alphasoftware.com/a5v12Download/northwindmysql.zip]* and unzip the file. This zip file contains a self-contained file of the MySQL Northwind database called "northwindmysql.sql".</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Contents of the northwindmysql.zip archive.</title>
                                        <link>images/northwindMySQL.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Import the self-contained Northwind database into MySQL. You can find instructions *[extlink:here@https://dev.mysql.com/doc/workbench/en/wb-admin-export-import-management.html#wb-mysql-connections-navigator-management-data-import-restore]* for using MySQL Workbench to Import the database. Use the "Import from Self-Contained File" option for the Data Import.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Doing a Data Import using MySQL Workbench</title>
                                        <link>images/mySQLDataRestore.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <note>*[Backup any existing MySQL databases]* before importing the Northwind database.</note>
                                    <warning>*[There is no schema specified in the northwindmysql.sql file.]* You must specify the *[ui:Default Target Schema]*, otherwise the tables will be imported into the active schema. *[This may result in data being overwritten]* if the active schema contains table names matching tables in the Northwind database!</warning>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Next, create a connection string to the Northwind MySQL database by creating a new AlphaDAO Connection. From the Web Projects Control Panel, select *[ui:[ManageConnStr] Manage Connection Strings]*
                                        <![CDATA[>]]>*[ui:Alpha DAO Connection strings]* from the *[ui:Edit]* menu to create a new connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Open the AlphaDAO Connections dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The AlphaDAO Connections Dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the *[ui:New]* button to create a new connection string. Type in "Northwind" for the *[ui:Connection Name]* and click the *[ui:Build]* button to build the *[ui:Connection String]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Creating a new connection to the Northwind MySQL database.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstring4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click the [...] button to change the *[ui:Connection Type]*. Select *[MySQL]* from the list of options in the *[ui:Select an API]* window and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Set the Connection Type to MySQL.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL1.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Create SQL Connection String dialog Options for a "MySQL" Connection Type.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL7.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Configure the MySQL *[ui:Options]* for the connection. Enter "localhost" in *[ui:Hostname]*.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter the MySQL *[ui:Port]* number. If you used the default port number for your MySQL install, the port should be "3306".</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter the *[ui:User]* for accessing the MySQL database. On your development machine, this can be "root" or a user account you created.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Enter the password for the *[ui:User]* account specified.</description>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Verify the connection to the Northwind database is correct by clicking the *[ui:Test Connection]* button. You should see a success message. If you receive an error message, verify the *[ui:Hostname]*, *[ui:Port]*, *[ui:User]*, and *[ui:Password]* are correct.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Success! The connection string to the MySQL database works.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL3.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Select the MySQL Northwind database you created from the *[ui:Database]* list. If *[ui:Database]* does not have any options, click the *[ui:Refresh]* button. If it still does not list any databases, verify the User you have chosen has access to the MySQL Northwind database.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Configuring the MySQL connection string. The Northwind database in this MySQL instance is named "northwind".</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL2.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to create the MySQL connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the MySQL Connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL4.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the new Northwind connection string.</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>Click OK to save the Northwind connection string.</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL5.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                                <step>
                                    <description>Now that you have created a MySQL AlphaDAO connection string to the Northwind database, you can start building your web application. Click the *[ui:Close]* button to exit the *[ui:Alpha DAO Connections]* dialog and proceed to [Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing].</description>
                                    <figure>
                                        <title>The Northwind AlphaDAO connection string for MySQL</title>
                                        <link>images/connectionstringMySQL6.png</link>
                                    </figure>
                                </step>
                            </steps>
                        </case>
                    </cases>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>You will be using the Flying Start Genie to quickly build an interface for viewing and editing tables in the Northwind database. At the end of the Flying Start Genie, you can choose to publish your web application to the local webroot and launch a web browser to view your web application. In order to publish the components generated by the Flying Start Genie locally, you need to [Configure the Development Server] and [Create a Publishing Profile].</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Configure the Development Server</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Alpha Anywhere Application Development Server enables you to test your web applications on your development machine before deploying them to a web server. The Development Server is required if you want to publish your web application to the local web root. The Development Server is also required if you want to use Alpha Anywhere's Live Preview or Remote Test features to test components in the development environment before publishing to the local webroot or a remote server.</p>
                        <p>Let's configure the Development Server to run locally on your machine.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the Web Projects Control Panel, open the Development Server Settings. They can be accessed under the Web menu. Select "Development Server".</description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/developmentServer1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>The Server Port is the port number that requests to the Alpha Anywhere Server are made. The default value for the Server Port is 80. In a production environment, requests to the Alpha Anywhere Server will be made on port 80. However, in a development environment, port 80 is usually in use by other applications. If you start the development server using port 80, you will see an error message stating port 80 is already in use.</p>
                                <p>Change the Server Port to another port number. Pick a high-number port, such as 8080, for your Server Port setting.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Error message stating that Port 80 is already in use.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the server port to 8080.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:Save]* to save the changes to the Development Server. If the Development Server was already running, click the *[ui:Restart Server]* button for the changes to take effect. If the Development Server is not running, click *[ui:Start Server]* to start the server.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Prompt asking to confirm starting the development server.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>If this is the first time you have started the development server, you will be asked if you wish to create the Document Root "C:\A5Webroot". This directory is where all files are published for local testing. Click *[ui:Yes]* to create the directory.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Message asking to create the C:\A5Webroot directory.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>You will see a confirmation pop-up that the development server settings were saved. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Pop-up confirming that settings were saved.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Windows Firewall may display a Windows Security Alert when the Alpha Anywhere application server starts. Click the *[ui:Allow access]* button to allow Alpha Anywhere to communicate through the firewall. If access is not given to Alpha Anywhere, you may not be able to use some features, such as Remote Testing, on your system.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Windows Security Alert from Windows Firewall asking to allow Alpha Anywhere to communicate over the network.</title>
                                <link>images/developmentServer8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>The development server should be running. Check the *[ui:Server Status]*. The icon should appear green with the words "Running" next to it. Underneath the server status is the *[ui:License State]*. The license state indicates how many simultaneous sessions you can have.</p>
                                <p>Click *[ui:Close]* to close the Development Server Settings and return to the Web Projects Control Panel.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <link>images/developmentServer9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>With the Development Server is configured, the last step is to create a Publishing Profile for your web application.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title nested="2">Create a Publishing Profile</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Publishing Profile describes where web application files will be published, either to the local webroot or on a remote server. During the publishing process, the project files for the web application are compiled and copied to the webroot for the Application Server. This section describes how to configure a project to publish an application to localhost on the development machine. </p>
                        <p>Let's setup a publishing profile that will be used to publish the web project to the local webroot.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>The publishing process to deploy an application to the local Development Server is similar to the process for publishing to *[link:Alpha Anywhere Application Server for IIS@IIS Getting Started Guide]* and Alpha Anywhere Application Server Classic.</note>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>From the *[ui:Web Projects Control Panel]*, open the *[ui:Web]* menu and select *[ui:Project Settings...]* to open the *[ui:Web Project Profiles]* dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Opening Project Settings</title>
                                <link>images/publishingProfile1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select the *[Local Webroot]* profile from the list of profiles listed in the left-hand column. This will display the settings for the Local Webroot publishing profile.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Web Project Properties</title>
                                <link>images/publishingProfile2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>All files published to localhost will be published in the webroot. The webroot is defined in the Alpha Anywhere Development Server settings. Every Alpha Anywhere application you create will be published to the same webroot. To make it easy to disambiguate between projects for testing purposes, you can set the *[ui:Target Folder]* property. The Target Folder is a directory inside the webroot. It's considered best practice to name the Target Folder after your project.</p>
                                <p>Enter "FlyingStartGenie" for the *[ui:Target Folder]* for the Local Webroot profile. Alpha Anywhere will create a directory called "FlyingStartGenie" inside the local webroot when you publish the web application.</p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Define a Target Folder for the Local Webroot publishing profile</title>
                                <link>images/publishingProfile3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to save the changes you made the Local Webroot publishing profile.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The completed publishing profile</title>
                                <link>images/publishingProfile4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>Now that the workspace and Development Server are configured with a connection string and publishing profile, you are ready to start building the web application.</description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Creating the Web Application</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Flying Start Genie is a tool that can help you to build a web application quickly. The Flying Start Genie generates a set of Grid Components for viewing, editing, and searching selected tables from a database. The generated components are placed in a Tabbed UI Component, which can be published immediately after completing the Flying Start Genie. Using the Flying Start Genie is a great way to start building a web application.</p>
                        <p>You will use the Flying Start Genie to generate a Tabbed UI interface for viewing and editing tables in the Northwind database.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <steps>
                        <step>
                            <description>From the *[ui:Web Projects Control panel]*, click the *[ui:[FileNew] New]* toolbar button.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Click [FileNew] New to open the New File dialog</title>
                                <link>images/addNewFile.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Select *[ui:Flying Start Genie]* and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The New File dialog</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie1.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the *[ui:Connect to Database]* tab, set the connection string. Select *[ui:SQL Database]* and click the *[ui:Define Connection String]* to open the Connection String dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Connect to Database page in the Flying Start Genie</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie2.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>
                                <p>Select *[ui:Use a named connection string]*. Click the *[ui:Select...]* button and select the *[Northwind]* connection string. The Flying Start Genie requires a named connection string. If you do not have a named connection string for the Northwind database, see [Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String] to create a named Northwind connection string.</p>
                                <p></p>
                            </description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Connection String dialog</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie3.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click *[ui:OK]* to set the connection string. Click *[ui:Next >]* to move to the next step in the Flying Start Genie.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Connection String is configured. The next step is to select tables from the database.</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie4.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The Flying Start Genie creates Grid Components for a set of tables or views that you pick from the selected database. The *[ui:Select Tables]* lists the available tables and views you can select. The SQL objects listed can be filtered. By default, all tables and views are displayed. Click *[ui:Filter available object types]* to open the Filter Table/View List dialog.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Select Tables page. By default, all tables and views in the database are listed.</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie5.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>In the Filter Table/View List dialog, uncheck the option for "Views". This will remove views from list of options for *[ui:Select Tables]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Filter Table/View List dialog</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie6.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Click the *[ui:[SelectAll]]* Select All button to select all tables in the Northwind database. A Grid Component will be created for each table selected. Click *[ui:Next >]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Select all the tables available on the Select Tables page</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie7.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The *[ui:Global Properties]* page is where you can view and edit the Global Settings for the Flying Start Genie. The Global Settings are the default settings used to generate the Grid Components for the tables you selected on the *[ui:Select Tables]* page. Check the *[ui:Show Global Settings]* box to expose the Global Settings.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Global Properties page</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie8.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Flying Start Genie Global Properties. These properties affect what options and features will be created for the generated Grid components and Tabbed UI.</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie9.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Change the *[ui:Grid name prefix]* in the Grid Part settings to *[Northwind_]*. This will prefix the name of the Grid Components generated for the selected tables with "Northwind_". Click *[ui:Next >]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Changing the Grid name prefix to "Northwind_"</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie10.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>On the *[ui:Finish]* page, you will see a summary of the tables for which the Flying Start Genie will create Grid Components. A Tabbed UI Component will also be created. A button to open each Grid Component will be added to the Tabbed UI Component. There is a checkbox above the table list, *[ui:Publish files to the 'Live Preview' folder and open the Tabbed UI component in your browser?]*. If this box is checked, all files created by the Flying Start Genie will be published to localhost and the web browser will be launched. Make sure the *[ui:Publish files to the 'Live Preview' folder and open the Tabbed UI component in your browser?]* box is checked and click *[ui:Finish]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Finish page for the Flying Start Genie</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie11.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>You will be asked if you want to save the Flying Start Genie settings. Click *[ui:Yes]* to save the settings.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Prompt asking if you would like to save the Flying Start Genie settings to use again in the future</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie12.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Name the Flying Start Genie settings *[Northwind]* and click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>The Flying Start Genie - Saved Settings dialog</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie13.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>A Notice will appear after you save the Flying Start Genie settings. If a large number of tables are selected, generating the Grid and Tabbed UI components can take some time. Click *[ui:OK]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Notice indicating that generating the Grid components may take a while</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie14.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The Wait dialog shows the Flying Start Genie progress. As each Grid Component is created, the progress bar will be updated. When the Flying Start Genie is done creating the Grid and Tabbed UI Components, the Wait dialog will automatically close. Leave this window alone until the Flying Start Genie finishes creating the components.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Progress dialog for the Flying Start Genie</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie15.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>If the Alpha Anywhere Development Server is not running, you will be prompted to start the server. Click *[ui:Yes]* to start the Development Server.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Prompt asking if you would like to start the Development Server</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie16.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>The Development Server will ask you if you want to start the server. Click *[ui:Yes]*.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>Confirmation dialog that you would like to start the Development Server</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie17.png</link>
                            </figure>
                        </step>
                        <step>
                            <description>Next, a small menu will appear asking if you would like to perform a *[ui:Live Preview]* or *[ui:Remote Test]*. Select *[ui:Live Preview]*. This will launch your web browser and load the .a5w page containing the Tabbed UI Component that was created by the Flying Start Genie.</description>
                            <figure>
                                <title>When the Flying Start Genie launches the preview, you can choose to do a Live Preview or a Remote Test</title>
                                <link>images/flyingStartGenie18.png</link>
                            </figure>
                            <note>See [Remote Testing] to learn more about how to do a remote test on another device that is on the same network as your development machine.</note>
                        </step>
                    </steps>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Using the Web Application</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>When the web browser is launched, you will see the Tabbed UI interface generated by the Flying Start Genie.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The generated Tabbed UI interface for the Northwind database using the Flying Start Genie</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>On the left side of the page is the Tabbed UI Buttons Panel. The buttons panel lists buttons that can be clicked to open components or .a5w pages in a new tab. The button's text corresponds to a table in the Northwind database. Clicking a button will open a Grid component that displays data for the table.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Clicking the customers button opens the Grid component for the customers table</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Each Grid component created by the Flying Start Genie has three parts: a Grid listing the records of interest, a Search Part for filtering the records, and a Detail View for viewing and editing records.</p>
                        <p>Records in the Grid can be sorted by clicking on the heading for a column. The records are displayed 10 records at a time. You can navigate between pages of records or change the number of records displayed per page using the navigation toolbar at the bottom of the Grid.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Grid part lists the records in the table</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The value in the first column of the Grid can be clicked to open the Detail View for a record. The Detail View displays all fields for a record. You can view, edit, and delete records using the Detail View. New records can be added by clicking the *[New Record]* link, located next to the navigation toolbar.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Clicking "ANTON" in the Grid opens the Detail View for the ANTON customers record</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal4.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Search Part is hidden by default. To view the Search Part, click *[Click here to search...]* located above the Grid. Click the title *[Search]*, located above the search fields, to hide the Search Part. </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Search Part for the customers Grid component</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal5.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>The available search fields correspond to the columns in the Grid. You can filter the records in the Grid by entering search criteria into the text boxes and clicking the *[ui:Search]* button. You can also reset the filter by clicking the *[ui:Clear Search Criteria]* link.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Typing "Manager" in the Contact Title field will filter the Grid to display only the records with the word "Manager" in the Contact Title field when the search is applied</title>
                        <link>images/webAppFinal6.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Appendix</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Appendix A: Flying Start Genie Videos</title>
                    <description>To learn more about the Flying Start Genie, watch the videos below:</description>
                    <videos>
                        <video>
                            <name>Flying Start Genie Part 1</name>
                            <link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library/?v=2982</link>
                        </video>
                        <video>
                            <name>Flying Start Genie Part 2</name>
                            <link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library/?v=3691</link>
                        </video>
                    </videos>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Appendix B: Helpful Resources</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>In addition to the Alpha Anywhere documentation system, located at *[link:http://documentation.alphasoftware.com]*, there are several other resources you may find useful for finding help or learning new tips and tricks about Alpha Anywhere:</p>
                    </description>
                    <list>
                        <item>
                            <name-title>Where You Should Go</name-title>
                            <description-title>Why You Should Visit</description-title>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Alpha Anywhere Video Library@http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>*[extlink:http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library]*</p>
                                <p>Alpha Anywhere has a vast array of videos covering a variety of topics. Find how-tos, overviews, recordings of webinars and classes, and more.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Alpha Users Forums@http://www.alphasoftware.com/alphaforum/]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>*[extlink:http://www.alphasoftware.com/alphaforum]*</p>
                                <p>The Alpha Forum is a highly active users forum and is an excellent resource for any Alpha Anywhere developer. Collaborate with other Alpha Anywhere developers on problems and show off apps you've built. No question is too simple nor complex.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>*[extlink:Alpha Software Blog@http://www.alphasoftware.com/blog/]*</name>
                            <description>
                                <p>*[extlink:http://www.alphasoftware.com/blog/]*</p>
                                <p>Learn about the latest features and news from Alpha Software. Posts range from what's hot in the market to development tips and announcements of new features in Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                            </description>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <links>
        <link href="/images/$$generic.link.png">ManageConnStr</link>
        <link href="/images/$$file.new.png">FileNew</link>
        <link href="/images/$$navigate.move.last.png">SelectAll</link>
        <link href="images/ellipsesButton.png">...</link>
        <link href="#section1_Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing">Lesson 3: Web Application Publishing</link>
        <link href="#section1_Lesson%202:%20Build%20a%20Database%20Connection%20String">Lesson 2: Build a Database Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20an%20Access%20Connection%20String">Build an Access Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20a%20SQL%20Server%20Connection%20String">Build a SQL Server Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Build%20a%20MySQL%20Connection%20String">Build a MySQL Connection String</link>
        <link href="#section2_Configure%20the%20Development%20Server">Configure the Development Server</link>
        <link href="#section2_Create%20a%20Publishing%20Profile">Create a Publishing Profile</link>
        <link href="/GettingStarted/GettingStartedTutorials/Basic Tutorials/RemoteTest.xml">Remote Testing</link>
    </links>
</page>