<page>
	<shortlink>Grid Builder Code</shortlink>
	<topic>Code</topic>
<description>The Code menu allows you to add Server-side Events, Client-side Events, Xbasic Functions, and Javascript Functions to your grid. You can adapt your code to examine the contents of a grid, properties of a grid, and the data being submitted. You can then take action to modify values or even cancel the submission.  
</description>


<sections>
	<section>
	
<title>Server-side Xbasic Event Code </title>
		<figure><link>images/WPT_Grid_Builder_Events.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
		<section>
	
<title>Client-side Javascript Event Handlers </title>
		<figure><link>images/A_client-sidejs.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
	
<title>The Xbasic Function Window 
</title>
		<figure><link>images/A_XbasicFunc.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
	
<title>The Javascript Function Window 
</title>
		<figure><link>images/A_jsfunctions.png</link></figure>
		
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>Code editing within a grid has become easier and more powerful, both for Xbasic and JavaScript code. 
</description>
	</section>
	<section>
		<description>There are separate, modeless editing panes for Server-side Events, Client-side Events, Xbasic Functions, and JavaScript Functions. All four panes do syntax-coloring and auto-suggest as you type. All four pane have companion tabs for an Interactive Window for the appropriate language, Xbasic or JavaScript, and have links to dialog that help you insert commonly used expressions for the event context. The two Events panes have event selectors, and the Client-side Events pane has a filter for the event 
</description>
		<figure><link>images/client-side_event_page_v11.png</link></figure>
	</section>
		<section>
		<description>Each pane has its own editing toolbar. The Xbasic Functions and Server-side Events toolbars include a Check Syntaxbutton for Xbasic. All four toolbars have buttons for cut, copy, paste, undo, redo, find, replace, indent, outdent, left align, format code, transform code, comment out, and un-comment out.
</description>
		<figure><link>images/xbasic_editing_toolbar_v11.png</link></figure>
	</section>
		
</sections>	
	
	
</page>