<page>
	<topic>Controlling the Font of Static Text
</topic>
<description>You can set the font of static text on a dialog using the {font=} command. After changing the font, the size of a character column changes to the new font's representation of a column.
The syntax of the {font=} command is:
</description>
<sections>
<section>
	
	<example><![CDATA[{font=fontname, fontsize, style}
]]></example>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>Here is the example from Controlling Word Wrap of Static Text with an additional font statement:
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[ui_dlg_box("Disclaimer",<<%dlg%
{wrap=40}
{font=Arial,12,i}
Alpha Anywhere contains a powerful programming language called Xbasic. Xdialog is an extension of Xbasic that allows you to create dialog boxes.;
{font=Arial,10}
<&Agree>  <&Disagree>
%dlg%) ]]></example>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>The above script creates this dialog:  
</description>
	<figure><link>images/XD_Font_syntax_1.gif</link></figure>
</section>	

<section>
	<description>Here is a variation that changes the style of the text: 
</description>
	<example><![CDATA[ui_dlg_box("Disclaimer",<<%dlg%
{wrap=40}
{font=Arial,12,b}
Alpha Anywhere contains a powerful programming language called Xbasic. Xdialog is an extension of Xbasic that allows you to create dialog boxes.;
{font=Arial,10}
<&Agree>  <&Disagree>
%dlg%) ]]></example>
</section>	

<section>
	
	<figure><link>images/XD_Font_syntax_2.gif</link></figure>
	<note>Multiple {font=} commands can be used in a dialog, and the font of any static text on the dialog is controlled by the most recent {font=} command in the script. However, you cannot change the font within a static text object (for example, changing from Arial to Times Roman). If you try to change the font within a static text object, by including a {font=} command within the static text, Alpha Anywhere will actually begin a new static text object when it encounters the next {font=} command. This will not give you the effect that you want. To change the font within a text object, you need to use Rich Text Font (RTF) objects, which we will discuss later.</note>
</section>	
	<section>
		<description>Limitations: Desktop applications only.
</description>
	</section>
	
</sections>	
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Dynamic Text">Dynamic Text</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Rich Text Field Control Syntax">Rich Text Field Control Syntax</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>