<page>
	<topic>Displaying Dynamic Help When Clicking on a Label</topic>
<description>Create 'hot labels' in Xdialog boxes. When the mouse is over the label, the label is underlined, indicating that the label can be clicked. When you click the label, a popup window appears, in which you can define help. Use HTML syntax to create beautifully formatted help. Even use a CSS style sheet to define a consistent look. </description>	
<sections>
<section>
	
	
	<figure><link>images/XD_Hot_Labels_1.gif</link></figure>
	<figure><link>images/XD_Hot_Labels_2.gif</link></figure>
	<figure><link>images/XD_Hot_Labels_3.gif</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<title>Example</title>
<description>dlg_body is an example of a text string that is pre-built for use in the UI_DLG_BOX()command at the bottom of the script.
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[dlg_body = <<%dlg%
{wrap=100}
This example demonstrates how you can create dialog boxes with 'hot' labels. When you click the mouse on a label, a small window pops up offering help to the user on the parameter referenced by the label. This is a convenient alternative to creating a stand-alone help file and hooking the help file into your Xdialog. \(See Lesson 9 - Adding Help to an Xdialog Box);
{lf};
{line=1,0};
{region}
##Suppress blank lines!suppress~~ | (suppress);
##Number of rows!rows~~ | [.20rows];
{lf};
{endregion};
##Click here for help on how this dialog was constructed!howbuilt~~;
{lf};
{line=1,0};
<10&OK!ok> <10&Close!close>;
%dlg% ]]></example>
</section>	

<section>
	
<description>dlg_event is another pre-built string.
</description>	
	<example><![CDATA[dlg_event = <<%code%
if a_dlg_button = "ok" then
    ui_msg_box("","User pressed the OK button.")
    a_dlg_button = ""
end if
%code%
help_howbuilt = <<%a%
<font size="2" face="Tahoma">The 'hot' labels are designated using this syntax:<br>
</font><font size="2" face="Courier New" color="#0000FF">##Label!variable_name~~</font><p>
<font size="2" face="Tahoma">where "<i>Help_variable_name</i>" is a variable in
your script that contains the help text that will be displayed when you click on
the hot label. <br>
<br>
For example, if you define a label like this:<br>
</font><font color="#0000FF"><font size="2" face="Courier New">##</font><font size="2" face="Tahoma">Account
number!accno~~</font></font><font size="2" face="Tahoma"><br>
<br>
then you must include a variable called 'help_accno' in your script that
contains the help text for this label. The string in "help_accno" can be any
HTML text that you want.</font></p>
<font face="Tahoma" size="2">Before the dialog box is displayed, the string that
defines the dialog body is "pre-processed" using the <b>a5_xdialogPreProcess()</b>
function. This function returns a dot variable with two properties, "dlg_body"
and "dlg_event". The "dlg_body" property is used in the ui_dlg_box() function,
and the "dlg_event" property is appended to the event handler for your dialog
box.</font><p><font face="Tahoma" size="2"><br>
</font></p>
</font><p><font face="Tahoma" size="2">Note: The <b>a5_xdialogPreProcess()</b>
function takes these arguments:</font></p>
<font face="Tahoma" size="2">a5_XdialogPreProcess(C dlg_string [,C
<i>default_body_tags</i> ,C <i>style_sheet</i> ])<br>
<br>
The <i>default_body_tags</i> parameter allows you to specify any default parameters,
such as background color, for the window. The <i>style_sheet</i> parameter allows you to
specify a CSS stylesheet that can be referenced by your help text.<br>
%a%
help_suppress = <<%a%
<body bgcolor="#CCFFCC">
<h4>Help on Suppressing Rows</h4>
This property allows you to suppress empty rows if there is not enough data to fill all rows in the grid.<br><br>
Notice that in defining the help text for this label, we have overwridden the default background color for the window by supplying a "BODY" tag.
You can use any HTML syntax that you want in the help text.
%a%
help_rows = <<%a%
Specify the number of rows to show in the grid.
%a%
x = a5_xdialogPreProcess(dlg_body)
dlg_body = x.dlg_body
dlg_event = x.dlg_event + dlg_event
ui_dlg_box("Hot Labels", dlg_body, dlg_event) ]]></example>
</section>	
	<section>
		<description>Limitations:
Desktop applications only.
</description>
	</section>
</sections>	
	<see>
		
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Displaying Time Variables">Displaying Time Variables</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Miscellaneous Examples">Miscellaneous Examples</ref>
	</see>
	
</page>