<page>
	<shortlink>server Installing an SSL Server Certificate</shortlink>
	<topic>Installing an SSL Server Certificate</topic>
	<description>When you receive the SSL Server Certificate:</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Ensure that your Certificate Authority (CA) provided the certificate in the standard X.509 format. If your CA does not list the specific certificate format, but instead lists the servers with which the certificate is compatible, choose an Apache compatible certificate.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Open a new document in a text editor and paste the certificate text.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Save the new document as ASCII text with any name you would like, although the standard convention is to use a file extension of .CRT or .CER.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Once you have saved this file, open the Application Server Control Panel.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Display the SSL Tab.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the path and name of the certificate file (that you just created) in the SSL Certificate File text box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Specify the matching key file in the Private Key File text box.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Whether or not you need to specify a password (in the Private Key Password text box) depends on if you assigned one when you generated the key file.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Your Certification Authority will also tell you if you need to specify a certificate chain file in the Certificate Chain File text box.</description>
				</step>
			</steps>
		</section>
		<section>
			<description>Below are links to the documentation for common Certification Authorities.</description>
			<list bullet="true">
				<item>
					<name>[Thawte]</name>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>[GoDaddy]</name>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>[GeoTrust/QuickSSL]</name>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>[Entrust]</name>
				</item>
				<item>
					<name>[Comodo/InstantSSL]</name>
				</item>
			</list>
		</section>
	</sections>
	<links>
		<link href="https://www.thawte.com/resources/getting-started/get-started-with-ssl/">Thawte</link>
		<link href="https://www.godaddy.com/help/ssl-certificates-1000006">GoDaddy</link>
		<link href="https://www.geotrust.com/support/ssl-validation-process">GeoTrust</link>
		<link href="http://www.entrust.net/ssl-technical/webserver.cfm">Entrust</link>
		<link href="https://www.instantssl.com/ssl-certificate-support/cert_installation/ssl-certificate-index.html">Comodo/InstantSSL</link>
	</links>
	<see>
		<ref link="alpha anywhere standard application server settings">Configuring the Classic Application Server</ref>
	</see>
</page>