<page>
   <topic>STRWORDITRAN Function</topic>
      <description>Replaces each occurrence of a word with another - compare is case insensitive.</description>

   <syntax>Output_String as C = STRWORDITRAN(C character,C substring,[C replacement,[N start_pos,[N occurrences[,N every]]]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     
     <argument>
         <name>character</name>
         <description>A character string.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>substring</name>
         <description>The word to find in the character string.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>replacement</name>
         <description>Default = "" (NULL). The word that replaces the substring. Optional.</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>start_pos</name>
         <description>Default = 1. Specifies which (and subsequent) occurrences will be replaced. A value N for the optional start_pos begins the replacement at the N th occurrence of substring. Numeric</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>occurrences</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = All. Specifies the maximum number of occurrences of substring to replace with replacement.
Numeric</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>every</name>
         <description>Numeric</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <discussion>
Looks for a substring in a character string, and replaces every occurrence of it with a replacement.  If replacement is omitted, substring is replaced with NULL characters. A value N for the optional start_pos begins the replacement at the N th occurrence of Word. A value for the optional Occurrences specifies the maximum number of occurrences of Word to be replaced.  STRWORDITRAN()  is case insensitive.
Note : You can use STRWORDTRAN() with memo fields.
   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
strworditran("partnership is the most important part of part of a successful relationship", "part", "element") -> "partnership is the most important element of element of a successful relationship"
STRTRAN("partnership is the most important part of part of a successful relationship", "part", "element") -> "elementnership is the most important element of element of a successful relationship"
strworditran("She sells sea shell on the sea shore","sea","ocean", 2, 1) -> "She sells sea shell on the ocean shore"
]]></example>
   
   <see>
      <ref href="/documentation/index?search=Character Replacement Functions">Character Replacement Functions</ref>
   </see>
<terms>string,replacement,case,defaults,function,memo,number</terms>
</page>