<page>
	<topic>Security Setting Server cache lifetime</topic>
<sections>
<section>
	<description>The web security settings and permissions are cached on the server for improved speed and are not automatically updated when the new settings are published.
</description>
	<figure><link>images/security cache lifetime.png</link></figure>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere uses a server cache to hold security settings for an application.
The cache is cleared when the application server is started and restarted.
The security settings for an application are loaded into the cache when the first request is made for the application.
The security cache on the local application server running in the current Alpha Anywhere instance is cleared when anything is published to Local Webroot. Therefore any changes to the settings will be reflected in the next request to the local server after publishing any file from the project.
If revised security settings are published to a remote server, the remote server cache is NOT cleared after publish. Therefore any changes made to security settings are NOT applied until the cache is reloaded.

The cache lifetime (in seconds) determines how often the server will check for updates to the security files. A value of 300 (the default) will allow the server to check for new published settings or values every 5 minutes. If new security files were published and the cache lifetime has not expired, they will not be applied until the next time scheduled for an update check.

Set the value to a few seconds if publishing to a remote server and the new values should be loaded as soon as possible. This may cause a slight speed impact and should only be done for testing.
Set the value to 0 to never check for updates. This would be a recommended value for a production server where security updates are rare. If a change is published, stopping and restarting the server will clear the cache and force a reload of security settings.

</description>
</section>
	
	
</sections>	
	
</page>