<page>
    <topic>How to use a Single Web Security User Database for Multiple Applications</topic>
    <description>Multiple Alpha Anywhere applications can reference the same user database for login and security. Using Groups, you can restrict user access to specific applications.</description>
    <groups>
        <group>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>Multiple Alpha Anywhere applications can reference the same web security tables in the web security configuration. This is different from creating a [multi-tenant application], wherein separate user databases or additional information is added to a users' table to identify data in a database that belongs to the logged-in user. If web security data is stored in a SQL database, the security information can be referenced by each web application. To restrict access to specific applications for specific users, security groups can be used to determine whether or not a user has permission to access an application. Creating a group for each application for which you want to restrict user access.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Configuring Security Setup for Multiple Apps</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Configuring Web Security to Reference a Single Web Users Database</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you are using the Alpha Anywhere Web Application Server, you can configure the security settings for each app to reference the same web users security database. The user data must be stored in a SQL Database. Mutliple applications cannot reference the same web security data if it is stored in DBF tables. (See [] to learn how </p>
                        <p>When configuring security for your web application, the security profile must be identical in all applications that will reference the same user data. If the profiles differ between apps, the login verification process will fail.</p>
                        <p></p>
                        <p>Password encryption settings must be identical in all applications. If encryption is enabled in one app, it must be enabled in all apps. Additionally, the password encryption key must also be identical in all apps that reference the same web user database.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Password encryption settings must be identical in all apps that reference the same user database.</title>
                        <link>images/userIDAndPasswordOptions.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Configuring an IIS Profile to Reference a Single Web Users Database</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If you are using IIS, your IIS publishing profile can be configured to allow mutliple apps to reference the same web users security database.</p>
                        <p>Accessing the same web user data across multiple apps is controlled through the publishing profile for each application under IIS. The membership and role provider settings must point to the same database and use the same value for the "Security application name" in the Publishing Profile.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Configuring an IIS Publishing Profile</title>
                        <link>images/iisPublishingProfile.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Using Groups to Restirct Users Access to Specific Apps</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>Groups can be used to define access privileges for each application. This requires one group or role per app that references the same user security tables.</description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    <see>
        <ref>Web Application Security Guide</ref>
        <ref>Sharing web security between projects</ref>
        <ref>Building Multi-Tenant Applications - Dynamic Connection Strings</ref>
    </see>
    <links>
        <link href="Building Multi-Tenant Applications - Dynamic Connection Strings">multi-tenant application</link>
    </links>
</page>