<page build="7902" api="js" generated="true">
	<shortlink>api client api a5 chart definition dimension number object</shortlink>
	<topic parent="A5.chart" parentType="namespace" elementName="Definition Dimension Number Object" >A5.chart.Definition Dimension Number Object</topic>
	<description> Definition of a number dimension.</description>
	<properties>
		<property>
			<name>as</name>
			<type>string</type>
			<description>To create a number dimension the value must be "number".</description>
		</property>
		<property>
			<name>src</name>
			<types><type>string</type><type>array</type><type>object</type><type>function</type></types>
			<description>Where the data for the dimension comes from. Can be a string with property name in the data the dimension is from. An array of property names if the dimension comes from multiple properties in the data. An object where each property name in the object will contain the value of the property name in the data. A function that gets the data and "temp" object and must return the value for the given data.</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>select</name>
			<types><type>string</type><type>boolean</type></types>
			<description>Defines the value to use if more then one value is gathered for a single data point. Values can be "last" (the default), "first", "min", "max", "sum", "avg" or a value of false, which will leave the values as an array.</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>base</name>
			<type>number</type>
			<description>The base of the number dimension. The default is "0".</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>stack</name>
			<types><type>boolean</type><type>string</type></types>
			<description>Whether or not the numeric value is stacked (dependant on an alternate dimension being discrete). Values can be false (the default), true, "percent", "percent-abs" or "percent-range" (100% to -100%).</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>discrete</name>
			<types><type>boolean</type><type>string</type><type>function(value,data,temp)</type></types>
			<description>If true then each number will be considered as a discrete value (e.g. a string). A value of "separate" will plot the dimension as discrete but separate values. A function can be used to do a custom conversion of the value. If a string is passed in then it will be used as the format to pass to the *[link:Number.toFormat]* method.</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>constrained</name>
			<type>boolean</type>
			<description>If the dimension is discrete and is not one of the explicitly constrained dimensions ("x", "y", "angle" and "distance"), then the dimension can be set to constrain the other dimensions. This will mean the continuous dimension with duplicate values from this dimension will be collected into a single point.</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>values</name>
			<type>array</type>
			<description>If the dimension is discrete an array of the discrete values for the dimension. Additional values that are found will be append to the end. This allows for explicit values to always appear on an dimension even if they are not found in the data.</description>
		</property>
		<property optional="true" >
			<name>sort</name>
			<types><type>boolean</type><type>function(valueA,valueB)</type></types>
			<description>If the dimension is discrete and needs to be sorted a boolean of true will sort them alphabetically, or a function may be passed in to do a custom sort.</description>
		</property>
	</properties>
	<!--list:.-->
	<annotations>/Ref/Client_Api/A5/chart_namespace/Definition Dimension Number_object/index.xml</annotations>
</page>
