<page>
    <topic>Action Javascript for the UX</topic>
    <description>Action Javascript adds functionality to your app by defining behaviors using property sheets. The code required to perform the actions is generated for you. These articles cover a wide variety of Action Javascripts available in the UX Component.</description>

    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>UX Actions</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Action</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Absolute Layout Container - Create PDF]</name>
                    <description>Create a PDF file from the contents of an Absolute Layout container.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Add Alternative Login to Current User]</name>
                    <description>Add account credentials for an alternative login provider such as Google.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition]</name>
                    <description>Export data to Excel, Word, HTML or Ascii using a Report Definition</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Ajax Callback]</name>
                    <description>Define a user-defined ajax callback. The callback can be handled by an Xbasic function that is defined in the component, by a separate .a5w page, or by another page (.e.g., .php, .asp, etc.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Ajax Callback - Cross Domain]</name>
                    <description>Define a user-defined cross-domain ajax callback.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Chart Control Actions]</name>
                    <description>Perform some action on a Chart control (e.g. refresh the chart, export to PDF, etc.).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[City, State Lookup from Zip Code]</name>
                    <description>For a given zip code, lookup the city and state on the USPS web site and fill in the city and state in the current record.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Clear a Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component]</name>
                    <description>For use in conjunction with the 'Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX' action. Clears the search form in the UX and removes the filter from the embedded Grid.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Client-side Data Cache Actions]</name>
                    <description>Perform some action on an item in the Client-side Data Cache (e.g. read the data, refresh the data, etc.).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Delete Alternative Login for Current User]</name>
                    <description>Delete account credentials for an alternative login provider such as Google.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Delete Record]</name>
                    <description>Deletes a record from the Primary Table in a Data Bound UX component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Dial Telephone Open SMS client]</name>
                    <description>Dial a telephone number or open the SMS client application to send a SMS message.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Display a 'Wait...' message]</name>
                    <description>Display a 'wait...' message when an javascript event happens. The message can include customized text, different display times, as well as custom animations and images.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Editor Actions]</name>
                    <description>Perform some action on an Editor in an Editor set.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Enable or Disable a Button]</name>
                    <description>Set a button's state to either enabled, or disabled.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Fade Out Message]</name>
                    <description>The Fade Out Message action displays a message on the screen for a short period of time. The message fades away after a specified duration.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[File Download]</name>
                    <description>Download a file from the server to the user's machine.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[File Upload]</name>
                    <description>Upload a file to the server and store a reference to the file in a Grid field, or embed the file in a Drid field.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere Server]</name>
                    <description>Upload one or more files to Amazon S3 or to the Alpha Anywhere server.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[File Upload - User Defined]</name>
                    <description>Upload one or more files to the server. A server-side event then gets called to allow you to process the uploaded files.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Filter Records in a List Control]</name>
                    <description>Create a highly customized 'Search Part' to filter the records shown in a List control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Form View Control Actions]</name>
                    <description>Perform some action on a Form View control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Geocode an address]</name>
                    <description>Makes an Ajax callback to a web service to geocode an address. Fill in the latitude and longitude fields in the current record with the information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Geolocation Functions]</name>
                    <description>Get geolocation information from the browser and store information in the current Grid/UX component object (e.g. if you are in a Grid, the data is stored in the {grid.object}.geoLocation object). (Requires an HTML5 browser).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Get Primary Key values for Records in Query]</name>
                    <description>Execute a query and then retrieve the primary key values for the parent table of a Data Bound UX component. (IMPORTANT: This action is intended for an event on a UX component).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Google Map Method (UX Component)]</name>
                    <description>Call a method to perform some action on a Google Map. Actions that you can perform include: Clearing markers, opening or closing an info box, adding a marker to the map, centering the map on an address, setting the map zoom factor.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Hide/Close a window]</name>
                    <description>Close a pop-up Window.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Hide/Close Container Window]</name>
                    <description>Hide (i.e. closes) a Container Window.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Hide/Close PanelOverlay Window]</name>
                    <description>Hides (i.e. closes) a PanelOverlay window. You can optionally animate the window as hidden.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library]</name>
                    <description>This action is used exclusively for image fields in a List Detail View. Capture an image using the camera, or from the photo library. 
               On devices that don't support a camera, select an image from the filesystem.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Image Capture - Camera/Photo Library]</name>
                    <description>Capture an image using the camera, or from the photo library. On devices that don't support a camera, select an image from the filesystem. 
               Action calls a function with the Image URI when the image has been obtained.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Image Delete]</name>
                    <description>Delete an image from an image field.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Image Upload]</name>
                    <description>Upload an image file to the server.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Inline-Javascript]</name>
                    <description>Allows developer to enter javascript code. Unlike most other actions there are no properties to check for the Inline-Javascript action, just the code you want to fire.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Link a Grid that has been embedded into a UX component]</name>
                    <description>Unlike the 'Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX' action which applies a filter to an embedded Grid, this action Links the embedded Grid.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[List Control Actions]</name>
                    <description>Perform some action on a List control (e.g. refresh the List, etc) in a UX Component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Lock/unlock a container, DIV or entire page (by showing an overlay over it)]</name>
                    <description>Lock a container, DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it so that the user can't click on the controls under the overlay, or unlock the element.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Login with Alternative Login Provider]</name>
                    <description>Login using account credentials from an alternative login provider such as Google.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Lookup and Fill-in Fields]
                    </name>
                    <description>Lookup values in a table and fill-in fields in the current row from fields in the Lookup Table.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Menus]
                    </name>
                    <description>Display a dropdown menu.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Merge data into client-side template]
                    </name>
                    <description>Merge Javascript into a client-side template and set the inner HTML to the result.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Message box]
                    </name>
                    <description>Displays a Javascript alert box on the screen.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [New Record]
                    </name>
                    <description>Displays a new record.</description>
                </item>

                <item>
                    <name>[Open a AppLauncher component]</name>
                    <description>Open a AppLauncher component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>

                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Calendar component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a Calendar component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Custom component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a Custom component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Google Map component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a Google Map component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Grid component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Opens a grid component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page. This requires first defining a grid component.</description>



                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Help Window]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a window to display a help topic from the Help Table.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a ImageGallery component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a ImageGallery component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
             [Open a Page Layout component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a Page Layout component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a generic, pop-up window (often called an overlay). The window can be modal, or modeless, and can be populated by making an Ajax callback.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Report, Label or Letter layout]
                    </name>
                    <description>Displays a report, label or letter layout as a PDF file using the Acrobat PDF reader. The report is displayed in either a pop-up window or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page, to edit the record currently being edited in the Grid or UX component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a UX component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Opens an UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page. (Only new Ajax components can be opened. Old dialogs built in V10 and earlier are not supported.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open an UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page, to edit the current row in a Grid component or to enter a new record. (Only new Ajax Components can be opened. Old Dialogs in V10 and earlier are not supported.)

                    </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in List Control in a UX, or add a new Record to a List Control in a UX]</name>
                    <description>Open a UX component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page, to edit the current page, to edit the current row in a List control in a UX component or to enter a new record into a List. (Applies only to Lists based on SQL or DBF data sources).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open a Video Player component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open a Video Player component in a pop-up window, or in a DIV on the current page.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV]
                    </name>
                    <description>Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Panel Actions]
                    </name>
                    <description>Perform some action on a Panel (e.g. setting focus to the next or previous Panel, or to a particular named panel).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PDF from HTML]</name>
                    <description>Get the HTML inside a container and convert to PDF.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PhoneGap - File Download]</name>
                    <description>Download one or more files and store the files in the filesystem on the mobile device. Uses the PhoneGap FileTransfer feature. (Only applies to UX components running in a PhoneGap shell.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PhoneGap - File System Actions]</name>
                    <description>Performs actions with the mobile device file system such as creating, reading, deleting file, creating directories, etc.(Only applies to UX components running in a PhoneGap shell.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PhoneGap - File System Actions (File URI Based)]</name>
                    <description>Performs actions with the mobile device file system such as creating, reading, deleting file, creating directories, deleteing directories, etc. (Only applies to UX components running in a PhoneGap shell.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PhoneGap - File Upload]</name>
                    <description>Upload one or more files to either the Alpha Anywhere server or to the Amazon S3 using the PhoneGap File Transfer feature. (Only applies to UX components running in a PhoneGap shell.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[PhoneGap - Notifications]</name>
                    <description>Display or initiate a native notification (for example, beep, native alert/prompt/confirmation, vibrate, etc.)</description>
                </item>


                <item>
                    <name>
            [PhoneGap - Send SMS message]
                    </name>
                    <description>Send a SMS message.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [PhoneGap - SQLite Actions]
                    </name>
                    <description>Performs actions with the SQLite database on the device. Also allows you to download a SQLite database from the server to the mobile device and create a SQLite database on the server and download it to the device.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Populate Controls in a UX Component with data from Tables]
                    </name>
                    <description>Populate the controls in a UX component with the data from Tables. (IMPORTANT: This action is intended for an event on a UX component).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Populate controls in an UNBOUND UX component with data from a table]
                    </name>
                    <description>Populates controls in a UX component with data from a table. Use this action (rather than the 'Populate Controls in a UX Component with data from Tables' action) if the UX component has not been bound to a database (see the 'Data Binding' pane in the builder).</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Refresh/synchronize embedded UX component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Updates the argument values in the child UX component and refreshes the data shown in List controls and other controls that are based on data Series. Also causes the embedded UX component's 'onSynchronizeDialog' (client-side) and 'onSynchronize' (server-side) events to fire.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Run a report that is embedded in a UXcomponent using a custom filter for the report]
                    </name>
                    <description>Create a highly customized 'Search Part' for a Report. Allows you to submit a UX component that contains 'search' fields to compute a filter expression and then run the report using the computed filter expression.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Run Action]
                    </name>
                    <description>The Run Action runs an action that was defined using Javascript.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component]
                    </name>
                    <description>Create a highly customized 'Search Part' for a Grid. Allows you to submit a UX component that contains 'search' fields to compute a filter expression and then filter a Grid component that has been embedded into the UX component.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Send email]
                    </name>
                    <description>This javascript action sends an email.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Show PanelOverlay Window]
                    </name>
                    <description>Show a PanelOverlay window. You can optionally animate the window as it is shown.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Stripe - Process Stripe Payment]
                    </name>
                    <description>Process payment using Stripe. See also the [Stripe Genie...].</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation]
                    </name>
                    <description>Adds toggle animation to a DIV or container. When the action is run the dive or container will be shown or hidden using a specified animation such as 'slide' or 'puff'. Different animations can be specified for the show and hide events.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Update, Insert or Delete data. (for use with an UNBOUND component)]
                    </name>
                    <description>Updates, inserts or deletes a record in a table using data submitted from a control on a UX component. The UX component need not have been 'Data Bound' in order to use this action. </description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Video Player Control Actions]
                    </name>
                    <description>Perform some type of action on a video player control.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [ViewBox Control Actions]
                    </name>
                    <description>Perform some action on a ViewBox control (e.g. refresh the ViewBox, etc.)</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Web-sockets Server Actions]
                    </name>
                    <description>Performs an action on the web-socket server, such as 'Send a message to the web-sockets server'. The message will be received by all UX and Grid components that are listening for web-socket messages and the 'webSocketOnMessage client-side event in all listening components will fire.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>
            [Zip Code Lookup from Address]
                    </name>
                    <description>For a given address, lookup the Zip code on the USPS web site and fill in the current record.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>About the Filter list in Action Javascript</title>
            <description>The Define Javascript Action dialog has a filter control to allow you to easily filter the list of actions. This is useful because some developers now have a large number of Javascript Actions defined in their components.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/javascriptactioneditor.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section build="5221">
            <title>Try/Catch Blocks</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can wrap individual actions or the entire event in a JavaScript try/catch block. A try/catch block is used to capture unexpected errors in JavaScript code. It is similar to Xbasic's [ON ERROR GOTO] construct.</p>
                <p>To wrap an action in a try/catch block, right-click on the action and select the Wrap action in try/catch block command. This will open an editor where you can define the code to run in the catch block. If an action is configured to use a try/catch block, the menu item will be checked.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/trycatch1.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>An event can include multiple actions. You can wrap the entire event in a try/catch block by checking the *[ui:Wrap all actions in a try/catch block]* checkbox at the bottom of the dialog.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/trycatch2.jpg</link>
            </figure>
            <note>See *[extlink:MDN's documentation on 'try...catch'@https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/JavaScript/Reference/Statements/try...catch]* to learn more about JavaScript try/catch blocks.</note>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="Using the Stripe API From Xbasic">Stripe Genie...</link>
        <link link="Absolute Layout Container - Create PDF">Absolute Layout Container - Create PDF</link>
        <link link="Add Alternative Login to Current User">Add Alternative Login to Current User</link>
        <link link="Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition">Advanced Export to Excel, Word, HTML, or Ascii using a Report Definition</link>
        <link link="Ajax Callback">Ajax Callback</link>
        <link link="Ajax Callback - Cross Domain">Ajax Callback - Cross Domain</link>
        <link link="Chart Control Actions">Chart Control Actions</link>
        <link link="City, State Lookup from Zip Code">City, State Lookup from Zip Code</link>
        <link link="Clear a Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component">Clear a Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component</link>
        <link link="Client-side Data Cache Actions">Client-side Data Cache Actions</link>
        <link link="Delete Alternative Login for Current User">Delete Alternative Login for Current User</link>
        <link link="Delete Record">Delete Record</link>
        <link link="Dial Telephone Open SMS client">Dial Telephone Open SMS client</link>
        <link link="Display a 'Wait...' message">Display a 'Wait...' message</link>
        <link link="Editor Actions">Editor Actions</link>
        <link link="Enable or Disable a Button">Enable or Disable a Button</link>
        <link link="Fade Out Message">Fade Out Message</link>
        <link link="File Download">File Download</link>
        <link link="File Upload">File Upload</link>
        <link link="File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere Server">File Upload - Amazon S3 Storage or Alpha Anywhere Server</link>
        <link link="File Upload - User Defined">File Upload - User Defined</link>
        <link link="Filter Records in a List Control">Filter Records in a List Control</link>
        <link link="Form View Control Actions">Form View Control Actions</link>
        <link link="Geocode an address">Geocode an address</link>
        <link link="Geolocation Functions">Geolocation Functions</link>
        <link link="Get Primary Key values for Records in Query">Get Primary Key values for Records in Query</link>
        <link link="Google Map Method UX Component">Google Map Method (UX Component)</link>
        <link link="Hide a 'Wait...' message">Hide a 'Wait...' message</link>
        <link link="Hide/Close a window">Hide/Close a window</link>
        <link link="Hide/Close Container Window">Hide/Close Container Window</link>
        <link link="Hide/Close PanelOverlay Window">Hide/Close PanelOverlay Window</link>
        <link link="Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library">Image Capture for List-Detail View - Camera/Photo Library</link>
        <link link="Image Capture - Camera/Photo Library">Image Capture - Camera/Photo Library</link>
        <link link="Image Delete">Image Delete</link>
        <link link="Image Upload">Image Upload</link>
        <link link="Inline-Javascript">Inline-Javascript</link>
        <link link="Link a Grid that has been embedded into a UX component">Link a Grid that has been embedded into a UX component</link>
        <link link="List Control Actions">List Control Actions</link>
        <link link="Lock unlock a container DIV or entire page by showing an overlay over it">Lock/unlock a container, DIV or entire page (by showing an overlay over it)</link>
        <link link="Login with Alternative Login Provider">Login with Alternative Login Provider</link>
        <link link="Lookup and Fill-in Fields">Lookup and Fill-in Fields</link>
        <link link="Menus">Menus</link>
        <link link="Merge data into client-side template">Merge data into client-side template</link>
        <link link="Message box">Message box</link>
        <link link="New Record">New Record</link>
        <link link="Open a AppLauncher component">Open a AppLauncher component</link>
        <link link="Open a Calendar component">Open a Calendar component</link>
        <link link="Open a Custom component">Open a Custom component</link>
        <link link="Open a Google Map component">Open a Google Map component</link>
        <link link="Open a Grid component">Open a Grid component</link>
        <link link="Open a Help Window">Open a Help Window</link>
        <link link="Open a ImageGallery component">Open a ImageGallery component</link>
        <link link="Open a Page Layout component">Open a Page Layout component</link>
        <link link="Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay">Open a Pop-up Ajax Window/Overlay</link>
        <link link="Open a Report Label or Letter layout">Open a Report, Label or Letter layout</link>
        <link link="Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record">Open a UX as an alternate editing view for current record</link>
        <link link="Open a UX component">Open a UX component</link>
        <link link="Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record">Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in Grid, or add a new Record</link>
        <link link="Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in List Control in a UX, or add a new Record to a List Control in a UX">Open a UX component to Edit Current Record in List Control in a UX, or add a new Record to a List Control in a UX</link>
        <link link="Open a Video Player component">Open a Video Player component</link>
        <link link="Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV">Open an .a5w page, static HTML page, URL, or PDF document, in a pop-up window or a DIV</link>
        <link link="Panel Actions">Panel Actions</link>
        <link link="PDF from HTML">PDF from HTML</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - File Download">PhoneGap - File Download</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - File System Actions">PhoneGap - File System Actions</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap File System Actions File URI Based">PhoneGap - File System Actions (File URI Based)</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - File Upload">PhoneGap - File Upload</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - Notifications">PhoneGap - Notifications</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - Send SMS message">PhoneGap - Send SMS message</link>
        <link link="PhoneGap - SQLite Actions">PhoneGap - SQLite Actions</link>
        <link link="Populate Controls in a UX Component with data from Tables">Populate Controls in a UX Component with data from Tables</link>
        <link link="Populate controls in an UNBOUND UX component with data from a table">Populate controls in an UNBOUND UX component with data from a table</link>
        <link link="Refresh/synchronize embedded UX component">Refresh/synchronize embedded UX component</link>
        <link link="Run a report that is embedded in a UX component using a custom filter for the report">Run a report that is embedded in a UXcomponent using a custom filter for the report</link>
        <link link="Run Action">Run Action</link>
        <link link="Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component">Search a Grid Component that is Embedded into a UX component</link>
        <link link="Send email">Send email</link>
        <link link="Show Container Window">Show Container Window</link>
        <link link="Show PanelOverlay Window">Show PanelOverlay Window</link>
        <link link="Stripe - Process Stripe Payment">Stripe - Process Stripe Payment</link>
        <link link="Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation">Toggle display of a container or DIV with animation</link>
        <link link="Update Insert or Delete data for use with an UNBOUND component">Update, Insert or Delete data. (for use with an UNBOUND component)</link>
        <link link="Video Player Control Actions">Video Player Control Actions</link>
        <link link="ViewBox Control Actions">ViewBox Control Actions</link>
        <link link="Web-sockets Server Actions">Web-sockets Server Actions</link>
        <link link="Zip Code Lookup from Address">Zip Code Lookup from Address</link>
        <link link="xbasic on error goto">ON ERROR GOTO</link>
    </links>
</page>