<page>
    <shortlink>tffr256</shortlink>
    <topic>TFFR-256: Change Status Button - Upload One Option Hangs</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Under a specific scenario, the filler app hangs when choosing the Upload One option after using the Change Status button to change the status for a form to one the user is not allowed to view.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>If the user does not have permission to view forms with a specific status, selecting the "Upload One" option after using a Change Status button to set the form's status to one of the statues the user cannot view can cause the filler app to hang.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <title>Permissions for User role configured to not allow user to List (i.e. view) forms with a Submitted status</title>
                <alt>Permissions for User role configured to not allow user to List (i.e. view) forms with a Submitted status</alt>
                <link>images/tffr256.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The filler app hang occurs when:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>The form is new and has never been synchronized.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The form's status is changed using a Change Status button to a status the user is not allowed to view in the filler app.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>The User selects "Upload One" when prompted.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Workaround</title>
            <description>
                <p>You can work around this issue by uploading the form using the following methods:</p>
                <p>
                    <list bullet="true">
                        <item>
                            <name>Choose *[Upload All]* after changing the status using the Change Status button.</name>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <name>Change the form's status using the hamburger menu option. Then, upload all changes using *[Upload Changes]* from the main form list.</name>
                        </item>
                    </list>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>You can also work around this issue by changing the User permissions to allow them to view forms with the status set when using the Change Status button. Note users will be able to see all forms in the filler app with said status, which may not be desired.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>