<page api="js" build="4902">
    <shortlink>ux component instantupdatecheckforupdate method</shortlink>
    <topic parent="{dialog.object}" parentType="object" elementName="instantUpdateCheckForUpdate Method">{dialog.object}.instantUpdateCheckForUpdate Method</topic>
    <description>
        <p>Checks for updates for a PhoneGap app with Instant Update.</p>
    </description>
    <prototypes>
        <prototype>{dialog.object}.instantUpdateCheckForUpdate(successCallback, errorCallback);</prototype>
    </prototypes>
    <arguments>
        <argument>
            <name>successCallback</name>
            <type>function</type>
            <description>The JavaScript function to call if an update is available. This function will be passed an object that includes a result property that indicates whether or not an update is available.</description>
        </argument>
        <argument>
            <name>errorCallback</name>
            <type>function</type>
            <description>The JavaScript function to call if an error occurs while checking for updates. This function will be passed an error object or string depending on the error.</description>
        </argument>
    </arguments>
    <discussion>
        <p>This method allows you check if an update is available in a PhoneGap application that was build with the Instant Update feature enabled. Since this is an asynchronous operation, you need to provide the JavaScript success and the error callback functions.</p>
        <p> If a result is returned within a 5 second time-frame, the *[js:successCallback]* is called and passed an object with a result property that will be either true or false. If true, an update is available. If a timeout or any other error occurs the *[js:errorCallback]* is passed an error object or a string, depending on the error.</p>
        <p> This method can be useful if you have turned off auto updates and want to programmatically check if an update is available.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var _successCallbackFunction = function(e) { 
    if(!e.result) { 
        //there is no update available
        alert('You are running the latest version');
        return false;
    }
    
    A5.msgBox.show('Notice','<div style="height: 1in; padding: 15pt;">An update for this application is available. 
    Click OK to install the update.</div>',
    [{name: 'ok', html: 'OK', value: 'ok'}],
    function(button) {if(button == 'ok') {
        setTimeout(function() {
            {dialog.object}.instantUpdateRefresh() //install the update
        }, 10)
    }
    });
    
}

var _errorCallbackFunction = function() { 
    alert('Could not determine if an update is available.');
}

{dialog.object}.instantUpdateCheckForUpdate(_successCallbackFunction, _errorCallbackFunction);]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <limitations>PhoneGap Applications with Instant Update Only</limitations>
    <see>
        <ref link="phonegap instant update">PhoneGap Instant Update</ref>
    </see>
    <terms>javascript functions</terms>
</page>