<page>
   <topic>{grid.object}.setValue Method</topic>
   <syntax>{grid.Object}.setValue(part,name,row - omit for Search and Detail View,value ,honorChangeEvent)</syntax>
   
  <arguments>
    <argument>
      <name>part</name>
      <description>'G' , 'D' or 'S' (Grid, Detail View or Search part).</description>
    </argument>
    
    <argument>
      <name>name</name>
      <description>MUST be all UPPERCASE. </description>
    </argument>
    
    <argument>
      <name>row</name>
      <description>Only needed for Grid part.</description>
    </argument>
    
  </arguments>
   
   
   <description>Set the value of a control in the Grid, Search or Detail View part.</description>
  
  <discussion>Set the value of a control in the Grid, Search or Detail View part. Part is 'G' , 'D' or 'S' (Grid, Detail View or Search part). Row is only needed for Grid part. For new record rows, row is negative. By default honorChangeEvent is true. This causes the onChange event for the control to fire when the value is set. 
IMPORTANT: The 'name' and 'part' parameters MUST be all UPPERCASE. Also, unlike standard Javascript techniques to set the value of a control, the .setValue() method sets the control's state in the Grid Object to be dirty (in the same way that the control becomes dirty if the user types a value into the control). This will set the row to become dirty and the Submit button to become enabled. 
Checkbox and Multi-value Dropdownbox Controls - See the example for information on how to set the value of a multi-valued control (e.g. Checkbox or multi-line Dropdownbox).</discussion>
 
 
 <example><![CDATA[    
   
 ]]></example>
 
 <sections>
   <section>
<title>Example</title>
     <description>MPORTANT NOTE ABOUT USING .setValue() on a Range field in the Search Part - You cannot use this method for a field in the Search Part that has been configured as a 'Range' search. See example for more information.
Set value in 'LASTNAME' field from the Grid part, row 4. Note that field name must be uppercase.
     </description>
     <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}.setValue('G','LASTNAME',4,'Smith');]]></example>
     
     
   </section>
 </sections>
 
 
  <sections>
   <section>
    
     <description>Set value in 'LASTNAME' field from the Grid part, 'current row'. Note that field name must be uppercase.</description>
     <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}.setValue('G','LASTNAME',{grid.rowNumber},'Smith'); ]]></example>
     
   </section>
 </sections>
 
  <sections>
   <section>
    
     <description>Set value in 'LASTNAME' field in the Search part.</description>
     <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}.setValue('S','LASTNAME','Smith');]]></example>
     
   </section>
 </sections>
 
 
  <sections>
   <section>
    
     <description>set value in 'LASTNAME' field in the Detail View part.</description>
     <example><![CDATA[{grid.object}.setValue('D','LASTNAME','Smith');]]></example>
     
   </section>
   
   <section>
    
     <description>set the value in 'FAVORITECOLOR'. Assume that 'FAVORITECOLOR' is a multi-valued field (e.g. a Checkbox control or a Dropdown control configured to allow multiple values):</description>
     <example><![CDATA[{grid.Object}.setValue('S','FAVAORITECOLOR[]','alpha','beta','gamma');
]]></example>
     
   </section>
   <section>
    
     <description>Notice that the fieldname has a trailing [] - to indicate that it is an array of values, and the values you want to set are passed in in the form of a Javascript array. 
Setting value of 'range' fields in the Search part. You can't use .setValue(). You have to use low level Javascript.</description>
     <example><![CDATA[$('{grid.componentname}.S.STARTDATE').value = '12/1/2010';
$('{grid.componentname}.S._TO.STARTDATE').value = '12/31/2010'; ]]></example>
     
   </section>
   
   
   
 </sections>
 
 
 
 
   <see>
      <ref>{grid.object}</ref>
   </see>

<terms>grid component,array,button,buttons,checkbox,checkbox control,control,defaults,detail view,dropdown,dropdown control,events,field,forms,javascript,new record,object,record,search,search part,submit,users</terms>


</page> 
