<page>
    <shortlink>ux list builder listscroller properties</shortlink>
    <topic>List Scroller</topic>
    <description>List scrollers allow you to quickly navigate to a particular record in a List. </description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>You can drag on the scroller in much the same way that you drag on the 'thumb' portion of a scrollbar in a desktop application. When you stop dragging on the scroller, the corresponding row in the List is brought into view.
            </description>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/26708a9b</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/listScrollerDemo.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>While you are dragging on the scroller, a message is displayed showing what record would be shown if you were to stop dragging. The contents of the message is completely customizable. It is actually a standard HTML List template and it supports all of the template features for List controls. The message can display fields from the data in the List.</p>
                <p>The List scroller is particularly useful for virtualized Lists because a virtualized List can contain a very large number of rows. Using the scroller you can quickly navigate to any row in the List without having to drag scroll one screen at a time.</p>
                <p>However, List scrollers are not limited to virtualized Lists. They can also be used with non-virtualized Lists.</p>
                <p>(See below for information on Virtualized Lists).</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/listscroller.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>To turn on the List scroller, check the 'Has scroller' property on the List Properties pane in the List builder.</p>
                <p>You can use placeholders for any field in the List in the template.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/listscroller2.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Dynamically Displaying the List Scroller</title>
            <description>You can dynamically show/hide the scroller for a List control. This is useful if you are dynamically populating the List and under some circumstances that are so few rows in a List that the scroller is not wanted, but in other cases there will be many rows in the List and the scroller would be wanted. The List's [.setDisplay() method] is used for this as follows:</description>
            <example code="js"><![CDATA[var lObj = {dialog.object}.getControl('myList');

if (lObj) {
    // assume flag is a true/false value calculated before getting
    // a pointer to the List object for 'myList'

    if (flag) {
        // if flag is true, we want to hide the scroller
        lObj.setDisplay('scroller',false); //hide
    } else {
        // otherwise, we want to show the scroller
       lObj.setDisplay('scroller',true); //show
    }
}
]]>            </example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>Other parts of the list that can be controlled with the .setDisplay() method are:</description>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>column-header</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>content-header</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>content-footer</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>header</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>footer</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>scroller</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="api client api a5 listbox setdisplay method">.setDisplay() method</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="ux list builder list properties Custom scroll indicator settings">Custom scroll indicator settings</ref>
        <ref link="ux listprop custom scroll properties">Custom scroll properties</ref>
        <ref link="ux data controls list control">List Control</ref>
        <ref link="list control ux api">List Control JavaScript Methods</ref>
    </see>
</page>