<page>
   <topic>FTP_GET_FILE Function</topic>
   <syntax>C ftp_get_file(C address ,C user ,C password ,C source_file ,C destination_file [,L modal [,C title ]])</syntax>
   <arguments>
     <argument>
         <name>address</name>
         <description>The FTP address of the transmission. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>user</name>
         <description>The user's identity. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>password</name>
         <description>The user's password. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>source_file</name>
         <description>The file to retrieve. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>destination_file</name>
         <description>The file to save locally. Character</description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>modal</name>
         <description>Logical. Optional. Default = .F. Whether to display a modal or modeless dialog box.

 .T. = Modal dialog box. Runs in the foreground.

 .F. = Modeless dialog box. Runs in the background. </description>
     </argument>
     <argument>
         <name>title</name>
         <description>Optional. Default = "FTP File Download". The title of the dialog box.</description>
     </argument>
   </arguments>
   <description>Uploads a file using FTP</description>
   <discussion>
The FTP_GET_FILE() function retrieves a file over a FTP connection.
 Note : The FTP protocol uses 2 ports for uploading and downloading files, port 21 and some random high-numbered port. 

 When publishing via FTP, Alpha Anywhere first opens a connection to port 21 on the remote server. This port is used for exchange of control information and for negotiating the second port to use. The second port is chosen by Windows and will be some value above 1024. This is the port used for the actual transfer of files. This is all standard FTP behavior. 

 Alpha Anywhere has no control over the second port used. Norton Antivirus apparently looks for activity on certain ports and flags any traffic on those ports as activity by a trojan. Phineas Phucker uses port 2801. Striker uses port 2565. WinCrash uses ports 2583, 3024, 4092 and 5742. These are all perfectly acceptable for use by an FTP upload.

   </discussion>
   <example><![CDATA[
ftp_get_file("www.alphasoftware.com", "alpha5", "password", "/technical_documentation/learningcenter.asp", "c:\learningcenter.asp")    

]]></example>
   
   <see>
      <ref>Internet Functions and Methods</ref>
   </see>
</page>