<page build="0">
    <shortlink>troubleshooting installer bug report</shortlink>
    <topic>How to Submit a Bug Report for the Alpha Anywhere Installer</topic>
    <description>
        <p>If you run into issues with the Alpha Anywhere Installer and cannot resolve them, send the log files to bugs@alphasoftware.com.</p>
    </description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The Alpha Anywhere installer keeps an installation record in a log file. This log file is helpful for us to track down installation issues. If you run into an installation problem you cannot figure out how to resolve, you can submit a bug report to Alpha Software along with your installer logs.</p>
        <p>You can locate the log file within the Alpha Anywhere Installer:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <important>
                <p>Before submitting a bug report, make sure to review the [Installer troubleshooting] topics.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Click the *[ui:View log]* button in the lower left-hand corner of the Installer on either the Installed or Available tab.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The View log button is found in the lower left-hand corner of the Installer.</title>
                        <alt>The Alpha Anywhere Installer Installed tab</alt>
                        <link>images/installer_logs1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Next, click *[ui:Locate log file]*. This will open the folder where the log files are stored.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Locate log file button opens the folder where the logs are stored.</title>
                        <alt>The Installer Log window</alt>
                        <link>images/installer_logs2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Copy the log file in the folder and send it to bugs@alphasoftware.com.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The logs are saved in the "AlphaAnywhereInstaller.log" file</title>
                        <alt>The Windows File Explorer opened to the location where the Alpha Anywhere Installer log is stored.</alt>
                        <link>images/installer_logs3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If for some reason you cannot access the *[ui:View log]* button, you can locate the installer logs in the ProgramData folder:</p>
                <p>
                    <example><![CDATA[C:\ProgramData\Alpha Software\Alpha Anywhere Installer\InstallerLogs]]></example>
                </p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="troubleshoot install">Installer troubleshooting</link>
    </links>
</page>