<page>
	<topic>Run multiple applications or web sites by using multiple Application Server configuration files</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Traditionally, Application Server administrators provide service for multiple applications by using a single instance of the Application Server, placing each distinct application within a different subfolder under the document root. While this is quite effective, it results in cluttered URLs, such as http://www.server.com/application1(external link) and http://www.server.com/application2(external link), and shares sessions between sites. By using multiple instances of the Application Server, each to provide service for only one specific application or site, sessions are no longer shared and URLs may be further customized. This configuration requires 1 IP address per application or site.</description>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Make sure that the server's operating system has at least one IP address for each application you would like to provide service for. For specific information on how to do this, consult your network administrator.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Configure DNS for www.application1.com(external link) to point to IP address 1 and www.application2.com(external link) to point to IP address 2. For specific information on how to do this, consult your network administrator.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Create an XML configuration file for each application and start server instances for each site (see above). Any errors about the servers being unable to start at this point are expected.
4.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Configure the server for application 1 to use the assigned IP address (on the Advanced tab). Also change the document root and any other settings as required. Repeat for application 2.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Start to start each instance of the Application Server.
 </description>
				</step>
				
			</steps>
			
			
		</section>
		
	</sections>
	
</page>