<page>
	<topic>Using InstallMaker to Build Installation Packages</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>The InstallMaker utility creates a package that will install your Alpha Anywhere Runtime application at your customer's site. To use this utility:</description>
			<note>InstallMaker is not available in V12 and above.</note>
			
		</section>
		<section>
			<steps>
				<step>
					<description>Run your new application with Alpha Anywhere Runtime.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Exit from the Alpha Anywhere Runtime application.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Run your new application with the Alpha Anywhere development software.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>From the Control Panel, select Tools > Utilities > Create Install Package.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>The first screen of the InstallMaker will identify the location of your Alpha Anywhere Runtime application.</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click OK to continue. </description>
				<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_01.gif</link></figure>
<note>Open an Existing Project: Optionally, click Open Project to display the Open InstallMaker Project dialog. Select the project from the list and click OK to continue.</note>	
			
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Step 1: Method: Make a selection from the Install list. The options are:</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Application Files only" - appropriate for an update of an existing application
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Both Alpha Anywhere Runtime and application files" - appropriate for a new installation
</description>
						</case>
						
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Define the name of the installation program, which is by default " c:\setup.exe ".
</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >>. </description>
					<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_02.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Step 2, Registry: In the Options list, place checkmarks next to the registry keys that you want to set upon installation. To place a checkmark, select the desired key and select the Include Key check box.
</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >>. </description>
					<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_03.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Step 3, Customizations: If you selected Both Alpha Anywhere Runtime and application files" in step 7, the Other files to include list will be enabled.

</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Place checkmarks next to the files to include. 
</description>
					<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_04.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If there are additional files to include (such as images):
</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>1. Click Install Additional Files to display the Select Additional Files dialog box.
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>2. Click the 'plus' icon to navigate to and select a file to add. This file must be in the application's folder or in a sub-folder.
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>3. To remove a file, select it in the Additional Files list and click the 'x' icon.
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>Click OK to continue.</description>
						</case>
						
					</cases>
					
					
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >>. </description>
					
					<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_05.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Step 4, Install Locations: Make a selection in the Install Location list. The options are:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Install the Runtime and Application files in the same folder"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Install the Runtime and Application files in different folders"
</description>
	</case>
</cases>
					
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Enter the location of the application files in the Default Application Folder field.
</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Install the Runtime and Application files in different folders" in step 14, enter the installation location of the Alpha Anywhere Runtime software in the Runtime Folder field.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >>. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_06.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				
				<step>
<description>Step 5, Display: Optionally, click 'open folder' icon in the Icon File field to select the icon image that you want to associate with your application.
</description>					
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, enter text to display in the background during installation into the Background text field.
</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>If you entered background text, select the where the text should be displayed from the Text Location list. The options are:
</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"Upper Left"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Upper Right"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Lower Left"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Lower Right"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Top Center"</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Bottom Center"
</description>
						</case>
						
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Optionally, click the 'open folder' icon in the Background BMP field to select an image to display in the background during installation.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Enter the text to display in the title bar of the installer into the Title Bar Text field.
</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>Click Next >>. </description>
					<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_07.gif</link></figure>
			<note>Save the Project. Optionally, click Save Project to display the Save InstallMaker Project dialog. Enter a name for the project and click OK.
</note>		
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Step 6, Shortcut: Click Modify Shortcut.</description>
					
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>On the General tab enter the name that will be attached to the shortcut in the Shortcut name field.
</description>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>Select the location for the shortcut. The options are:
</description>
					<cases>
						<case>
							<description>"None"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Custom Group"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Desktop"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Start Menu"
</description>
						</case>
						<case>
							<description>"Startup Folder"
</description>
						</case>
						
					</cases>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If the target computer is running Windows NT, Windows 2000, or Windows XP, in the Owner field select whether the program will be available to the Current user or All users. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_08.gif</link></figure>
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>On the Appearance tab select whether the main Alpha Anywhere window will have a custom title. If so, enter the title in the Use custom title field.
</description>
				</step>
				
				<step>
					<description>When loading, select whether Alpha Anywhere will use:</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>its Default splash screen
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>No splash screen
</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>a Custom bitmap
</description>
					</case>
					
				</cases>
				
				
				</step>
				<step>
					<description>If you selected "Custom bitmap", click the 'open folder' icon in the Custom bitmap field to select an image to display when Alpha Anywhere is loading.
</description>
				</step>
			
			<step>
				<description>When loading, select whether Alpha Anywhere will use:
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>its Default icon
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Custom icon</description>
	</case>
</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>If you selected "Custom icon", click 'open folder' icon in the Custom icon field to select an icon to display when Alpha Anywhere is loading. 
</description>
			<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_09.gif</link></figure>	
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>On the Window tab select the size of the main Alpha Anywhere window. The options are:
</description>
				<cases>
					<case>
						<description>Default - previous size of main Alpha Anywhere window</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Maximized - maximize the main Alpha Anywhere window</description>
					</case>
					<case>
						<description>Minimized - minimize the main Alpha Anywhere window
</description>
					</case>
					
					
					
				</cases>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Select whether to disable the ability to minimize or maximize the main Alpha Anywhere program window.
</description>
			</step>
			
			<step>
				<description>Select whether to open Alpha Anywhere without a system menu.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>On the Advanced tab, enter Xbasic commands to run when Alpha Anywhere is started.
</description>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click OK to continue. 
</description>
<figure><link>images/UG_Installmaker_10.gif</link></figure>
			</step>
			<step>
				<description>Click Create Install. InstallMaker will create a self extracting ZIP file named (by default) setup.exe. This name was defined on the first page of the InstallMaker utility.</description>
			</step>
			
			</steps>
			
			
			
		</section>
		
	
	</sections>
<see>
	<ref>How to Distribute a Runtime Application</ref>
</see>	
	
</page>