<page>
	<topic>Web Publishing vs. ASP Programming</topic>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>Web Publishing as supported by Alpha Anywhere represents a new generation of technology that simplifies and speeds the process of giving access to database applications to Internet users.

While ASP (Active Server Pages) is a programming intensive process that requires a great deal of patience and skill, the Web Publishing process is reliant on intuitive genies and dialog boxes that anyone can master. In fact, using the default values for field and form properties, a developer can produce an Internet equivalent version of a database form, browse, or view in just minutes.

Having said this, Web Publishing offers a great deal of potential for customization of grids, forms, and pages. Most of these options simply require an ability to navigate through the menus and make selections. Some of these options require an ability to write Xbasic and HTML code. as with standard Alpha Anywhere applications, genies can only take you so far. At a certain point, your requirements for customization require that you learn to manipulate the code that the genies are creating.
Hopefully, you will find that this tutorial will show how to gradually add customization to your web applications.
</description>
			
		</section>
<section>
	<title>Why Web Publishing is Better</title>
	<description>The Web Publishing approach is better for several reasons.</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>It reduces the skill level required to produce web applications. You no longer have to understand how to program to develop applications of moderate complexity and sophistication.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>It reduces the time to develop applications. Because the Web Publishing genies produce error-free code, you avoid the time-consuming process of debugging conventionally programmed (e.g. ASP) applications.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>It reduces the complexity and cost of application maintenance. With ASP the process of validating user input is very complex. Changing the validation of a single field requires programming, testing, and debugging. With Web Publishing, it is as simple as selecting different menu options and republishing a page.</description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
</section>
	</sections>
	
</page>