<page>
   <topic>Web Functions</topic>
   <description>Helper functions for Web Applications, including Security, Publishing and Work Queues.</description>
   <!--list:.-->
   
   
   
   <sections>
       <section>
           <title>Form Related Functions</title>
        
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>BROWSE.LOAD() - Loads a browse window into memory, but does not display the window until the .SHOW() method is used. Allows you to manipulate data in the browse before displaying the browse.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>BROWSE.VIEW() - Opens a browse window. All records in the table will be displayed unless the browse layout definition specifies a filter.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>BROWSE.VIEWQUERIED() - Opens a browse window and applies an optional filter and order expression. Use this method when you want to restrict the records displayed in the browse.</description>  
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>A5_OPEN_DEFAULT_BROWSE() - Opens a browse window and applies an optional filter and order expression.</description>
       </section>
        <section>
           <description>FORM.DIALOG() - A "quick and dirty" way to open a form as a modal dialog window. You can also open a form as a modal dialog by using the "dialog" keyword in the .VIEW()and .VIEWQUERIED() methods.
</description>
       </section>
        <section>
           <description>FORM.LOAD() - Loads a form window into memory, but does not display the window until the .SHOW() method is used. Allows you to manipulate data in the form before displaying the form.
</description>
       </section>
        <section>
           <description>FORM.VIEW() - Opens a form window. All records in the table will be displayed unless the form layout definition specifies a filter. Use the "dialog" keyword to open the form as a modal dialog box.
</description>
       </section>
        <section>
           <description>FORM.VIEWQUERIED() - Opens a form window and applies an optional filter and order expression. Use this method when you want to restrict the records displayed in the form. Use the "dialog" keyword to open the form as a modal dialog box.

</description>
       </section>
   </sections>
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   <sections>
       <section>
           <title>Functions for controlling the Web Application Server.
</title>
<description>A5_COUNT_WEBSESSIONS() - Returns the number of active sessions.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>SERVER.RESET() - Deletes all server variables.</description>
       </section>
       <section>
           <description>SESSION.RESET() - Resets the current session by clearing out all variables that are stored in the current client session.</description>
       </section>
       
   </sections>
   
   
   
   
   <see>
       <ref>Internet Functions and Methods</ref>
       
       
   </see>
   
   
</page>