<page>
	<topic>Customizing the Marker Title and Info Box</topic>
<description>This video continues from video GM1. The video shows how you can customize the 'info box' for each marker on the map. The 'info box' is a small window that pops up when the user clicks on a marker.    
</description>

<sections>
	<section>
		<description>The video shows how you can put any HTML that you want in the info box and how the html can include placeholders to include data from the corresponding row in the Grid. The HTML can also include Javascript commands. In the video we show how you can insert the Javascript to open the corresponding Detail View part for the current record.</description>
	</section>
	<section>

<videos>
	<video>
		<name>Watch Video GM2 </name>
		<link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V11Videos/GoogleMapping_2.swf</link>
	</video>
	
	
</videos>
	</section>	
	<section>
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>Define the titles. Smart field = name of airport the city and then the state</description>
	<example><![CDATA[tbl.data("NAME") + " (" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " + tbl.data("STATE") + ")"]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Can now see the name of the airport and the city and state in parens. Now when I click on the icon I want bubble help to open up.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Can define an expression that returns the text we would like to appear. We can also do a template. A template is any HTML text that you want to put into the info box. And the template can include placeholders for field values in the current row.
</description>
<example><![CDATA[Airport location: {}]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>want to add fields, any thing placed inside the placeholder will be an expression
</description>
<example><![CDATA[Airport location: {tbl.data("NAME") + "in" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " +tbl.data("STATE") }.
]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>add Hyperlink that allows us to open a detail view for this record.
</description>
<example><![CDATA[Airport location: {tbl.data("NAME") + "in" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " +tbl.data("STATE") }.
]]></example>
	</step>
	
	<step>
		<description>Copy this to clipboard and switch to template. Paste in template and add some javascript
</description>
<example><![CDATA[Airport location: {tbl.data("NAME") + "in" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " +tbl.data("STATE") }.
]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Insert Method. search for {grid.Object}detailview(rowNumber).
</description>
<example><![CDATA[Airport location: {tbl.data("NAME") + "in" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " +tbl.data("STATE") }.
]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Replace Rownumber with rownumber placeholder
</description>
<example><![CDATA[{tbl.data("NAME") + "in" + tbl.data("CITY") + ", " +tbl.data("STATE") }.
]]></example>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Save and run. Put mouse over marker, see pop-up bubble help, click on icon, see bubble text. Click on hyperlink, see detail view.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
	
</steps>
	</section>	
	
	</sections>
	
	
</page>