<page build="7199">
    <shortlink>reporting pdfreports pdfdirect</shortlink>
    <topic>Generating Reports with "Direct to PDF"</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere uses the "Direct to PDF" to generate reports. Direct to PDF replaces the Amyuni driver, which is obsolete and no longer supported nor shipped with Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The default for creating PDF reports has changed with the release of Alpha Anywhere 4.6.2.6 (Released December 1, 2020). Previously, PDF reports were created using the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver. Now, the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver is no longer used and a new "Direct to PDF" option is used.</p>
        <p>Since the release of Alpha Anywhere 4.6.2.6, the Amyuni drivers are no longer shipped with Alpha Anywhere and generating reports using the Amyuni drivers is no longer supported.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <obsolete build="7661">
                <p>Generating reports using the Amyuni Drivers is no longer supported.</p>
            </obsolete>
        </section>
        <section build="7661">
            <title>Generating Reports in Web Applications</title>
            <description>
                <p>For web applications, Action JavaScript offers these options:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pdf23.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When choosing a PDF printing option for the report Action Javascript, you may see two choices: *[ui:PDF]* and *[ui:PDFDirect]*. Both options will generate the PDF report using PDFDirect. The *[ui:PDFDirect]* option was introduced when the Direct to PDF option was initially introduced. At that time *[ui:PDF]* produced reports using the Amyuni drivers while *[ui:PDFDirect]* used the new "Direct to PDF" method.</p>
                <p>The *[ui:PDFDirect]* option is now identical to the *[ui:PDF]* option as support for generating reports with the Amyuni drivers has been removed.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Known issues with the PDFDirect method of generating PDF Reports</title>
            <description>
                <p>For reports that use non-latin character sets (e.g. CJK or Hebrew), you may need to changed the font used in the report.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How to report PDF reporting issues to Alpha Software</title>
            <description>
                <p>If your report does not render correctly when printed as a PDF, right click on the report in the Web Project Control Panel and select the Create Bug Report menu option under the Datasources menu. Select a location to store the .zip file and be sure to check the Include Raw Pages option. Send the zip file to [bugs@alphasoftware.com].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="mailto:bugs@alphasoftware.com">bugs@alphasoftware.com</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="server%20ref%20web%20project%20settings#section1_PDF%20Printing%20Options">Web Project Settings - PDF Printing Options</ref>
        <ref link="open%20a%20report,%20label%20or%20letter%20layout">Open a Report, Label or Letter layout Action Javascript</ref>
    </see>
</page>