<page build="7199">
    <shortlink>reporting pdfreports pdfdirect</shortlink>
    <topic>Generating Reports with "Direct to PDF"</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere is phasing in a new PDF generation engine, "Direct to PDF". This method of generating PDF reports replaces the Amyuni printer, which is deprecated and slated for removal in a future release of Alpha Anywhere.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The default manner for creating PDF reports has changed with the release of Alpha Anywhere 4.6.2.6 (Released December 1, 2020). Previously, PDF reports were created using the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver. Now, the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver is no longer used and a new "Direct to PDF" option is used.</p>
        <p>For *[ui:desktop applications]* you can control whether PDF reports should still use the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver by going to the *[ui:View]* &gt; *[ui:Settings]* menu option and then in the *[ui:Preferences]* section set the option for *[ui:PDF]* to *[ui:Yes]*. The default setting is *[ui:No]*, meaning the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver will not be used.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pdfdirect.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <important>
                <p>The Amyuni Printer is no longer distributed with Alpha Anywhere starting with version 4.6.2.7 (build 7544). To get the Amyuni Printer drivers, you must first install an older version of Alpha Anywhere.</p>
            </important>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>For web applications, Action JavaScript offers these options:</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pdf23.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>The *[ui:PDF]* option and *[ui:PDFDirect]* option are now the same - both options will generate the PDF report in the same way - i.e. they will not use the Amyuni printer driver.</p>
                <p>The reason that the *[ui:PDF]* option is the same as the *[ui:PDFDirect]* option is that the *[ui:Use direct to PDF option]* in *[ui:Web Project Properties]* now defaults to true.</p>
            </description>
            <note>
                <p>You can force your web app to use the *[ui:Amyuni]* printer driver by setting the *[ui:Use direct to PDF]* option to false in *[ui:Web Project Properties]* and then selecting the *[ui:PDF]* option in Action JavaScript.</p>
                <p>The option to force *[ui:Amyuni]* will be removed in a future version so it is important to resolve all issues as soon as possible by reporting any issues to Alpha.</p>
            </note>
            <figure>
                <link>images/pdfdirect.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Known issues with the PDFDirect method of generating PDF Reports</title>
            <description>
                <p>For reports that use non-latin character sets (e.g. CJK or Hebrew), you may need to changed the font used in the report.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>How to report PDF reporting issues to Alpha Software</title>
            <description>
                <p>If your report does not render correctly when printed as a PDF, right click on the report in the Web Project Control Panel and select the Create Bug Report menu option under the Datasources menu. Select a location to store the .zip file and be sure to check the Include Raw Pages option. Send the zip file to [bugs@alphasoftware.com].</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="mailto:bugs@alphasoftware.com">bugs@alphasoftware.com</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="server%20ref%20web%20project%20settings#section1_PDF%20Printing%20Options">Web Project Settings - PDF Printing Options</ref>
        <ref link="open%20a%20report,%20label%20or%20letter%20layout">Open a Report, Label or Letter layout Action Javascript</ref>
    </see>
</page>