<page>
  <shortlink>ux checkbox orientation</shortlink>
  <topic>Orientation</topic>
  <description>Choose how the CheckBox options are rendered: vertically, horizontally, or in mulitple columns.</description>
  <description>
    <p>Orientation determines whether the checkboxes are laid out vertically, horizontally, or in columns. If you choose the columns option, you can specify the 'snaking style'. This is either Left-to-Right-Top-to-Bottom (LRTB) or or Top-to-Bottom-Left-to-Right (TBLR).</p>
    <p>Columns are not supported for ButtonList style.</p>
  </description>
  <sections>
    <section>
      <figure>
        <title>The Orientation property</title>
        <link>images/ori4.png</link>
      </figure>
      <note>You might have to play with the width and height of the control's Field Properties when configuring a checkbox control's orientation. The Field Properties also appear in the control properties list.</note>
    </section>
    <section>

      <figure>
        <title>Horizontal orientation</title>
        <link>images/ori.png</link>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>

      <figure>
        <title>Vertical</title>
        <link>images/ori2.png</link>
      </figure>
    </section>
    <section>

      <figure>
        <title>Columns</title>
        <link>images/ori3.png</link>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section>
      <description>For information on formating snaking columns, watch part 2 of the videos below. The easy way to set this format is to change the Column flow property (which is also in the CheckBox Properties section).</description>
      <videos>
        <title>Dynamically Repopulate a CheckBox or RadioButton Control</title>
        <description>
          <p>In some applications, it might be necessary to repopulate the choices shown in a radiobutton or CheckBox control with a new set of choices after the UX Component has initially been rendered. An Ajax callback is made where the new choices are computed on the server, then a Javascript response is sent to the browser to update the choices for the control. These videos show how this can be done.</p>
          <p>In part 2, the CheckBox is populated with a much larger set of choices and a snaking layout (left-to-right, top-to-bottom) for the CheckBoxes is specified. </p>
        </description>
        <video>
          <name>Watch Video - Part 1</name>
          <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/LHx7ruinNpCkQxuPz9K9SW</link>
        </video>
        <video>
          <name>Watch Video - Part 2</name>
          <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/DaR8ehE2nubwUmygTjWp6q</link>
        </video>
      </videos>
    </section>
  </sections>
</page>