<page>
    <topic>Alpha Anywhere Photo App Tutorial</topic>
    <description>In this 90 minute video, Dan Bricklin walks you through the process of building a web and mobile application that can capture and store images in a SQL database.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The tutorial begins the course by setting up a SQL table, which you then use to build a browser application. The application is then further built to work on a mobile device and access a phone camera.</p>
        <p>The pace is slow enough so that you can build the application along with the video, without needing to stop and rewind. If you have a second monitor or tablet, we suggest that you view the video on that while following along in Alpha Anywhere to build the application.</p>
    </discussion>
    <groups>
        <group background="true">
            <title>Important Notice for Community Edition Users</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <description>
                        <p>This tutorial was built using the full Alpha Anywhere Development Environment. Portions of this tutorial may not apply due to features that are not available in Community Edition. Community Edition users may encounter screens that don't match their environment due to differences between the two development environments.</p>
                        <p>We strongly recommend starting with the tutorials in the *[extlink:Alpha Software Learning Center@https://learn.alphasoftware.com]* to start learning Alpha Anywhere.</p>
                    </description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
        <group>
            <title>Photo App Tutorial</title>
            <sections>
                <section>
                    <title>Setting up a Workspace</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>Before starting this tutorial, you must first create a new, empty workspace. Follow the instructions in our [Create a Workspace] guide to create a workspace before starting this tutorial.</p>
                        <p>Once you have created a workspace, click on the video link below to start the tutorial.</p>
                    </description> 
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>Photo App Tutorial</title>
                    <description>Click the video link below to start the tutorial.</description>
                    <videos>
                        <video>
                            <name>Photo App Tutorial</name>
                            <link>https://share.vidyard.com/watch/TRTcz5BouFgp5ynQEbHu7W</link>
                        </video>
                    </videos>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <description>If you prefer written instruction instead of a video, a [complete transcript] with step-by-step instructions is available for download.</description>
                </section>
                <section>
                    <title>More Getting Started Tutorials</title>
                    <description>Visit [Getting Started Tutorials] to find more tutorials.</description>
                </section>
            </sections>
        </group>
    </groups>
    
    <links>
        <link href="http://alphasoftware.com/photodemoscript.asp">complete transcript</link>
        <link link="Getting Started with Alpha Anywhere Tutorials">Getting Started Tutorials</link>
        <link link="Create a new Alpha Anywhere Workspace">Create a Workspace</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref link="build a mobile app">Build Your First Mobile App</ref>
        <ref link="build a web app">Build Your First Web App</ref>
        <ref link="how to articles">How To Articles</ref>
    </see>
</page>