<page>
    <topic>Alpha Anywhere Photo App Tutorial</topic>
    <description>In this 90 minute video, Dan Bricklin walks you through the process of building a web and mobile application that can capture and store images in a SQL database.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The tutorial begins the course by setting up a SQL table, which you then use to build a browser application. The application is then further built to work on a mobile device and access a phone camera.</p>
        <p>The pace is slow enough so that you can build the application along with the video, without needing to stop and rewind. If you have a second monitor or tablet, we suggest that you view the video on that while following along in Alpha Anywhere to build the application.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Setting up a Workspace</title>
            <description>
                <p>Before starting this tutorial, you must first create a new, empty workspace. Follow the instructions in our [Create a Workspace] guide to create a workspace before starting this tutorial.</p>
                <p>Once you have created a workspace, click on the video link below to start the tutorial.</p>
            </description> 
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Photo App Tutorial</title>
            <description>Click the video link below to start the tutorial.</description>
            <videos>
                <video>
                    <name>Photo App Tutorial</name>
                    <link>http://www.alphasoftware.com/video-library/?v=4850</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If you prefer written instruction instead of a video, a [complete transcript] with step-by-step instructions is available for download.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>More Getting Started Tutorials</title>
            <description>Visit [Getting Started Tutorials] to find more tutorials.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="http://alphasoftware.com/photodemoscript.asp">complete transcript</link>
        <link href="../index.xml">Getting Started Tutorials</link>
        <link href="../Basic Tutorials/Create a Workspace.xml">Create a Workspace</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="../Build a Mobile App/index.xml">Build Your First Mobile App</ref>
        <ref href="../Build a Web App/index.xml">Build Your First Web App</ref>
        <ref link="How To... Articles">How To... Articles</ref>
    </see>
</page>