<page>
    <shortlink>Sample and Tutorial Workspaces</shortlink>
    <topic>Installing Sample and Tutorial Workspaces</topic>
    <description>Alpha Anywhere ships with sample and tutorial workspaces that can be installed.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>How to Install a Sample Workspace</title>
            <description>Sample and Tutorial Workspaces must first be installed before you can use them.</description>
            <steps>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>Open the *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog. The *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog opens automatically when Alpha Anywhere is launched.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Select Workspace dialog</title>
                        <link>images/selectWorkspaceDialog.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>
                        <p>If *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog does not appear when you launch Alpha Anywhere or Alpha Anywhere is already running, you can click the *[ui:Recent Workspaces]* button on the toolbar to open the *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog.</p>
                    </description>
                    <note>All open workspaces must first be closed before the *[ui:Recent Workspaces]* option appears on the toolbar.</note>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Click Recent Workspaces in the toolbar after closing all open workspaces to open the Select Workspace dialog</title>
                        <link>images/recentWorkspaces.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Make sure the *[ui:Web/Mobile]* checkbox is checked. This ensures all sample and tutorial applications for mobile and web applications will be listed.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/sampleWorkspace1.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>In the *[ui:Select Workspace]* dialog, click *[ui:Sample and Tutorial Workspaces]* to show a list of all available Sample Applications.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/sampleWorkspace2.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
                <step>
                    <description>Select the sample or tutorial workspace you wish to install, specify the installation folder, and click *[ui:OK]* to install the workspace.</description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/sampleWorkspace3.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </step>
            </steps>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Available Web and Mobile Sample Workspaces</title>
            <description>There are several web and mobile application sample and tutorial applications that ship with Alpha Anywhere. Each sample workspace is described below.</description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title>Application Server Demo</title>
                    <description>Learn how to build powerful applications using Alpha Anywhere's Web Component Builders and the Alpha Application Web Server.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Demo Mobile Application</title>
                    <description>This sample application demonstrates how to building a mobile business application that works against the sample Northwind database. The instructions for this tutorial can be found in our Getting Started Tutorials. Check out [Building the Sample Mobile Application] to get started.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Email Features Demo</title>
                    <description>Learn how to automate email tasks, including populating tables in a database with the contents of an email.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Learning Xbasic</title>
                    <description>This workspace is the sample 'Phone Messages' database used as part of the Learning Xbasic tutorial.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>Simple Web Contact Manager</title>
                    <description>The Simple Web Contact Manager demonstrates how to build a simple web-based contact manager using Alpha Anywhere's Web Component Builders.</description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title>AlphaSports</title>
                    <description>The AlphaSports sample application shows you how to build a full featured application for the fictitious AlphaSports company. It includes sample reports that can be used in web applications.</description>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Pre-Built Sample Apps</title>
            <description>
                <p>Additional pre-built sample applications are available on the Alpha Software website. *[extlink:Click here to see what is available in our Pre-Built Sample Apps library.@http://www.alphasoftware.com/mobile-app-development/sample-apps/]*</p>
                <p>The pre-built sample apps library do not come with step-by-step instructions describing how they were built. They can, however, be modified to create an application that meets your needs.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link href="/documentation/index?search=building the sample mobile application">Building the Sample Mobile Application</link>
    </links>
    <see>
        <ref href="../Build a Mobile App/index.xml">Build Your First Mobile App</ref>
        <ref href="../Build a Web App/index.xml">Build Your First Web App</ref>
    </see>
</page>