<page>
	<topic>Password Protecting Your Scripts</topic>
<description>How to password protect your scripts to prevent users from changing the scripts.</description>	
<sections>
	
<section>
	<description>If you are designing an application for others to use, you may want to password protect your scripts to prevent users from changing the scripts. You may also have created a commercial application in Alpha Anywhere and you may want to protect your intellectual property by hiding the scripts.

Alpha Anywhere allows you to password protect any script that is attached to an event, a Global Script, or a Global Function. Your script must be in Xbasic. You cannot password protect Action Scripts. If you need to password protect an Action script, you must first convert it to Xbasic.
To password protect an Xbasic script:
</description>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<description>Edit the script.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<description>Add the following to the first line of the script: 'PASSWORD </description>
		</case>
		
	</cases>
	
</section>	
<section>
	<note>You can also select File, Set Password from the Code Editor menus. This will insert the appropriate comment into your script.</note>
</section>
<section>
	<description>For example if you want to protect a script with the password FOO, you would add the following to the first line of the script:</description>
<example><![CDATA['PASSWORD FOO]]></example>	
	<note>The password test is not case sensitive so:</note>
</section>
<section>
	
<example><![CDATA['PASSWORD FOO]]></example>	
	
</section>	
<section>
	<description>and</description>
<example><![CDATA['password foo]]></example>	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<description>are considered identical.
When a script or function is password protected you will prompted for the password when you attempt to edit the code. You can run a password protected script without knowing the password.
The script's password system remembers the last password you entered and will automatically attempt to use that password whenever a new script with a password is loaded. Therefore, if you give all your scripts the same password, you will only have to enter your password for the first script that you edit.</description>
	
	
</section>	
</sections>	

<see>
	<ref>The Xbasic Explorer</ref>
	<ref>Compiling the Script</ref>
	<ref>Comments and Commands</ref>
	<ref>The Code Editor</ref>
	
</see>

	
</page>