<page>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere offers new and optional PDF printing utilities. To access these new tools select Tools > PDF Tools from the main menu. 
</description>
	
	<sections>
<section>
	<title>Utilities</title>
<cases>
	<case>
		<title>Combine files
</title>
		<description>Combines 2 or PDF files into a single file, which will contain the pages of both files.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Merge files</title>
		<description>Merges 2 PDF files, placing the pages of the second file either above or below the pages of the first file. Typically, used to place a watermark on pages.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Linearize</title>
		<description>Converts a PDF file to a format that is better for web viewing. This format makes it possible to view the first page before all remaining pages are downloaded.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Encrypt</title>
		<description>[key_img] Adds password security and other user restrictions to a PDF file.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Export to RTF</title>
		<description>[w_img] Converts a PDF file to RTF format, with various options for formatting the resulting file.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Export to HTML</title>
		<description>[e_img] Converts a PDF file to HTML format, with various options for formatting the resulting file.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Export to Text</title>
		<description>[text_img] Converts a PDF file to text, with various options for formatting the resulting file.</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<title>Create from Bitmap</title>
		<description>Converts a Windows Bitmap (.BMP) or JPEG (.JPG) file to PDF format. Typically, used to create a watermark to place on PDF pages.</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Combine Files</title>
<description>Combining PDF files appends them end-to-end, so that the resulting file contains all the pages of the input files. To combine PDF files:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Combine Files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Add File, select the PDF file you want, and click Open. Repeat for all the input files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>If you want to remove a PDF file from the list, select it and click Remove File.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>The combine utility places the top entry in the list first in the resulting file, and works down the list, placing the last entry last. Optionally, select a PDF file and click Up or Down to reposition it in the list.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select and click [glasses_img] to view a PDF file (you must have a program, such as  Adobe Acrobat, capable of displaying PDF files).
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter the name of the Result file. If you do not specify a name, the first PDF file in the input list will be overwritten with the result.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to define the Result file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to combine the files. After the files are combined, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Merge Files
</title>
<description>Merging 2 PDF files combines them into a new file that contains as many pages as the longest of the input files. This utility is typically used to place a watermark on the pages of a PDF document. There are 3 options:
</description>	
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>Place the merge file on top of the base file
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Place the merge file below the base file
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>Place the merge file on all pages of the base file
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	
<description>To merge 2 PDF files:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Merge Files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the base PDF file. This is the file to which the watermark or logo is added.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the merge PDF file. This is the source for the watermark or logo. Use the Create from Bitmap utility to convert a bitmap into a PDF file suitable for this process.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result PDF file. If you leave this blank,Alpha Anywhere will create a backup of the base file with a ".bak" extension and overwrite the base file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Merge file on top?
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, check Merge all pages? to place a watermark on all pages. Leave unchecked to place the watermark on the first page only.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to merge the files. After the files are merged, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Linearize</title>
<description>The linearize utility makes it easier for web users to read long PDF files. To linearize a PDF file.
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Linearize.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the source PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result PDF file. If you leave this blank,Alpha Anywhere will create a backup of the source file with a ".bak" extension and overwrite the source file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to linearize the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Encrypt
</title>
<description>The encryption utility can prevent users from opening, modifying, copying, or printing the content of a PDF file. To encrypt a PDF file.
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Encrypt.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the source PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result PDF file. If you leave this blank, Alpha Anywhere will create a backup of the source file with a ".bak" extension and overwrite the source file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter the Owner password. The user must supply the password to change the security settings.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, enter the User password. The user must supply the password in order to open and read the file. This password must be different from the Owner password.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Can Print? check box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Can Modify Document? check box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Can Copy? check box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Can Add Notes? check box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, set the Use 128 bit encryption check box. If not set, the utility will use 40 bit encryption. Users will need Adobe Acrobat version 5 or higher to read 128 bit encrypted files.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to encrypt the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>

</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Export to RTF
</title>
<description>This utility creates a RTF version of the PDF file. It saves any images in .JPG format. To convert the file to RTF:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Export to RTF.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the source PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result file. If you leave this blank, Alpha Anywhere will use the name of the source file, but add a ".rtf" extension.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Make a selection from the RTF Option list.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Advanced RTF" - exports text and graphics, and uses frames to position objects.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Full RTF" - exports text and graphics, but does not use frames to position objects. This format is easier to edit.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Formatted Text" - exports RTF text only.
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Simple Text" - exports unformatted ASCII text.
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Make a selection from the Text Optimization list to specify how the text should be regrouped prior to output. Line optimization is recommended.
</description>
		<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"No optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Line optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Paragraph optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Table optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to export the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Export to HTML</title>
<description>This utility creates a HTML version of the PDF file. It saves any images in .JPG format. To convert the file to HTML:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Export to HTML.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the source PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result file. If you leave this blank, Alpha Anywhere will use the name of the source file, but add a ".html" extension.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Make a selection from the RTF Option list.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Layers" - exports content as a single file with layers. Note : Mozilla and Firefox may have problems displaying this HTML. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Single" - exports content as a single file. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Multiple" - exports content as multiple files. 
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Make a selection from the Text Optimization list to specify how the text should be regrouped prior to output. Line optimization is recommended.
</description>
		<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"No optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Line optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Paragraph optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Table optimization" 
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to export the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Export to Text</title>
<description>This utility creates a HTML version of the PDF file. It does not export any images. To convert the file to ASCII text:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Export to Text.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click Select to choose the source PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Select to choose the result file. If you leave this blank, Alpha Anywhere will use the name of the source file, but add a ".text" extension.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Make a selection from the Text Optimization list to specify how the text should be regrouped prior to output. Line optimization is recommended.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"No optimization"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Line optimization"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Paragraph optimization"
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Table optimization"
</description>
	</case>
	
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to export the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
<section>
	<title>Create from Bitmap</title>
<description>The Create from Bitmap utility converts a Windows Bitmap or JPEG file into a PDF file. To convert an image to PDF format:
</description>	
<steps>
	<step>
		<description>In the main menu select Tools > PDF Tools > Create from Bitmap.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click [folder_img] in the Bitmap filename field to choose the source image file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click [folder_img] in the Output filename field to choose the destination PDF file location and name.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the height of the resulting PDF image in the Image height field. The measurement is in inches.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the width of the resulting PDF image in the Image width field. The measurement is in inches.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Select the scaling method in the Image scaling list.
</description>
<cases>
	<case>
		<description>"Best-fit" - will preserve the aspect ratio of the image while scaling to fit within the height and width dimensions specified above. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Stretch" - will scale both height and width to fill the specified dimension, and may result in image distortion. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Tile" - will repeat the image horizontally and vertically within the boundaries of the page. 
</description>
	</case>
	<case>
		<description>"Absolute" - will not scale the image 
</description>
	</case>
	
</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the height of the page in the P age height field. The measurement is in inches.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Enter the width of the page in the P age width field. The measurement is in inches.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Center bitmap check box.</description>
		<cases>
			<case>
				<description>1. Enter the distance from the top of the page (in inches) in the Top position of bitmap field.
</description>
			</case>
			<case>
				<description>2. Enter the distance from the left side of the page (in inches) in the Left position of bitmap field.
</description>
			</case>
			
			
		</cases>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, clear the Convert color to gray check box.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, change the Grayscale level value. 100 is the maximum and makes the image very light. 0 is the minimum and shows the image at full intensity.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click [binoculars_img] to view the underlying Xbasic of the operation.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Optionally, click Preview Page to view the new PDF file.
</description>
	</step>
	<step>
		<description>Click OK to convert the file. After the process is completed, the utility will present an option to view the result.
</description>
	</step>
	
	
</steps>	
	
	
</section>		
		
	</sections>
	
<links>
	<link href="images/Encrypt_icon.gif">key_img</link>
	<link href="images/Word_icon.gif">w_img</link>
	<link href="images/IE_icon.gif">e_img</link>
	<link href="images/Notepad_icon.gif">text_img</link>
	<link href="images/Preview_Button.gif">binoculars_img</link>
	<link href="images/View_Xbasic_Button.gif">glasses_img</link>
	<link href="images/Load_button_2.gif">folder_img</link>
</links>	
	
	<see>
		<ref>Print and PDF Functions</ref>
		<ref>Print Topics</ref>
		<ref>Report Topics</ref>
		<ref>Print Options Dialog</ref>
		
		
	</see>
</page>