<page>
	<topic>Publishing Security Files</topic>
<description>After you have defined security settings, page security, and a login dialog component, you need to publish these files to the Application Server.</description>	
<sections>
	<section>
		<title>UPDATE</title>
		<note>This page needs an update</note>
	</section>
<section>
	<cases>
		<case>
			<title>Guid.SecuritySettings </title>
			<description>This is a simple text file that contains a unique identifier to identify the current project folder when validating security for every page request. If it is missing, the server can not identify the project and will block all pages and files.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Project.SecuritySettings </title>
			<description>This file contains the main security parameters set in the security settings genie. Even if security is set as off in the genie, this file must be present in the published project folder. If it is missing, the server can not can not determine the security configuration and will block all pages and files.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>Pages.SecuritySettings </title>
			<description>This is a simple text file that contains the permissions for every page. If security is turned on in the security settings, this file must be present. If the file does not exist, the server will redirect the user to the login denied page. No other page will be available.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>SecurityGroups.SecuritySettings </title>
			<description>This contains the security group definitions and is not needed for most normal operation. It is only used in the code used for a dialog component to show the current user security group assignments. If it is missing and a dialog using the code is opened, no security groups will be shown on the dialog; if the record is saved, all user permissions will be removed.</description>
		</case>
		<case>
			<title>SecurityQuestions.SecuritySettings</title>
			<description>This text contains a list of security questions that may be used for user validation. It is only used in a dialog component to show security questions that may be available for selection. If it is missing and a dialog using the code is opened, the dialog will not display any questions. as a result, the record cannot be saved.</description>
		</case>
		
		
	</cases>
	
	
	
</section>	
	
	
</sections>	
	<limitations>Web publishing applications only.</limitations>
<see>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Defining Security Settings">Defining Security Settings</ref>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Defining Page Security">Defining Page Security</ref>
	<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Creating Login Components">Creating Login Components</ref>
	
</see>	
</page>