<page>
    <shortlink>ux controlbar items item properties item type property</shortlink>
    <topic>Item type</topic>
    <description>Specify the item type. If you just want to insert some text into the ControlBar, select 'html'.</description>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>html</title>
            <description>Used to display text on the ControlBar. The text can include any HTML markup and use Client-side templating features to reference ControlBar data. For example, if the ControlBar data contains a variable called *[html:Name]*, then the HTML can reference the data using *[html:{Name}]*.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>button</title>
            <description>
                <p>Used to display a button on the ControlBar. The button will invoke an *[ui:Action]*, defined on the *[ui:Actions]* tab. </p>
                <p>The *[ui:Pre-defined buttons]* hyperlink can be used to select from a sections of pre-defined buttons to add to the ControlBar. Pre-defined buttons exist for submitting or resetting UX controls, List Detail View buttons, List Search Part buttons, List Navigation buttons, and setting the active panel.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/buttonItem.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>button-toggle</title>
            <description>Used to display a toggle button on the ControlBar. The button can be set to toggle two or more states. The button will change to the next state when tapped. If the final state has been reached, it cycles back to the first state.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>button-list</title>
            <description>Used to display a button  list on the ControlBar. The button list can be configured to behave like a radio button group (where only one button can be selected at a time) or a checklist where multiple buttons can be selected simultaneously. Tapping a button toggles between its selected and deselected state.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>disclosure-button</title>
            <description>Used to display a disclosure. A disclosure is similar to a pop-up window with additional content.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>edit</title>
            <description>Used to display an edit control in the ControlBar. Typically used to prompt for a value, such as a search string.</description>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>
