<page>
	<shortlink>Security for Your Database</shortlink>
	<topic>Securing Your Database in Desktop Applications</topic>
	<description>Alpha Anywhere provides numerous ways for you to protect your desktop application design and the data in your database.</description>
	<sections>
		<section>
			<description>A good starting point when deciding what security measures to implement is to look at the [Startup Event Sequence].</description>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Protecting Your Desktop Application Design</title>
			<description>The best way to protect your application design is to:</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Compile your scripts and functions into a binary .AEX file. This makes it impossible for someone to see their source code.</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>	
		<section>
			<title>Controlling Access to Data</title>
			<description>There are several ways to control access to the data in your database.</description>
			<cases>
				<case>
					<description>Require a master password to open the database</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Create a list of authorized users with individual passwords</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Create one or more groups of users</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Assign privileges to application objects (tables, forms, etc.) to groups</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Encrypt passwords and limit the number of login attempts</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Run a script when Alpha Anywhere opens a database</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Hide the Control Panel to prevent access to developer tools</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Customize the menus and toolbars that appear to control access to tables, tools, and layouts</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Encrypt tables to prevent them from being read by other programs</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Password protect layouts (forms, browses, reports, etc.)</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Run a script when Alpha Anywhere closes a database</description>
				</case>
				<case>
					<description>Run a script after Alpha Anywhere closes a database</description>
				</case>
			</cases>
		</section>	
	</sections>
	<limitations>Desktop Applications Only</limitations>
	<links>
		<link href="Startup Event Sequence.xml">Startup Event Sequence</link>
	</links>
	<see>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Startup Event Sequence">Startup Event Sequence</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Object Permissions">Object Permissions</ref>
		<ref href="/documentation/index?search=Users and Groups">Users and Groups</ref>
	</see>
</page>