<page>
    <shortlink>ux formview builder group properties</shortlink>
    <topic>Group Properties</topic>
    <description>The *[ui:Create/manage/edit Groups]* link is used to create, manage, and edit Group Editors for the FormView control.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>Groups can be used to edit multiple fields at once. For example, assume the FormView control contains the following fields:</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item><name>Address</name></item>
                <item><name>City</name></item>
                <item><name>State</name></item>
                <item><name>Zip</name></item>
                <item><name>Country</name></item>
            </list>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>When the user taps on any one of these fields in the form, you would like the Editor shown to display edit controls for all of the fields - not just the field the user tapped on.</p>
                <p>This is accomplished by defining a Group and setting the *[link:Group name@ux formview builder editing Group name]* property for ech fields to this group.</p>
                <p>You will need to specify that the Editor used to edit this group includes text box controls for each feild in the group.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/groupDialog.png</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Introduction to Group Editors</title>
                <description>
                    <p>The common pattern when using a FormView control is to edit a single value in a FormView with its associated editor at a time. For example, when the user clicks on 'field1' in the FormView, the associated editor for 'field1' is shown and the user can edit the value in 'field1'. </p>
                    <p>In some cases, however, you might want to edit the value of multiple fields simultaneously. For example, if the user fields on ANY of 'field1', 'field2', or 'field3', for example, you might want to open an editor that allows you to edit all of the fields at once. </p>
                    <p> This is easily accomplished using the concept of 'Group Editors'. </p>
                    <p>In this video we show how the Address, City, State and Country field in a form are edited using a Group Editor for this group of fields.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2015-08-13</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>https://www.viddler.com/v/2afc6672</link>
                </video>
                <resources>
                    <resource>
                        <link>http://www.ajaxvideotutorials.com/V12Videos/FormView_GroupEditors.zip</link>
                    </resource>
                </resources>
            </videos>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Group Properties</title>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Property</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Group name</name>
                    <description>The name of the group that appears in the list when setting the *[link:Group]* property for a field.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Method for specifying Editor set/Editor</name>
                    <description>If you select 'Static' then you can specify the Editor Set and Editor for this field now. If you specify 'Javascript Function' or 'Javascript Code' you can dynamically specify the Editor Set and Editor at run-time. See the *[link:Method for specifying Editor set/Editor@ux formview builder editing Method for specifying Editor editor set]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Editor set</name>
                    <description>The Editor set that contains the Editor used to edit the value in the field. See the *[link:Editor set@ux formview builder editing Editor set]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Editor</name>
                    <description>The Editor used to edit the value in the field. See the *[link:Editor@ux formview builder editing Editor]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript function to specify Editor set/Editor</name>
                    <description>See the *[link:Javascript function to specify Editor set/Editor@ux formview builder editing javascript function to specify editor seteditor property]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>Javascript Code to specify Editor set/Editor</name>
                    <description>See the *[link:Javascript Code to specify Editor set/Editor@ux formview builder editing javascript code to specify editor set/editor property]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>User defined editor settings</name>
                    <description>Custom settings that can be added. See the *[link:User defined editor and template settings@ux formview builder editor settings user defined editor and template settings]* property for more information.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
</page>