<page build="5441">
    <shortlink>ux list hasnavigationbar</shortlink>
    <topic>Has Navigation Bar</topic>
    <description>Enables or disables the built-in List Control Navigation Bar. Available in a paginated List control using the "NavigationButtons" *[ui:Pagination method]*.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The image below shows a List with a Navigation Bar. The Navigation bar has been configured to show an input control for the current page number. The user can enter a target page number into the input control and press Enter to navigate directly to the target page. The Navigation Bar also shows a 'records per page' selector so the user can dynamically change the number of records per page.</p>
        <p>The number of target buttons before and after the current page number can be configured. In the image below, the Navigation Bar has been configured to show a total of 6 target buttons.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <figure>
                <link>images/recnavbar.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>In the image below, the Navigation Bar does not show a 'records per page' selector. The current page number is shown using a disabled button (rather than an input control as shown in the above example) and there are no target buttons before or after the current page number. </p>
                <p>Also, the Navigation Bar has bee configured to display in the List itself (in the List Header or List Footer section). In the above example, the Navigation Bar display outside the List at a location specified by a placeholder DIV in the UX component. </p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/navbar1.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>If you are using a 'version 4' style (e.g. 'Alpha', or any style inherited from 'Alpha', such as 'Alpha-Rose') you can choose a compact style for the Navigation Bar buttons, as shown in the image below.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/navbarcompact.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Adding the Navigation Bar</title>
            <description>
                <p>To turn on the Navigation Bar, check the *[ui:Has Navigation Bar]* property in the List Builder on the Data Source pane.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/navbar2.gif</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuring the Navigation Bar</title>
            <description>
                <p>To configure the Navigation Bar, click the *[ui:Navigation Bar settings]* smart field.</p>
                <p>This will open the builder where you can set properties for the Navigation Bar.</p>
            </description>
            <figure>
                <link>images/navbarsettings.jpg</link>
            </figure>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>See [Navigation Bar settings] for more information about how to configure the Navigation Bar.</p>
            </description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Videos</title>
            <videos>
                <title>Page Navigation Bar</title>
                <description>
                    <p>In a Grid component you can add a Navigation Bar to allow the user to navigate from one 'page' or records to another. In a List control (that is based on a SQL database, has pagination tuned on and has the pagination method set to Navigation Buttons), you can also add a Navigation Bar to allow the user to navigate from one 'page' or records to another.</p>
                    <p> In this video we show how to configure a List control to display a Navigation Bar.</p>
                </description>
                <date>2018-11-05</date>
                <video>
                    <name>Watch Video</name>
                    <link>http://www.viddler.com/v/e75af277</link>
                </video>
            </videos>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux list navigationbar settings">Navigation Bar settings</link>
    </links>
</page>