<page build="5441">
    <shortlink>ux list navigationbar settings</shortlink>
    <topic>Navigation Bar settings</topic>
    <description>If enabled, the Navigation Bar settings are used to configure the List Control's Navigation Bar. The Navigation Bar can be shown either in the List's footer or in a DIV in the UX Component.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p>The List Control supports using a Navigation Bar for navigate pages of records in a List based on a SQL Data Source. The List must be configured to use Pagination with the *[ui:Pagination method]* set to "NavigationBar". The *[ui:Navigation Bar settings]* are used to configure the built-in Navigation Bar, which can be turned on by checking the [Has Navigation Bar] property.</p>
        <p>The built-in Navigation Bar offers several advantages over the [List-Navigation Buttons] and [List-Navigation Icons] pre-built controls for List navigation. While these controls can be used to add navigation to a UX Component for a paginated List Control, the List-Navigation Buttons and Icons have several drawbacks:</p>
        <p>
            <list bullet="true">
                <item>
                    <name>List-Navigation Buttons and Icons do not include numbers for pages relative to the current page.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>If the List Control is duplicated, you must manually add the List-Navigation Buttons and Icons for the new List.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>If the List Control is copied to another Component, you must manually copy the List-Navigation Buttons and Icons.</name>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>If the List Control's name changes (such as when it is copied to another UX that already contains a list with the same name), you must manually update the List-Navigation Buttons and Icons to use the new List name.</name>
                </item>
            </list>
        </p>
        <p>The Navigation Bar can be placed in the List Footer or a custom DIV on the page. For information on where you can go to extend the buttons with custom client-side JavaScript, see [Events] below.</p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <title>Properties</title>
            <description>
                <p>The properties available to you for configuring the built-in Navigation Bar for a List Control are explained below:</p>
            </description>
            <cases>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Number of buttons</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>This setting controls the number of "target page" buttons shown in the Navigation Bar. The target page buttons are shown for pages before and after the current page. If the user is not on the first or last page of the List, the target page buttons are distributed equally about the current page. For example, if the user is on page 10 of 20 and *[ui:Number of buttons]* has been set to 6, target buttons will be shown for pages 7, 8, 9, 11, 12, and 13.</p>
                        <p>To control whether or not the current page number is shown, see *[ui:Show current page number]* below.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar with 6 target buttons on first page.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsFirstPage.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar with 6 target buttons on page 10.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsPage10.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar with 6 target buttons on last page.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsLastPage.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">First record icon</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:First record icon]* is the icon shown for the button to navigate to the very first page of data in the List Control. The default image used is the one defined for the {images.grid.firstPage} placeholder. The image can be any image, SVG Icon, or Font Icon.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/buttonsFirst.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Previous record icon</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Previous record icon]* is the icon shown for the button to navigate to the previous page of data in the List Control relative to the current page. The default image used is the one defined for the {images.grid.prevPage} placeholder. The image can be any image, SVG Icon, or Font Icon.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/buttonsPrev.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Next record icon</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Next record icon]* is the icon shown for the button to navigate to the next page of data in the List Control relative to the current page. The default image used is the one defined for the {images.grid.nextPage} placeholder. The image can be any image, SVG Icon, or Font Icon.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/buttonsNext.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Last record icon</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Last record icon]* is the icon shown for the button to navigate to the very last page of data in the List Control. The default image used is the one defined for the {images.grid.lastPage} placeholder. The image can be any image, SVG Icon, or Font Icon.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/buttonsLast.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Button size</title>
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Size</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Normal</name>
                                    <description></description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Compact</name>
                                    <description>Uses the "compact" theme for the style. This style is more appropriate in a desktop web application.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>This property only applies if you are using a Version 4 style, such as the 'Alpha' style.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>"Normal" Navigation Bar buttons.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsNormal.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>"Compact" Navigation Bar buttons.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsCompact.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Buttons using the 'GrBlue' theme. The 'GrBlue' theme does not support the Button Size property.</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsGrBlue.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Navigation Bar justification</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The Navigation Bar's alignment can be controlled using the *[ui:Navigation Bar justification]* property. The following alignment options are available:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list bullet="true">
                                <item>
                                    <name>Left</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Center</name>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Right</name>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>The alignment only applies if the *[ui:Navigation bar placement]* has been set to "ListFooter".</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show current page number</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, the page number will be shown in the Navigation Bar. Use the *[ui:Current page number template]* property to specify how the page number is displayed.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Current page number template</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>This property defines the template for the current page number. The template can include any HTML you want as well as the following place holders:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Placeholder</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>{pageNumber}</name>
                                    <description>The current page number.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>{pageCount}</name>
                                    <description>The total page count.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                        <p>For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[{pageNumber} of {pageCount}]]></example>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar using the template *[cst:{pageNumber} of {pageCount}]*</title>
                        <link>images/buttonsPageTemplate.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <important>
                        <p>If the *[cst:{pageNumber}]* placeholder is not included in the template, the page number will not be shown. Similarly, if *[ui:Show input control for current page number]* has been enabled and the *[cst:{pageNumber}]* placeholder is not used in the template, the textbox for entering the page number will also not be shown.</p>
                    </important>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show input control for current page number</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, the *[cst:{pageNumber}]* placeholder will be rendered as a textbox in the Navigation Bar. allowing the user to change the current page by typing the page number.</p>
                        <p>This option is only available if *[ui:Show current page number]* has been checked.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/barPageInput.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Target page input control size</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If *[ui:Show input control for current page number]* has been checked, this property is shown. The *[ui:Target page input control size]* defines the width of the textbox shown for the page number. The width is specified using CSS units. For example, *[css:100px]*, *[css:1in]*, or *[css:50%]*.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Show page size selector</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If checked, a dropdown box will be added to the Navigation Bar allowing the user to change the number of records per page.</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/barPageSizeSelector.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Page sizes</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If *[ui:Show page size selector]* has been checked, the *[ui:Page sizes]* property is available. This property is used to define the page sizes available for the user to choose from for the List Control.</p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Page size selector template</title>
                    <description>
                        <p></p>
                    </description>
                    <example><![CDATA[Page size: {pageSizeSelector}]]></example>
                    <figure>
                        <link>images/barPageSelectorTemplate.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Navigation bar placement</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>The *[ui:Navigation bar placement]* defines where to render the List's Navigation Bar. It can be placed in one of two locations:</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Location</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>ListFooter</name>
                                    <description>The Navigation Bar will be placed in the footer of the List control. The *[ui:List footer placement]* property can be used to control where the Navigation Bar should appear relative to any custom footer HTML content that has been defined.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>Custom</name>
                                    <description>The Navigation Bar will be placed in a custom location. The locations defined using the *[ui:Navigation Bar div]* property, which specifies the ID of a DIV on the UX component where the Navigation Bar should be placed.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">List footer placement</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Navigation bar placement]* has been set to "ListFooter", this property can be used to configure where the Navigation Bar should be shown relative to any custom content in the List Footer.</p>
                        <p>
                            <list>
                                <item>
                                    <name-title>Location</name-title>
                                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>AboveUserContent</name>
                                    <description>The Navigation Bar will be shown above any custom footer content.</description>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <name>BelowUserContent</name>
                                    <description>The Navigation Bar will be shown below any custom footer content.</description>
                                </item>
                            </list>
                        </p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar placement set to "AboveUserContent"</title>
                        <link>images/barAboveFooter.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <figure>
                        <title>Navigation Bar placement set to "BelowUserContent"</title>
                        <link>images/barBelowFooter.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <title nested="2">Navigation Bar div</title>
                    <description>
                        <p>If the *[ui:Navigation bar placement]* has been set to "Custom", this property can be used to configure where the Navigation Bar should be shown. You must specify the ID of a DIV in the UX Component. The DIV can be an HTML DIV element in the UX Component. It can also be the ID of a Static Text or Placeholder control. For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <example caption="The DIV can be the ID of a Static Text Control. This example demonstrates how you would specify the ID for a Static Text control with the name 'STATICTEXT_1'."><![CDATA[{dialog.componentName}.V.R1.STATICTEXT_1]]></example>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Navigation Bar placed in a DIV in a Static Text Control inside a Panel Footer.</title>
                        <link>images/barInPanelFooterDiv.png</link>
                    </figure>
                </case>
                <case>
                    <description>
                        <p>You can also an Injectible Container with a DIV in it. This makes it easier to embed the Navigation Bar in other places in the UX Component. For example:</p>
                    </description>
                    <figure>
                        <title>The Navigation Bar is easily placed in Fixed List Footer using an Injectible Container.</title>
                        <link>images/barInjectible.png</link>
                    </figure>
                    <note>*[link:Click here@./components/listNavInAnInjectibleContainer.zip]* to download an example component that demonstrates using an Injectible Container to inject the Navigation Bar in a Fixed List Footer.</note>
                </case>
            </cases>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Events</title>
            <description>You can use the following List Control events to add custom JavaScript to execute when the user navigates the List:</description>
            <list>
                <item>
                    <name-title>Event</name-title>
                    <description-title>Description</description-title>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[onNavigate]</name>
                    <description>Fires when the List has been navigated.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[beforePageNavigate]</name>
                    <description>Fires before an Ajax Callback to navigate to a different page of records.</description>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <name>[afterPageNavigate]</name>
                    <description>Fires after an Ajax Callback to fetch more records has completed.</description>
                </item>
            </list>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <links>
        <link link="ux list hasnavigationbar">Has Navigation Bar</link>
        <link href="#section1_Events">Events</link>
        <link link="ux defined controls list navigation icons">List-Navigation Buttons</link>
        <link link="ux defined controls list navigation buttons">List-Navigation Icons</link>
        <link link="ux list clientside event onnavigate">onNavigate</link>
        <link link="ux list clientside event beforepagenavigate">beforePageNavigate</link>
        <link link="ux list clientside event afterpagenavigate">afterPageNavigate</link>
    </links>
</page>