<page>
    <shortlink>data series editor defining data extraction templates</shortlink>
    <topic>Defining Data Extraction Templates</topic>
    <description>The Data Extraction Template defines how a SQL-CrossSection or DBF-CrossSection series is created by extracting data from the columns in a record.</description>
    <discussion>
        <p></p>
    </discussion>
    <sections>
        <section>
            <description>The data extraction template enables you to create a data series from multiple columns in a result set. Each field in a result set is referenced using curly brace syntax. For example, the example below would create a data series that groups three fields from the result set into a single series:</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{field1}
{field2}
{field3}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>Values that are not enclosed in curly braces are treated as static values.</p>
                <p>Multiple sub-series can be defined by separating each value with a pipe "|". The label for each sub-series is specified in the first row of the template. The sub-series label row is required if multiple sub-series are defined.</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[subseriesLabel1|subseriesLabel2|subseriesLabel3
staticValue1|{field1}|{field2}
staticValue2|{field3}|{field4}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>If a data series only contains one sub-series, the sub-series label can be omitted.</description>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Data Extraction Template Examples</title>
            <description>This template creates a series of values with data from the following fields in a result set: 'Sales_01', 'Sales_02', 'Sales_03'. This series does not define any sub-series, therefore the sub-series labels are not necessary.</description>
            <example><![CDATA[{Sales_01}
{Sales_02}
{Sales_03}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This template creates a series with two sub-series. The first sub-series is a list of static values. The second sub-series is data from the following fields in a result set: 'Sales_01', 'Sales_02', 'Sales_03'.</p>
                <p>This series specifies two sub-series; therefore the first line of the template must define the sub-series labels.</p>
            </description>
            <example><![CDATA[Month|Sales
Jan|{Sales_01}
Feb|{Sales_02}
Mar|{Sales_03}]]></example>
        </section>
        <section>
            <description>
                <p>This template demonstrates creating three sub-series. The first sub-series is a list of static values. The second sub-series is data from the following fields in the result set: 'Sales_01', 'Sales_02', 'Sales_03'. The third sub-series is data from the following fields in the result set: 'PrevSales_01', 'PrevSales_02', 'PrevSales_03'</p>
                <p>Because this series has multiple sub-series, the sub-series labels must be specified on the first row of the template.</p>
            </description>
                <example><![CDATA[Month|SalesCurrentYear|SalesPreviousYear
Jan|{Sales_01}|{PrevSales_01}
Feb|{Sales_02}|{PrevSales_02}
Mar|{Sales_03}|{PrevSales_03}]]></example>
        </section>
    </sections>
    <see>
        <ref link="how to base a chart on cross sectional data">How to Base a Chart on Cross-sectional Data</ref>
    </see>
</page>